<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Let&amp;#039;s Encrypt tls-sni-01 disabled due to credible vulnerability report</title>
<link>https://letsencrypt.status.io/pages/incident/55957a99e800baa4470002da/5a55777ed9a9c1024c00b241</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://letsencrypt.status.io/pages/incident/55957a99e800baa4470002da/5a55777ed9a9c1024c00b241</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-12 col-md-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pull-left text event_inner_title&quot;&gt;Components&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-12 col-md-10&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;incident_section event_inner_text&quot;&gt;acme-staging-v02.api.letsencrypt.org (Staging), acme-staging.api.letsencrypt.org (Staging), acme-v01.api.letsencrypt.org (Production)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-xs-12 col-md-10&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;incident_section event_inner_text&quot;&gt;High Assurance Datacenter 1, High Assurance Datacenter 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;incident_time&quot;&gt;January 10, 2018 09:35 UTC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Identified]&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;statusio_incident_message_5a55de7fc57eca4cc552e3df&quot; class=&quot;incident_message_details&quot;&gt;Update regarding TLS-SNI validation can be found here: https://community.letsencrypt.org/t/2018-01-09-issue-with-tls-sni-01-and-shared-hosting-infrastructure/49996&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;incident_time&quot;&gt;January 10, 2018 02:16 UTC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Investigating]&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;statusio_incident_message_5a55777ed9a9c1024c00b246&quot; class=&quot;incident_message_details&quot;&gt;The tls-sni challenge has been disabled due to strong credibility of a vulnerability report.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 02:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>regecks</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://letsencrypt.status.io/pages/incident/55957a99e800baa4470002da/5a55777ed9a9c1024c00b241</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Type of Road Junction that Kills Cyclists</title>
<link>http://singletrackworld.com/2018/01/collision-course-why-this-type-of-road-junction-will-keep-killing-cyclists/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://singletrackworld.com/2018/01/collision-course-why-this-type-of-road-junction-will-keep-killing-cyclists/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Ipley Cross is a largely unremarkable place, an open plain where two roads cross: Beaulieu Road running north-to-south and Dibden Bottom running roughly east-to-west.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Yet it is a place of notoriety. For good reason.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Two Deaths And A Lucky Escape&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;In August 2011 a 15 year old boy was cycling along Beaulieu Road when he was struck from his left by a driver who failed to see him and failed to give way at the junction. The boy was sent flying, but somehow escaped with only a broken collarbone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;In May 2012 a second, almost identical incident occurred. Mark Brummell was cycling along Beaulieu Road when he was struck from his left by Stephen Chard, who failed to see Brummell and failed to give way at the junction. Brummell was killed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;In December 2016 a third, almost identical incident occurred. Kieran Dix was cycling along Beaulieu Road when he was struck from his left by Viral Parekh, who failed to see Dix and failed to give way at the junction. &lt;a href=&quot;https://beyondthekerb.org.uk/incident/4103/&quot;&gt;Dix, too, was fatally injured.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Chard was charged with causing death by careless driving and pleaded guilty; Parekh was charged with causing death by dangerous driving and pleaded guilty to causing death by careless driving, but was found not guilty of the more serious offence by a jury despite having driven through the junction’s “give way” line at 37mph without slowing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Two questions present themselves.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Firstly, why it that the same collision keeps occurring at this junction? And secondly, why is such a standard of driving considered only to be “careless” rather than “dangerous”?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;As we shall see, the answers to both are closely related.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;By understanding one of the most likely causes for “failure to see” collisions at this junction, not only can we answer those questions but we can offer surprisingly straightforward solutions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Existing Layout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Ipley crossroads has a very simple layout: two straight sections of road cross at an angle of 69 degrees, with the north-south road (Beaulieu Road) having priority.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-4716 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://beyondthekerb.org.uk/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ipley-cross.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;The innocuous, yet dangerous Ipley crossroads
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Sight lines are good, although &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/Yo8zWHf69Dq&quot;&gt;the rightward view from the easterly approach&lt;/a&gt; is affected somewhat by a gentle slope which rises to the northeast of the junction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;So, if it’s so easy to see, why is it apparently so easy to &lt;em&gt;fail&lt;/em&gt; to see?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hidden In Plain View&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Far and away the most plausible answer is a phenomenon known as “constant bearing, decreasing range”, or CBDR. Originally noted by sailors, it is the phenomenon whereby two vessels, or vehicles, moving at steady speeds in straight lines towards a collision will maintain the same bearing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;If you’re a dab hand with basic trigonometry, you can probably figure the principles out for yourself, but if not then of course &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constant_bearing,_decreasing_range&quot;&gt;Wikipedia has an explanation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBDR is required knowledge in maritime and aviation, where ships and aircraft travel significant distances with constant speed and bearing, but it is rarely taught in the context of highways, where motion is generally less constant. But it is nonetheless important where two straight routes cross: not just two roads, but also where roads and railways cross at unsignalled level crossings (a design which is rarely if ever found in the UK but which is not uncommon in parts of the US).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Sailors and pilots are taught to detect ships and planes at a constant bearing and to take avoiding action. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;When it comes to drivers, however, things are very different, because almost all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt; motor vehicles have a design flaw which means not only that a CBDR condition precedes a collision, but that unless (as we shall see) the driver does one of two things, the same condition means that the driver will never even see the phenomenon occurring.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;That design flaw is the front ‘A’ pillar, at the edge of the windscreen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Pillar Shadow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Take a look at this plan view of a Vauxhall Zafira (as driven by Viral Parekh). When the driver looks towards the horizon, the front pillar will obscure some of the view. The red ellipse represents an approximate cross section at that point, with the shaded area beyond it being obscured as a result.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-4721 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://beyondthekerb.org.uk/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/zafira-pillar.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;280&quot; /&gt;The driver’s blind spot in a &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Vauxhall Zafira.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Once you extrapolate that obscured area, the extent of its effect is obvious. Here’s the same set of lines drawn on the Zafira, scaled up and overlaid on Ipley Cross.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-4717 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://beyondthekerb.org.uk/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ipley-cross-pillar-shadow.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;A projection of the driver’s blind spot.
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;At the position shown, approximately 100m from the junction at Ipley Cross, the pillar obscures roughly 12m of Beaulieu road. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;That’s six bicycle lengths: enough to hide not just a cyclist but a small group of riders.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Of course, as the driver approaches that junction, that obscured section of road moves towards the junction with them. As does the cyclist.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Parekh’s car had a black box type device, which (contrary to his statements to police) recorded his approach to the junction at a steady speed of 37mph. At this speed it would have taken six seconds to cover the 100m to the collision, and the following image shows the approximate areas obscured by the Zafira’s pillar at six points in time representing each incremental second leading up to impact, with the red area showing the pillar shadow one second prior to impact.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-4718 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://beyondthekerb.org.uk/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ipley-cross-pillar-shadows-6-seconds.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;The obscured section of road becomes smaller as the driver nears the intersection.
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Although the obscured section of road becomes smaller as the driver approaches, it remains large enough to completely obscure a bicycle until less than a second prior to impact: too late for either party to react.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;The light blue line in the following diagram represents the approximate length of a bicycle and fits comfortably within the pillar shadow at one second before impact.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-4720 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://beyondthekerb.org.uk/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ipley-cross-pillar-shadows-bike-zoom.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;The light blue line represents the cyclist.
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Naturally, as per the conditions of a collision course being signalled by a constant bearing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;, for any speed of the approaching car there is a speed at which a cyclist will remain obscured by the front pillar almost until the point of impact. The angles of the triangles define a ratio of speeds, and with this geometry that ratio is a little over 3:1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;So, in the case of a vehicle moving at 37mph westwards along Dibden Bottom, the CBDR speed southbound along Beaulieu Road is roughly 13.5mph. A very plausible speed for a cyclist.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;But such a degree of coincidence is actually not required.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Due to the width of the pillar and the extent shadow it casts, which is much larger than a bicycle until impact is inevitable, true CBDR is not even necessary: it would be perfectly possible for a cyclist to be moving at around 17.5mph and then hit the brakes two seconds prior to impact, without ever appearing in the driver’s view. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;There’s a whole range of steady speeds at which someone could approach this junction from the north and remain obscured to a driver approaching at a steady speed from the east (and, likewise, also from the south and east respectively).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Crucially, for any likely speed of an approaching car, any speed in that range is a perfectly feasible speed for a cyclist.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s one more thing about Ipley Cross that makes it especially dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Critical Angles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keen triangle enthusiasts may have started thinking about this already, but there are of course three angles to consider here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the angle between the two approach paths, which is a constant value defined by the road. At Ipley Cross this is 69 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is the angle between the driver’s line of travel and the line from their eyes to the front pillar. This will vary depending on the vehicle and the driver, but the approximations above put the angle at around 17 degrees to the centre of the pillar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third is the angle between the cyclist’s line of travel and the line from their eyes to the vehicle which will hit them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this location, with this vehicle, it is 94 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A car which is on a collision course at Ipley Cross with a cyclist who is obscured from the driver’s view by the front pillar &lt;em&gt;will approach the cyclist from behind&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ipley Cross is constructed in such a way that not only is it possible for a careless driver to drive straight into a cyclist without seeing them until a fraction of a second before impact, but under the exact same circumstances it is also possible for that cyclist not to see the car that hits them until the same moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone were to take a highway engineer to a wide open space and ask them to design a junction which would readily enable two road users to collide with neither of them ever seeing each other, I doubt any would be able to manage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet this is precisely what exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exact numbers, of course, depend on the driver’s height and seating position, the geometry of their vehicle, and—if you wanted to apply this to other locations—the angle at which the roads meet. The 3:1 speed ratio will vary slightly according to all these factors, and it will not always be the case that the deadly vehicle will be so hard for its victim to see, but the angle between a driver’s line of travel and the line between their eyes and the pillar will always be such that it is the slower road user who is at risk of not being seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is this: given the design of almost every motor vehicle on the road, the crossing of two straight roads can make for a perfect storm when combined with typical speeds of drivers and cyclists. Ipley Cross represents possibly the most perfect of such storms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These collisions are, therefore, inevitable—aren’t they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Human Error: The Eternal Excuse&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;“None of us are perfect drivers,” remarked Parekh’s defence barrister, attributing the whole affair to “human error”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;The human error in this case, and the other cases, may have been for the drivers to have maintained a constant speed (as we know Parekh did) without having physically moved their head either side of the pillar to rigorously scan the area ahead and to their right.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;There are two very simple solutions to the very real risk of a driver-vs-cyclist CBDR collision.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Firstly, by slowing down significantly, any vehicle approaching from the right at a constant speed will move out of the obscured area and into view at the right of the windscreen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;And secondly, significant movement of the head will bring previously obscured sections of road into view.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;It’s quite plausible that these simple strategies—either of them—could have prevented two fatalities at this one junction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;One of those strategies can, however, be easily enforced.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Simple Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;In 2015, nearly three years after the death of Mark Brummell, a local resident sent a pencil sketch to councillor David Harrison, which he passed on to Hampshire County Council.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;It was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dharrison.org.uk/ipley-crossroads/&quot;&gt;a simple plan of Ipley Cross, with one modification&lt;/a&gt;: the western approach now had a short kink at its meeting with Beaulieu Road, making the junction offset.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-4722 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://beyondthekerb.org.uk/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ipley-cross-before-after.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;385&quot; /&gt;Before, and a potential after.
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;With this design, no longer would it be reasonably possible for any driver to simply blow through the junction. Drivers would have to come almost to a stop.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;This design would, very simply, force the slowing down that eliminates the problem of CBDR.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;The image above is, of course, a mock-up. The junction was never altered.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Two years after that simple sketch was handed to the authority responsible for the junction, Kieran Dix was dead.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Is This Not Dangerous?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;And, lest we forget: what of the criminal proceedings against Parekh? Why is it not deemed “dangerous” to approach this junction at 37mph without slowing?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;We must note that there are two parts to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1988/52/section/2A&quot;&gt;the definition of dangerous driving&lt;/a&gt;. Firstly the standard of driving must be “far below what would be expected of a competent and careful driver”, and secondly it must be “obvious to a competent and careful driver that driving in that way would be dangerous”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;People are often drawn to the term “far below”, which offers only a vague difference from “below” as used in the definition of careless driving, but generally &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;problematic clause is more likely the latter: it simply doesn’t matter how dangerous the driving is if it’s not &lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;/em&gt; that it’s dangerous.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;If we don’t teach people that to approach a junction at a constant speed is inherently dangerous, and if we don’t offer a basic explanation as to why, then it is surely not obvious to most people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Human error” may be real, but so are techniques to mitigate or eliminate its effects—and driver training is poor when it comes to equipping people with those techniques, let alone habituating them. (And let alone reviewing knowledge of those techniques every few years.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;It would appear from media reports that Parekh’s defence was simply that he did not see Dix; the implied logic being that since he saw no other vehicles he felt no compulsion to slow down. The jury’s acquittal equally implies that they agree with this logic: it was not &lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;/em&gt; to them that failing to see another vehicle is anything other than unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, once the nature of a collision course is explained, the need to slow down becomes obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truly contemptible human error is not in a single person carelessly failing to see. It is in our failure to continually improve the training and licensing system so as to render the need to slow down &lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;/em&gt;; it is in our incessant support of a system which cries “human error” as an excuse to do nothing, rather than as a stimulus to understand that error in order to create a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Constant Bearing, Reducing Distance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;So we can easily answer both of our original questions: why the same collision keeps occurring at this junction, and why driving straight through it at a steady 37mph is not deemed “dangerous” by law.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;The question we still &lt;em&gt;can’t&lt;/em&gt; answer is that of why, when clear solutions to both problems exist, no-one ever does anything about it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We remain on the same bearing, heading for the next collision.&lt;/p&gt;




</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 02:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>thebent</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://singletrackworld.com/2018/01/collision-course-why-this-type-of-road-junction-will-keep-killing-cyclists/</og:url>
<og:title>Collision Course: Why This Type Of Road Junction Will Keep Killing Cyclists</og:title>
<og:description>Bez suggests that sometimes a steady driver can be the most dangerous driver</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>http://singletrackworld.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2018/01/ipley-cross-before-after.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://singletrackworld.com/2018/01/collision-course-why-this-type-of-road-junction-will-keep-killing-cyclists/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trends to Avoid When Founding a Startup</title>
<link>http://www.fast.ai/2018/01/08/startups/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://www.fast.ai/2018/01/08/startups/</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;post-date&quot;&gt;08 Jan 2018 &lt;em&gt;Rachel Thomas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;[ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fast.ai/tag/advice&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highligher-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;advice&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was inspired by a round-table discussion I led on the topics of founding start-ups and personal branding at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wimlworkshop.org/2017/&quot;&gt;Women in Machine Learning Workshop&lt;/a&gt;, co-located with deep learning conference &lt;a href=&quot;https://nips.cc/&quot;&gt;NIPS&lt;/a&gt;. I covered &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fast.ai/2017/12/18/personal-brand/&quot;&gt;personal branding in a previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first moved to San Francisco in 2012, I was thrilled by how many startups there are here; the culture seemed so creative! Then I realized that most of the startups were &lt;strong&gt;indistinguishable&lt;/strong&gt; from one another: nearly everyone was following the &lt;strong&gt;same destructive trends&lt;/strong&gt; which are &lt;strong&gt;bad for employees&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;bad for products&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are working on a startup, I want you to know that there are options in how to to do things. After working at several startups and watching friends found start-ups, I took the leap and started fast.ai, together with Jeremy Howard. We are unusual in many ways: we have no interest in growing our tiny team; we are allergic to traditional venture capital; and we don’t plan to hire any deep learning PhDs. Yet we are still having a big impact!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;image&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;http://www.fast.ai/images/nikkei.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fast.ai founders Jeremy and Rachel speaking at the Nikkei Innovation Forum&quot;/&gt; fast.ai founders Jeremy and Rachel speaking at the Nikkei Innovation Forum
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to avoid making the same mistakes that so many entrepreneurs have made, the first step is to be able to recognize them. I’ve identified 5 dominant narratives in Bay Area Tech start-ups that not only harm employees, but lead to weaker companies and worse products. This post offers a high-level overview, and I’ll dig into the trends in greater detail in future posts (adding links as I do so):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venture Capital&lt;/strong&gt; often pushes what could’ve been a successful small business to over-expand and ultimately fail; prevents companies from focusing their priorities; distracts from finding a monetization plan; causes conflict due to the misalignment of incentives between VCs and founders; and is full of far too many unethical bullies and thugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypergrowth&lt;/strong&gt; is nearly impossible to manage and leads to communication failures, redundant work, burnout, and high employee attrition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trying to be “like a family”&lt;/strong&gt; severely limits your pool of potential employees, leaves you unprepared for conflict or HR incidents, and sets employees up to feel betrayed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attempting to productionize a PhD thesis&lt;/strong&gt; is rarely a good business plan. The priorities and values of academia and business are drastically different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiring a bunch of academic researchers&lt;/strong&gt; will not improve your product and harms your company by diverting so many resources (unless your goal is an aquihire).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recognize that there are many startups following these trends that have high-valuations on paper. However, that does not mean that these companies will succeed in the long-term (we’ve already seen many highly valued, high profile startups fail in recent years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;negative-trend-1-venture-capital&quot;&gt;Negative trend 1: Venture Capital&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you were to create a business where you could profitably support yourself and 10 employees selling a product your customers liked, and after running it for 10 years you sold it for $10 million, of which half ended up in your pocket and half with your employees. Most VCs would consider that an &lt;strong&gt;abject failure&lt;/strong&gt;. They are looking for at least 100x returns, because all of their profits come from the one or two best performers in their portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, VCs often push companies to grow too quickly, before they’ve nailed down product-market fit and monetization. Growing at a slow, sustainable rate helps keep your priorities in order. Funding yourself (through part-time consulting, saving up money in advance, and/or getting a simple product to market quickly) will force you to stay smaller and grow more slowly than VC funded businesses, but &lt;strong&gt;this is good&lt;/strong&gt;. Staying small keeps you focused on a &lt;strong&gt;small number of high-impact features&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have seen a lot of deeply unethical, bullying, and downright illegal behavior by venture capitalists against close friends of mine. This is not just a few bad actors: the behavior is wide-spread, including by many well-known and ultra-wealthy investors (although founders often don’t speak out about it because of fear of professional repercussions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;negative-trend-2-hypergrowth&quot;&gt;Negative trend 2: Hypergrowth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypergrowth typically involves: &lt;strong&gt;chaos&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;inefficiency&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;severe burn-out&lt;/strong&gt; (none of which is good for your business) I’ve worked at several companies that have doubled in size in just a year. It was always painful and chaotic. Communication broke down. There was duplicate and redundant work. Company politics became increasingly destructive. Burnout was endemic and many people quit. In all cases, &lt;strong&gt;the quality of the product suffered&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management is hard, and management of hypergrowth is an order of magnitude harder. So many start-ups work their employees into the ground for the sake of short-term growth. Burnout is a very real and expensive problem in the tech industry, and hypergrowth routinely leads to burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;negative-trend-3-our-startup-is-like-a-family&quot;&gt;Negative trend 3: “Our startup is like a family”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many startups claim that they’re creating a family-like culture amongst their employees: they don’t just work together, they go out after work, share the same hobbies, and are best friends. Doing this &lt;strong&gt;severely limits&lt;/strong&gt; your pool of potential employees. Employees with &lt;strong&gt;health problems, long commutes, families, outside hobbies, outside friendships, or from under-represented groups&lt;/strong&gt; may all struggle to thrive in such a culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, you are making a promise you can’t keep, which sets people up for &lt;strong&gt;feeling betrayed&lt;/strong&gt;. You’re not actually a family; you are a company. You will need to make hard decisions for the sake of the business. You can’t actually offer people anything remotely close to lifelong loyalty or security, and it’s dishonest to implicitly do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;negative-trend-4-ai-specific-productionizing-your-phd-thesis&quot;&gt;Negative trend 4 (AI specific): Productionizing your PhD thesis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best approach to starting a start-up is to address a problem that people in the business world have. Your PhD thesis is not doing this, and it is highly unlikely that it will give you a competitive edge. You and your adviser picked your thesis topic because it’s an interesting technical problem with good opportunities to publish, &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; because it has a large opportunity for impact in an underserved market with few barriers to entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the business world, products are not evaluated on underlying theoretical novelty, but on implementation, ease-of-use, effectiveness, and how they relate to revenues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;negative-trend-5-ai-specific-hiring-a-bunch-of-phds&quot;&gt;Negative trend 5 (AI specific): Hiring a bunch of PhDs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You almost certainly do not need a bunch of PhDs. There are so many things that go into a successful product beyond the algorithm: the product-market fit, software engineering that productionizes and deploys it, the act of selling it, supporting your users, etc. And even for highly technical aspects like deep learning, fast.ai has shown that people with 1-year of coding experience can become world-class deep learning practitioners; you don’t need to hire Stanford PhDs. By diverting valuable resources into academic research at your startup, you are hurting the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-journey-to-fastai&quot;&gt;My journey to fast.ai&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst avoiding these trends, fast.ai has accomplished far more than I ever expected in our first year and a half: over 100,000 people have started our &lt;a href=&quot;http://course.fast.ai/&quot;&gt;Practical Deep Learning for Coders course&lt;/a&gt; and fast.ai students have landed new jobs, launched companies, had their work &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@timanglade/how-hbos-silicon-valley-built-not-hotdog-with-mobile-tensorflow-keras-react-native-ef03260747f3&quot;&gt;shown on HBO&lt;/a&gt;, been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/mariyayao/2017/04/10/why-we-need-to-democratize-ai-machine-learning-education/#7b9552a81197&quot;&gt;featured in Forbes&lt;/a&gt;, won hackathons, and been accepted to the Google Brain AI Residency. Fast.ai has been mentioned in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/cover-story/2017/07/the-business-of-artificial-intelligence&quot;&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/22/technology/artificial-intelligence-experts-salaries.html&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast.ai is solving a problem that I experienced first-hand: how hard it can be to break into deep learning and gain practical AI knowledge if you don’t have the “right” background and didn’t train with the academic stars of the field. I have seen and experienced some of the &lt;strong&gt;obstacles facing outsiders: inequality, discrimination, and lack of access&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up in Texas (not in a major city) and attended a poor, predominantly Black public high school that was later ranked in &lt;strong&gt;the bottom 2% of Texas schools&lt;/strong&gt;. We had far fewer resources and opportunities compared to the wealthier, predominantly White schools around us. In graduate school, the sexism and harassment I experienced led me to abandon my dreams of becoming a math professor, although &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/tech-diversity-files/if-you-think-women-in-tech-is-just-a-pipeline-problem-you-haven-t-been-paying-attention-cb7a2073b996&quot;&gt;I then experienced similar problems in the the tech industry&lt;/a&gt;. When I first became interested in deep learning in 2013, I found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/214233053&quot;&gt;experts weren’t writing down the practical methods&lt;/a&gt; they used to actually get their research to work, instead just publishing the theory. I believe deep learning will have a huge impact across all industries, and I want the creators of this technology to be a more diverse and less exclusive group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With fast.ai, I’m finally able to do work completely in line with my values, on a tiny team characterized by trust and respect. Having a small team forces us to prioritize ruthlessly, and to focus only on what we value most or think will be highest impact. Something that has surprised me with fast.ai is how much I’ve been able to invest in my own career and own skills, in ways that I never could in previous jobs. Jeremy and I are committed to fast.ai for the long term, so neither of us has any interest in burning out. We believe you can have an impact with your work, without destroying your health and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d love to see more small companies building useful products in a healthy and sustainable way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;To discuss this post at Hacker News, &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:window.location=%22http://news.ycombinator.com/submitlink?u=%22+encodeURIComponent(document.location)+%22&amp;amp;t=%22+encodeURIComponent(&amp;quot;Five%20Trends%20to%20Avoid%20When%20Founding%20a%20Startup&amp;quot;)&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rmason</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://www.fast.ai/2018/01/08/startups/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intel has released new CPU microcode for download</title>
<link>https://downloadcenter.intel.com/download/27431/Linux-Processor-Microcode-Data-File</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://downloadcenter.intel.com/download/27431/Linux-Processor-Microcode-Data-File</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The terms of the software license agreement included with any software you download will control your use of the software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;license-text&quot;&gt;INTEL SOFTWARE LICENSE AGREEMENT
&lt;p&gt;IMPORTANT - READ BEFORE COPYING, INSTALLING OR USING.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not use or load this software and any associated materials (collectively,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the &quot;Software&quot;) until you have carefully read the following terms and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;conditions. By loading or using the Software, you agree to the terms of this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agreement. If you do not wish to so agree, do not install or use the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICENSES: Please Note:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- If you are a network administrator, the &quot;Site License&quot; below shall&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;apply to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- If you are an end user, the &quot;Single User License&quot; shall apply to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- If you are an original equipment manufacturer (OEM), the &quot;OEM License&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;shall apply to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SITE LICENSE. You may copy the Software onto your organization's computers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for your organization's use, and you may make a reasonable number of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;back-up copies of the Software, subject to these conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. This Software is licensed for use only in conjunction with Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;component products. Use of the Software in conjunction with non-Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;component products is not licensed hereunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. You may not copy, modify, rent, sell, distribute or transfer any part&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of the Software except as provided in this Agreement, and you agree to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;prevent unauthorized copying of the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. You may not reverse engineer, decompile, or disassemble the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. You may not sublicense or permit simultaneous use of the Software by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more than one user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. The Software may include portions offered on terms in addition to those&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;set out here, as set out in a license accompanying those portions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SINGLE USER LICENSE. You may copy the Software onto a single computer for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;your personal, noncommercial use, and you may make one back-up copy of the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software, subject to these conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. This Software is licensed for use only in conjunction with Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;component products. Use of the Software in conjunction with non-Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;component products is not licensed hereunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. You may not copy, modify, rent, sell, distribute or transfer any part&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of the Software except as provided in this Agreement, and you agree to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;prevent unauthorized copying of the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. You may not reverse engineer, decompile, or disassemble the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. You may not sublicense or permit simultaneous use of the Software by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more than one user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. The Software may include portions offered on terms in addition to those&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;set out here, as set out in a license accompanying those portions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OEM LICENSE: You may reproduce and distribute the Software only as an&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;integral part of or incorporated in Your product or as a standalone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software maintenance update for existing end users of Your products,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;excluding any other standalone products, subject to these conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. This Software is licensed for use only in conjunction with Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;component products. Use of the Software in conjunction with non-Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;component products is not licensed hereunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. You may not copy, modify, rent, sell, distribute or transfer any part&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of the Software except as provided in this Agreement, and you agree to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;prevent unauthorized copying of the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. You may not reverse engineer, decompile, or disassemble the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. You may only distribute the Software to your customers pursuant to a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;written license agreement. Such license agreement may be a &quot;break-the-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;seal&quot; license agreement. At a minimum such license shall safeguard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel's ownership rights to the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. The Software may include portions offered on terms in addition to those&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;set out here, as set out in a license accompanying those portions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NO OTHER RIGHTS. No rights or licenses are granted by Intel to You, expressly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or by implication, with respect to any proprietary information or patent,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;copyright, mask work, trademark, trade secret, or other intellectual property&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;right owned or controlled by Intel, except as expressly provided in this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OWNERSHIP OF SOFTWARE AND COPYRIGHTS. Title to all copies of the Software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;remains with Intel or its suppliers. The Software is copyrighted and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;protected by the laws of the United States and other countries, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;international treaty provisions. You may not remove any copyright notices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from the Software. Intel may make changes to the Software, or to items&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;referenced therein, at any time without notice, but is not obligated to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;support or update the Software. Except as otherwise expressly provided, Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;grants no express or implied right under Intel patents, copyrights,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;trademarks, or other intellectual property rights. You may transfer the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software only if the recipient agrees to be fully bound by these terms and if&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you retain no copies of the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIMITED MEDIA WARRANTY. If the Software has been delivered by Intel on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;physical media, Intel warrants the media to be free from material physical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;defects for a period of ninety days after delivery by Intel. If such a defect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is found, return the media to Intel for replacement or alternate delivery of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Software as Intel may select.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EXCLUSION OF OTHER WARRANTIES. EXCEPT AS PROVIDED ABOVE, THE SOFTWARE IS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot; WITHOUT ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF ANY KIND&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INCLUDING WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, NONINFRINGEMENT, OR FITNESS FOR A&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PARTICULAR PURPOSE. Intel does not warrant or assume responsibility for the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;accuracy or completeness of any information, text, graphics, links or other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;items contained within the Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIMITATION OF LIABILITY. IN NO EVENT SHALL INTEL OR ITS SUPPLIERS BE LIABLE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER (INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, LOST PROFITS,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUSINESS INTERRUPTION, OR LOST INFORMATION) ARISING OUT OF THE USE OF OR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INABILITY TO USE THE SOFTWARE, EVEN IF INTEL HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. SOME JURISDICTIONS PROHIBIT EXCLUSION OR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIMITATION OF LIABILITY FOR IMPLIED WARRANTIES OR CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAMAGES, SO THE ABOVE LIMITATION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU. YOU MAY ALSO HAVE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OTHER LEGAL RIGHTS THAT VARY FROM JURISDICTION TO JURISDICTION.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TERMINATION OF THIS AGREEMENT. Intel may terminate this Agreement at any time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you violate its terms. Upon termination, you will immediately destroy the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software or return all copies of the Software to Intel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APPLICABLE LAWS. Claims arising under this Agreement shall be governed by the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;laws of California, excluding its principles of conflict of laws and the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Convention on Contracts for the Sale of Goods. You may not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;export the Software in violation of applicable export laws and regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel is not obligated under any other agreements unless they are in writing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and signed by an authorized representative of Intel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GOVERNMENT RESTRICTED RIGHTS. The Software is provided with &quot;RESTRICTED&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RIGHTS.&quot; Use, duplication, or disclosure by the Government is subject to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;restrictions as set forth in FAR52.227-14 and DFAR252.227-7013 et seq. or its&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;successor. Use of the Software by the Government constitutes acknowledgment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of Intel's proprietary rights therein. Contractor or Manufacturer is Intel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2200 Mission College Blvd., Santa Clara, CA 95052.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mrmondo</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://downloadcenter.intel.com/download/27431/Linux-Processor-Microcode-Data-File</og:url>
<og:title>Download Linux* Processor Microcode Data File</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Linux* Processor Microcode Data File</og:description>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://downloadcenter.intel.com/download/27431/Linux-Processor-Microcode-Data-File</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tim Sweeney on the First Version of the Unreal Editor</title>
<link>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/DavidLightbown/20180109/309414/Classic_Tools_Retrospective_Tim_Sweeney_on_the_first_version_of_the_Unreal_Editor.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/DavidLightbown/20180109/309414/Classic_Tools_Retrospective_Tim_Sweeney_on_the_first_version_of_the_Unreal_Editor.php</guid>
<description>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;The following blog post, unless otherwise noted, was written by a member of Gamasutra’s community.&lt;br/&gt;The thoughts and opinions expressed are those of the writer and not Gamasutra or its parent company.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/Tim_Sweeney_blog1-pcgh%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, retrospectives of classic games have been well received at GDC, but there have been very few stories about classic game tools. This series of articles will attempt to fill that gap, by interviewing key people who were instrumental in the history of game development tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first article in this series was an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/DavidLightbown/20170223/289955/Classic_Tools_Retrospective_John_Romero_talks_about_creating_TEd_the_tile_editor_that_shipped_over_30_games.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;interview with John Romero about TEd&lt;/a&gt;, the Tile Editor he created at Id Software, that went on to ship over 30 games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second article, I am fortunate to have the opportunity to speak to &lt;strong&gt;Tim Sweeney &lt;/strong&gt;about the first version of the &lt;strong&gt;Unreal Editor&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;UnrealEd.&lt;/strong&gt; We spoke at the Unreal booth during the GamesCom 2017 conference in Cologne, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fallacies and BSPs: &quot;I'll write an editor&quot;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you for taking the time to talk to me, Tim! Let's start with the early days of the Unreal Editor. I read that James Schmaltz – creator of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epic_Pinball&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Epic Pinball&lt;/a&gt; – showed you a game that he was working on, and when you saw it, you offered to build an editor for it. Is that correct?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah! He had been inspired by Bullfrog’s game, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magic_Carpet_(video_game)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Magic Carpet&lt;/a&gt;. James is this insanely brilliant programmer, but he only wrote code in assembly language, he didn't want to learn C. [laughs] And so – in pure assembly language – he wrote this 3D engine that rendered terrain backgrounds and game objects. He didn't want to build an editing tool, so he actually built a BSP tree by hand and placed a capsule in the middle of this terrain. When I saw that, I was like &quot;No, no, no, James, James... this is not how we do things.&quot; [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;James Schmaltz&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/james_schmalz_owler_20160227_032610_original%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Magic Carpet, by Bullfrog&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/8a6ec15fe182bd6fc9b1b81e76352f4017abb3e2bea80399c45a48b6933d2905_product_card_screenshot_600%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;James Schmaltz and Magic Carpet, by Bullfrog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said &quot;I'll write an editor”, and so I set about building the user interface for the Unreal Editor, laying out the UI in Visual Basic, of all things. It had a text mode command-line interface to the C++ engine that was doing the rendering. Next I wrote the wireframe editor, and it went from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it was a funny learning process. I thought I was just going to write this editor and integrate it into James's renderer. At some point, I said &quot;Can you send me the code? I'd like to figure out how to integrate the renderer.” So he sent me 30,000 lines of assembly code. [laughs] The 3D rendering engine had some elements of Epic Pinball in it and some other prior assembly code that he had been copy / pasting, and I was like &quot;Oh my god, what is this stuff? I don't wanna touch this!&quot; [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I said to myself, before I figure this out, I'm just going to write a little texture mapper. So, I went through &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Abrash&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Michael&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Abrash&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Abrash&lt;/a&gt;'s articles on texture mapping and looked at some stuff that Billy Zelsnack has shared early on. The texture mapping was actually pretty simple, so I said, &quot;I guess I can figure this out&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one real piece of wizardry in the early Unreal Editor – before I implemented lighting and things like that – was the real-time BSP tree creation. The idea is that you can reposition brushes in 3-D space, and then all the BSP work is updated completely in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/unrealed.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;It was a real example of programmer geekery&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This had some mind-boggling implications, and I created this torus-building tool just to show off how cool it was. I got together with James – who, remember, had been building his BSPs by hand – and I said &quot;check this out.&quot; I created two toruses that were interlocked, and subtracted them from the world, and he said &quot;Whoa, no way? That's awesome!&quot; It was a real example of programmer geekery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Speaking of BSPs, it was my understanding that John Carmack was one of the first people to use BSPs in a game engine, and that the idea of working with BSPs was fairly new in the games industry at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Carmack had written this really advanced editor on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NeXT_Computer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NeXT&lt;/a&gt;. I'd read all about it and I had seen screenshots of it, but I never actually used it. At the time, I thought to myself &quot;Holy shit, Carmack wrote a real-time BSP editor!&quot; What I didn't realize was that it wasn't actually real-time, there was this re-build process and all this other offline stuff. I didn't know that, and so I thought I had to create a completely real-time thing, and so I did. [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/jrbase1%5B1%5D.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/jrbase1%5B1%5D.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/3349a9feee8073cb4fc6b46864ad713f--id-software-source-code%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;QuakeEd on NeXT and John Carmack&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; [laughs] You thought that's how it was, and so you accepted the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah! A lot of the features in Unreal arose from fallacies of what I misperceived other people did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;A lot of the features in Unreal arose from fallacies of what I misperceived other people did.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, a bunch of the former Future Crew demo-scene guys had formed a hardware company, and they had released some screenshots with incredibly realistic volumetric lighting in an indoor scene. There were some lights with really big spheres around them, and the volumetric lighting was really clearly clipped by all the geometry around it. It looked completely physically accurate. I was like &quot;Oh my god, it's something I've never seen before, I have to figure it out!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I figured out that I needed to compute the line integral from the eye to every point on the screen. I learned some calculus in college, so I said to myself &quot;I should be able to do this.&quot; So I figured out the formula for it with some crazy complicated trigonometry. I implemented it, but it was 100 times too slow. Then I realized, &quot;Oh wait, I can do this in the lightmap space”, because the lightmap is a discretization of geometry into bite-sized chunks. I did that with lightmaps, so it was real-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/516587-unreal-macintosh-screenshot-upper-level-of-prison-cell%5B1%5D.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/516590-unreal-macintosh-screenshot-the-floor-is-slippery-like-ice%5B1%5D.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Examples of lightmap-based lighting from Unreal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a screenshot of it, and I emailed it to the guy I knew at the hardware company in Finland. He replied &quot;Oh that's really awesome! But, our picture is just a rendering from 3D Studio Max because we couldn't figure out how to do that in real-time. [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; [laughs] Wow…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Author's Note: The company that Tim is referring to is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitBoys&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bit Boys&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;There was this huge leap frogging process, where Carmack was implementing crazy new things, [and] I was implementing crazy new things&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; So Unreal Engine was the first one with volumetric lighting, anywhere, I think... and it was based on that fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a real cool time in the early history of the games industry, because 3D was just becoming possible. There were several software renderers that people had written, and nobody had really solved the large scale challenges of how to make lighting work in a large world, or how to make real time geometry work in a large world. There was this huge leap frogging process, where Carmack was implementing crazy new things, I was implementing crazy new things, and we were constantly releasing screenshots showing what was possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at it, we – in about a four year period of time – re-created about 20 years of rendering research from the 1980s and 1990s that had previously only been possible offline and not in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Right, like how the idea for BSPs was based on a paper written in 1969.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, that's before I was born!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/bsp.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TurboPascal and Maya: The inspirations behind UnrealEd&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; What were some of the sources of inspiration for the design philosophy of the Unreal Editor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; There were really several sources of inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ZZT&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ZZT&lt;/a&gt; from 1991, you'll see the core feature set of the Unreal Engine. It's basically a game engine with a game implanted in it. The engine exposes a little scripting language, which – while it was very basic – was a full scripting language that you could use to write little game scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Author's Note: For more about ZZT, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bossfightbooks.com/products/zzt-by-anna-anthropy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check out the book by Anna Anthropy&lt;/a&gt;, published by Boss Fight Books]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had a real time what-you-see-is-what-you-get interactive editor for creating levels. You could go back and forth with a few keystrokes, adding a level, and play-testing it, and iterating on it. That interactive workflow was really the key to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/1892-zzt-dos-screenshot-the-title-screen-of-the-world-s-first-zzt%5B1%5D.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/1892-zzt-dos-screenshot-the-title-screen-of-the-world-s-first-zzt%5B1%5D.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/zzt_4_large%5B1%5D.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/zzt_4_large%5B1%5D.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ZZT, in game mode and editor mode&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was largely inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turbo_Pascal&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Turbo Pascal&lt;/a&gt;, which was the first toolset I used that I really loved. It was such an easy-to-use editor for creating code and compiling stuff. You would be typing code, and then several seconds later it would be compiled, and you'd be running it. The iterative process of creating stuff was just awesome, compared to everything I had used up until that point. If you look at ZZT's implementation, it really was like the text version of the Unreal Engine. The entire model for Unreal was driven by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;That was largely inspired by Turbo Pascal, which was the first toolset I used that I really loved&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was one other really big inspiration that led to a lot of the design elements of the underlying engine, and that was Visual Basic, which was like Microsoft's clone of Delphi – the visual user interface editing version of Object Pascal for Windows that Borland had created – but I never used Delphi, I only used Visual Basic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was that you had this form editor, you'd draw some form elements and boxes and things like that, and then you'd click on it and bring up the code. The code would immediately be there and you just type it out and just go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/Turbopascal_6%5B1%5D.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/Turbopascal_6%5B1%5D.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/output%5B1%5D.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/output%5B1%5D.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TurboPascal, from Borland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I carried all those principles over to Unreal: you can drop an object in the level, double click on it and there would be the script editor, and you could go type some script down and change it. It would be just a few mouse clicks to be able to write code, create 3-D objects, and do everything all interactively in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing that was really tied into the development of Unreal is that Epic bought a few Silicon Graphics workstations, and we had the first version of Maya up and running on them. Maya was a total piece-of-shit back then, but the one thing that was really cool was it had this interactive 3D mode where you had this blue, red, and black background space with these object outlines and wireframes that were completely in real time, which none of the other programs running and PC had really achieved at that point in time; they were still so lost in legacy code and legacy UI patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/o2__%5B1%5D.jpeg&quot;/&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/750px-Maya_3_0_1%5B1%5D.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the very first thing I did when I started building the Unreal Editor was creating a black background with the blue / red on it – copying Maya – and I wrote a line drawing routine and had 3D wireframe outlines for all the objects going around. That was the initial inspiration to prove that it was possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Visual Basic to Slate: The evolution of the UnrealEd interface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Author's Note: At the beginning of the interview, I had set up a version of UnrealEd 1 running in a virtual machine on my laptop. I hand Tim the mouse so he can use it.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Hey, neat, you really have it running here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes! So, I imagine that the version we're seeing here is all Visual Basic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Author's Note: Tim is having a great time building a level from scratch. It's great to see, almost like seeing two old friends re-united after a long time apart]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; What led you to use Visual Basic for the interface of the first version of UnrealEd, and what were some of the other options that were out there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/ux_0000s_0016_AlanCooper%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/vb4prowin95-3%5B1%5D.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/vb4prowin95-3%5B1%5D.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alan Cooper and Visual Basic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; So, this was 1995. At that point in time, the state of the art in C++ user interface frameworks was just abysmal. There was Microsoft Foundation Classes which was the most miserable piece-of-shit API you can imagine. You'd start drawing some controls on to a window and it would be generating massive amounts of C++ code that had a bunch of comments saying &quot;oh, here we're creating this control for you!&quot; Then you'd move an object around and it would update part of the code but not other parts, and it would just get continually broken all the time, and so I said &quot;I'm not touching this.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual Basic had this awesome user interface designer where you laid out all the controls and menu items and bits of UI in a really productive way. It was more productive than any like UI toolkit I had seen, mostly because it was just like this one really clean holistic program: you draw UI, you click on it, you add basic code of how it will interact. I found that it was much easier to build a UI that way, and then to interface it to C++ through this command line interface, sending text back and forth, as a way of marshaling data. I think that remained true for about a decade and was really only in the early 2000s that C++ UI toolkits got into a decent state, with Qt and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Author's Note: The first version of Visual Basic was designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Cooper&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alan Cooper&lt;/a&gt;, who is often referred to as the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cooper.com/alan/father_of_vb.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Father of Visual Basic&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. He is also one of the most important figures in the field of usability and user experience]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/wxWidgetsLogo2-e1503721646998%5B1%5D.png&quot;/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/Unreal%2BEngine%2B3%5B1%5D.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/Unreal%2BEngine%2B3%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UnrealEd 3, which had elements of wxWidgets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL&lt;/strong&gt;: And then, over time, I guess there are pieces that started to be pulled out and replaced with other parts. How did that evolution go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; After finishing Unreal Editor 1, I went off and started doing a whole bunch of next generation research that generally didn't reach fruition, while Warren Marshall jumped in and rewrote the Visual Basic portions of the Unreal Editor in C++ using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WxWidgets&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wxWidgets&lt;/a&gt; which, at the time, was the best thing available. That was the basis of the UI framework in Unreal Editor 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;By the time we got to the very beginning of the Unreal Engine 4 development cycle, we had five different UI toolkits&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the middle of the Unreal Engine 2 generation, Visual Basic was totally gone from the process. There was this nicer, cleaner C++ framework there. That achieved basically the same UI but without the language challenges. The real problem was, over time, wxWidgets didn't improve and other UI toolkits came out, and so we kept integrating new ones for special tools. So, by the time we got to the very beginning of the Unreal Engine 4 development cycle, we had five different UI toolkits...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; That's not uncommon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; ...including some crazy WPF stuff written in C#, and integrated in Unreal Engine 4 that just didn't work on Mac, for example. So there was this a giant mess we had at that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Nick Atamas was prototyping a new UI layer in C++ and we eventually decided to adopt that, and that became Slate. So we re-wrote 100 percent of the Unreal Engine user interface, got rid of all of these plug-in UI toolkits, and re-wrote it in a unified way. So, that gave us the ability to scale up to what we have today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/east-coast-devcon-2014-the-slate-ui-framework-architecture-tools-3-638%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screenshot of UnrealEd with the Slate UI&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But still, nobody's really achieved the sweetness that existed back then with Visual Basic. Even the C# User Interface framework is just a massive complicated piles of XML and other craziness that's unnecessary. It feels like every generation that tries to do it does it in a more elaborate way and it gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots and XCopy: The importance of licensing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Which companies were the first to use the Unreal Editor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Very early on – two years before we shipped – we already had licensees: Microprose was using Unreal Engine, and then Legend Entertainment was using it for Wheel of Time, and we were providing them with support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/Wheeloftimegame%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/25169-the-wheel-of-time-windows-screenshot-the-majestic-white-tower%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wheel of Time, by Legend Entertainment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; They helped you out as well, right? That was sort of part of that relationship, working together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, their license fees kept Epic afloat throughout the development of Unreal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;The joke – at the time – was that licensing from Id was like a quarter million dollar XCopy&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We really took licensing seriously at that point because it was paying the bills, and it led us to look at engine licensing quite differently than Id did. The joke -- at the time -- was that licensing from Id was like a quarter million dollar XCopy: you'd pay a quarter million dollars, and they'd use the DOS XCopy command to give you a copy of the source... and that would be it. [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; [laughs] OK, so what led to Microprose and Legend Entertainment licensing Unreal Engine even before Unreal 1 was released?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; I think it was probably the fact that we released amazing screenshots of our game, but also screenshots of our editor early on, around 1995. That led those companies to call us. Microprose called us and they said &quot;we're interested in licensing your engine!&quot; and we're like &quot;Engine? What engine? Oh! Right, our engine! It's very expensive.&quot; [laughs] And literally that was the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/uned800.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/uned800.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/uncb1.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/uncb1.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two of the earliest screenshots of the Unreal Editor and Unreal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Dinosaurs and Lizards: The terminology and iconography of UnrealEd&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; So, speaking of screenshots, here is one that was posted to Blue's News in late 90s. There are some subtle differences to the virtual machine instance that we have running here: for example, there are Play, Help, and Epic buttons in the top left corner, which were not in the final version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you talk a bit about this screenshot?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/ide1.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screenshot of UnrealEd posted on Blues News in 1998&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; That's definitely Unreal Engine 1, probably around 1998, because it has a bunch of Steve Polge's code that was used for coordinating multiplayer early on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;Epic&quot; button was just a web page thing which everybody found annoying because they'd click on it accidentally and say &quot;Ahhh, my web browser is popping up!&quot; [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;Nobody is really sure what it is, some people think it's a dinosaur, a lizard, or something... but those have been our icons for a decade.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; [laughs] OK, can you tell me a bit about the iconography?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; I had drawn some really, really horrible icons for all of these things, and then I sent them to Dan Cook, the artist who did the artwork on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tyrian_(video_game)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tyrian&lt;/a&gt;, our early shooter game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was supposed to draw an icon for a pawn, so he created a chess piece. I was like &quot;no no no&quot;, and he said &quot;OK, so tell me what a pawn is&quot;. So I said &quot;It's like a monster, like really bad-ass thing&quot; so he drew the head, which nobody is really sure what it is, some people think it's a dinosaur, a lizard, or something... but those have been our icons for a decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/portrait%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/uedicons.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daniel Cook and the icons he created for UnrealEd. The &quot;Add Pawn&quot; icon is in the bottom row, third from right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; We spoke about the word “pawn” before. Was that something that you had come up with, or had you seen that somewhere else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; I think that was Steve Polge's or James Schmaltz's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; What about “actors”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Carmack had come up with some terminology calling things &quot;entities&quot;, and I was like &quot;No, we need some more flair.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; We decided that we’d have something called &quot;actors&quot;, because there are these &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Actor_model&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;actor-based programming laws&lt;/a&gt; defined in the 1980s in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smalltalk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SmallTalk&lt;/a&gt;, which I'd really been enamored with at the time. It was all object-oriented. That seems like an appropriate start. So we came up with the idea of pawns, as well as instigators for defining who started a series of events, who gets credit for a kill, and all the other terminology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Schmaltz-isms and the Voodoo Brain Virus: Creating UnrealScript&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Tell me more about how James and Steve were involved in the use and design of UnrealScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; James Schmaltz is like a super-brilliant jack of all trades. He was the best artist on the team, an amazing level designer, and could also program in UnrealScript as well as assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobygames.com/game/windows/unreal/credits&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the credits for Unreal&lt;/a&gt;, his name appears in a couple of different categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;He'd have this multi-line expression that's like: 'something dot instigator dot blah blah blah' and I'd replace it with something like… 'self'&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; There are very, very few people with that level of talent in the whole games industry, and he deserves all the success he has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he went from assembly language to UnrealScript, and he was writing this insane UnrealScript code where he would just type stuff until it worked, and so I'd go in at night and simplify his code. He'd have this multi-line expression that's like: &quot;something dot instigator dot blah blah blah&quot; and I'd replace it with something like… &quot;self&quot;. [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; We'd call those Schmaltz-isms. And then Polge would have these magic numbers in code, like &quot;walk speed = run speed x 3.072&quot;. So I'd ask &quot;is 3.072 some constant in physics I’m not aware of?&quot; [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/assembler.png&quot;/&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/base_ed_unrealscript%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; UnrealScript itself was inspired by Java, at the time, which was seen as a successor to C++. They copied a lot of the design decisions and then they added a lot of new concepts on top it. There are the beginnings of some generic containers in UnrealScript that didn't exist in Java until several generations later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always thought when the C# language was designed, they must have really looked over UnrealScript, because I saw a few features from UnrealScript that surfaced in C#. It was always my hope that they had borrowed some of these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, the more I dug into object oriented programming and really dug into SmallTalk and the state of the art research with metaclasses, I came to the realization that it was this kind of voodoo brain virus that didn't have any real theoretical underpinnings. Whereas, when you look into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haskell.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curry%E2%80%93Howard_correspondence&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Curry Howard iso-morphism&lt;/a&gt;, and other really advanced principles in programming, you see that there is a source and structure that should inspire us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;SoftDisk, Id, and million-dollar cheques: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; With their business focus and shareware history, did Jay Wilbur and Mark Rein have an impact on the engine, the tools, or the editor, or the resources that were put towards them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; In the early days, Epic really worked because of the combination of me on the technical side and Mark on the business side. Mark would be going around the world and doing crazy business deals that get the cash rolling in.  It was absolutely critical if we didn't have him, we would never survived those early days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/Mark_Rein_Headshot_400x400%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/11%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mark Rein and Jay Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, we were out of money, and what we were spending was completely financed by Mark's American Express card, which would eventually get taken away from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; And so he flew off to meet with TG Interactive, and came back with a million dollar cheque. That saved us. That was repeated several times in our history. It's so important to have really great business guys out negotiating. He was the first president of Id, and -- after Mark -- Jay was the first CEO of Id.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; He was at SoftDisk before that, with Carmack, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah! It's funny because I had actually submitted my first game ZZT to SoftDisk. It was Jay Wilbur who was doing the deal for SoftDisk. I got $3,000 from SoftDisk as a result of that negotiation, so I knew Jay going way back to very, very early days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/jonromeroyoung%5B1%5D.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The early days of Id Software. Jay Wilbur is on the extreme right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Id guys were so inspirational to work with early on. I went to this goofy shareware conference, and Id showed up. They were the darlings of the industry back then because they put out Wolfenstein 3D and it had been by far the biggest success in the history of shareware. They actually hung out with us and took us out to dinner, they were spending time with us. It was so cool to see that the superstars of the industry were just down-to-earth guys. John Romero is just the sweetest game developer ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Author's Note: Agreed. John Romero was very generous with his time during our TEd interview.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;WYSIWYG and Ease-of-use: Tools perspective first&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; So in the November 1998 issue of Maximum PC, there was an interview with you that also talked about some of the various technologies that were available at the time. In the article, they said &quot;the [Unreal Editor] is light-years easier to use&quot;, and &quot;Quake technology is hard to work with.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also wrote &quot;The technology [for Quake III: Arena] is indeed impressive&quot;, and &quot;Prey and Trespasser look and perform better than Unreal. If these prove difficult to work with, however, developers will stay with Unreal.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, was the goal from the start to make ease-of-use tool as a competitive advantage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/2017-11-13%2023_54_38-Microsoft%20Edge.png&quot;/&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/2017-11-14%2000_01_09-Microsoft%20Edge.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maximum PC, November 1998&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, absolutely. You know, that was always my focus: to build an editor enabling level designers to build awesome stuff. From the beginning, it clear that making everything work in real-time and do super-fast iteration was the key to that. To be completely &quot;what-you-see-is-what-you-get.&quot; Then, you're limited only by your ability to think of new ideas. We've always had a big focus on tools at Epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; What's the process that Epic uses to ensure that there's more attention and time and care put into making the tools easier to use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;You can't treat ease-of-use as a stand-alone concept&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Development at Epic is a combination of the engine team, building systems, features, and tools, and the game teams consuming them while building games. There's this iterative process where the engine teams is out creating new ideas, and then sharing them with the game teams and getting constant feedback on what works and what doesn't work. That's really what has shaped our process: the fact that we have to satisfy our own internal game developers keeps the tools team honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do we want to build tools that are easy to use, but also ensure that they're making the right tradeoffs, and that you can actually produce the content that you need in the ship the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the flip-side of ease-of-use. You can't treat ease-of-use as a stand-alone concept. It's no good if the tools are super easy to get started with, so you can start building a game, but they're super hard to finish the game with, because they impose workflow burdens or limited functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/Unity_3D_1%5B1%5D.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the last five or six years of engines, the competition between Epic and Unity has been defined by initial ease-of-use, where Unity has the advantage. Whereas over the life cycle of actually shipping a game, for performance, on multiple platforms, Unreal has had the advantage. That's because everything we do is aimed at being able to ship epic-scale games, which are the kind of games we build. That's actually quite a bit trickier than making it easy for a team of three people to create something quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the Unreal Engine is about 20 times the code size of Unreal Engine 1. The tools are maybe 10 times the complexity, and necessarily so. People come into Unreal and they say &quot;oh my god&quot; because there are a lot of menu options. Then they go with Unity, and they say &quot;oh so nice and easy.&quot; And they get to the point where they're trying to ship their product, and they go &quot;oh shit, now we need to license source code, so we can add some features to the engine because they're not in the menus!&quot; So, you know, that's the dichotomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Inspiration and Legacy: The impact of UnrealEd&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; UnrealEd inspired some game developers like myself to not only start making games, but to build their own tools. What kind of impact do you think that UnrealEd has had on the industry?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; I think every game editor you look at nowadays draws some inspiration from UnrealEd. Because it was one of the earliest editors, we got a number of fundamental decisions right, like the way you deal with 2D grids, object placement, and navigation through the world. I think you can really trace the lineage that goes from the original Doom editor through to the Quake editor through Unreal. Now everything you look at is -- to some extent -- based on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-person_shooter_engine#/media/File:FPSChart.svg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/FPSChart.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A diagram showing the history of FPS engines, from Wikipedia. Click for larger verison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of those are because of general influences like Maya that affected all of them, but some are really quite specifically Unreal, in the way that people structure class hierarchies, implement undo systems, or all of these other thorny problems of game development. Anybody who came into the industry in the early 2000s typically came through either the Unreal or the Quake path. Even though Quake was a much bigger game, I think more designers came in through UnrealEd because the tools were so gratifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Multiplying and Dividing Productivity: Advice for game developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; There is an interview that you did with Kotaku in 2011. I'm going to read a few quotes from you that I feel are related:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We always approach game development from the tools perspective first. We build the tools we need, we build a user friendly set of tools and carry them forward.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We think long term at Epic. We're like Intel. We look at what we're going to do in five to ten years from now, and set our direction that way, whereas most companies are like we need to ship our next game. we'll put all of our resources on this and then we'll worry about the next one.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Big game companies like EA or Activision don't make the tools investment, they don't do the sort of long term thinking we do and realize that we have to make game development processes as efficient as possible.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/kotaku.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/kotaku2.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my interview with John Romero, he summed up this all up very nicely, when he said: &quot;Tools live longer than games do&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;So many companies are now crippling their production process by building engines that are perfectly fine with tools that are not fine at all. It's always the tools that kill people.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What advice do you have for game developers to avoid this mistake, so they can understand the long-term value of investing in tools?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Well... don't &quot;kind-of&quot; build an engine. Either build an engine, or don't... right? So many companies are now crippling their production process by building engines that are perfectly fine with tools that are not fine at all. It's always the tools that kill people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at all these internal engines... for example, Frostbite has more advanced rendering features than we have and they're producing prettier pixels than we are in a lot of cases, but Unreal developers can produce content much more productively, maybe 30 to 50 percent more productively, which means that a team half the size can produce a game that's just as good. They can iterate on it more, and polish it more than they could with these less polished toolsets. So, everybody should really make a conscientious decision to either fully invest in producing awesome tools for internal use, or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;I think every company needs to make the decision to either invest significantly more in tools, or just not bother.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Because you feel that going half-way hurts developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes. There must be some really fucking stupid accountants at the core of these companies, saying &quot;Oh, wow, limiting tools development can save two percent of our budget.&quot; Then they end up increasing the budget by 50 percent, because they have to spend significantly more time and manpower to create their game. So, it creates this crazy false economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think every company needs to make the decision to either invest significantly more in tools, or just not bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/db_area/images/blog/309414/DSC_3337.JPG&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That applies to everything. It's not only for the 3d editor used to build your levels, but it's your build system, and it's your programming language, it's your production pipeline, it's the DCC tools you use, all of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools are supposed to have a multiplying impact on productivity, and when you find that they have a dividing impact on productivity, get the hell out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DL:&lt;/strong&gt; Perfect. Thank you for taking the time to talk with me.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you're interested in game engines and tools, don't miss the Tools Tutorial Day at the Game Developers Conference in San Francisco!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This full-day gathering of tools developers will feature speakers from EA, Media Molecule, Infinity Ward, Ubisoft Montreal, Unity, Guerilla Games, Massive, Quel Solaar, Rebellion, Remedy, Blizzard, and Bungie.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't miss the inaugural Tools Tutorial Day, on Monday, March 19th, 2018.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vesrah</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/DavidLightbown/20180109/309414/Classic_Tools_Retrospective_Tim_Sweeney_on_the_first_version_of_the_Unreal_Editor.php</og:url>
<og:title>Classic Tools Retrospective: Tim Sweeney on the first version of the Unreal Editor</og:title>
<og:description>Tim Sweeney talks to David Lightbown about UnrealEd, one of the most popular level editors in the games industry, which was used to build levels for Unreal, Deus Ex, Gears of War, BioShock, Rainbow Six, Splinter Cell, and Mass Effect, and many, many more.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/DavidLightbown/20180109/309414/Classic_Tools_Retrospective_Tim_Sweeney_on_the_first_version_of_the_Unreal_Editor.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Dolan, co-creator of SecureDrop, has died</title>
<link>https://freedom.press/news/tribute-james-dolan-co-creator-securedrop-who-has-tragically-passed-away-age-36/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://freedom.press/news/tribute-james-dolan-co-creator-securedrop-who-has-tragically-passed-away-age-36/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Beyond a couple references on our website, that New Yorker story is virtually all that is in the public domain about James’s involvement in the project—and that’s how he preferred it. James was an intensely private and modest person, and despite the fact the SecureDrop soon got a lot of attention when Freedom of the Press Foundation (FPF) took the project over, he constantly insisted that Aaron deserved all the credit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet SecureDrop would not currently exist without James, and he deserves all the commendation in the world for making it what it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2013, Aaron Swartz himself committed suicide as the US government was attempting to prosecute him for violating the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act related to allegedly copying academic articles from JSTOR. SecureDrop was an unrelated side project he was working on at the time. A few months after Aaron’s tragic death, Kevin Poulsen donated the SecureDrop project to FPF, in the hopes that we could revive it and get it in a place where more news organizations could use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point, James was literally the only person in the world who knew all the ins and outs of the system, how to install it, and how to make it better. He had a high-paying computer security job at a large company by then, but I asked him if he’d be willing to come work for us so we could try to get SecureDrop into more newsrooms. We had hardly any money at the time, yet he immediately agreed—even though it meant taking an 80% pay cut. (Later, he would even refuse to accept a raise, insisting that we use any new funding to hire additional people to work on the project instead.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was our first full-time employee at Freedom of the Press Foundation, and quickly set out to teach other developers, contributors, and anyone interested in how the system worked. He poured his heart and soul into the work, traveling to newsrooms around North America to teach IT staffs and journalists in person how to install and use SecureDrop. He completely reworked the installation process, he pushed us to get independent security audits of the system, and he helped us hire the initial team that would take over SecureDrop once he was gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James’s encyclopedic knowledge of computer and network security was a key reason why newsrooms were comfortable adopting SecureDrop when it was still seen as something relatively new and unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James left FPF in August of 2015 after he felt the project was in a place where it could survive without him. Ever since, he had been working on the security team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.classy.org/&quot;&gt;Classy&lt;/a&gt;, a crowdfunding site for non-profit organizations located in San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t know why James took his own life; we do know, however, he long suffered from PTSD from his time serving in the Marines during the Iraq War. It was an experience that affected him in multiple ways. He often cited the Iraq War as his inspiration for wanting to help journalists and whistleblowers; it made him realize governments needed to be much more transparent and accountable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memorial services have not yet been finalized, but if you knew James personally, please feel free to reach out to us through &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom.press/contact/&quot;&gt;our contact form&lt;/a&gt;, and we are happy to keep you informed of anything we learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you suffer from depression or PTSD and are considering harming yourself, please reach out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/&quot;&gt;Suicide Prevention Lifeline&lt;/a&gt;. Some of our best and brightest minds have suffered in silence, and sometimes keep loved ones in the dark. Please know that you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to overstate how fundamentally important James Dolan was to the development of both Freedom of the Press Foundation and SecureDrop. We are heartbroken he is gone, but we are also eternally grateful to have known and worked with him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 19:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:title>A tribute to James Dolan, co-creator of SecureDrop, who has tragically passed away at age 36</og:title>
<og:url>https://freedom.press/news/tribute-james-dolan-co-creator-securedrop-who-has-tragically-passed-away-age-36/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>In memory of computer security expert James Dolan, 1981-2017. </og:description>
<og:image>https://freedom.press/media/images/dolan.width-1600.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://freedom.press/news/tribute-james-dolan-co-creator-securedrop-who-has-tragically-passed-away-age-36/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A letter about Google AMP</title>
<link>http://ampletter.org/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://ampletter.org/</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;x-ua-compatible&quot; content=&quot;ie=edge&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;AMP letter&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;style.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;120.81714560925&quot;&gt;
&lt;header readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;container&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; readability=&quot;36.432422717469&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are a community of individuals who have a significant interest in the development and health of the World Wide Web (“the Web”), and &lt;strong&gt;we are deeply concerned&lt;/strong&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;https://ampproject.org&quot;&gt;Accelerated Mobile Pages&lt;/a&gt; (“AMP”), a Google project that purportedly seeks to improve the user experience of the Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, AMP keeps users within Google’s domain and diverts traffic away from other websites for the benefit of Google. At a scale of billions of users, this has the effect of further &lt;strong&gt;reinforcing Google’s dominance of the Web&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We acknowledge the problem of Web pages being slow to load, relative to alternative, proprietary technologies such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://instantarticles.fb.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook Instant Articles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/news-publisher/&quot;&gt;Apple News&lt;/a&gt;. Publishers (especially in news media) have long faced difficult choices and poor incentives, leading to bad decisions and compromises, and ultimately to terrible user experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search engines are in a powerful position to wield influence to solve this problem. However, Google has chosen to create a premium position at the top of their search results (for articles) and a “lightning” icon (for all types of content), which are only accessible to publishers that use a Google-controlled technology, served by Google from their infrastructure, on a Google URL, and placed within a Google controlled user experience. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/guides/about-amp&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AMP format is not in itself, a problem, but two aspects of its implementation reinforce the position of Google as a de facto standard platform for content, as Google seeks to drive uptake of AMP with content creators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Content that “opts in” to AMP and the associated hosting within Google’s domain is granted preferential search promotion, including (for news articles) a position above all other results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user navigates from Google to a piece of content Google has recommended, they are, unwittingly, remaining within Google’s ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Google’s objective with AMP is indeed to improve user experience on the Web, then we suggest some simple changes that would do that while still allowing the Web to remain dynamic, competitive and consumer-oriented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Instead of granting premium placement in search results only to AMP, provide the same perks to all pages that meet an objective, neutral performance criterion such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/a/webpagetest.org/docs/using-webpagetest/metrics/speed-index&quot;&gt;Speed Index&lt;/a&gt;. Publishers can then use any technical solution of their choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not display third-party content within a Google page unless it is clear to the user that they are looking at a Google product. It is perfectly acceptable for Google to launch a “news reader”, but it is not acceptable to display a page that carries only third party branding on what is actually a Google URL, nor to require that third party to use Google’s hosting in order to appear in search results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;We don’t want to stop Google’s development of AMP, and these changes do not require that. We also applaud search engines that give ranking preference to fast-loading pages. AMP can remain one of a range of technologies that give publishers high quality options for delivering Web pages quickly and making users happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, publishers should not be compelled by Google’s search dominance to put their content under a Google umbrella. &lt;strong&gt;The Web is not Google, and should not be just Google.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;As individuals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On behalf of organisations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Signatories are listed in alphabetical order of family name. If you would like to sign this letter please make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/amp-letter/amp-letter&quot;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;container&quot; lang=&quot;fr&quot; readability=&quot;59.792578935239&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nous sommes une communauté d’individus ayant un intérêt particulier pour le développement et la bonne santé du World Wide Web (“le Web”), et sommes fortement préoccupés par les “Accelerated Mobile Pages” (AMP), un projet de Google qui prétend améliorer l’expérience utilisateur sur le web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En réalité, AMP enferme les utilisateurs et utilisatrices dans l’espace de Google en reroutant le trafic des autres sites au profit de Google. À l’échelle de milliards d’utilisateurs et d’utilisatrices, cela renforce la position déjà largement dominante de Google sur le web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nous reconnaissons le problème de la lenteur de chargement des pages sur le web, par rapport à d’autres technologies propriétaires alternatives telles que Facebook Instant Articles et Apple News. Dans le but de maximiser leurs recettes, les éditeurs de contenu (particulièrement la presse) ont depuis toujours dû faire face à de mauvais choix et des incitations fallacieuses qui ont mené à des décisions qui leur sont nuisibles ainsi qu’aux utilisateurs et utilisatrices qui souffrent d’une mauvaise expérience d’utilisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les moteurs de recherche se trouvent dans une position privilégiée pour exercer leur influence dans la résolution de ce problème. En revanche, Google en a profité pour créer un placement préférentiel en haut des pages de résultats pour les articles et une icône “éclair” pour tous types de contenus, uniquement accessibles aux éditeurs qui utilisent une technologie contrôlée par Google, servie par Google via leur infrastructure, sur une adresse web (URL) Google, et insérée dans une expérience utilisateur contrôlée par Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le format AMP n’est pas un souci en soi, mais deux aspects de sa mise en œuvre renforcent la position de Google en tant que standard de facto pour la création et l’hébergement de contenu, à mesure que Google promeut AMP auprès de ceux qui en produisent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tout contenu qui choisit de supporter AMP ainsi que l’hébergement affilié sous le domaine Google acquiert une promotion privilégiée dans les résultats de recherche, y compris (pour les articles) un placement au dessus des autres résultats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Les utilisateurs et utilisatrices naviguant depuis Google vers un contenu recommandé par Google restent, sans le savoir, dans l’enceinte de l’écosystème Google.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Si l’objectif de Google avec AMP est en réalité d’améliorer l’expérience utilisateur sur le web, alors nous suggérons de simples changements qui serviraient cette cause tout en permettant au web de rester dynamique, compétitif et tourné vers les consommateurs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Au lieu de réserver un placement préférentiel pour les seuls contenus AMP dans les résultats de recherche, il suffirait de procurer des privilèges similaires à toute page qui satisferait à des critères de performance neutres et objectifs, comme, par exemple, le Speed Index. Les éditeurs pourront ainsi utiliser la solution technique de leur choix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ne pas intégrer de contenus tiers externes dans une page Google, à moins qu’il ne soit clair pour l’utilisateur ou l’utilisatrice d’avoir affaire à un produit Google. Il est parfaitement acceptable que Google lance un “lecteur de nouvelles”, mais il n’est ni acceptable de servir une page n’affichant que du contenu tiers depuis une URL de Google, ni d’obliger le tiers à utiliser l’hébergement de Google pour apparaître plus en évidence dans les résultats de recherche.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nous ne cherchons pas à stopper le développement de AMP par Google, et ces changements ne le requièrent pas. Aussi, nous approuvons la promotion par les moteurs de recherche des pages performantes. AMP peut demeurer l’une des technologies qui donnent aux éditeurs le choix entre une variété d’options de grande qualité afin de servir des pages Web rapidement et de rendre leur utilisation plus satisfaisante.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cependant, les éditeurs ne devraient pas être contraints, par la domination de Google parmi les moteurs de recherche, à mettre leur contenu sous l’égide de Google. Le Web n’est pas Google à lui seul, et ne devrait pas se réduire uniquement à Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincèrement,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;For signatories please refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ampletter.org/?lang=en&quot; data-langswitch=&quot;en&quot;&gt;English version&lt;/a&gt;. Translations are provided for information but should not be considered normative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;container&quot; lang=&quot;ja&quot; readability=&quot;41.86641221374&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;私たちはワールド・ワイド・ウェブにおける健全さと発展に関して大いに関心を持っている個人達であり、私たちは、ウェブにおけるユーザ体験を向上させる、と喧伝しているGoogleのプロジェクト、AMP(Accelerated Mobile Pages)に対して深い憂慮を抱いています。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;実際にAMPはGoogleのドメイン内にユーザを留め、Googleの利益のためにトラフィックを他のウェブサイトから迂回させています。数十億のユーザを有するGoogleにおいて、そうすることは、より完全なウェブの独占を推し進めることと同義と言えるでしょう。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebookのインスタント・アーティクルやAppleニュースなどのような独自の技術と比べ、ウェブページの読み込みが遅いという問題は確かに存在しています。パブリッシャーは(特に報道メディアにおいては)難しい選択と不十分なインセンティブに長い間直面しており、売上げを最大化するために間違った意志決定や妥協をし、最終的には酷いユーザ体験を提供することになってしまっています。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;検索エンジンはこの問題の解決に対して影響を与える強大なポジションを有しています。しかし、GoogleはGoogleがコントロールするユーザ体験の中、GoogleのURLで、Googleが所有するインフラから、Googleが有する技術を利用したパブリッシャーに対してのみ、その検索結果で記事に対して、よりよい表示場所を提供し、またそれ以外のコンテンツには特別なアイコンを表示させるという方法をとっています。(参照)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMPのフォーマットそれ自体は問題ではなく、AMPの利用率が上がるにつれ、その実装のうち以下の2点がGoogleのコンテンツプラットフォームとしてのポジションをデファクト・スタンダード化することにつながっています。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;AMPの利用を”選択”し、Googleのドメインでホストされたコンテンツは検索結果において優先的なプロモーションが許され、ニュースコンテントにおいてはほかの検索結果よりも上位に表示される点&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ユーザがGoogleが推奨するコンテントへナビゲートした際、ユーザは気がつかないうちにGoogleのエコシステム内に留まっている点&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;AMPにおけるGoogleの目標が純粋にウェブのユーザ体験を向上させる事に向けられているなら、以下のシンプルな変更を行うことでウェブをダイナミックで、競争原理の働く、利用者を中心としたままにすることができるでしょう。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;AMPにのみ検索結果での優遇的ポジションを提供するのではなく、Speed Indexのような中立的なパフォーマンス評価を使って同等の目標を達していると判断できる全てのページに対して、同じ処遇を提供するべきだと考えています。そうすることでパブリッシャーは各自の技術的選択をが可能になります&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ユーザが明確にGoogleのプロダクトを閲覧していると分かる形でなければ、Googleのページ内に第三者のコンテントを表示させない。Googleが「ニュースリーダー」を提供することにはなんら問題はありませんが、GoogleのURLであるにも関わらず、第三者のブランディングを表示することや、第三者がGoogleによるホスティングを行わない限り検索結果で上位に表示されない、といったことは受け入れがたい&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Googleに対しAMPの開発を辞めて欲しいと提案しているわけではなく、これらの変更にはその必要もありません。検索結果において読み込みが速いページに対してよいランキングを与えることは素晴らしいことだと思います。AMPがユーザに対して早いウェブページを提供し、ユーザを幸せにするためにパブリッシャーが活用できる高品質な選択肢の1つとしての存在であり続けることは可能でしょう。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;しかし、パブリッシャーがGoogleの検索における独占的な地位を背景にコンテントをGoogleの中に入れざるを得ない状況は避けるべきだと考えています。 ウェブはGoogleではありませんし、Googleのみがウェブではないのですから。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬具&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;For signatories please refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ampletter.org/?lang=en&quot; data-langswitch=&quot;en&quot;&gt;English version&lt;/a&gt;. Translations are provided for information but should not be considered normative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;article class=&quot;container&quot; lang=&quot;es&quot; readability=&quot;59.769585253456&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Somos una comunidad de individuos con un gran interés en la salud y el desarrollo de la World Wide Web (“la Web”), y estamos profundamente preocupados con Accelerated Mobile Pages (“AMP”), un proyecto de Google que supuestamente busca mejorar la experiencia de usuario en la Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De hecho, AMP mantiene a los usuarios dentro del dominio de Google y desvía hacia fuera el tráfico de otras páginas Web en beneficio de Google. Con una escala de mil millones de usuarios, AMP tiene la consecuencia de reforzar aún más el dominio que Google tiene en la Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entendemos el problema de que las páginas Web sean lentas para cargarse, en comparación a otras tecnologías propietarias como Facebook Instant Articles y Apple News. Los editores (sobre todo los medios de comunicación) llevan tiempo enfrentándose a cuestiones difíciles e incentivos malos, que les ha llevado a malas decisiones y concesiones, resultando en una mala experiencia de usuario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los motores de búsqueda se encuentran en una posición poderosa para influenciar en la solución al problema. Google ha decidido crear una posición destacada en la parte superior de sus resultados de búsqueda (para artículos) y un icono de un rayo (para todos los tipos de contenidos), que solo están disponibles para publicadores que utilicen una tecnología controlada por Google, servida por Google utilizando su infraestructura, en una URL de Google, y colocada dentro de una experiencia de usuario controlada por Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El formato AMP no es un problema en sí mismo, pero hay dos aspectos de su implementación que refuerzan la posición de Google como la plataforma estandarizada para contenidos, ya que Google busca incrementar la popularidad de AMP ante los creadores de contenido:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Al contenido que utiliza AMP y se aloja en el dominio de Google se le concede una condición privilegiada en los resultados de búsqueda, incluyendo (para artículos de noticias) una posición por encima de todos los demás resultados.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cuando un usuario navega desde Google a un contenido que Google ha recomendado, están, inconscientemente, quedándose en el entorno de Google.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Si el objetivo de Google con AMP es, efectivamente, mejorar la experiencia de usuario en la Web, recomendamos unos simples cambios que bastarían, a la vez que permitirían a la Web permanecer dinámica, competitiva y orientada a los consumidores:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;En lugar de solamente ofrecer una posición privilegiada en los resultados de búsqueda a AMP, proporcionar los mismos beneficios a todas las páginas que alcancen un criterio de rendimiento objetivo y neutral, tal como el speed index. Los publicadores podrán entonces utilizar la solución técnica que deseen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No mostrar contenido de terceros dentro de una página de Google salvo que quede claro para el usuario que están mirando un producto de Google. Es perfectamente aceptable que Google lance un “lector de noticias”, pero no es aceptable mostrar una página que solo lleva la imagen corporativa de un tercero en lo que es realmente una URL de Google, ni exigir que un tercero utilice el alojamiento de Google para aparecer en los resultados de búsqueda.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;No queremos parar el desarrollo de AMP por parte de Google, y estos cambios no lo requieren. También aplaudimos a los motores de búsqueda que ofrecen una mejor posición en los resultados de búsqueda a páginas que carguen rápido. AMP puede permanecer como una más de un rango de tecnologías que dan a los editores opciones de alta calidad para servir páginas Web rápidamente y complaciendo a los usuarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin embargo, los editores no deberían sentirse, por el dominio de Google, obligados a poner su contenido bajo el paraguas de Google. La Web no es Google, y no debería ser sólo Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cordialmente,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;For signatories please refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ampletter.org/?lang=en&quot; data-langswitch=&quot;en&quot;&gt;English version&lt;/a&gt;. Translations are provided for information but should not be considered normative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;container lang-switcher&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Available in:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 18:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lainon</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://ampletter.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Building for the Blockchain</title>
<link>http://blog.ycombinator.com/building-for-the-blockchain/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://blog.ycombinator.com/building-for-the-blockchain/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re here, we assume that you’re a developer/hacker who’s intrigued by the blockchain. You’re convinced that you understand how it works and now you’re itching to figure out what the blockchain means for you and your developer skill set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need more of a primer we’d recommend starting with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;bitcoin white paper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/White-Paper&quot;&gt;Ethereum white paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal in this post is to:&lt;br/&gt;1. Explain how blockchain development differs from existing development paradigms&lt;br/&gt;2. Provide context for the opportunities and challenges in this space&lt;br/&gt;3. Point you to resources that will give you the foundation to start developing in this new paradigm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Paradigm Shifts for Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet applications benefit from network effects because they maintain centralized silos of information. Built upon shared, open protocols (e.g. TCP/IP, HTTP), companies like Yelp, Facebook, and Amazon benefit from having all of their users – and, as a result, data – in one place. This way they not only have an advantage over competitors with less data but also complete control over the way they monetize the data. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usv.com/blog/fat-protocols&quot;&gt;In the words&lt;/a&gt; of crypto investor Joel Monegro, the current Internet paradigm captures most of its value through &lt;em&gt;fat&lt;/em&gt; application layers, whereas the &lt;em&gt;thin&lt;/em&gt;, underlying communication protocols capture minimal value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, the distribution of value in the blockchain paradigm can be described with &lt;em&gt;fat&lt;/em&gt; protocols and a &lt;em&gt;thin&lt;/em&gt; application layer. This paradigm shift is possible due to the innovation of cryptographic tokens, which are described well by Albert Wagner of USV:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Historically the only way to make money from a protocol was to create software that implemented it and then try to sell this software (or more recently to host it)… With [cryptographic] tokens, however, the creators of a protocol can ‘monetize’ it directly and will in fact benefit more as others build businesses on top of that protocol.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, the creators of open communication protocols for the Internet, largely &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DARPA&quot;&gt;DARPA&lt;/a&gt; researchers and non-profit contributors, could not align financial incentives with protocol development. In contrast, protocol creators today can issue “tokens”, like Bitcoin and Ethereum, that represent the value of their decentralized protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usv.com/blog/fat-protocols&quot;&gt;Monegro believes&lt;/a&gt; that this paradigm shift affects the way that developers should think about their applications: “The combination of shared open data with an incentive system that prevents “winner-take-all” markets changes the game at the application layer and creates an entire new category of companies with fundamentally different business models at the protocol layer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ethereum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve come to the understanding that in the blockchain paradigm, developers can capture value through protocol innovation. To continue our discussion, we review how blockchain technologies evolved to eventually cater to developers. Eight years ago, Bitcoin was conceived as a virtual currency that removed the need for centralized financial systems. Initially, developers actually tried building applications upon the Bitcoin blockchain by storing data in the blockchain itself, but it turned out to be pretty inefficient (as described in &lt;a href=&quot;http://joel.mn/post/104755282493/the-shared-data-layer-of-the-blockchain&quot;&gt;another old Joel post&lt;/a&gt;!). One of these developers, Vitalik Buterin, was frustrated by Bitcoin’s immobilism and risk averse culture for adopting new developer-friendly features. So, he built his own platform, Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Bitcoin was originally intended to serve as a new medium for financial store of value, Ethereum was invented to serve as a Turing complete developer environment. In Ethereum, developers write smart contracts in the Solidity programming language, and those smart contracts are run in the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM). Here, we observe an opportunity for developers to fork and implement their own blockchains to serve different purposes. To do so, however, would require rekindling developer support and network effects that existing blockchain technologies had previously achieved. Today, building on top of existing networks like Ethereum allows developers to become stakeholders in not only their own applications, but also the underlying protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dapps, App Coins, and Smart Contracts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s blockchain developers often build decentralized applications, or dapps, on top of existing protocols to address specific markets and end users. In doing so, developers can issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.0xproject.com/the-difference-between-app-coins-and-protocol-tokens-7281a428348c&quot;&gt;tokens, or app coins&lt;/a&gt;, that are used to execute certain “functions” of the dapps themselves, not unlike Chuck-E-Cheese tokens are used for specific purposes like skeeball. These “functions” are the “smart contracts” that promise a dapp’s services in return for a digital asset, thereby removing the need for a middle-man to ensure the transaction. In other words, smart contracts promise that for one Chuck-E-Cheese token, you can exchange one game of skeeball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the functionality of the dapp becomes more sought after, the fixed number of app coins increase in value as a function of supply and demand. In other words, if it turns out that the Chuck-E-Cheese experience is truly remarkable and highly-demanded, the fixed supply of tokens become more valuable. This is the underlying principle that informs all ICOs (initial coin offerings), in which dapp developers solicit investment by offering app coins in return for capital to fund their projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, you might ask, “Why not use an existing token as opposed to issuing your own, dapp-specific token in the first place?” Dapp-specific app coins enable small-scale economies that facilitate the application’s purpose. These &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ycombinator.com/the-token-effect/&quot;&gt;tokens&lt;/a&gt; serve as scarce resources that can be regulated and governed to more closely align with the functionality of a dapp. This is where Ethereum comes back into the picture — with Ethereum, developers can very easily issue their own tokens for the specified use of their own dapps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Early Opportunities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an understanding of the underlying mechanisms of dapps, it’s important to think carefully about how decentralization would benefit your end users. Rather than jumping into a list of side projects, swapping relational databases for blockchain implementations, we urge you to consider the benefits of decentralization. For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://augur.net/&quot;&gt;Augur&lt;/a&gt; creates prediction markets by relying on decentralized participants to make correct predictions because they share financial incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a meta-level, there are also opportunities for innovation in the developer stack. Many blockchain developers liken the maturity of the blockchain tools and frameworks to those of the web during early days of the Internet. We spoke to Ben Yu of &lt;a href=&quot;https://streamtoken.net/&quot;&gt;Stream&lt;/a&gt;, who described this as a new opportunity for developers: “There is extremely low-hanging fruit in making the field more accessible, and a lot of technical infrastructure needs to be built up to bring blockchain from 1994, in internet terms, to 2017.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the innovation of the blockchain, many have identified the opportunity to build a new, decentralized web stack that does not depend on centralized government or corporate entities. The traditional web stack is composed of building blocks like TCP/IP, DNS, databases, web servers, authentication systems and CDNs, and we are in the midst of replicating these components by using platforms like Ethereum as the base layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Challenges of Immutability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, a technology that is likened to the early iterations of JavaScript almost certainly comes with challenges, the most apparent of which is related to the immutability of new protocols. Developers cannot change the underlying blockchain or higher-level smart contracts. Libraries or contracts cannot be easily versioned. The recent Parity bug that &lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2017/11/08/ethereum-parity-bug/&quot;&gt;locked 150MM USD in funds&lt;/a&gt;, among many other similar incidents, reminds us of the urgent need to build “future-proof” architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brandon Millman, an &lt;a href=&quot;http://0xproject.com&quot;&gt;engineer at 0x&lt;/a&gt;, described how blockchain immutability affects the way he thinks about security concerns: “Being in this space means being a lot more careful, especially because people’s money is at risk. Part of the benefit of the blockchain paradigm is that if you’re holding onto your private key, it’s hard for people to take money from you, but a lot of scams are getting you to willingly send your money to the wrong place instead of reaching in to steal money from your wallet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers, especially those accustomed to the fast pace of the startup world, are forced to consider tradeoffs between speed and security. As Ben Yu of Stream describes, “You have to move extremely fast, because the space is going enormously fast, but you can’t move fast and break things, which is the traditional philosophy for development being done now. If you break things, you lose hundreds of millions of dollars.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on the blockchain requires a different level of planning. Developers can no longer apply hot-fixes or overnight patches, because they no longer have centralized control over entire systems. Instead, introducing system changes often involves hard forking entire protocols, or in some cases, providing separate sources for protocol parameters that aren’t tied directly into the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ethereum’s Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the general challenges of immutability, Ethereum includes several limitations that blockchain developers might encounter. For one, Ethereum is unable to access real time data from outside the blockchain. Developers need to rely on trusted third party data providers, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oraclize.it/&quot;&gt;called oracles&lt;/a&gt;, to provide smart contracts with outside information like weather, random numbers, or currency values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Ethereum’s specification prevents real-time computations. Processing of block transactions takes upwards of 15 seconds (which is lightning fast compared to Bitcoin’s 10 minutes). As a result, developers need to write asynchronous code with front-end frameworks that can update states accordingly (like React).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Ethereum, you are also tied to paying for your transactions by the operation with gas that translates into Ethereum’s ether. As a result, using the current version of Solidity, you could very feasibly find yourself hitting a transaction limit if the computation you intend to perform is too expensive (like verifying checkmate in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@graycoding/lessons-learned-from-making-a-chess-game-for-ethereum-6917c01178b6&quot;&gt;game of chess&lt;/a&gt;). As a result, on-chain computations because become costly in terms of money and network bandwidth. There are interesting alternatives like &lt;a href=&quot;https://truebit.io/&quot;&gt;Truebit&lt;/a&gt; to perform more intensive computation off-chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, it can certainly feel overwhelming getting into this space. It’s an interdisciplinary field, spanning domains of economics, game theory, finance, computer science, math, cryptography, and more. However, that also means that there’s a lot of surface area to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brandon of 0x recommends diving into areas where you have some interest or experience instead of trying to learn everything at once: “If you’ve done JS development beforehand, there are a lot of JS libraries that you can contribute to. While you will definitely need to know [how everything fits together] eventually, you don’t need to feel like you need to take an entire course initially.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of decentralization, most of the code for projects on the blockchain are also available through open-source. There are a number of good resources to get your hands dirty:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the developer communities are remarkably receptive and helpful. Check out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you learn primarily by coding up your own projects, here are some ideas to get started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build your own wallet. It can be a be a web, mobile app or desktop app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create your own ERC-20 token and deploy it on the test net.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modify crypto kitties (dogs, tanks, zombies…) and deploy it on the test net.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its current state, yes, blockchain development is messy. No, there aren’t clean frameworks and tools analogous to those that exist for modern web development. But why not see the blockchain’s nascent state as an opportunity to impact a paradigm-shifting technology?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the blockchain, you don’t need to deploy any centralized servers, which means that there’s no single point of failure. If your whole stack is decentralized, there is no trusted third party involved making it censorship resistant, and your database is publicly verifiable. As the new paradigm offers opportunity to publicly share data, we observe a supreme advantage to decentralizing databases. This is the future we’re building towards on the Blockchain— where information and power are distributed systematically by cutting out the middleman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=16107597&quot;&gt;Comment on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Ben Yu (Stream) and Brandon Millman (0x) for lending their time to be interviewed, and thanks to Niharika Bedekar, Craig Cannon, Claire Shu for reading drafts of this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 17:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vincentschen</dc:creator>
<og:title>Building for the Blockchain</og:title>
<og:url>http://blog.ycombinator.com/building-for-the-blockchain/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Our goal in this post is to: 1. Explain how blockchain development differs from existing development paradigms. 2. Provide context for the opportunities and challenges in this space. 3. Point you to resources that will give you the foundation to start developing in this new paradigm.</og:description>
<og:image>http://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Building-for-the-Blockchain.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://blog.ycombinator.com/building-for-the-blockchain/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Meltdown Proof-of-Concept</title>
<link>https://github.com/IAIK/meltdown/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/IAIK/meltdown/</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repository contains several applications, demonstrating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://meltdown.help&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Meltdown bug&lt;/a&gt;. For technical information about the bug, refer to the paper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meltdown.help/meltdown.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Meltdown&lt;/a&gt; by Lipp, Schwarz, Gruss, Prescher, Haas, Mangard, Kocher, Genkin, Yarom, and Hamburg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The applications in this repository are built with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/IAIK/Meltdown/tree/master/libkdump&quot;&gt;libkdump&lt;/a&gt;, a library we developed for the paper. This library simplifies exploitation of the bug by automatically adapting to certain properties of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repository contains several videos demonstrating Meltdown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/IAIK/meltdown/master/videos/spy.mp4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video #1&lt;/a&gt; shows how Meltdown can be used to spy in realtime on a password input.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/IAIK/meltdown/master/videos/memdump.mp4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video #2&lt;/a&gt; shows how Meltdown leaks physical memory content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/IAIK/meltdown/master/videos/cat1.mp4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video #3&lt;/a&gt; shows how Meltdown reconstructs a photo from memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/IAIK/meltdown/master/videos/cat2.mp4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video #4&lt;/a&gt; shows how Meltdown reconstructs a photo from memory which is encoded with the FLIF file format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.rawgit.com/IAIK/meltdown/master/videos/uncached.mp4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video #5&lt;/a&gt; shows how Meltdown leaks uncached memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Demos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repository contains five demos to demonstrate different use cases. All demos are tested on Ubuntu 16.04 with an Intel Core i7-6700K, but they should work on any Linux system with any modern Intel CPU since 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For best results, we recommend a fast CPU that supports Intel TSX (e.g. any Intel Core i7-5xxx, i7-6xxx, or i7-7xxx). Furthermore, every demo should be pinned to one CPU core, e.g. with taskset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Build dependency for demos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a pre-requisite, you need to install glibc-static on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For RPM-based systems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;sudo yum install -y glibc-static
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Demo #1: A first test (&lt;code&gt;test&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most basic demo. It uses Meltdown to read accessible addresses from the own address space, not breaking any isolation mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this demo does not work for you, the remaining demos most likely won't work either. The reasons are manifold, e.g., the CPU could be too slow, not support out-of-order execution, the high-resolution timer is not precise enough (especially in VMs), the operating system does not support custom signal handlers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Build and Run&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
make
taskset 0x1 ./test
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see an output similar to this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Expect: Welcome to the wonderful world of microarchitectural attacks
   Got: Welcome to the wonderful world of microarchitectural attacks
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then the basic demo works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Demo #2: Breaking KASLR (&lt;code&gt;kaslr&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with Linux kernel 4.12, KASLR (Kernel Address Space Layout Randomizaton) is active by default. This means, that the location of the kernel (and also the direct physical map which maps the entire physical memory) changes with each reboot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This demo uses Meltdown to leak the (secret) randomization of the direct physical map. This demo requires root privileges to speed up the process. The paper describes a variant which does not require root privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Build and Run&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
make
sudo taskset 0x1 ./kaslr
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few seconds, you should see something similar to this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[+] Direct physical map offset: 0xffff880000000000
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Demo #3: Reliability test (&lt;code&gt;reliability&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This demo tests how reliable physical memory can be read. For this demo, you either need the direct physical map offset (e.g. from demo #2) or you have to disable KASLR by specifying &lt;code&gt;nokaslr&lt;/code&gt; in your kernel command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Build and Run&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build and start &lt;code&gt;reliability&lt;/code&gt;. If you have KASLR enabled, the first parameter is the offset of the direct physical map. Otherwise, the program does not require a parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
make
sudo taskset 0x1 ./reliability 0xffff880000000000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few seconds, you should get an output similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[-] Success rate: 99.93% (read 1354 values)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Demo #4: Read physical memory (&lt;code&gt;physical_reader&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This demo reads memory from a different process by directly reading physical memory. For this demo, you either need the direct physical map offset (e.g. from demo #2) or you have to disable KASLR by specifying &lt;code&gt;nokaslr&lt;/code&gt; in your kernel command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In principal, this program can read arbitrary physical addresses. However, as the physical memory contains a lot of non-human-readable data, we provide a test tool (&lt;code&gt;secret&lt;/code&gt;), which puts a human-readable string into memory and directly provides the physical address of this string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Build and Run&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the demo, first run &lt;code&gt;secret&lt;/code&gt; (as root) to get the physical address of a human-readable string:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
make
sudo ./secret
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should output something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[+] Secret: If you can read this, this is really bad
[+] Physical address of secret: 0x390fff400
[+] Exit with Ctrl+C if you are done reading the secret
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the &lt;code&gt;secret&lt;/code&gt; program running, and start &lt;code&gt;physical_reader&lt;/code&gt;. The first parameter is the physical address printed by &lt;code&gt;secret&lt;/code&gt;. If you do not have KASLR disabled, the second parameter is the offset of the direct physical map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
taskset 0x1 ./physical_reader 0x390fff400 0xffff880000000000
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few seconds, you should get an output similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[+] Physical address       : 0x390fff400
[+] Physical offset        : 0xffff880000000000
[+] Reading virtual address: 0xffff880390fff400

If you can read this, this is really bad
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Demo #5: Dump the memory (&lt;code&gt;memdump&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This demo dumps the content of the memory. As demo #3 and #4, it uses the direct physical map, to dump the contents of the physical memory in a hexdump-like format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, as the physical memory contains a lot of non-human-readable content, we provide a test tool to fill large amounts of the physical memory with human-readable strings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Build and Run&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the demo, first run &lt;code&gt;memory_filler&lt;/code&gt; to fill the memory with human-readable strings. The first argument is the amount of memory (in gigabytes) to fill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
make
./memory_filler 9
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, run the &lt;code&gt;memdump&lt;/code&gt; tool to dump memory contents. If you executed &lt;code&gt;memory_filler&lt;/code&gt; before, you should see some string fragments. If you have Firefox or Chrome with multiple tabs running, you might also see parts of the websites which are open or were recently closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first parameter is the physical address at which the dump should begin (leave empty to start at the first gigabyte). If you do not have KASLR disabled, the second parameter is the offset of the direct physical map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
taskset 0x1 ./memdump 0x240000000 0xffff880000000000 &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-c&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt; start at 9 GB&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should get a hexdump of parts of the memory (potentially even containing secrets such as passwords, see example in the paper), e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt; 240001c9f: | 00 6d 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 | .m.............. |
 24000262f: | 00 7d 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 | .}.............. |
 24000271f: | 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 65 6e 20 75 | ............en u |
 24000272f: | 73 65 72 20 73 70 61 63 65 20 61 6e 64 20 6b 65 | ser space and ke |
 24000273f: | 72 6e 65 6c 57 65 6c 63 6f 6d 65 20 74 6f 20 74 | rnelWelcome to t |
 24000298f: | 00 61 72 79 20 62 65 74 77 65 65 6e 20 75 73 65 | .ary between use |
 24000299f: | 72 20 73 70 61 63 65 20 61 6e 64 20 6b 65 72 6e | r space and kern |
 2400029af: | 65 6c 42 75 72 6e 20 61 66 74 65 72 20 72 65 61 | elBurn after rea |
 2400029bf: | 64 69 6e 67 20 74 68 69 73 20 73 74 72 69 6e 67 | ding this string |
 240002dcf: | 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 c8 | ................ |
 2400038af: | 6a 75 73 74 20 73 70 69 65 64 20 6f 6e 20 61 00 | just spied on a. |
 240003c8f: | 00 00 1e 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 | ................ |
 24000412f: | 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 65 74 73 2e | ............ets. |
 24000413f: | 2e 2e 57 65 6c 63 6f 6d 65 20 74 6f 20 74 68 65 | ..Welcome to the |
 2400042ff: | 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 6e 67 72 61 74 75 6c | .........ngratul |
 24000430f: | 61 74 69 6f 6e 73 2c 20 79 6f 75 20 6a 75 73 74 | ations, you just |
 24000431f: | 20 73 70 69 65 64 20 6f 6e 20 61 6e 20 61 70 70 |  spied on an app |
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Warnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning #1&lt;/strong&gt;: We are providing this code as-is. You are responsible for protecting yourself, your property and data, and others from any risks caused by this code. This code may cause unexpected and undesirable behavior to occur on your machine. This code may not detect the vulnerability on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning #2&lt;/strong&gt;: If you find that a computer is susceptible to the Meltdown bug, you may want to avoid using it as a multi-user system. Meltdown breaches the CPU's memory protection. On a machine that is susceptible to the Meltdown bug, one process can read all pages used by other processes or by the kernel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning #3&lt;/strong&gt;: This code is only for testing purposes. Do not run it on any productive systems. Do not run it on any system that might be used by another person or entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 16:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>__init</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/2519532?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>IAIK/meltdown</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/IAIK/meltdown</og:url>
<og:description>meltdown - This repository contains several applications, demonstrating the Meltdown bug.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/IAIK/meltdown/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Legends of the Ancient Web (2017)</title>
<link>http://idlewords.com/talks/ancient_web.htm</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://idlewords.com/talks/ancient_web.htm</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.001.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possibly my favorite technical work is a book that predates information technology by 2300 years, the Book of Ecclesiastes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're not familiar with it, Ecclesiastes is a rant by an angry, elderly atheist that through some editorial oversight found its way into the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is full of wisdom about technology, and how it interacts with human folly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.003.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author of Ecclesiastes had this to say about technological progress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;There is no remembrance of the former generations; neither shall there be any remembrance of the latter generations that are to come, among those that shall come after.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about one of those forgotten generations, secure in the knowledge that no matter how bad my talk, it won't be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about the political history of radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/radio_dish.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you didn't know radio existed, the whole thing would sound like a bunch of pseudoscientific hokum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So-called &quot;radio waves&quot; are invisible, transmit energy, easily penetrate matter, including stone walls and human bodies, and can be heard hundreds or even thousands of kilometers away if you prepare the right occult configuration of metal wires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;25.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.018.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radio was predicted in 1864 by James Clark Maxwell, who showed that a wiggling magnetic field could conjure up a companion electric field, and that the two would kind of egg each other on and sustain each other, propagating away at a constant speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That speed just happened to be the observed speed of light. This was too much of a coincidence for Maxwell, who (correctly) posited that light itself must be an electromagnetic phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1886, Hertz demonstrated that these mutually sustaining waves were real, and could be detected. For a long time they were called Hertzian waves in his honor. (Asked about a practical use for radio, Hertz said &quot;it's of no use whatsoever&quot;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1895, Marconi built the first practical radio system, which could transmit and receive bursts of noise over a short distance—a wireless telegraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.019.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the Internet, radio technology was on the horizon for a long time before it arrived, and it arrived in a rudimentary form that didn't strike anyone as a qualitatively new technology, let alone one that could upend politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world that radio arrived in already had ways to communicate in real time over long distances—telegraphs and telephones. It wasn't clear at the outset that Hertzian waves could be detected at distances much greater than a few hundred meters, let alone that they might become a practical method to transmit the human voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At best, they might prove a useful method for detecting lightning at a distance, or communicating with ships at sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world that radio was born into had a group of telegraphy enthusiasts who ran their own little networks, the Usenet of their day. And there was also an assortment of thriving small-scale telephone networks, including rural ones where the telephone wires were run over barbed wire fencing, connecting thirty or forty farms on a circuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these people became the first radio &quot;hams&quot;—amateur hobbyists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;18.035066505441&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.017.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;19.933494558646&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first radio sets used a spark gap and could only send buzzing sounds, so people communicated in Morse code. This was the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_the_Internet,_nobody_knows_you%27re_a_dog&quot;&gt;on the Internet, nobody knows you're a dog&lt;/a&gt;&quot; period of amateur radio. Some intrepid women who found a way to make and operate a set enjoyed the freedom the pseudonymous radio subculture of the time offered them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We forget how complete the isolation was in rural areas in the days before mass media. Many of the most active radio enthusiasts lived out in the sticks, a dynamic that comes up again and again with new communications technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, the range of these devices improved to where they could cover dozens of kilometers. People also learned how to amplify radio signals. The Navy became seriously interested in wireless sets as a military technology, and made them mandatory on ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;14.141634980989&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.022.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;16.579847908745&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An article about how early radio hobbyists created headaches for the Navy &lt;a href=&quot;http://earlyradiohistory.us/1909amat.htm&quot;&gt;conveys some of the flavor&lt;/a&gt; of this era:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;When the wireless telegraph operator at the Portsmouth Navy Yard tried, a week ago last Saturday, to reach the fleet that was returning from its voyage around the world, he was able to catch only a single message, and that was from the cruiser Yankton a thousand miles in advance of the other ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble was that the air was full of unimportant electric messages sent by young amateur operators in the region of Boston. The number of such amateurs who are experimenting with this new form of telegraphy is surprising; and their feats are interesting and picturesque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One boy, for example, in a New York suburb, has a wireless installation which is practically entirely the work of his own hands. In the evening or after school hours he often sits at his instrument and &quot;talks&quot; with one or another of half a dozen of his friends who have similar installations, or &quot;listens&quot; at random to the messages with which the air is filled.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;12.971134020619&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.025.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;13.451546391753&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wonderful website called &lt;a href=&quot;http://earlyradiohistory.us/&quot;&gt;Early Radio History&lt;/a&gt; has collected a number of these articles. The read just like newspaper profiles of the early web pioneers, a mix of condescension at their nerdiness and appreciation of their technical achievements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest difference in tone is that living in your mom's basement was considered a responsible sign of adulthood in 1912. It meant that you weren't out in the streets, doing God knows what, and might actually make something of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;20&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.026.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;News of the Titanic sinking in 1912 is slow to arrive in Washington, because so many people are trying to forward it at the same time, and the crosstalk slows the message down. At this point, President Taft starts grumbling about regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1914, war breaks out in Europe. Despite pleas from amateur radio hams, the American government bans all civilian radio use for the duration of the war. For five years, amateur radio is dead. The Navy even makes an attempt right after the war to buy out every radio operator and get a monopoly, until Congress slaps them down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;18.507772020725&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/radio_boys.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;18.507772020725&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ban is lifted in 1919, precipitating a full-on radio boom very reminiscent of the dot-com bubble. Money starts pouring in. Everything is radio themed. There's young adult fiction being published about boys and girls who use radio to solve crimes and have adventures—the Radio Boys series. Fortunes are made and lost speculating on radio companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every business is told that radio will transform their lives. Jewelers, for example, will no longer have to lease a dedicated telegraph line to get an exact time signal for their high-end watches. Their trade journal &lt;a href=&quot;http://earlyradiohistory.us/1919jewl.htm&quot;&gt;publishes an article&lt;/a&gt; explaining what the ether is, how it works, how you send waves through it, and how you can save a bundle by getting your official time from the Navy radio transmitter at Arlington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;29&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.023.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;31&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But mass-market radio also means the end of the informal, participatory radio web that preceded it. Now you need a license and a budget to play the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporations take over, and within a few years there are just a couple of giants running the national radio networks, to the point where one of them is broken up, back when breaking up monopolies was still a thing we did. The work becomes professionalized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry, which in the beginning had been run on a mix of enthusiasm and government money, finds its way to a workable business model: advertising. The big players wage a war over copyright to determine how artists should get paid for broadcasts over this new medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In just a few years, radio completes the transition from an eclectic group of participatory amateurs, to a mass audience of passive consumers and a professional class of producers. It assumes its place along newsprint as a mass medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unlike newspapers or the telegraph, this new medium can reach into people's homes, and talk to them in a human voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;16.961974110032&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.027.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;19.385113268608&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't take long for politically talented people to discover how to use radio for their own ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these early pioneers in the United States is Charles Coughlin, a Catholic priest and early religious broadcaster who notices that his angry rants on political topics net him a much bigger audience than his discourses on religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the middle of the 1930's, Coughlin has an active audience of ten million tuning in to hear him rail against against bankers and international conspiracies, in a way that sounds uncomfortably familiar in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's Father Coughlin at the top of his game, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oPBooPu28QY&amp;amp;t=46s&quot;&gt;yelling about banks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;29.818773234201&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.028.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;31.742565055762&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other great political radio talent in America is the new President, Franklin Roosevelt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facing a hostile press controlled by his opponents, Roosevelt decides to speak directly to the people in a series of what he terms &quot;fireside chats&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are not delivered in the bombastic style of political speeches, or in the angry right-wing talk radio style pioneered by Father Coughlin, but conversationally, as if the President were at home with you in your parlor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roosevelt exploits the intimacy of radio, speaking to people gathered in their homes, in the evening, in the company of friends and loved ones. Here's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r6nYKRLOFWg&quot;&gt;what his first fireside chat sounded like&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You wouldn't think that a lecture about the banking system could be very appealing. But in an atmosphere of crisis, people listen. For the first time, they can directly hear their leader discuss an issue of enormous consequence to their lives, in their own homes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These fireside chats help win Roosevelt a lasting popularity that will confound his enemies over the years. He will go on to win re-election three times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.029.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;26.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saul Bellow wrote about what it was like to experience one of Roosevelt's broadcasts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;drivers had pulled over, parking bumper to bumper, and turned on their radios to hear Roosevelt. They had rolled down the windows and opened the car doors. Everywhere the same voice, its odd Eastern accent, which in anyone else would have irritated Midwesterners. You could follow without missing a single word as you strolled by. You felt joined to these unknown drivers, men and women smoking their cigarettes in silence, not so much considering the President's words as affirming the rightness of his tone and taking assurance from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right there, in that Saul Bellow quote, we also find a warning about the danger of this intimate new medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Not considering but affirming.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the power that radio has to persuade through emotion, repetition, familiarity, and tone, rather than facts or argument. A good radio broadcast makes you feel like a part of something bigger, even as you listen alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15.405940594059&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.030.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;14.443069306931&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe also finds a first-class radio genius, in the person of Joseph Goebbels, the Nazi propaganda minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Goebbels's first acts after the Nazis seize power in 1933 is to start the production of cheap radios, the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Volksempf%C3%A4nger&quot;&gt;Volksempfänger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, or &quot;people's receiver&quot;. Goebbels believes it essential to the success of National Socialism that there be a radio in every home, and a loudspeaker at the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;26&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.032.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time as it is changing politics, radio technology revolutionizes the ability to make war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portable radio sets give armies what they lacked in World War I—a way to communicate in real time while in motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the First World War, armies had been paralyzed by a lack of real-time communication. Battles were run by timetable, with no way to coordinate between soldiers and artillery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blitzkrieg tactics of World War II would not have been possible if every tank crew, without exception, had not had a radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radio would come to play a pivotal role in that war, as a weapon (radar was born in that war), a source of intelligence, a means of command, and a propaganda tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/hitler_speech.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;24.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At his trial after the war, Albert Speer argued that radio was also an essential prerequisite for the political rise of the Third Reich:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hitler's dictatorship differed in one fundamental point from all its predecessors in history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His was the first dictatorship that made the complete use of all technical means for domination of its own country. Through technical devices like the radio and loudspeaker, 80 million people were deprived of independent thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speer made this claim while on trial for his life, so it was in his interest to disclaim personal agency. But there is some truth mixed in with his dissembling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radio was a force of persuasion different in kind from anything the world had seen before. Those who learned to use it first for political ends had a tremendous advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In less than four decades, radio had completed the journey from fledgeling technology, to nerdy hobby, to big business, to potent political weapon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;25.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.031.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trajectory must have come as a shock to its pioneers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its birth, it seemed like radio would only be a force for good. How could something that connects people together be anything but beneficial?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radio brought music into hospitals and nursing homes, it eased the profound isolation of rural life, it let people hear directly from their elected representatives. It brought laugher and entertainment into every parlor, saved lives at sea, gave people weather forecasts for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But radio waves are just oscillating electromagnetic fields. They really don't care how we use them. All they want is to go places at the speed of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to accept that good people, working on technology that benefits so many, with nothing but good intentions, could end up building a powerful tool for the wicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we can't afford to re-learn this lesson every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;40.665551839465&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.036.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;41.633779264214&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Rwandan genocide in 1994, one radio station, Radio Télévision Libre des Mille Collines, is estimated to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/qje/article-abstract/129/4/1947/1853091&quot;&gt;instigated the deaths of 50,000 people&lt;/a&gt;. They radicalized and goaded on the killers with a mix of jokes, dance music, and hatred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's no accident that whenever there's a coup, the first thing the rebels seize is the radio station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology interacts with human nature in complicated ways, and part of human nature is to seek power over others, and manipulate them. Technology concentrates power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to assume the new technologies we invent will concentrate power, too. There is always a gap between mass adoption and the first skillful political use of a medium. With the Internet, we are crossing that gap right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's possible that people like Putin, or the campaign that won the Brexit vote, or the Trump campaign in the United States, are the geniuses of this new medium, like Roosevelt was in his day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I worry that they're just beginners. I don't think we've even seen a Father Coughlin of the Internet, let alone a Goebbels, when it comes to making effective political use of the technology we've deployed at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not taking the threat seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;18&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.033.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google had a conference last week called Google I/O, where they showed off some truly amazing technology. The theme of it was AI in everything, both directly in their products, and by improving the tools they make available for everyone else. The subtext was that nothing but good could come out of moving these techniques into the real world as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left unsaid was the fact that to train the AI, and to fund the whole enterprise, you need a program of mass surveillance. It's significant to me that none of the companies that make their money from such surveillance are comfortable talking about their business model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's that business model that's enabling authoritarians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;14.44099378882&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.034.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;16.366459627329&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't get a clear warning that you're working on something that's bad for the world. They put you to work designing a machine that answers to &quot;OK Google&quot;, not &quot;OK Goebbels&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I bet even Goebbels' engineers could rationalize to themselves that the people's radio made lives better, and was an interesting engineering challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But being ashamed of your own business model is a clear warning that you’re not working on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hn1VxaMEjRU&quot;&gt;side of the angels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outcomes matter, not intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;25&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.037.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Book of Ecclesiastes has this to say about mass surveillance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not revile the king even in your thoughts,&lt;br /&gt;Or curse the rich in your bedroom,&lt;br /&gt;Because a bird in the sky may carry your words,&lt;br /&gt;And a bird on the wing may report what you say.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our life now is full of these birds on the wing. Radios don't just talk to us anymore, they listen, and they know how to whisper algorithmically-targeted messages to us in ways we’ll find persuasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a scary world we're building. And building it this way is a choice, not a necessity. We can't un-invent the Internet, but we can decide that the right way to fund it is not by building a Panopticon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you didn't come to this conference to hear a political talk. But the work you do matters a lot. Your choices matter a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote Ecclesiastes again: &quot;&lt;em&gt;As fish are caught in a cruel net, or birds are taken in a snare, so men are trapped by evil times that fall unexpectedly upon them.&lt;/em&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.038.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to finish with a true story from here in Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan Hanasz was one of a group of radio astronomers in the city of Toruń, and the leader of the Toruń branch of Solidarity, the trade union that was banned in 1981.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the fall of 1982, his underground chapter of Solidarity decided to make some broadcasts, to lift people's spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People in Warsaw had tried making illegal broadcasts from rooftops, but these transmitters were too easy for the Security Bureau to find by triangulation. The radio astronomers had a more clever idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of them calculated how far the broadcast from a low-powered radio transmitter could reach if it was suspended from a balloon, and the figure he came up with was surprisingly high—a few kilometers at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group thought about using weather balloons, but those would be too easy to trace. Instead, they settled on inflatable beach balls that could be purchased in a sporting goods store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chemist colleague provided them with a supply of hydrogen, which they kept in a fire extinguisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to imagine this extinguisher hanging on a hook in the lab, being used to prank people. &quot;Hey Jacek, let me put out your cigarette!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;20.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.041.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;29&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone else in the group figured out how to make a lightweight antenna out of copper foil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The part they had the most trouble finding was a tape deck, not because it was suppressed by the Polish government, but because the Americans had put an embargo on advanced electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, a colleague in France arranged to send them used automobile tape decks that they could strip down to make as light as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Hanasz describes it in an interview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The underground press would announce broadcasts in advance. Sometimes they pasted flyers on walls. People knew to scan the UHF band at a certain hour. We didn't announce a specific frequency range so that there wouldn't be interference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The broadcasts began with a long call signal: &quot;THIS IS RADIO SOLIDARITY TORUŃ&quot;, to give people time to tune their radios, followed by fifteen minutes of programming. The limiting factor was battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quoting Hanasz again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a really safe undertaking—no one got caught. The Security Bureau boys knew about the broadcasts in advance because of our flyers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Radio direction finding vans roved around the city but couldn't pinpoint the transmitter. We were able to watch them search. Once they even wound up on the banks of the Vistula, completely lost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seeing the Security Bureau so helpless brought laughter and satisfaction to people who were tired of the repression of martial law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;29.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/bolek_lolek.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1982, eleven clandestine Radio Solidarity radio stations were shut down across Poland. The scientists who cooperated in the balloon project were risking serious jail time in addition to the loss of their career and livelihood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their act of defiance didn't bring down the state. It didn't do much more than give hope and brighten the day of a few hundred people. But it went straight back to that first idealistic promise of radio: that there existed magic, invisible rays that had the power to erase the distance between people, bypass all intermediaries, and penetrate even the thickest walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell this story to reassure you that just because everything is heavy and political right now, it doesn't mean we can't also fight these fights on our own terms, as nerds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Utopian qualities that made us love the web have not disappeared, even as it's become centralized and corporate, and we can find ways to defend and express them in our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important thing is to recognize that there is a fight, and a need for individual acts of creative resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to make sure that the powerful don't get comfortable using our tools. And we have to find ways to dismantle the surveillance economy before it becomes a poltical weapon turned against our democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;24.5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.pinboard.in/ancient/thumbs/law.042.thumb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;24.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to leave you with a final quote from Ecclesiastes. This one would be perfect for a graduation speech:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Whatsoever thy hand findeth to do, do it with thy might; for there is no work, nor device, nor knowledge, nor wisdom, in the grave, whither thou goest.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope your journey to the grave is long and enjoyable! And I hope you find work to do that, in later years, you will turn back and look on with pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether for good or bad, you are the pioneers in a field that is changing the world. The decisions that you make matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please think about that in the weeks and months to come, not just as tech workers, but as citizens and as fellow human beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 14:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>panic</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://idlewords.com/talks/ancient_web.htm</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>