<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Facebook, Twitter block the NY Post from posting</title>
<link>https://www.nationalreview.com/news/twitter-cites-hacked-materials-policy-to-justify-censorship-of-ny-post-hunter-biden-article/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nationalreview.com/news/twitter-cites-hacked-materials-policy-to-justify-censorship-of-ny-post-hunter-biden-article/</guid>
<description>&lt;img width=&quot;789&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; src=&quot;https://www.nationalreview.com/news/twitter-cites-hacked-materials-policy-to-justify-censorship-of-ny-post-hunter-biden-article/&quot; class=&quot;lazyload&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?w=2057&amp;amp;ssl=1 2057w, https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?resize=300%2C175&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?resize=1024%2C597&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?resize=768%2C448&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?resize=1536%2C896&amp;amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?resize=2048%2C1195&amp;amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?resize=459%2C268&amp;amp;ssl=1 459w, https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?resize=789%2C460&amp;amp;ssl=1 789w, https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?resize=987%2C576&amp;amp;ssl=1 987w, https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?resize=50%2C29&amp;amp;ssl=1 50w&quot; data-src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?fit=789%2C460&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 789px) 100vw, 789px&quot; srcset=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;cite&gt;(Dado Ruvic/Reuters)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter said Thursday that it censored a &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt; article based on emails between Hunter Biden and a Burisma executive in accordance with its “hacked materials policy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In line with our Hacked Materials Policy, as well as our approach to blocking URLs, we are taking action to block any links to or images of the material in question on Twitter,” a Twitter spokesperson told &lt;span class=&quot;small_caps&quot;&gt;National Review&lt;/span&gt; when asked why the platform was not allowing users to share the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt;’s article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-unit ad-unit--center ad-unit--inline&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-unit--inline__label&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter’s Hacked Materials Policy &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/hacked-materials&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;states&lt;/a&gt; that it does not “permit the use of our services to directly distribute content obtained through hacking that contains private information, may put people in physical harm or danger, or contains trade secrets,” though the platform does currently allow leaked and hacked material from other sources, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wikileaks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wikileaks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, to be shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform said that the policy applied in this case due to concerns about the “lack of authoritative reporting” in regards to the origins of the material included in the article, and subsequently &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/noahmanskar/status/1316459416414302208&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;locked&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Post’&lt;/em&gt;s Twitter account. Twitter’s actions came after Facebook &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalreview.com/news/facebook-to-reduce-distribution-of-ny-post-story-on-hunter-biden-before-fact-check/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; it would limit the sharing of the story while fact-checkers reviewed the piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2020/10/14/email-reveals-how-hunter-biden-introduced-ukrainian-biz-man-to-dad/?utm_source=NYPTwitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=SocialFlow&amp;amp;utm_medium=SocialFlow&amp;amp;__twitter_impression=true&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; an article Wednesday morning based on emails between Hunter Biden and Burisma adviser Vadym Pozharskiy discussing an apparent meeting with Joe Biden in Washington, D.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-unit ad-unit--center ad-unit--inline&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-unit--inline__label&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-unit ad-unit--native&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-unit--inline__label&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Dear Hunter, thank you for inviting me to DC and giving an opportunity to meet your father and spent [sic] some time together,” Pozharskiy wrote to Hunter Biden on April 17, 2015. “It’s realty [sic] an honor and pleasure.” Joe Biden has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalreview.com/news/biden-says-he-wont-look-further-into-hunters-ukrainian-business-dealings-i-trust-my-son/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;previously said&lt;/a&gt; that he has “never spoken to my son about his overseas business dealings” and that Hunter Biden was appointed to the board of Burisma &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalreview.com/news/biden-defends-sons-appointment-to-burisma-board-hes-a-very-bright-guy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;“cause he’s a very bright guy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





&lt;p&gt;In a Thursday afternoon statement, the Biden campaign said the paper “never asked . . . about the critical elements of this story,” and that a review of “Joe Biden’s official schedules from the time” show that “no meeting, as alleged by the New York Post, ever took place.” The Biden campaign did not dispute the veracity of the emails, though no other media outlet has confirmed the &lt;em&gt;Post’&lt;/em&gt;s story so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report also mentioned other documents that Rudy Giuliani provided to the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; on Sunday. Giuliani told the paper that his lawyer received the files, including the emails, on a copied hard drive from a Delaware computer shop owner, who discovered them on a laptop that was brought in for repair but was never picked up. The paper reported that the FBI subpoenaed the original laptop computer in December 2019, and included pictures of the alleged subpoena. When asked for confirmation by the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt;, the FBI referred questions to the Delaware U.S. Attorney’s Office, where a spokesperson said “my office can neither confirm nor deny the existence of an investigation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;ad-unit ad-unit--center ad-unit--inline&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ad-unit__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-unit--inline__label&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt;‘s coverage drew &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kylegriffin1/status/1316375735179780096&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;condemnations&lt;/a&gt; from journalists on Twitter, over fears that the article could stem from “disinformation.” But Twitter’s actions outraged conservatives, with the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt;‘s opinion editor Sohrab Ahmari calling the move “digital civil war.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;500&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;14.005934718101&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This is a Big Tech information coup. This is digital civil war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, an editor at The New York Post, one of the nation’s largest papers by circulation, can’t post one of our own stories that details corruption by a major-party presidential candidate, Biden. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/BKNQmAG19H&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/BKNQmAG19H&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Sohrab Ahmari (@SohrabAhmari) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SohrabAhmari/status/1316446749729398790?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 14, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;news-tip-cta&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalreview.com/tips/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Send a tip to the news team at&lt;/em&gt; NR.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;footer class=&quot;inline-author-card&quot;&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;inline-stories inline-stories--more&quot;&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>henriquez</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Twitter Cites ‘Hacked Materials Policy’ to Justify Censorship of NY Post Hunter Biden Article | National Review</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.nationalreview.com/news/twitter-cites-hacked-materials-policy-to-justify-censorship-of-ny-post-hunter-biden-article/</og:url>
<og:description>The Biden campaign did not dispute the veracity of the emails.</og:description>
<og:image>https://i2.wp.com/www.nationalreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/2020-05-29T000000Z_446905231_RC28YG9SLRKZ_RTRMADP_3_TWITTER-TRUMP-MINNEAPOLIS.jpg?fit=1200%2C700&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nationalreview.com/news/twitter-cites-hacked-materials-policy-to-justify-censorship-of-ny-post-hunter-biden-article/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to build a great Series A deck and pitch</title>
<link>https://www.ycombinator.com/library/8d-how-to-build-a-great-series-a-pitch-and-deck</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.ycombinator.com/library/8d-how-to-build-a-great-series-a-pitch-and-deck</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As YC’s Series A Program Manager, my job is to help YC founders raise their Series As. After spending hundreds of hours working 1:1 with founders to workshop their pitches and decks, I’ve found myself giving the same feedback repeatedly. I’ve decided to compile that feedback into a single post and make it available to any founder looking to put together a great Series A pitch and deck. Every single piece of feedback given here is something we’ve told one of our founders internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s the purpose of a Series A pitch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of a Series A pitch is to show investors why they should invest in your business. It should provide a clear and concise overview of the business you’ve built, and then paint a picture of where that business could go and why raising money will help you get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s break this down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Why they should invest&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; - This is an investor pitch, not a customer pitch. Investors may not have encountered the problem you’re solving, and won’t intuitively understand how your product solves it. That’s why good pitches do 3 key things: they explain the problem your customers face and the impact it has on them, they show how your product solves this need and makes your customer’s life better, and they demonstrate why doing so is a good business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Clear and concise”&lt;/strong&gt; - Think of investor attention as a limited resource that you need to spend wisely. Making your pitch as simple and straightforward as possible minimizes the time required to understand your business. Investors should be able to glance at each slide and immediately understand the point that is being made. The best pitchers use plain English and avoid jargon as much as possible. Where jargon is necessary, they define each term clearly the first time they use it (and modulate this based on how much domain expertise their audience has.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Overview”&lt;/strong&gt;: Your goal is not to download everything about your business, but to tantalize investors with enough information to keep them interested. Leave room for questions. A successful pitch lays the groundwork for a subsequent productive, in-depth conversation. Pitches should be 15-20 minutes, with the goal of setting the stage for the subsequent 40-45 minute discussion. On that note, if investors aren’t asking questions or engaging at all, that’s a red flag — it likely means your slides are too complicated for them to understand enough to even be curious about what you’re saying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Of the business you’ve built”&lt;/strong&gt;: Start by talking about what you’ve already built. Compared to your seed round, it’s harder to raise an A based purely on promise. Investors will want to know what you have to show for the time and money you already had.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Paint a picture of where it’s going”&lt;/strong&gt;: Getting investors to believe your vision starts by showing how your present reality is trending towards it. Once you’ve established that you’ve already built something impressive, then you have the credibility you need to show how it could grow into a massive company. Venture capitalists are looking for outsize returns, so they have to believe your company can get there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Why raising money will help you get there”&lt;/strong&gt;: The deck should make clear that the obstacle to your growth is actually money (not incompetence, poor product quality, a lack of product-market fit, etc.). The deck should end by making this explicit and showing how you plan to invest that money to get you to the next level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Starting Exercise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Start by writing out your narrative as a list of bullet points. The more concise, the better - aim for 10-15 bullet points max. In YC, we call this your “fundraising vertebrae”. YC founders should be familiar with this process from Demo Day preparations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under each bullet point, list the data points you have as evidence that your argument is true. For example, if the point is that you acquire customers profitably, your subpoints would be numbers around what % of your acquisition is organic vs. paid, what your CAC/LTV or payback per customer is etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your deck around this list. Each bullet point is one slide. The high level point is the slide’s title, and the data points comprise the content of the slide that help prove your point is true. If you’re trying to make more than one point per slide, your slide is too complicated. By extension, your deck should range from 10-15 slides, not including your appendix. See below for a more detailed explanation of how to structure each slide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write out a list of questions investors could ask, especially metrics, and make sure you can answer every one of them in a clear and credible way. Have data to support where available. You need to demonstrate a solid grasp of your business to be taken seriously as a founder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Deck Outline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title (1 slide)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your title slide should list your company name or logo and a one sentence description of what you do. Anyone reading your one-liner should immediately be able to picture what you do in their head. This means it should be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concrete:&lt;/strong&gt; Example - “Reinventing agriculture” vs. “We build and operate robot greenhouses” - “Reinventing” is too abstract and “agriculture” is so broad that I don’t get any new information about what you do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use terms common enough for a layperson to understand:&lt;/strong&gt; Example -“Creating behavior change among nicotine addicts” vs. “Help people quit smoking” - “behavior change” may be a specific, meaningful term to psychology PhDs and healthcare executives, but that meaning will likely be lost on the average person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specific to what YOU do:&lt;/strong&gt; Example - “Plant-based dairy” vs. “We make plant-based cheese” - in the first case, it’s unclear what you do around plant-based dairy. Do you produce or distribute it? What kind of dairy products? Your one-liner should make clear what your market is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traction (teaser, 1 slide)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-1.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;At every point during your pitch, investors are going to be evaluating whether you are worth their time. Putting this slide early grabs the investor’s attention and convinces them that your presentation is worth listening closely to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also provides a smooth lead in from your one-liner (“We help people quit smoking. Our product is so good that in just the past 2 years, we’ve reached 500k WAU growing at 20% m/m.”) and transitions well into your problem (“The reason people need this product is that smoking is the leading cause of lung cancer…”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem (1 slide)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-15.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outline the problem you’re solving. How does the world currently work for your customers, and what’s wrong with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure it’s a problem your specific product actually solves.&lt;/strong&gt; The problem slide is a setup for the solution slide, which goes over how you solve this problem. The solution you present needs to seem like a natural fit for the problem you’re solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bad problem statement: “Americans spend $400B on mental health problems.” There’s no way a tiny startup can solve this $400B mental health problem - each startup only focuses on a piece of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good problem statement: “x Americans need therapy but can’t pay for it…” This carves out a specific part of the problem you’re focused on - lack of access to therapy. This sets up your solution slide to focus on how you’re making therapy more affordable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Present the problem from your customer’s perspective.&lt;/strong&gt; Your customer is whoever is paying you for your product. This distinction is especially important if the people that use your product are different from the people paying you for your product. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Healthcare - you’re usually paid by insurers even though your users are patients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employee benefits - you’re usually paid by employers (specifically, HR departments) even though your users are employees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a marketplace, you have to pick one perspective to talk about the problem from. It typically makes sense to talk about the side of the marketplace you’ve prioritized solving for. For example, if you’re pitching Airbnb, is the problem that landlords want to find short-term renters, or that it’s hard for short-term renters to find a place to stay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain how the world currently works. Aim to show, not tell.&lt;/strong&gt; Some problems investors are familiar with; for others, you need to show them that the problem actually exists. The best way to do this is to tell the story of what currently happens in a concrete and specific way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bad problem statement: “Medical billing is broken.” This is vague. If I disagree with this statement, there are no data points or examples to show me why I’m wrong. Even if I agree with this statement, I may not believe medical billing is broken for the same reasons you do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good problem statement: “Here’s how medical billing works today: patients need to do X very inconvenient steps, which takes Y months of delay in reimbursement and results in only Z% of claims being approved…”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution (1 slide)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-16.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve described how the world works, explain what you do and how it changes the way the world works. What do you do to fix the problem you just outlined?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do a side by side comparison.&lt;/strong&gt; Your problem slide perfectly sets you up for this. It’s one of the clearest ways we’ve found to demonstrate exactly how you change your customer’s experience in a concrete way, and therefore, what value you provide to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quantify your impact with numbers.&lt;/strong&gt; This goes back to showing, not telling. Don’t tell me you have the fastest / easiest / cheapest product on the market, actually show me numbers around the speed, ease of price of your product vs. the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of these 2 points in action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Problem slide: “When businesses want to verify the identity of other businesses, they had to manually look up businesses in X databases. This process took Y days and Z% of these results were inaccurate.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solution slide: “With us, all businesses have to do is submit a query to just one database - ours. This process takes A days and is B% accurate. This means they can verify C% more people D times faster.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on what you do right now, not what you plan to do in the future.&lt;/strong&gt; Too often I’ve listened to pitches where founders paint a vision of an awesome-sounding product, only to be disappointed when I poke at it and realize they’ve only really built the very first piece. This comes across to investors like you’re compensating for not actually having accomplished much - and investors will discount these hand-wavy hypotheticals to zero because you haven’t actually done it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t just tell me what your product can do, tell me how your customer actually uses it and why that’s valuable to them.&lt;/strong&gt; In this vein, showing screenshots of the product or long lists of features is rarely helpful. Explain just enough of what the product does to show how it solves your customer’s problem and changes their experience. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“We have a database of 100k entries” → “Our database allows customers to verify someone’s identity with X% accuracy in Y minutes.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Here’s a screenshot of what our recruiting CRM looks like” → “Our recruiting CRM allows customers to tabulate and report what their hiring funnel looks like at every stage of the process in real-time, allowing them to immediately flag problems.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traction (in-depth, a few slides)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traction 1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-17.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traction 2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-18.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traction 3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-19.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your numbers should tell a story. The story should start with the most important metric to investors. If you have revenue, this should be revenue. When you present revenue, make sure you explain how you earn that revenue - i.e. your business model. This helps investors understand what drives your revenue, and therefore how your revenue might change based on various factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specifics of what numbers to report depend on your business, but ultimately the purpose of all of these numbers are to convince the investor of an argument. (This is why our starting exercise above begins by deciding what arguments you need to make in your pitch, and then collecting the data points that show those arguments are right.) Here’s a common narrative in traction sections specifically tailored to enterprise and consumer companies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We have revenue that’s growing really fast (revenue plus growth rate), based on a solid business model (key revenue drivers, margins and how those margins are tracking over time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re great at acquiring customers (customer acquisition) and are able to do this profitably (unit economics)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For enterprise sales, key numbers could include: sales cycle, average contract value, salesperson efficiency, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For consumer, key numbers could include: breakdown of organic vs. paid acquisition, CAC/LTV, distribution channels, conversion rates etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They love our product (engagement and retention)
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For enterprise sales, key numbers could include: time to onboard, % adoption within organization, churn etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For consumer, key numbers could include: DAU/WAU/MAU, retention after one day/week/month, average amount of time spent on platform, average spend etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For hardtech and biotech companies, this section might focus on numbers showing the efficacy of the technology you’ve developed, how many patents you’ve filed, how many partnerships or LOIs you’ve signed and what the value and terms of those commitments are, or a specific milestone you’ve hit (for example, filing your 510(k) or IND application).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show trends.&lt;/strong&gt; What’s more important than where your traction is at this point in time is where it’s going. Your current scale matters in that you need to hit a certain scale for investors to trust that growth: you might start off growing 25% m/m off a base of $200k, but it’s sustaining that growth when you hit $1m that’s impressive. More important, however, is how those numbers are changing over time. This is why a monthly or quarterly graph is better than a summed up annual number. You also need to show at least 4-6 months of this trend for it to be believable (see our article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/library/1z-the-importance-of-trends&quot;&gt;The Importance of Trends).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also why the amount of time it took you to accomplish these milestones is crucial context: it shows the speed at which you move. That’s why we tell companies that the longer they’ve been around, the more they have to have done. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ycombinator.com/library/1k-benchmarks&quot;&gt;benchmarks&lt;/a&gt; we compiled in our Series A guide are based on the typical timeline of raising your Series A 18-24 months after your seed, but if you’ve been around for longer, you’ll need to have to have more to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Present numbers clearly and concisely.&lt;/strong&gt; Founders typically fall into 3 traps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Throwing reams of numbers at investors:&lt;/em&gt; information overload makes it hard to digest any information at all. Your job is to guide investors to the most important parts of your business. A good way to do this is to identify what your “hero facts” are. These are headline numbers that prove a key point you want to make. They should stick in investor’s minds after the pitch, and be what they use when pitching you to their partners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Too few numbers:&lt;/em&gt; at the Series A, you need to have data to show you’ve made good on the promises you made at the seed. At best, not being detailed enough with your data wastes precious time making the investor dig for it; at worst, it feels like you’re hiding your numbers because you think they’re weak.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unclear numbers&lt;/em&gt;: making your numbers hard to understand, usually due to either calculating or presenting them confusingly.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Calculating numbers confusingly diminishes your credibility. It suggests you either don’t understand how to calculate the number correctly (i.e. incompetence) or are not being forthright about what these numbers actually mean (i.e. dishonesty). A classic example of this is showing cumulative numbers. Almost every time I’ve seen cumulative numbers in a Series A deck, it’s because founders are trying to hide their monthly/quarterly numbers because they don’t think they’re strong enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presenting them confusingly limits investor understanding of your business. At best, it takes awhile for the investor to grok what’s going on; at worst, they zone out and never actually get to understand what your numbers mean. A classic example of this is using double axis graphs - time is always wasted in clarifying which line goes with which axis, and then figuring out what those lines mean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here are a couple of good rules of thumb to avoid falling into these traps.
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Graphs should be understandable at first glance. If it requires a deeper explanation to understand, it’s too complex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be very clear about exactly what your numbers are measuring. When you say users, are you talking about monthly actives or daily actives? When you say revenue, are you talking about gross or net?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market (1 slide)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-20.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Show how big of an opportunity you’re tackling. We usually suggest a bottoms-up calculation. A general formula for this is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;number of prospective customers x value of each customer to you&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bottoms-up calculation should rely on real numbers gleaned from your current business - the number of prospective customers is based on the customer segments you currently serve, and the value of each customer should be based on their actual value to you right now. Top down numbers from reports are often not specific enough to the market your product plays in, especially if you’re tackling a subset of the market, or if you’re creating an entirely new segment. If you’re creating a category, it’s also useful to show a couple good analogies of massive companies that have done similar things that you can pattern match against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competition (1 slide)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-21.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Show why you’re 10x better than everyone else trying to do what you’re trying to do. The key here is to convince the investor that you have a high enough moat to make your business defensible against competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vision (1 slide)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-22.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Show how you become a $10B company. This is a thought exercise we used to make all of the companies in our Series A program do to expand their ambition as much as possible. Here’s where you can dream and talk about all of the hypotheticals you’ve judiciously kept from the first part of your deck. You’ve spent the past 10 or so slides building your credibility by demonstrating the incredible business you’ve already created. Now when you talk about the future, investors are more likely to believe you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team (1 slide)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-23.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your team is one of your comparative advantages, then this should be your second or third slide. A team is a comparative advantage if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You have had a successful prior exit (e.g. started and sold a previous company for &amp;gt;$100M).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are one of the few people in the world uniquely equipped to start this company. This is typically true for biotech or hardtech companies where domain expertise is critical. (e.g. PhD in cellular immunology, former senior executive at Amgen, ex-professor of electrical engineering)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, this slide has 2 goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;To show who the founders are and why they’re the right people to start and grow this company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To show how great of a team you’ve recruited, and demonstrate that you’re able to hire the skill sets you need to execute on your vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;As before, try to quantify the quality of your team by showing impressive logos, educational degrees, or years of experience. If there are some particularly awesome accomplishments (e.g. I built out unicorn X’s growth team), call it out. Remove anything else - yes, this means leaving off the headshots for every employee in your 12 person team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been lean (e.g. accomplished everything with only a team of 4) or capital efficient (e.g spent $1m to get to $1.2m ARR), this is a good place to highlight it. You can also optionally add a slide with your advisors (if they’re impressive and especially if your company requires domain expertise) and existing investors. Just beware of signaling risk - if you include a Series A fund on the list of existing investors, you’ll be asked whether or not they’re leading your round. If the answer is yes, then why are you giving the pitch? If the answer is no or that you’re not sure, that could be a negative signal. In general, best to leave those logos off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Funds (1 slide)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.ycombinator.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Series-A-Program-Deck-24.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ask is the climax of your whole deck. It’s what everything else has been building towards, so be sure to include it (weirdly, I’ve seen many decks without one). It should cover how much you are raising, what you will use it for (on a high level), and where that will get you in 18-24 months (the typical time horizon for raising your next round) in terms of your traction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix (as many slides as necessary)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appendix should include ammunition for the subsequent Q&amp;amp;A/conversation that follows the pitch. If you’ve done the starting exercise outlined above, you should have a list of questions that investors might ask. Where having a visual aid would help, create a slide to answer each of the questions on your list. Other good things to include in your appendix are financial projections and a more detailed use of funds. This section will expand significantly once you start pitching, as you develop more content to answer investor questions that arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A note on design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimize for clarity and understanding, not beauty. Deck design should be focused on aiding comprehension over being aesthetically pleasing. In our experience, this usually means keeping it as simple and bare-bones as possible. Avoid anything that might distract from your main point. Two of the most common culprits here are fancy, complicated diagrams that are hard to understand or colorful images that look nice but don’t help illustrate your point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pitch Practice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have your deck, it’s time to practice. Reach out to angels or other founders that have raised their Series A to set up practice pitches. A good format is to schedule an hour with a 20 minute pitch, a 20 minute conversation, and 20 minutes of feedback. Here’s how we’d suggest running it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;During the pitch section, time yourself. Is your pitch 20 minutes or less? Pay attention to how you felt during pitching - did you feel confident? Convinced of what you were saying?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the conversation section, note what kind of conversation you’re having, and whether it was the kind of conversation you wanted to set up with your pitch. What are things you wanted your audience to ask about that they didn’t? What are pieces they asked about that you hadn’t thought about and need to better prepare for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the feedback section, ask your audience (these are questions we suggest YC founders ask during Demo Day pitch practice):
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Were you confused? If so, when?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Were you bored? If so, when?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did my deck help or hurt?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are a couple hard questions I need great answers to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another good way to test individual slides is to flash the slide to a friend who’s never seen it before, and ask them to tell you what point the slide is making. If it isn’t immediately understandable, you have some work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Presenting Over Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most initial pitches now happen over video (though some may progress to socially distanced hangouts, based on investors’ individual preferences). This changes the dynamics of your pitch. Here are some important things to do when pitching over a video call:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Turn on your video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revamp your video and audio set up.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make sure you’re looking into the camera, not to another screen set up on the side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure your face is well lit (one founder found the ring lights that TikTokers use to be a cheap and easy way to upgrade your lighting), at an attractive angle (please, not up your nostrils), and that you have a non-distracting background (use Zoom backgrounds if necessary).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure your audio is working well, and that you have a quiet room to take the call in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One person should pitch. This is almost always better, but it is especially true for pitches over video call. Switching speakers is usually confusing and hard to coordinate, especially if the two founders are in different places. However, it’s often useful for another founder to come to answer questions and take notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record and watch yourself on video to see how you’re coming across. You’re going to have to overcompensate in energy and verve to make up for the fact that you’re a tiny box in a corner of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a rough outline of a script: we suggest writing out at least a bullet-pointed script (if you’ve done the starting exercise, you already have an outline of one). This script helps make sure you hit all the important points in the right order. Plus, the benefit of pitching over a video call is that you can have it in front of you during the pitch without the investor knowing. If you know that you tend to be long-winded, writing out a word-for-word script can help you figure out how to convey your points concisely. However, avoid just reading off of it -- you want your pitch to come across as natural and conversational.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[If needed] Hire a pitch or speaking coach, especially if you know you’re not a great presenter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Refining Your Deck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We suggest setting aside 1-2 hours every day of your fundraise to go over how each meeting went and use that to improve your deck and pitch. Here’s a set of questions to ask yourself after each pitch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What did investors seem to get most excited or energized by? Usually, this is indicated by where they asked the most questions or were the most attentive. Would it help to emphasize this in future pitches?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What parts did they seem to zone out in? This could be because you weren’t explaining it well, or they didn’t buy what you were saying. Is there anything you could do to make this section clearer or more compelling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What objections were raised, and did you have a well thought through, convincing answer to them? Look at your vertebrae - what pieces of it seemed to be the weakest or least compelling to the investor? Is there data you can pull, slides you can create, examples you can give, or people you can talk to that will help you better respond to these concerns?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 18:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>janellehmtam</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.ycombinator.com/library/8d-how-to-build-a-great-series-a-pitch-and-deck</og:url>
<og:title>How to Build a Great Series A Pitch and Deck: Series A</og:title>
<og:description>YC’s Series A Program Manager Janelle Tam on how to put together a great Series A pitch and deck.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.ycombinator.com/library/8d-how-to-build-a-great-series-a-pitch-and-deck</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The real prices of the iPhone 12 and iPhone 12 mini</title>
<link>https://sixcolors.com/post/2020/10/apple-fibs-about-iphone-12-pricing-to-promote-wireless-carriers/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://sixcolors.com/post/2020/10/apple-fibs-about-iphone-12-pricing-to-promote-wireless-carriers/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;column1&quot; readability=&quot;6.1428571428571&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;By Jason Snell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;dateline&quot;&gt;October 13, 2020 5:47 PM PT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column2&quot; readability=&quot;42.240938166311&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/sixcolors.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/hans-from-verizon.jpg?ssl=1&quot; data-image-w=&quot;&quot; data-image-h=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; jetpack-broken-image&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s one of the weirdest aspects of &lt;a href=&quot;https://sixcolors.com/post/2020/10/quick-thoughts-on-apples-october-event/&quot;&gt;Tuesday’s iPhone launch event&lt;/a&gt;: Apple has been less than forthright about the real prices of the iPhone 12 and iPhone 12 mini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the event, Apple referred to these products as starting at $699 (iPhone 12 mini) and $799 (iPhone 12), but those prices are not actually accurate unless you slap a big asterisk on there. (As Apple does on its marketing pages, because it must.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s actually happening, at least in the U.S.: Apple has cut deals with AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon that give existing customers of those carriers $30 off their purchases. The &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; prices of the two models are $729 and $829, and that’s what you’ll pay if you’re a U.S. subscriber to Sprint, T-Mobile, any smaller pay-as-you-go carriers, or if you want to buy a SIM-free model with no carrier connection at all. (The 12 Pro and 12 Pro Max are the same price on all carriers.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s embarrassing that Apple is hiding the real price of the iPhone 12. More troubling is the suggestion that Apple is now happy to join forces with its carrier partners to play marketing games—not just with the price of the iPhone 12 and 12 mini, but with the embarrassing amount of screen time Apple gave to Verizon’s CEO on Tuesday so he could flog his company’s 5G network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Joe Rossignol of MacRumors &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MacRumors/status/1316490399758921733&quot;&gt;reports that&lt;/a&gt; T-Mobile claims it will have iPhone 12-related offers available beginning Friday, when phones go on sale. Unclear if this means it’ll also be providing a straight-up $30 discount or if it’ll be tied to other promotions. And of course, it leaves users of alternative carriers paying more.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you appreciate articles like this one, support us by &lt;a href=&quot;https://sixcolors.com/subscribe/&quot;&gt;becoming a Six Colors subscriber&lt;/a&gt;. Subscribers get access to an exclusive podcast, members-only stories, and a special community.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 18:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cglong</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Apple fibs about iPhone 12 pricing to promote wireless carriers</og:title>
<og:url>https://sixcolors.com/post/2020/10/apple-fibs-about-iphone-12-pricing-to-promote-wireless-carriers/</og:url>
<og:description>Here’s one of the weirdest aspects of Tuesday’s iPhone launch event: Apple has been less than forthright about the real prices of the iPhone 12 and iPhone 12 mini. At the event, Apple r…</og:description>
<og:image>https://149426355.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/hans-from-verizon.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://sixcolors.com/post/2020/10/apple-fibs-about-iphone-12-pricing-to-promote-wireless-carriers/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>HashiCorp Boundary</title>
<link>https://www.hashicorp.com/blog/hashicorp-boundary</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.hashicorp.com/blog/hashicorp-boundary</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce HashiCorp &lt;a href=&quot;https://boundaryproject.io/&quot;&gt;Boundary&lt;/a&gt;, a new open source project that enables practitioners and operators to securely access dynamic hosts and services with fine-grained authorization without requiring direct network access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boundary is designed to grant access to critical systems using the principle of least privilege, solving challenges organizations encounter when users need to securely access applications and machines. Traditional products that grant access to systems are cumbersome, painful to maintain, or are black boxes lacking extensible APIs. Boundary allows authenticated and authorized users to access secure systems in private networks without granting access to the larger network where those systems reside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;traditional-workflow&quot;&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;traditional-workflow&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.hashicorp.com/blog/hashicorp-boundary#traditional-workflow&quot;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt; Traditional Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better understand how Boundary works, and why we are building it, we want to provide a few examples that highlight the challenges users and operators face when securely connecting to applications and critical systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram below illustrates a typical connection workflow and the challenges that occur when a user requires remote access to a production system located in a private network. Usually a gateway bridges access into these private networks through a VPN or SSH bastion host. Both solutions offer varying degrees of security which could provide a user with direct access on the private network and not just access to the intended systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img srcset=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530950-boundary-blog-3-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=250 250w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530950-boundary-blog-3-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=500 500w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530950-boundary-blog-3-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=750 750w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530950-boundary-blog-3-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=1000 1000w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530950-boundary-blog-3-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=1500 1500w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530950-boundary-blog-3-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=2000 2000w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530950-boundary-blog-3-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=2500 2500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 100vw) 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530950-boundary-blog-3-edited.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Traditional Workflow&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This traditional access model assumes resources are mostly static, and it is not well suited for the cloud with highly ephemeral and dynamic environments. Scaling the solutions as workforces and infrastructure grow creates additional pain points and complexity for administrators to manage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once users are on these private networks, they can access any system and not just the intended target. If the credentials used to access the VPN or SSH host are lost or stolen, an adversary could access the entire network. To safeguard against that risk, a traditional workflow will typically place a firewall inside these private networks that restricts what users have access to in order to safeguard against this risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, managing internal firewalls is time consuming and wasteful when the system granting access should have followed the principle of least privilege from the outset. Boundary was designed with these core problems in mind: grant access to critical systems with least privilege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;boundary-workflow&quot;&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;boundary-workflow&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.hashicorp.com/blog/hashicorp-boundary#boundary-workflow&quot;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt; Boundary Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Boundary is to simplify the workflow for securely accessing hosts and services while also reducing risk and attack surface associated with traditional solutions. With Boundary, access is based on the trusted identity of the user, rather than their network location. The user connects and authenticates to Boundary, then based on their assigned roles they can connect to available hosts, services, or cloud resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trusted identities and roles are a core principle in Boundary; they define which users are allowed to connect with a specific set of resources. For example, with Boundary, you could grant only developers access to connect to databases. This model allows Boundary to define logical sets of systems and applications and removes the brittleness associated with static IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img srcset=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477814-boundary-blog-2.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=250 250w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477814-boundary-blog-2.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=500 500w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477814-boundary-blog-2.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=750 750w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477814-boundary-blog-2.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=1000 1000w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477814-boundary-blog-2.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=1500 1500w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477814-boundary-blog-2.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=2000 2000w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477814-boundary-blog-2.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=2500 2500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 100vw) 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477814-boundary-blog-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Boundary Workflow&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boundary authenticates and authorizes each request, mapping users to services or hosts at the application layer. There are no VPN credentials or SSH bastion host keys to manage, which simplifies onboarding and reduces risk of a credential compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img srcset=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530901-boundary-blog-1-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=250 250w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530901-boundary-blog-1-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=500 500w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530901-boundary-blog-1-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=750 750w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530901-boundary-blog-1-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=1000 1000w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530901-boundary-blog-1-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=1500 1500w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530901-boundary-blog-1-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=2000 2000w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530901-boundary-blog-1-edited.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=2500 2500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 100vw) 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602530901-boundary-blog-1-edited.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Boundary Workflow&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boundary provides an easy-to-use, platform-agnostic way to access all of your hosts and services across clouds, Kubernetes or Nomad clusters, and on-premises datacenters through a single workflow based on trusted identity. It lets you remove hard-coded credentials and firewall rules, and makes access control more dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-boundary-works&quot;&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;how-boundary-works&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.hashicorp.com/blog/hashicorp-boundary#how-boundary-works&quot;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt; How Boundary Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boundary 0.1 enables authenticated and authorized TCP sessions to applications with role-based access controls (RBAC). Users can automate access management to dynamic targets with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hashicorp/terraform-provider-boundary&quot;&gt;Boundary Terraform provider&lt;/a&gt;, the API, or SDK. Boundary also supports monitoring and logging of session metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We designed the architecture of Boundary to be easy to understand, highly scalable, and fault tolerant. Users can interact with Boundary through the CLI, API, or a web interface. It can run on-premises, in the cloud, or in secure enclaves, and it does not require you to install an agent on target hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img srcset=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477868-boundary-blog-4.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=250 250w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477868-boundary-blog-4.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=500 500w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477868-boundary-blog-4.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=750 750w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477868-boundary-blog-4.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=1000 1000w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477868-boundary-blog-4.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=1500 1500w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477868-boundary-blog-4.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=2000 2000w, https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477868-boundary-blog-4.png?fit=max&amp;amp;fm=png&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=2500 2500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 100vw) 100vw&quot; src=&quot;https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602477868-boundary-blog-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Boundary Architecture&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better explain how Boundary works, let's walk through how an end-to-end connection is established. When a user authenticates to Boundary, they can choose from a selection of hosts or applications based on their roles, and then connect through Boundary to access those hosts or applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a user establishes a TCP session through Boundary, a Boundary worker node seamlessly proxies the connection. This makes Boundary more secure than traditional access systems such as a VPN or SSH bastion hosts because Boundary makes the connection for the user and limits the user’s access. Since Boundary controls access directly for end users, all the way to the intended target system, it makes your organization’s network more secure by never allowing users access to the private network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;next-steps&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://www.hashicorp.com/blog/hashicorp-boundary#next-steps&quot;&gt;»&lt;/a&gt; Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boundary 0.1 is available today as an open source project. Note that the project is under active development and we are working on adding OIDC authentication, a HashiCorp Vault integration, and dynamic target catalogs pulled from HashiCorp Consul, AWS, Azure, and GCP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Boundary, please visit the project website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://boundaryproject.io/&quot;&gt;boundaryproject.io&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hashicorp/boundary&quot;&gt;github.com/hashicorp/boundary&lt;/a&gt; for the source code, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.hashicorp.com/collections/boundary/getting-started&quot;&gt;HashiCorp Learn&lt;/a&gt; to find our step-by-step tutorials to get started with Boundary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you experience any issues, please report them on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hashicorp/boundary&quot;&gt;Boundary GitHub issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; or post to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.hashicorp.com/c/boundary/50&quot;&gt;Boundary discuss forum&lt;/a&gt;. We hope you enjoy Boundary 0.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 15:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yongshin</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>Simple and secure remote access — to any system anywhere based on trusted identity.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.datocms-assets.com/2885/1602281050-boundaryhashiconf.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.hashicorp.com/blog/hashicorp-boundary</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: I wrote a book on writing good developer resumes</title>
<link>https://thetechresume.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thetechresume.com/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;48.604651162791&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Author&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Gergely Orosz&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Uber, Microsoft, Skype, Skyscanner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Technical reviewers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;James Stanier&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;VP Engineering, Brandwatch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Sofi Djelassi&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Miro, Uber, Altassian, Spotify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Manan Patel&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Coinbase, Uber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Matt Dickenson&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Square, Uber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Rodrigo Pimentel&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;CTO, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jump.work/&quot;&gt;Jump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Angelica Shah&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Uber, Airbnb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Keki Mwaba&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Disney Streaming Services, Uber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;EDITOR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;57.103448275862&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contributing Experts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Blake Stockman&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Outrider, Google, Facebook, Uber, Flexport&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Victoria Farrelly&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Uber, Booking.com, ING&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Ken Liu&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Microsoft, Skype, Microsoft Game Studios&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Jorick Thijs Polderman&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Transferwise, Randstad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Veronika Nagy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Uber, Capgemini, Mobgen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Chukwuemeka Ugorji&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Facebook, Andela&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Sebastian Prieto Tovar&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Uber, Nike&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Claire Taylor&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Uber university &amp;amp; campus recruitment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Neville Kuyt&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Equal Experts, AKQA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Csudi Csudutov&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Mimox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Yinka Coker&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;Andela&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Steve Ball&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;social&quot;/&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;company&quot;&gt;CTO at high-growth startups&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 15:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gregdoesit</dc:creator>
<og:type>books.book</og:type>
<og:title>The Tech Resume Inside Out</og:title>
<og:url>https://thetechresume.com/</og:url>
<og:image>assets/images/TheTechResumeInsideOut_og_Image.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>What a good developer resume looks like and how to write one. Principles to stand out - from from technical recruiters and hiring managers running the hiring process.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thetechresume.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Room-Temperature Superconductivity Achieved for the First Time</title>
<link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/physicists-discover-first-room-temperature-superconductor-20201014/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.quantamagazine.org/physicists-discover-first-room-temperature-superconductor-20201014/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;A team of physicists in New York has discovered a material that conducts electricity with perfect efficiency at room temperature — a long-sought scientific milestone. The hydrogen, carbon and sulfur compound operates as a superconductor at up to 59 degrees Fahrenheit, the team &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2801-z&quot;&gt;reported today in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. That’s more than 50 degrees hotter than the previous high-temperature superconductivity record set last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is the first time we can really claim that room-temperature superconductivity has been found,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://cfm.ehu.es/team/ion-errea-lope/&quot;&gt;Ion Errea&lt;/a&gt;, a condensed matter theorist at the University of the Basque Country in Spain who was not involved in the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s clearly a landmark,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msm.cam.ac.uk/people/pickard&quot;&gt;Chris Pickard&lt;/a&gt;, a materials scientist at the University of Cambridge. “That’s a chilly room, maybe a British Victorian cottage,” he said of the 59-degree temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet while researchers celebrate the achievement, they stress that the newfound compound — created by a team led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hajim.rochester.edu/me/people/faculty/dias-ranga/index.html&quot;&gt;Ranga Dias&lt;/a&gt; of the University of Rochester — will never find its way into lossless power lines, frictionless high-speed trains, or any of the revolutionary technologies that could become ubiquitous if the fragile quantum effect underlying superconductivity could be maintained in truly ambient conditions. That’s because the substance superconducts at room temperature only while being crushed between a pair of diamonds to pressures roughly 75% as extreme as those found in the Earth’s core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People have talked about room-temperature superconductivity forever,” Pickard said. “They may not have quite appreciated that when we did it, we were going to do it at such high pressures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials scientists now face the challenge of discovering a superconductor that operates not only at normal temperatures but under everyday pressures, too. Certain features of the new compound raise hopes that the right blend of atoms could someday be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrical resistance occurs in normal wires when freely flowing electrons bump into the atoms that make up the metal. But researchers discovered in 1911 that at low temperatures, electrons can induce vibrations in a metal’s atomic lattice, and those vibrations in turn draw electrons together into couples known as Cooper pairs. Different quantum rules govern these couples, which stream together in a coherent swarm that passes through the metal’s lattice unimpeded, experiencing no resistance whatsoever. The superconducting fluid also expels magnetic fields — an effect that could allow magnetically levitating vehicles to float frictionlessly above superconducting rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the temperature of a superconductor rises, however, particles jiggle around randomly, breaking up the electrons’ delicate dance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers have spent decades searching for a superconductor whose Cooper pairs tango tightly enough to withstand the heat of everyday environments. In 1968, Neil Ashcroft, a solid-state physicist at Cornell University, &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.aps.org/prl/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevLett.21.1748&quot;&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; that a lattice of hydrogen atoms would do the trick. Hydrogen’s diminutive size lets electrons get closer to the nodes of the lattice, augmenting their interactions with the vibrations. Hydrogen’s lightness also allows those guiding ripples to vibrate faster, further strengthening the glue that binds the Cooper pairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impractically high pressures are needed to squash hydrogen into a metallic lattice. Still, Ashcroft’s work raised hopes that some “hydride”— a mixture of hydrogen and a second element — might deliver metallic hydrogen’s superconductivity at more accessible pressures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progress &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev-conmatphys-031218-013413&quot;&gt;took off in the 2000s&lt;/a&gt;, when supercomputer simulations let theorists predict the properties of various hydrides, and the widespread use of compact diamond anvils let experimentalists squeeze the most promising candidates to test their mettle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, hydrides started setting records. A team in Germany showed in 2015 that a metallic form of hydrogen sulfide — a pungent compound found in rotten eggs — superconducts at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature14964&quot;&gt;−94 degrees Fahrenheit under 1.5 million times the pressure of the atmosphere&lt;/a&gt;. Four years later, the same lab used lanthanum hydride to hit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-019-1201-8&quot;&gt;−10 degrees under 1.8 million atmospheres&lt;/a&gt;, even as another group &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.aps.org/prl/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevLett.122.027001&quot;&gt;found evidence&lt;/a&gt; for superconductivity in the same compound at 8 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dias’ lab in Rochester has now shattered those records. Guided by intuition and rough calculations, the team tested a range of hydrogen compounds searching for the goldilocks ratio of hydrogen. Add too little hydrogen, and a compound won’t superconduct as robustly as metallic hydrogen does. Add too much, and the sample will act too much like metallic hydrogen, metalizing only at pressures that will crack your diamond anvil. Over the course of their research, the team busted many dozens of $3,000 diamond pairs. “That’s the biggest problem with our research, the diamond budget,” Dias said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winning recipe proved to be a riff on the 2015 formula. The researchers started with hydrogen sulfide, added methane (a compound of carbon and hydrogen), and baked the concoction with a laser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We were able to enrich the system and introduce just the right critical amount of hydrogen necessary to maintain these Cooper pairs at very high temperatures,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unlv.edu/people/ashkan-salamat&quot;&gt;Ashkan Salamat&lt;/a&gt;, Dias’ collaborator and a condensed matter physicist at the University of Nevada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the fine details of the hydrogen-carbon-sulfur potion they’ve cooked up elude them. Hydrogen is too small to show up in traditional probes of lattice structure, so the group doesn’t know how the atoms are arranged, or even the substance’s exact chemical formula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acsu.buffalo.edu/~ezurek/&quot;&gt;Eva Zurek&lt;/a&gt;, a computational chemist at the University at Buffalo, belongs to a group of theorists loosely affiliated with Dias’ lab. Earlier this year they &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.aps.org/prb/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevB.101.134504&quot;&gt;predicted the conditions&lt;/a&gt; under which one metal that might have formed between the diamond anvils should superconduct, and they found different behavior. She suspects that high pressures instead transformed Dias’ substance into an unknown form whose superconductivity is especially robust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Dias’ group can figure out exactly what they’ve got on their hands (details he and Salamat say are coming soon), theorists will build models exploring the features that give this hydrogen-carbon-sulfur mixture its superconducting power, in hopes of further modifying the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physicists have proved most two-element hydrogen hybrids to be dead ends, but the new three-element blend marks a potentially significant advance into the world of complex chimera materials. One of the elements involved seems particularly promising to some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What I like about this work: They bring carbon into the system,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mpic.de/3538358/Eremets_Group&quot;&gt;Mikhail Eremets&lt;/a&gt;, an experimentalist at the Max Planck Institute for Chemistry in Germany whose lab set the hydride records of 2015 and 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He explained that the lightness of hydrogen is not the only way to beef up the vibrations that steer electrons into Cooper pairs. Stronger links between neighboring atoms in the lattice also help, and, he said, “carbon has very strong covalent bonds.” Materials with carbon frames could bring the added benefit of preventing the whole assembly from tumbling down at the low pressures humans find comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zurek agrees. “Room pressure I thought would be very challenging,” she said. “But if we can bring carbon compounds into the mix, I think that presents a way forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 15:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>theafh</dc:creator>
<og:title>Room-Temperature Superconductivity Achieved for the First Time</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.quantamagazine.org/physicists-discover-first-room-temperature-superconductor-20201014/</og:url>
<og:image>https://d2r55xnwy6nx47.cloudfront.net/uploads/2020/10/diamond_anvil_1200_Social.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.quantamagazine.org/physicists-discover-first-room-temperature-superconductor-20201014/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>PRISM – NSA surveillance program did not prevent a single terrorist attack</title>
<link>https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/nsa-phone-surveillance-illegal-expensive/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/nsa-phone-surveillance-illegal-expensive/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;nsa-phone-surveillance&quot;&gt;NSA phone surveillance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSA phone surveillance program has been in place as part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PRISM_(surveillance_program)&quot;&gt;PRISM&lt;/a&gt; from 2008 to 2019 in the USA. It &quot;specifically authorizes intelligence agencies to monitor the phone, email, and other communications of U.S. citizens for up to a week without obtaining a warrant&quot; when one of the parties is outside the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSA phone surveillance program to date has cost American tax payers over $100 Million, according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/02/25/us/politics/nsa-phone-program.html&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, it did not prevent one single terrorist attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program ceased to exist end of 2019 and is no longer in place. Warrantless surveillance of citizens is &lt;a href=&quot;https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/bnd-german-surveillance-unconstitutional&quot;&gt;unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt; - in the USA, in Germany as well as in most democratic countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;warrantless-surveillance-of-citizens&quot;&gt;Warrantless surveillance of citizens&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, PRISM was in place more than a decade, and during this time American citizens were monitored by the secret services without their knowledge. The NSA argued that it needed this kind of information to stop terrorist attacks and keep American people safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a judge &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/nsa-phone-snooping-illegal-court-finds-2020-9&quot;&gt;ruled&lt;/a&gt; beginning of September 2020 that not [one single terrorist attack had been stopped with the help of the NSA's phone surveillance program. The ruling was about the one and only case that a study by the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board found where the NSA produced successful evidence against terrorists based on phone surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ruling concluded that the evidence produced from the (illegal) phone surveillance was not necessary to convict the criminal and did not bring any further information forward than what was already known to the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mass-surveillance-not-necessary-to-fight-crime&quot;&gt;Mass surveillance not necessary to fight crime&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar investigation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/exploiting-terror-for-surveillance&quot;&gt;terrorist attacks&lt;/a&gt; in Europe came to the same conclusion: Between 2014 and 2017, 13 Islamist terrorist attacks took place in Europe after which 24 offenders were convicted. All 24 of them - one hundred per cent - were already known to the authorities prior to the attack and had been classified as violent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion from this investigation is that we do not need more surveillance to achieve better security. What we do need is better trained and better equipped police officers so that they can identify potential threats faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While investing in mass surveillance tools seems a lot easier, all data shows that no one benefits if everyone is monitored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;end-mass-surveillance&quot;&gt;End mass surveillance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What comes clear from the examples in the USA and in Europe is that we must end mass surveillance. It is neither an adequate tool to fight - let alone predict - crime, nor is it possible to bring it in-line with the constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of calling for more surveillance, politicians should focus on protecting citizens' human rights, like our right to privacy and our right to freedom of speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These human rights are severely damaged when warrantless mass surveillance is in place. In its worst form - and with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/facial-recognition-ban-privacy&quot;&gt;facial recognition&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/google-tracking-suspect&quot;&gt;location tracking&lt;/a&gt; - it might lead to a society no longer free to discuss opinions openly and without fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As new and better surveillance technologies arise, it becomes more and more important that we uphold our democratic values and make sure that our human rights are respected, also, and particularly, by the authorities. For this, we also need strong &lt;a href=&quot;https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/why-a-backdoor-is-a-security-risk&quot;&gt;encryption without backdoors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, it all comes down to a simple choice: Do we want to give all power to the authorities, or do we want that all power remains with the people?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 14:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Pick-A-Hill2019</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>The NSA phone surveillance program was illegal and expensive: And it did not stop a single terrorist attack.</og:title>
<og:description>Mass surveillance costs millions of Dollars. Yet, it does not improve security.</og:description>
<og:url>https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/nsa-phone-surveillance-illegal-expensive</og:url>
<og:image>https://tutanota.com/blog/images/phone-surveillance.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/nsa-phone-surveillance-illegal-expensive/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dockerfile Security Best Practices</title>
<link>https://cloudberry.engineering/article/dockerfile-security-best-practices/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://cloudberry.engineering/article/dockerfile-security-best-practices/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Container security is a broad problem space and there are many low hanging fruits one can harvest to mitigate risks. A good starting point is to follow some rules when writing Dockerfiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve compiled a list of common security issues and how to avoid them. For every issue I’ve also written an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openpolicyagent.org/&quot;&gt;Open Policy Agent&lt;/a&gt; (OPA) rule ready to be used to statically analyze your Dockerfiles with &lt;a href=&quot;https://conftest.dev&quot;&gt;conftest&lt;/a&gt;. You can’t shift more left than this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the &lt;code&gt;.rego&lt;/code&gt; rule set in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gbrindisi/dockerfile-security&quot;&gt;this repository&lt;/a&gt;. I appreciate feedback and contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-not-store-secrets-in-environment-variables&quot;&gt;Do not store secrets in environment variables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secrets distribution is a hairy problem and it’s easy to do it wrong. For containerized applications one can surface them either from the filesystem by mounting volumes or more handily through environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;ENV&lt;/code&gt; to store secrets is bad practice because Dockerfiles are usually distributed with the application, so there is no difference from hard coding secrets in code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to detect it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;secrets_env = [
    &quot;passwd&quot;,
    &quot;password&quot;,
    &quot;pass&quot;,
 #  &quot;pwd&quot;, can't use this one   
    &quot;secret&quot;,
    &quot;key&quot;,
    &quot;access&quot;,
    &quot;api_key&quot;,
    &quot;apikey&quot;,
    &quot;token&quot;,
    &quot;tkn&quot;
]

deny[msg] {    
    input[i].Cmd == &quot;env&quot;
    val := input[i].Value
    contains(lower(val[_]), secrets_env[_])
    msg = sprintf(&quot;Line %d: Potential secret in ENV key found: %s&quot;, [i, val])
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;only-use-trusted-base-images&quot;&gt;Only use trusted base images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supply chain attacks for containerized application will also come from the hierarchy of layers used to build the container itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main culprit is obviously the base image used. Untrusted base images are a high risk and whenever possible should be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker provides a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/docker-hub/official_images/&quot;&gt;set of official base images&lt;/a&gt; for most used operating systems and apps. By using them, we minimize risk of compromise by leveraging some sort of shared responsibility with Docker itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to detect it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;deny[msg] {
    input[i].Cmd == &quot;from&quot;
    val := split(input[i].Value[0], &quot;/&quot;)
    count(val) &amp;gt; 1
    msg = sprintf(&quot;Line %d: use a trusted base image&quot;, [i])
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rule is tuned towards DockerHub’s official images. It’s very dumb since I’m only detecting the absence of a namespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The definition of trust depends on your context: change this rule accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-not-use-latest-tag-for-base-image&quot;&gt;Do not use ‘latest’ tag for base image&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pinning the version of your base images will give you some peace of mind with regards to the predictability of the containers you are building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you rely on latest you might silently inherit updated packages that in the best worst case might impact your application reliability, in the worst worst case might introduce a vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to detect it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;deny[msg] {
    input[i].Cmd == &quot;from&quot;
    val := split(input[i].Value[0], &quot;:&quot;)
    contains(lower(val[1]), &quot;latest&quot;])
    msg = sprintf(&quot;Line %d: do not use 'latest' tag for base images&quot;, [i])
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-curl-bashing&quot;&gt;Avoid curl bashing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulling stuff from internet and piping it into a shell is as bad as it could be. Unfortunately it’s a widespread solution to streamline installations of software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget https://cloudberry.engineering/absolutely-trustworthy.sh | sh
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risk is the same framed for supply chain attacks and it &lt;strong&gt;boils down to trust&lt;/strong&gt;. If you really have to curl bash, do it right:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;use a trusted source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use a secure connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;verify the authenticity and integrity of what you download&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to detect it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;deny[msg] {
    input[i].Cmd == &quot;run&quot;
    val := concat(&quot; &quot;, input[i].Value)
    matches := regex.find_n(&quot;(curl|wget)[^|^&amp;gt;]*[|&amp;gt;]&quot;, lower(val), -1)
    count(matches) &amp;gt; 0
    msg = sprintf(&quot;Line %d: Avoid curl bashing&quot;, [i])
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-not-upgrade-your-system-packages&quot;&gt;Do not upgrade your system packages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be a bit of a stretch but the reasoning is the following: you want to pin the version of your software dependencies, if you do &lt;code&gt;apt-get upgrade&lt;/code&gt; you will effectively upgrade them all to the latest version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do upgrade &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; you are using the &lt;code&gt;latest&lt;/code&gt; tag for the base image, you amplify the unpredictability of your dependencies tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you want to do is to pin the base image version and just &lt;code&gt;apt/apk update&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to detect it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;upgrade_commands = [
    &quot;apk upgrade&quot;,
    &quot;apt-get upgrade&quot;,
    &quot;dist-upgrade&quot;,
]

deny[msg] {
    input[i].Cmd == &quot;run&quot;
    val := concat(&quot; &quot;, input[i].Value)
    contains(val, upgrade_commands[_])
    msg = sprintf(“Line: %d: Do not upgrade your system packages&quot;, [i])
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-not-use-add-if-possible&quot;&gt;Do not use ADD if possible&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One little feature of the &lt;code&gt;ADD&lt;/code&gt; command is that you can point it to a remote url and it will fetch the content at building time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;ADD https://cloudberry.engineering/absolutely-trust-me.tar.gz
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically the official docs suggest to use curl bashing instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a security perspective the same advice applies: don’t. Get whatever content you need before, verify it and then &lt;code&gt;COPY&lt;/code&gt;. But if you really have to, &lt;strong&gt;use trusted sources over secure connections&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: if you have a fancy build system that dynamically generate Dockerfiles, then &lt;code&gt;ADD&lt;/code&gt; is effectively a sink asking to be exploited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to detect it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;deny[msg] {
    input[i].Cmd == &quot;add&quot;
    msg = sprintf(&quot;Line %d: Use COPY instead of ADD&quot;, [i])
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-not-root&quot;&gt;Do not root&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Root in a container is the same root as on the host machine, but restricted by the docker daemon configuration. No matter the limitations, if an actor breaks out of the container he will still be able to find a way to get full access to the host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this is not ideal and your threat model can’t ignore the risk posed by running as root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such is best to always specify a user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;USER hopefullynotroot
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that explicitly setting a user in the Dockerfile is just one layer of defence and won’t solve the whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/understanding-root-inside-and-outside-container&quot;&gt;running as root problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead one can — and &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; — adopt a defence in depth approach and mitigate further across the whole stack: strictly configure the docker daemon or use a rootless container solution, restrict the runtime configuration (prohibit &lt;code&gt;--privileged&lt;/code&gt; if possible, etc), and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to detect it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;any_user {
    input[i].Cmd == &quot;user&quot;
 }

deny[msg] {
    not any_user
    msg = &quot;Do not run as root, use USER instead&quot;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-not-sudo&quot;&gt;Do not sudo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a corollary to &lt;code&gt;do not root&lt;/code&gt;, you shall not sudo either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you run as a user make sure the user is not in the &lt;code&gt;sudoers&lt;/code&gt; club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;deny[msg] {
    input[i].Cmd == &quot;run&quot;
    val := concat(&quot; &quot;, input[i].Value)
    contains(lower(val), &quot;sudo&quot;)
    msg = sprintf(&quot;Line %d: Do not use 'sudo' command&quot;, [i])
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;acknowledgements&quot;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work has been inspired and is an iteration on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.madhuakula.com/dockerfile-security-checks-using-opa-rego-policies-with-conftest-32ab2316172f&quot;&gt;prior art&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.madhuakula.com/@madhuakula&quot;&gt;Madhu Akula&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 14:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gbrindisi</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://cloudberry.engineering/article/dockerfile-security-best-practices/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook account banned after linking Oculus account</title>
<link>https://www.reddit.com/r/OculusQuest/comments/japo1j/facebook_account_banned_within_10_minutes/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reddit.com/r/OculusQuest/comments/japo1j/facebook_account_banned_within_10_minutes/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;Got my Quest 2 today and created a new Facebook account with my real name (never had one previously) and merged my 4 year old Oculus account with it. Promptly got banned 10 minutes later and now cannot access my account or use my device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;Sent drivers license photo ID as requested by Facebook and my account now says &quot;We have already reviewed this decision and it can't be reversed.&quot; upon trying to login so it looks like I've lost all my previous Oculus purchases and now have a new white paperweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;Screw Facebook &amp;amp; Oculus. Be warned folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/bLPgbir.jpg&quot; class=&quot;_3t5uN8xUmg0TOwRCOGQEcU&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow ugc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://i.imgur.com/bLPgbir.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;_1qeIAgB0cPwnLhDF9XSiJM&quot;&gt;Facebook signup email, ban page and Oculus support email &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/nZ7Hoe2&quot; class=&quot;_3t5uN8xUmg0TOwRCOGQEcU&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow ugc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://imgur.com/a/nZ7Hoe2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 14:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>warp</dc:creator>
<og:title>r/OculusQuest - Facebook account banned within 10 minutes, reviewed and cannot be reversed.</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.reddit.com/r/OculusQuest/comments/japo1j/facebook_account_banned_within_10_minutes/</og:url>
<og:description>2,134 votes and 749 comments so far on Reddit</og:description>
<og:image>https://external-preview.redd.it/klSFl41LMqFuimbbrU-6kvi7wY_vuFMubpPQiwl65Cw.jpg?auto=webp&amp;s=73b4d8e43792facc9ab1880b35361d86a91b166d</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reddit.com/r/OculusQuest/comments/japo1j/facebook_account_banned_within_10_minutes/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A 3D sculpting web application</title>
<link>https://stephaneginier.com/sculptgl/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stephaneginier.com/sculptgl/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://stephaneginier.com/sculptgl/&quot;&gt;https://stephaneginier.com/sculptgl/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24775500&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24775500&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 343&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 60&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>parisianka</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stephaneginier.com/sculptgl/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>