<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Pyston v2: Faster Python</title>
<link>https://blog.pyston.org/2020/10/28/pyston-v2-20-faster-python/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.pyston.org/2020/10/28/pyston-v2-20-faster-python/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;We’re very excited to release Pyston v2, a faster and highly compatible implementation of the Python programming language. Version 2 is 20% faster than stock Python 3.8 on our macrobenchmarks. More importantly, it is likely to be faster on your code. Pyston v2 can reduce server costs, reduce user latencies, and improve developer productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyston v2 is easy to deploy, so if you’re looking for better Python performance, we encourage you to take five minutes and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.pyston.org/2020/10/28/pyston-v2-20-faster-python/#availability&quot;&gt;try Pyston&lt;/a&gt;. Doing so is one of the easiest ways to speed up your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyston v2 provides a noticeable speedup on many workloads while having few drawbacks. Our focus has been on web serving workloads, but Pyston v2 is also faster on other workloads and popular benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team put together a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pyston/python-macrobenchmarks/&quot;&gt;public Python macrobenchmark suite&lt;/a&gt; that measures the performance of several commonly-used Python projects. The benchmarks in this suite are larger than those found in other Python suites, making them more likely to be representative of real-world applications. Even though this gives us a lower headline number than other projects, we believe it translates to better speedups for real use cases. Pyston v2 still shows sped-up performance on microbenchmarks, being twice as fast as standard Python on tests like chaos.py and nbody.py.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are our performance results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CPython 3.8.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pyston 2.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PyPy 7.3.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;flaskblogging warmup time [1]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;85s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;flaskblogging mean latency&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.1ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.1ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.5ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;flaskblogging p99 latency&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.3ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.2ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.8ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;flaskblogging memory usage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;47MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;54MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;228MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;djangocms warmup time [1]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;djangocms mean latency&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14.1ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11.8ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15.9ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;djangocms p99 latency&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15.0ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12.8ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;179ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;djangocms memory usage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;84MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;91MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;279MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pylint speedup&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.16x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.50x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;mypy speedup&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.07x [2]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;unsupported&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;PyTorch speedup&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.00x [2]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;unsupported&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;PyPy benchmark suite [3]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.36x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.48x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
Results were collected on an m5.large EC2 instance running Ubuntu 20.04
&lt;p&gt;[1] Warmup time is defined as time until the benchmark reached 95% of peak performance; if it was not distinguishable from noise it is marked “n/a”. Only post-warmup behavior is considered for latency measurement.&lt;br/&gt;[2] mypy and PyTorch don’t support automatically building their C extensions from source, so these Pyston numbers use our unsafe compatibility mode&lt;br/&gt;[3] The PyPy benchmark suite was modified to only run the benchmarks that are compatible with Python 3.8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our targeted benchmarks (djangocms + flaskblogging), Pyston v2 provides an average 1.22x speedup for mean latency and an 1.18x improvement for p99 latency while using a just few more megabytes per process. We have not yet invested time in optimizing the other benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“p99 latency” is the upper 99th percentile of the response-time distribution, and is a common metric used in web serving contexts since it can provide insight into user experience that is lost by taking an average. PyPy’s high p99 latency on djangocms comes from periodic latency spikes, presumably from garbage collection pauses. CPython and Pyston both exhibit periodic spikes, presumably from their cycle collectors, but they are both less frequent and much smaller in magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mypy and PyTorch benchmarks show a natural boundary of Pyston v2. These benchmarks both do the bulk of their work in C extensions which are unaffected by our Python speedups. We natively support the C API and do not have an emulation layer, so we are still able to provide a small boost to mypy performance and do not degrade pytorch or numpy performance. Your benefit will depend on your mix of Python and C extension work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re planning on going into more detail in future blog posts, but some of the techniques we use in Pyston v2 include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A very-low-overhead JIT using &lt;a href=&quot;https://luajit.org/dynasm.html&quot;&gt;DynASM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.python.org/issue14757&quot;&gt;Quickening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General CPython optimizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build process improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Compatibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Pyston is a fork of CPython, we believe it is one of the most compatible alternative Python implementations available today. It supports all the same features and C API that CPython does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Pyston is identically functional in theory, in practice there are some temporary compatibility hurdles for any new Python implementation. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pyston/pyston/wiki&quot;&gt;our wiki&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;availability&quot;&gt;Availability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyston v2.0 is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pyston/pyston/releases&quot;&gt;immediately available&lt;/a&gt; as a pre-built package. Currently, we have packages for Ubuntu 18.04 and 20.04 x86_64. If you would like support for a different OS, let us know by filing an issue in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pyston/pyston/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying out Pyston is as simple as installing our package, replacing &lt;code&gt;python3&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;pyston3&lt;/code&gt;, and reinstalling your dependencies with &lt;code&gt;pip-pyston3 install&lt;/code&gt; (though see our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pyston/pyston/wiki&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; for a known issue about setuptools). If you already have an automated build set up, the change should be just a few lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan is to open-source the code in the future, but since compiler projects are expensive and we no longer have benevolent corporate sponsorship, it is currently closed-source while we iron out our business model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reaching us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are designing Pyston for developers and love to hear about your needs and experiences. So, we’ve set up a &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/S7gsqnb&quot;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; where you can chat with us. If you’d like a commercially-supported version of Pyston, please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:business@pyston.org&quot;&gt;send us an email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve optimized Pyston for several use cases but are eager to hear about new ones so that we can make it even more beneficial. If you run into any problems or instances where Pyston does not help as much as expected, please let us know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We designed Pyston v1 at Dropbox to speed up Python for its web serving workloads. After the project ended, some of us from the team brainstormed how we would do it differently if we were to do it again. In early 2020, enough pieces were in place for us to start a company and work on Pyston full-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyston v2 is inspired by but is technically unrelated to the original Pyston v1 effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re on a mission to make Python faster and have plenty of ideas to do so. That means we’re actively looking for people to join the team. &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/S7gsqnb&quot;&gt;Let us know&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like to get involved. Otherwise stay tuned for future releases and reach out if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;jp-post-flair&quot; class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-like-enabled sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-block sd-like jetpack-likes-widget-wrapper jetpack-likes-widget-unloaded&quot; id=&quot;like-post-wrapper-74522776-895-5f9a1341ef695&quot; data-src=&quot;//widgets.wp.com/likes/index.html?ver=20200826#blog_id=74522776&amp;amp;post_id=895&amp;amp;origin=pystonblog.wordpress.com&amp;amp;obj_id=74522776-895-5f9a1341ef695&amp;amp;domain=blog.pyston.org&quot; data-name=&quot;like-post-frame-74522776-895-5f9a1341ef695&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;likes-widget-placeholder post-likes-widget-placeholder&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Like&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;loading&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 17:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>kmod</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Pyston v2: 20% faster Python</og:title>
<og:url>https://blog.pyston.org/2020/10/28/pyston-v2-20-faster-python/</og:url>
<og:description>We’re very excited to release Pyston v2, a faster and highly compatible implementation of the Python programming language. Version 2 is 20% faster than stock Python 3.8 on our macrobenchmarks…</og:description>
<og:image>https://s0.wp.com/i/blank.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.pyston.org/2020/10/28/pyston-v2-20-faster-python/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Woman allegedly impersonated prosecutor, dropped charges against herself</title>
<link>https://www.unionleader.com/news/courts/woman-accused-of-impersonating-prosecutor-dropping-criminal-charges-against-herself/article_1fdb1551-147d-53dd-ad45-6680bfc556fa.html?block_id=897573</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.unionleader.com/news/courts/woman-accused-of-impersonating-prosecutor-dropping-criminal-charges-against-herself/article_1fdb1551-147d-53dd-ad45-6680bfc556fa.html?block_id=897573</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;subscriber-preview&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Littleton woman allegedly impersonated a Hillsborough County prosecutor when she filed bogus documents with court officials declaring that the drug possession and stalking case against her had been dropped, according to recently released indictments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subscriber-preview&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa Landon, 33, of Railroad Street, Littleton, faces one charge of false personation and six charges of falsifying physical evidence, according to Hillsborough County grand jury indictments handed up earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subscriber-only&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indictments allege that Landon submitted the fake documents in three different court cases last November and December. In several instances, she used the New Hampshire court system’s electronic system to file documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subscriber-only&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November, Hillsborough County prosecutors became suspicious when they heard from a state forensic examiner, who had been scheduled to perform a competency evaluation on Landon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subscriber-only&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examiner saw a notice in Landon’s court file that prosecutors had dropped charges; the examiner wanted to know if the examination should go forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;subscriber-only&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The file purported to contain a nolle prosequi (drop the charges) filed by Assistant County Attorney Patrice Casian, but it quickly became evident to the State that the document, as well as other documents in the file, had been filed fraudulently,” wrote Superior Court Judge David Anderson in a ruling regarding the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subscriber-only&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indictments allege Landon also filed an order falsifying a decision of retired Superior Court Judge Gillian Abramson to waive filing fees in a lawsuit she brought against Hillsborough County. And she allegedly filed an order on behalf of a relative to halt guardianship proceedings involving Landon’s child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subscriber-only&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landon’s history includes criminal charges in Manchester related to stalking and possession of methamphetamine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;subscriber-only&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grand jury also returned indictments of burglary and theft against Landon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 17:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>coloneltcb</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.unionleader.com/news/courts/woman-accused-of-impersonating-prosecutor-dropping-criminal-charges-against-herself/article_1fdb1551-147d-53dd-ad45-6680bfc556fa.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/unionleader.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/4/ca/4caae2ab-f5be-5ee7-833a-ddbd20b641e9/5f97480d96eee.image.jpg?crop=329%2C409%2C161%2C18&amp;resize=329%2C409&amp;order=crop%2Cresize</og:image>
<og:title>Woman accused of impersonating prosecutor, dropping criminal charges against herself</og:title>
<og:description>A Littleton woman allegedly impersonated a Hillsborough County prosecutor when she filed bogus documents with court officials declaring that the drug possession and stalking case against her had been dropped,</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.unionleader.com/news/courts/woman-accused-of-impersonating-prosecutor-dropping-criminal-charges-against-herself/article_1fdb1551-147d-53dd-ad45-6680bfc556fa.html?block_id=897573</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Graphical User Interface Using Flutter in Embedded Systems [pdf]</title>
<link>https://static.sched.com/hosted_files/osseu2020/e0/Oct%2027_Graphical%20User%20Interface%20Using%20Flutter%20in%20Embedded%20Systems_Hidenori%20Matsubayashi.pdf</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://static.sched.com/hosted_files/osseu2020/e0/Oct%2027_Graphical%20User%20Interface%20Using%20Flutter%20in%20Embedded%20Systems_Hidenori%20Matsubayashi.pdf</guid>
<description>&lt;a href=&quot;https://static.sched.com/hosted_files/osseu2020/e0/Oct%2027_Graphical%20User%20Interface%20Using%20Flutter%20in%20Embedded%20Systems_Hidenori%20Matsubayashi.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>timsneath</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.unionleader.com/news/courts/woman-accused-of-impersonating-prosecutor-dropping-criminal-charges-against-herself/article_1fdb1551-147d-53dd-ad45-6680bfc556fa.html</og:url>
<og:image>https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/unionleader.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/4/ca/4caae2ab-f5be-5ee7-833a-ddbd20b641e9/5f97480d96eee.image.jpg?crop=329%2C409%2C161%2C18&amp;resize=329%2C409&amp;order=crop%2Cresize</og:image>
<og:title>Woman accused of impersonating prosecutor, dropping criminal charges against herself</og:title>
<og:description>A Littleton woman allegedly impersonated a Hillsborough County prosecutor when she filed bogus documents with court officials declaring that the drug possession and stalking case against her had been dropped,</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://static.sched.com/hosted_files/osseu2020/e0/Oct%2027_Graphical%20User%20Interface%20Using%20Flutter%20in%20Embedded%20Systems_Hidenori%20Matsubayashi.pdf</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AMD Reveals the Radeon RX 6000 Series, Coming November 18th</title>
<link>https://www.anandtech.com/show/16202/amd-reveals-the-radeon-rx-6000-series-rdna2-starts-at-the-highend-coming-november-18th</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.anandtech.com/show/16202/amd-reveals-the-radeon-rx-6000-series-rdna2-starts-at-the-highend-coming-november-18th</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Preparing to close out a major month of announcements for AMD – and to open the door to the next era of architectures across the company – AMD wrapped up its final keynote presentation of the month by announcing their Radeon RX 6000 series of video cards. Hosted once more by AMD CEO Dr. Lisa Su, AMD’s hour-long keynote revealed the first three parts in AMD’s new RDNA2 architecture video card family: the Radeon RX 6800, 6800 XT, and 6900 XT. The core of AMD’s new high-end video card lineup, AMD means to do battle with the best of the best out of arch-rival NVIDIA. And we’ll get to see first-hand if AMD can retake the high-end market on November 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, when the first two cards hit retail shelves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMD’s forthcoming video card launch has been a long time coming for the company, and one they’ve been teasing particularly heavily. For AMD, the Radeon RX 6000 series represents the culmination of efforts from across the company as everyone from the GPU architecture team and the semi-custom SoC team to the Zen CPU team has played a role in developing AMD’s latest GPU technology. All the while, these new cards are AMD’s best chance in at least half a decade to finally catch up to NVIDIA at the high-end of the video card market. So understandably, the company is jazzed – and in more than just a marketing manner – about what the RX 6000 means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anchoring the new cards is AMD’s RDNA2 GPU architecture. RDNA2 is launching near-simultaneously across consoles and PC video cards next month, where it will be the backbone of some 200 million video game consoles plus countless AMD GPUs and APUs to come. Accordingly, AMD has pulled out all of the stops in designing it, assembling an architecture that’s on the cutting-edge of technical features like ray tracing and DirectX 12 Ultimate support, all the while leveraging the many things they’ve learned from their successful Zen CPU architectures to maximize RDNA2’s performance. RDNA2 is also rare in that it isn’t being built on a new manufacturing process, so coming from AMD’s earlier RDNA (1) architecture and associated video cards, AMD is relying on architectural improvements to deliver virtually all of their performance gains. Truly, it’s AMD’s RDNA2 architecture that’s going to make or break their new cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/Die-Shot_Color-Front.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/Die-Shot_Color-Front_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the coming months, RDNA2 will filter down into an increasing number of AMD chip designs. But for now, in the PC space, AMD is starting with enthusiast-level video cards. The first RDNA2 GPU out of the works is Navi 21 – AKA “Big Navi” – which AMD will be using as the basis of a trio of video cards. These are the Radeon RX 6900 XT, 6800 XT, and 6800 respectively. With these latest cards, AMD is aiming squarely at NVIDIA’s recently-launched GeForce RTX 30-series lineup, aiming to meet (or beat) the RTX 3090, 3080, and 3070 respectively. Suffice it to say, AMD hasn’t been able to match NVIDIA’s top cards for several years now, so these are very bold claims from a company that has re-learned how to become very bold in the last five years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;650&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tgrey&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; colspan=&quot;7&quot;&gt;AMD Radeon RX Series Specification Comparison&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;tlblue&quot;&gt;&lt;td width=&quot;155&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;&gt;AMD Radeon RX 6900 XT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;&gt;AMD Radeon RX 6800 XT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;&gt;AMD Radeon RX 6800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; width=&quot;120&quot;&gt;AMD Radeon RX 5700 XT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stream Processors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;5120?&lt;br/&gt;(80 CUs)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;4608?&lt;br/&gt;(72 CUs)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;3840&lt;br/&gt;(60 CUs)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;2560&lt;br/&gt;(40 CUs)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROPs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;96&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Clock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;2015MHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;2015MHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;1815MHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;1755MHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boost Clock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;2250MHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;2250MHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;2105MHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;1905MHz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Throughput (FP32)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;20.6 TFLOPs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;18.6 TFLOPs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;13.9 TFLOPs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;9.75 TFLOPs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory Clock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;16 Gbps GDDR6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;16 Gbps GDDR6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;16 Gbps GDDR6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;14 Gbps GDDR6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory Bus Width&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;256-bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;256-bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;256-bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;256-bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VRAM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;16GB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;16GB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;16GB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;8GB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infinity Cache&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;128MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;128MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;128MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Board Power&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;300W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;300W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;250W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;225W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manufacturing Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;TSMC 7nm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;TSMC 7nm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;TSMC 7nm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;TSMC 7nm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transistor Count&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;26.8B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;26.8B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;26.8B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;10.3B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;RDNA2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;RDNA2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;RDNA2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;RDNA (1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPU&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;Navi 21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;Navi 21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;Navi 21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;Navi 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launch Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;12/08/2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;11/18/2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;11/18/2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;07/07/2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tlgrey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launch Price&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;$999&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;$649&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;$579&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;$399&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;As today’s announcement is not a full tech deep dive – like the Zen 3 announcement, the deep dive will come closer to launch – AMD is only sharing some high-level specifications of the new cards. But with information on the number of CUs, memory support, and power consumption now in hand, we have a good idea of what AMD is bringing to the table, and why they believe the RX 6000 series will once again make them fully-competitive at the high-end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Radeon RX 6900 XT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amongst AMD’s video card stack, the company is taking a very similar tack as NVIDIA. So although the RX 6900 XT is technically their flagship part, at $999 it's still in a similar “more money than sense” category as the RTX 3090 – which is to say that AMD is looking to charge a good premium for the card. Since it’s based on a fully-enabled and undoubtedly heavily binned Navi 21 GPU, it’s the hardest part for AMD to produce, and thus the rarest. How rare remains to be seen, but as Navi 21 is undoubtedly a large chip thanks to the 26.8 billion transistors housing 80 CUs and 128MB Infinity Cache (more on that later), I don’t expect AMD to be flooding the market with 6900 XTs any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any rate, the card will be the full Navi 21 experience. All 80CUs will be enabled, and thanks to AMD’s efforts in optimizing the RDNA2 architecture for clockspeeds, it will have a game clock of 2015MHz and a peak turbo clock (boost clock) of 2250MHz. Assuming that AMD hasn’t done anything &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; crazy with the RDNA2 architecture, this means that the card will have an average FP32 shader throughput of around 20.6 TFLOPS, more than double the throughput of the RX 5700 XT – and right in line with AMD’s goals to double their performance over the RX 5000 series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/Radeon-RX-6900-XT_front-background.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/Radeon-RX-6900-XT_front-background_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On the memory side of matters the card comes with 16GB of GDDR6. AMD is not officially disclosing the memory clockspeed, but based on current tech trends we’re expecting that GDDR6 to be running at 16 Gbps/pin (which AMD has since confirmed). Meanwhile, based on other AMD slides, it looks like this memory is attached to a 256-bit memory bus, which would give the card a total memory bandwidth of 512GB/sec. This is admittedly a bit anemic for a flagship video card, and is where AMD’s new Infinity Cache technology will come into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, AMD says that the card will have a Total Board Power (TBP) of 300W. At a time when ASIC designers everywhere are struggling to keep power consumption in check – and when even NVIDIA’s top cards now hit 350W – a 300W TBP is a significant claim. Not only is it potentially a competitive advantage for AMD, but it means they haven’t needed to increase their TBP versus their previous high-end card, the also 7nm-based Radeon VII.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of that said, however, some expectation management is in order. Although AMD is comparing the RX 6900 XT to NVIDIA’s RTX 3090, there are a few potential gotchas involved. We’ll break down AMD’s specific performance claims and benchmark slides later, but suffice it to say and as AMD is pitching things now, if the RX 6900 XT can match the 3090, it’s going to be at the very top edge of the AMD card’s performance profile, overclocking include. Which would go hand-in-hand with the heavy binning mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Radeon RX 6800 XT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving down the line we have the Radeon RX 6800 XT. Based on a slightly cut-down Navi 21 GPU, this is the AMD card that mere mortals can afford. At $650 it’s still &lt;em&gt;expensive&lt;/em&gt;, to say the least, but significantly less so than the $1000 6900 XT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, the RX 6800 XT comes with 72 CUs enabled. Combined with clockspeeds identical to the RX 6900 XT – a game clock of 2015MHz and a boost clock of 2250MHz – and pending additional technical details from AMD, the card should average around 18.6 TFLOPS of FP32 shader performance. Relative to the RX 5700, this is just under 2x the performance of AMD’s last-gen leading card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/6800XT.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/6800XT_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other than the reduction in CUs, according to AMD’s specifications there are no other notable differences between the RX 6800 XT and RX 6900 XT. The more affordable card still comes with 16GB of GDDR6 memory, and I expect it’ll be clocked at 16Gbps/pin as well, giving it an expected total bandwidth of 512GB/sec. Augmenting this, like all of today’s cards, will be 128MB of AMD’s Infinity Cache. Meanwhile the card’s TBP carries the same 300W rating as the 6900 XT as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMD is positioning this card directly against NVIDIA’s RTX 3080; and unlike the 6900 XT, there are no asterisks to speak of here. So if AMD can deliver on their claims, then this 6800 XT will be doing so right out of the box. In which case, meeting the 3080 in performance and possibly beating it in power consumption would be a big win for AMD and the RDNA2 architecture, and a sign of how far they’ve come in the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, given AMD’s performance expectations and pricing, along with the expected competition, it’s unsurprising that AMD lead with this card today for the Radeon keynote. It’s technically not the flagship, but like the RTX 3080 on NVIDIA’s side, it’s going to be the card that garners the most attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Radeon RX 6800&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be the final card in AMD’s new product stack, however, that will garner the most in sales. Rounding out the Navi 21 trio of cards we have the Radeon RX 6800, a further cut-down Navi 21 part that trades off a drop in performance for lower power consumption and a lower $579 price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RX 6800 will ship with 60 CUs (3 shader engines) enabled, and with the fourth shader engine disabled, this by and large makes it three-quarters of a full Navi 21. Relative to the other cards, clockspeeds are going to be lower, with a game clock of 1815MHz and a boost clock of 2105MHz. Which, per our math, would give the card 13.9 TFLOPS of FP32 shader performance, or around 75% of the shader performance of the RX 6800 XT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/6800.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/6800_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, AMD isn’t dialing at all on the memory. Despite being the third and most budget-friendly card in the stack, it still ships with 16GB of GDDR6 memory. &lt;del&gt;And while I suspect AMD will go with cheaper 14Gbps memory here – giving the card 448GB/sec of bandwidth – that’s still a lot of memory overall.&lt;/del&gt; Similarly, AMD isn't using lower-clocked memory either; even the RX 6800 gets the same top-tier 16 Gbps/pin memory (and resulting 512GB/sec of memory bandwidth) that the other cards are getting. Furthermore the complete 128MB Infinity Cache will be available as well, so the GPU itself still has a full pool of its fastest local memory on-hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical for lower-tier cards, the RX 6800 also carries a lower TBP rating of 250W, 50W less than the RX 6800 XT. AMD of course is no stranger to offering high-powered cards, but in some respects the RX 6800 is going to be the most interesting of the bunch, as it’s going to be our first chance to look at what RDNA2 can do at a more reasonable TBP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the moment, AMD is classifying the RX 6800’s performance relative to NVIDIA’s RTX 2080 Ti. In reality this is card that will (roughly) compete with the RTX 3070 – the same card that replaced the RTX 2080 Ti – but as RTX 3070 doesn’t launch until tomorrow, AMD doesn’t have a card that they draw apples-to-apples comparisons against. So for the moment, AMD is instead playing with the transitive property of equality. With AMD’s own launch not coming until November 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, there’s still plenty of time for AMD to frame this card’s performance with respect to the RTX 3070, so it will be interesting to see what (if anything) they have to say in a week’s time. AMD’s promotional material places the RX 6800 ahead of the RTX 2080 Ti, but we’ll see if that holds true for the RTX 3070 as well. For now, AMD seems very confident that they're going to beat NVIDIA's cheapest RTX-30 series card, and with a projected performance and VRAM capacity lead they've priced it accordingly at $579.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other curiosity on positioning is that AMD is also promoting the RX 6800 as a 4K gaming card, just like its more powerful siblings. Working to the card’s advantage, its 16GB of VRAM means that it has plenty of memory to handle the larger buffers that come with the higher resolution. However as the card only has 75% of the RX 6800 XT’s theoretical shader performance, I do wonder whether it’s going to be outright fast enough for 4K over the long run. Current-generation games should be very doable, judging from what the RTX 3080 and RTX 2080 Ti can do, however there’s a bit more concern over the long run as game developers switch to the next-gen consoles as their performance and feature baselines. In which case, the RX 6800 will instead be AMD’s 1440p gaming king, and fittingly the company has published some 1440p performance slides for the card as well, alongside the 4K performance slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/RX6800_35.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/RX6800_35_575px.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Overall, AMD some very ambitious performance goals for the Radeon RX 6000 series of cards. At this point AMD knows exactly what kind of performance they need to deliver to take on NVIDIA for the high-end, and the company believes that the Navi 21 GPU they’ve built is just the tool to do that. Now with 3 weeks to go until the first RX 6800 series cards launch, it’s just a matter of time until we can see first-hand whether AMD can deliver on those ambitious, RDNA2-fueled promises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 16:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator>
<og:title>AMD Reveals The Radeon RX 6000 Series: RDNA2 Starts At The High-End, Coming November 18th</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.anandtech.com/show/16202/amd-reveals-the-radeon-rx-6000-series-rdna2-starts-at-the-highend-coming-november-18th</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.anandtech.com/doci/16202/RX6000_car_Lisa_678x452.jpg</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.anandtech.com/show/16202/amd-reveals-the-radeon-rx-6000-series-rdna2-starts-at-the-highend-coming-november-18th</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Abandoning the X Server</title>
<link>https://ajaxnwnk.blogspot.com/2020/10/on-abandoning-x-server.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ajaxnwnk.blogspot.com/2020/10/on-abandoning-x-server.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;There's been some recent discussion about whether the X server is abandonware. As the person arguably most responsible for its care and feeding over the last 15 years or so, I feel like I have something to say about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about being the maintainer of a public-facing project for nearly the whole of your professional career is it's difficult to separate your own story from the project. So I'm not going to try to be dispassionate, here. I started working on X precisely because free software had given me options and capabilities that really matter, and I feel privileged to be able to give that back. I can't talk about that without caring about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's the thing: X works extremely well for what it is, but what it is is deeply flawed. There's no shame in that, it's 33 years old and still relevant, I wish more software worked so well on that kind of timeframe. But using it to drive your display hardware and multiplex your input devices is choosing to make your life worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is, however, uniquely well suited to a very long life as an application compatibility layer. Though the code happens to implement an unfortunate specification, the code itself is quite well structured, easy to hack on, and not far off from being easily embeddable.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue, then, is how to get there. And I don't have any real desire to get there while still pretending that the xfree86 hardware-backed server code is a real thing. Sorry, I guess, but I've worked on xfree86-derived servers for very nearly as long as XFree86-the-project existed, and I am completely burnt out on that on its own merits, let alone doing that and also being release manager and reviewer of last resort. You can only apply so much thrust to the pig before you question why you're trying to make it fly at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, is Xorg abandoned? To the extent that that means using it to actually control the display, and not just keep X apps running, I'd say yes. But xserver is more than xfree86. Xwayland, Xwin, Xephyr, Xvnc, Xvfb: these are projects with real value that we should not give up. A better way to say it is that we can finally abandon xfree86.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if that sounds like a world you'd like to see, please, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.x.org/wiki/DeveloperStart/#talkingtothedevelopers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;come talk to us&lt;/a&gt;, let's make it happen. I'd be absolutely thrilled to see someone take this on, and I'm happy to be your guide through the server internals.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 15:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>cheshire_cat</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://ajaxnwnk.blogspot.com/2020/10/on-abandoning-x-server.html</og:url>
<og:title>on abandoning the X server</og:title>
<og:description>There's been some recent discussion about whether the X server is abandonware. As the person arguably most responsible for its care and feed...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ajaxnwnk.blogspot.com/2020/10/on-abandoning-x-server.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SparkFun À La Carte</title>
<link>https://www.sparkfun.com/news/3422</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sparkfun.com/news/3422</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;title-bar&quot; readability=&quot;5.3652694610778&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Point and click your way to a fully-populated, custom board from SparkFun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;avatar&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.sparkfun.com/avatar/1ff6ad39b8c242a14296a76845e116cd?d=retro&amp;amp;s=40&amp;amp;r=pg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sparkfun.com/users/7185&quot;&gt;Nate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta sfedate&quot; data-date=&quot;1603890711&quot;&gt;October 28, 2020 1:11 pm UTC&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sparkfun.com/news/3422#comments&quot; title=&quot;0 comments&quot;&gt;0 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;fave_widget verbose&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sparkfun.com/news/3422#&quot; class=&quot;fave_btn&quot; title=&quot;Add to favorites&quot; data-entity=&quot;blog_posts&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;3422&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fave_yes&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Favorited&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;fave_no&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Favorite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;fave_count&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SparkFun is proud to introduce&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center-block text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.sparkfun.com/assets/home_page_posts/3/4/2/2/ALC-logo-reflection.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.sparkfun.com/assets/home_page_posts/3/4/2/2/ALC-logo-reflection.png&quot; alt=&quot;SparkFun A La Carte Custom Pce&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Bridging the gap between prototype and production.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;tall&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not often I get to give &quot;turtleneck&quot; sorts of talks so buckle up. For too many months to count, we’ve been working quietly to iron out the details. Today, it’s with great excitement that I tell you about &lt;a href=&quot;https://alc.sparkfun.com/&quot;&gt;SparkFun À La Carte&lt;/a&gt;, or ALC, the world’s first board building service &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; the need for an EE degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.sparkfun.com/assets/home_page_posts/3/4/2/2/SparkFun_Point_to_Point_Soldering.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.sparkfun.com/assets/home_page_posts/3/4/2/2/SparkFun_Point_to_Point_Soldering.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A collection of point to point soldered projects and rats nest of wires&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small text-center&quot;&gt;That was fun. Once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.sparkfun.com/assets/home_page_posts/3/4/2/2/alc-sample-board8.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.sparkfun.com/assets/home_page_posts/3/4/2/2/alc-sample-board8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fully assembled custom PCB&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small text-center&quot;&gt;Much better. Let ALC do the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like soldering just as much as the next nerd but there are times when it can be really painful to build multiples of a device. That's where ALC comes in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALC is a manufacturing service for professionals who understand the value of their time. How many times have you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cut and stripped wires, point-to-point soldered breakout boards, anchored everything to the proverbial breadboard, and after four hours sat back to realize you only had &lt;strong&gt;five&lt;/strong&gt; more devices to build?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found yourself with a great idea, but unsure of how to bring it to life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had an amazing prototype but needed to create a demo ready proof-of-concept?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alc.sparkfun.com&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-lg btn-primary&quot;&gt;Start your Design with ALC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;tall&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can build your idea with SparkFun breakout boards, you can have a fully assembled, custom board delivered to your door in a few weeks. ALC is the point-and-click tool to get a bunch of technologies onto a single board, fully assembled, right here in Colorado. No more late night soldering sessions before the big day; leverage our designs, our circuit know-how, and our machines to have a professional device made just for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alc.sparkfun.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.sparkfun.com/assets/home_page_posts/3/4/2/2/ALC-screenshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SparkFun's custom pcb designer&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;À La Carte designer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;À La Carte is based on blocks. An ALC block contains the module to be added to the board along with information about nets, classes, connection restrictions, and other electrical design needs and constraints. By including all of this information, ALC is able to remove the need for users to have intimate knowledge of a technology that usually only comes with lots of trial and error. SparkFun has been doing this for nearly 20 years; we know firsthand what it's like to mess up a PCB or fight jumpers on a small IC. Let us remove that frustration so that you can get back to your larger project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a board with ALC, simply select the various blocks you need on your design and the system figures out the rest as you go, ensuring an electrically sound board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video-wrap clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FEkppV2zSvw/?autohide=1&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;wmode=opaque&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select your controller.&lt;/strong&gt; Today, we offer five controllers: Artemis, SAMD51, ATmega328, ATtiny84 and ESP32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select your components.&lt;/strong&gt; We have 85 sensors, actuators, radios, switches and LEDs available today, and piles of new blocks planned to release soon. ALC will ensure all blocks chosen are compatible with your current design as you go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add connectors.&lt;/strong&gt; The classic PTH header, a latching terminal or any number of terminals can be added to make your design really flexible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pick how you’re going to power your board.&lt;/strong&gt; Wall, solar, battery, even car power are all available. This tells the system how many components you can add to your board before you may run into power constraints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s as simple as that, and feels more like shopping for parts than designing a board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;tall&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Sample boards assembled with ALC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alc.sparkfun.com&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-lg btn-primary&quot;&gt;Design a board with ALC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;tall&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The not-so-hidden fees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design fee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - There’s a $949 design fee on all new orders. For businesses, this is much lower than you’ll find with comparable do-it-yourself board designers, definitely less expensive than hiring a contractor or employee to design the board for you, and clearly more efficient than trying to do it on your own. We’ve been using it to run new product ideas and it’s amazing how much it saves us in schematic and hardware mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself wondering why it costs so much for something that seems so simple (it’s just blocks, after all!) then we’ve done our job! The best designed interfaces are the ones you don’t notice. We’ve spent a tremendous amount of time boiling down a very complex process into the best user experience possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design files&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - All ALC orders include a downloadable version of the Gerber files and PDF of the schematic. If you need the Eagle source files (BRD and SCH) to edit the design, they can be purchased separately for $150; these files are routed and ready for manufacture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it. Those are the only two fees not included in the per board price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Point-and-click board design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number one question we’ve received about ALC is: “Why can’t I move the blocks around?” While we could absolutely design a tool that allows you to poke and prod down to the mil, there are already piles of tools that do that: Upverter, KiCad, EAGLE, Altium, Orcad, Pads, it goes on. For now, we want to focus the interface on being as simple to use as possible. When a block is placed on the board, ALC takes into account the needs of that block, as well as all the other blocks on the board, to determine its optimal placement. This optimization is what allows ALC to take care of all the traces and other electrical needs for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SparkFun is not another contract manufacturer - we’re one of the only companies in the world that has the latest sensors, hard-to-find ICs, the know-how to integrate them, and the tools to solder it all together. It’s &lt;em&gt;what we do, every day&lt;/em&gt;! Now we want to enable you to enjoy the benefits of all that knowledge. So the next time you think, “How am I going find someone to design that board?” - think À La Carte instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Give me all the details!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with the main &lt;a href=&quot;https://alc.sparkfun.com/&quot;&gt;ALC page&lt;/a&gt; but don’t forget to hit up our &lt;a href=&quot;https://alc.sparkfun.com/faq&quot;&gt;FAQs&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve covered as many bases as possible but if there’s something you still have questions about, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.sparkfun.com/viewforum.php?f=178&quot;&gt;let us know in the ALC forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited and it’s been a lot of fun watching what people create. But this is just the beginning! Please kick the tires today but check back in over the coming months. We’ve got a lot more to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-default&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-12&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interested in trying SparkFun À La Carte?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;To encourage you to give ALC a try, we’re offering &lt;strong&gt;50% off the design fee&lt;/strong&gt; on all new orders through 11:59 p.m. on 12/31/2020 with promocode: &lt;strong&gt;ALCSPARKFUN50&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alc.sparkfun.com&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-lg btn-primary&quot;&gt;Design a board with ALC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 15:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zdw</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sparkfun.com/news/3422</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>That company whose name used to contain HTML script tags Ltd</title>
<link>https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/company/12956509</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/company/12956509</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;company-header&quot; readability=&quot;4.7777777777778&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;heading-xlarge&quot;&gt;THAT COMPANY WHOSE NAME USED TO CONTAIN HTML SCRIPT TAGS LTD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;company-number&quot;&gt;Company number &lt;strong&gt;12956509&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Registered office address&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd class=&quot;text data&quot;&gt;9 Park Mews, Old Hertford Road, Hatfield, England, AL9 5EP&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;grid-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;column-two-thirds&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Company status&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd class=&quot;text data&quot; id=&quot;company-status&quot;&gt;Active&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid-row&quot;&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;column-two-thirds&quot;&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Company type&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd class=&quot;text data&quot; id=&quot;company-type&quot;&gt;Private limited Company&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl class=&quot;column-third&quot;&gt;&lt;dt id=&quot;company-birth-type&quot;&gt;Incorporated on&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd class=&quot;data&quot; id=&quot;company-creation-date&quot;&gt;16 October 2020&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grid-row&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column-half&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;heading-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First accounts made up to &lt;strong&gt;31 October 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;due by &lt;strong&gt;16 July 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;column-half&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;heading-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmation statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First statement date &lt;strong&gt;15 October 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;due by &lt;strong&gt;29 October 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sic-title&quot; class=&quot;heading-medium&quot;&gt;Nature of business (SIC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;sic0&quot;&gt;62020 - Information technology consultancy activities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;heading-medium&quot; id=&quot;header&quot;&gt;Previous company names&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 15:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>marinintim</dc:creator>
<og:image>//d9wt7fz2oscre.cloudfront.net/images/opengraph-image.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/company/12956509</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wikimedia is moving to Gitlab</title>
<link>https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#Outcome</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#Outcome</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Outcome&quot;&gt;Outcome&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2020-10-23&lt;/strong&gt;: The working group decided that migrating our code repositories from Gerrit to a self-hosted Gitlab Community Edition installation is the right decision. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab&quot; title=&quot;GitLab&quot;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt; is a portal for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Why&quot;&gt;Why&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past two years, our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Developer_Satisfaction_Survey/2020&quot; title=&quot;Developer Satisfaction Survey/2020&quot;&gt;developer satisfaction survey&lt;/a&gt; has shown that there is some level of dissatisfaction with Gerrit, our code review system. This dissatisfaction is particularly evident for our volunteer communities. The evident dissatisfaction with code review, coupled with an internal review of our CI tooling and practice makes this an opportune moment to revisit our code review choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Gerrit’s workflow is in many respects best-in-class, its interface suffers from usability deficits, and its workflow differs from mainstream industry practices. This creates barriers to entry for the community and slows onboarding for WMF technical staff. In addition, there are a growing number of individuals and teams (both staff and non-staff) who are opting to forgo the use of Gerrit and instead use a third-party hosted option such as GitHub. Reasons vary for the choice to use third-party hosting but, based on informal communication, there are 3 main groupings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;lower friction to create new repositories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easier setup and self-service of Continuous Integration configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more familiarity with pull-request style workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;All these explanations point to friction in our existing code-review system slowing development rather than fostering it. The choice to use third-party code-hosting hurts our collaboration (both internal and external), adds to the confusion of onboarding, and makes it more difficult to maintain code standards across repositories. At the same time, there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Writing_an_extension_for_deployment&quot; title=&quot;Writing an extension for deployment&quot;&gt;requirement&lt;/a&gt; that all software which is deployed to Wikimedia production is hosted and deployed from Gerrit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we fail to address the real usability problems that users have with Gerrit, people will continue to launch and build projects on whatever system it is they prefer—Wikimedia's GitHub already contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Gerrit/GitHub#Projects_on_GitHub&quot; title=&quot;Gerrit/GitHub&quot;&gt;152 projects&lt;/a&gt; , the Research team has &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/wikimedia-research&quot;&gt;127 projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Gerrit_improvements&quot;&gt;Gerrit improvements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raises the question: if Gerrit has identifiable problems, why can't we solve those problems &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; Gerrit? Gerrit is open source (Apache licensed) software; modifications are a simple matter of programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are unique in the community of Gerrit users which include large companies such as SAP, Ericsson, Qualcomm, and Google. Google, in particular, is singular in their use of Gerrit for projects like Android and Chromium. To support these large, open projects multi-site capabilities are needed; however, much of that work is either closed-source or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://gerrit.googlesource.com/plugins/multi-site&quot;&gt;does not support multi-site writes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upstream has improved the UI in recent releases, and releases have become more frequent; however, upgrade path documentation is often lacking. The migration from Gerrit 2 to Gerrit 3, for example, required several &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/g/repo-discuss/c/G5wucKJg9Ag/m/pLin-i3mBgAJ&quot;&gt;upstream patchsets&lt;/a&gt; to avoid the recommended path of several days of downtime. This is the effort required to maintain the status quo. Even small improvements require effort and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://gerrit-review.googlesource.com/c/plugins/go-import/+/190630&quot;&gt;time&lt;/a&gt; as, often, our use-case is very different from the remainder of the Gerrit community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;What&quot;&gt;What&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wikimedia Release Engineering team has taken an initial look at GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitLab is a capable and scalable code review system written in Ruby. GitLab is available for self-hosting, as required for parity with the rest of our development tooling infrastructure and to alleviate concerns about data privacy or usage restrictions of third-party hosting. As GitLab offers an MIT licensed community edition (CE), it adheres to the Foundation's guiding principle of &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Wikimedia_Foundation_Guiding_Principles#Freedom_and_open_source&quot; class=&quot;extiw&quot; title=&quot;metawiki:Wikimedia Foundation Guiding Principles&quot;&gt;Freedom and open source&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, GitLab was evaluated as part of the Release Engineering team's Continuous Integration working group. While GitLab's continuous integration systems were found to be adequate for our needs, code review was out of scope for the charter of that working group. Therefore GitLab's capabilities were weighed against the likelihood of introducing social friction and added complexity—integrating GitLab's CI with Gerrit. Replacing Gerrit with GitLab would significantly change the equation of our CI tooling—allowing us to use an industry-standard workflow and self-serve CI tooling built into GitLab. For these reasons we'd like to limit the scope of this discussion to evaluation of whether it’s feasible and advisable to move from Gerrit to GitLab for code review. Things within scope include: code review workflows and processes; tools and bots involved in the code review process; merge, branch, and deployment strategies; as well as unforeseen blockers to adopting a new code review system within our technical community. For the avoidance of doubt, continuous integration (CI) and task/project tracking are out of scope of this evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Definitions_and_comparisons&quot;&gt;Definitions and comparisons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few useful terms and definitions for the comparison of GitLab and Gerrit code review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Mainline branch&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A single, shared branch that acts as the current state of the repo. &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#cite_note-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Integration&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The process of combining a new piece of code into a mainline codebase.&lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#cite_note-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Patchset&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The method of integration in Gerrit. A single commit under review. It is very common to amend a commit during the code review process. &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-3&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#cite_note-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Merge request&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The method of integration in GitLab. A request to merge one branch into another. &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-4&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#cite_note-4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Feature branching&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Put all work for a feature on its own branch, integrate into mainline when the feature is complete. &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-5&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#cite_note-5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; These branches are often short-lived. &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-6&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#cite_note-6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Continuous integration&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Developers do mainline integration as soon as they have a healthy commit they can share. &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-7&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#cite_note-7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Squashing&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Making a series of Git commits into a single git commit. &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-8&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#cite_note-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Fast-forward&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Merging git commit history retaining git commit history without a merge commit. &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-9&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation#cite_note-9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Who&quot;&gt;Who&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Decision_making&quot;&gt;Decision making&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the RACI &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Responsibility_assignment_matrix&quot; class=&quot;extiw&quot; title=&quot;en:Responsibility assignment matrix&quot;&gt;responsibility assignment framework&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsible&lt;/strong&gt; (the primary driver of this decision):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tyler Cipriani, Engineering Manager for the Wikimedia Release Engineering team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountable&lt;/strong&gt; (the final decider based on the Responsible’s recommendation):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Grant Ingersoll, CTO of the Wikimedia Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consulted&lt;/strong&gt; (those who will have a 2-way communication relationship with this evaluation):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Technical community members and organizations that use Gerrit (via on-wiki and mailing list requests)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikimedia Foundation Technology and Product departments management and staff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TechCom members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informed&lt;/strong&gt; (those who will have a 1-way communication relationship):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Broader Wikimedia movement (via the consultation’s talk page, mailing list messages to wikitech-l@ and wikitech-ambassadors@, and the TechNews newsletter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Working_Group&quot;&gt;Working Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Working Group is responsible for engaging with the discussion, surfacing and weighting feedback from consulted groups, providing recommendations, and directly informing the outcome of the consultation. Members of the Working Group:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;SRE/Service Ops - Effie Mouzeli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release Engineering - Brennen Bearnes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security - Chase Pettet and Scott Bassett&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical Engagement - Andre Klapper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product - Daniel Cipolleti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikimedia Germany (WMDE) - Lucas Werkmeister and Conny Kawohl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HalloWelt - Markus Glaser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Community - Derk-Jan Hartman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TranslateWiki - Niklas Laxström&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Communications&quot;&gt;Communications&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication between the various groups involved in this consultation will be important to achieving an equitable outcome of this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Announcements&quot;&gt;Announcements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Announcements will be made on Wiki, via mailing lists, and via the TechNews newsletter. It will be announced when each stage of the process outlined below begins and ends. Additionally, a summary of feedback will be amalgamated at the end of the entire consultation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;With_those_being_consulted&quot;&gt;With those being consulted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback will be solicited on Wiki, via mailing lists, and via TechNews.  Feedback will be collected for the duration of the consultation period via on-wiki talk pages. Members of the working group will strive to engage in discussions that happen on-wiki during the consultation period. At the end of the entire process a summary of the feedback collected during the consultation will be shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;When&quot;&gt;When&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this decision has secondary effects on our continuous integration system, which is also planned to be replaced in the near future, we hope to follow the below timeline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;wikitable&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Time length&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;What&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Who&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Begin
&lt;p&gt;(Sept 2nd)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Public announcement of this proposal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Working group&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 month
&lt;p&gt;(Sept 2nd - Oct 2nd)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consultation and feedback period. Specific areas to discuss include:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Workflows and processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tooling and features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge, branch, and deployment strategies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consulted groups + Working group&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;3 weeks
&lt;p&gt;(Oct 2nd -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oct 23rd)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Review and incorporation of feedback.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Working group&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;End
&lt;p&gt;(Oct 23rd)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Share summary of feedback received.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Working group&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Decision&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Responsible&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;After consultation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Depending on outcome, the implementation timeline will be created and shared&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Responsible teams (Release Engineering &amp;amp; SRE)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Where&quot;&gt;Where&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A test instance of GitLab, hosted on Wikimedia Cloud Services infrastructure, is available at: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external free&quot; href=&quot;https://gitlab-test.wmcloud.org/&quot;&gt;https://gitlab-test.wmcloud.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: This is a test instance only. Any data should be expected to be lost. Do not reuse any passwords when registering. For bugs or configuration / feature requests while using the test instance, please file tasks in Phabricator using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/tag/gitlab-test/&quot; class=&quot;extiw&quot; title=&quot;phab:tag/gitlab-test/&quot;&gt;GitLab-Test&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Evaluation_Considerations&quot;&gt;Evaluation Considerations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wikimedia technical community has many workflows and participants from all over the world with differing levels of technical knowledge and expertise. To arrive at an equitable decision concerning the adoption of GitLab there's a need to weigh valid concerns against the longevity of the technical projects that the community stewards while also considering the needs of all contributors. These are the considerations that will be used in the evaluation. The evaluation will be completed by the members of the Working Group initially and shared during the consultation period. Topics of discussion include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Workflows
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ACL and privilege policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repository creation and deletion/archival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflows and Code Review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Branching and merging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bot workflows (e.g.: localization, bot comments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI/UX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administration
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;WMF Privacy Policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operations (backups, upgrades, maintenance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upstream
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Free/Open Source Software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Free Knowledge/Software community users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Outputs&quot;&gt;Outputs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab&quot; title=&quot;GitLab&quot;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt; is a portal for all of the outputs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Recommendation &amp;amp; Decision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluation of the suitability of the review tooling across dimensions:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ACL and privilege policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repository creation and deletion/archival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workflows and Code Review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Branching and merging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bot workflows (e.g.: localization, bot comments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;FAQ&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Would we use GitLab Enterprise or Community Edition?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Community Edition (CE). It is the Free Software release of GitLab that runs optional non-free software such as Google Recaptcha to block abuse, which we do not plan to use. This is similar to other Free Software/Culture groups who use GitLab, for example: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://salsa.debian.org/help&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://gitlab.gnome.org/help&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://invent.kde.org/help&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; (each of which use the non-free Recaptcha tool).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is Continuous Integration (CI) out of scope?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CI is out of scope because that infrastructure is secondary to code review. In other words, ideally the details of how CI is set up and maintained are not important to developers on a day to day basis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is GitHub not considered?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;GitHub would be the first tool required to participate in the Wikimedia technical community that would be non Free Software and non self-hosted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub also does not meet all of our needs; for example, GitHub grants little control of metadata, no influence over privacy policy/data retention, sanctions and bans, little control over backups and data integrity checks, and no long-term guaranteed access to underlying repository settings and configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens to repositories developed on GitHub if we move to GitLab?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Given that GitLab provides a very similar workflow and feature set, we will strongly encourage all developers to use GitLab instead of GitHub for all development. Repositories will still be mirrored to GitHub, for visibility purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What about using other GitLab built in features like Issues, Wikis, Pages, etc if we decide to use GitLab for code review?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This consultation is focused only on code review, not issue tracking or replacing other functionalities already provided to Wikimedia developers. To pre-empt a segmentation in our issue tracking we would turn off issue tracking on GitLab. In addition we would turn off repository wikis, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; class=&quot;external text&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/project/pages/&quot;&gt;GitLab Pages&lt;/a&gt;, and other features overlapping with currently provided tooling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Past_Migration_Documentation&quot;&gt;Past Migration Documentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012 SVN to Gerrit migration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canceled Gerrit to Phabricator Differential Migration (declined in 2018):&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 15:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>input_sh</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/GitLab_consultation</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stripe Climate</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/climate</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/climate</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Early purchasers can help new carbon removal technologies get down the cost curve and up the volume curve. Experience with manufacturing learning and experience curves has shown repeatedly that deployment and scale beget improvement, a &lt;a class=&quot; Link&quot; href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0052669&quot; data-js-controller=&quot;AnalyticsButton&quot; data-analytics-category=&quot;Links&quot; data-analytics-action=&quot;Clicked&quot; data-analytics-label=&quot;Phenomenon CTA&quot;&gt;phenomenon&lt;/a&gt; seen across DNA sequencing, hard drive capacity, and solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 14:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>constantinum</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stripe Climate</og:title>
<og:description>Stripe Climate allows you to remove carbon as you grow your businesss</og:description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/climate</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spy agency ducks questions about &amp;#039;back doors&amp;#039; in tech products</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-security-congress-insight/spy-agency-ducks-questions-about-back-doors-in-tech-products-idUSKBN27D1CS</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-security-congress-insight/spy-agency-ducks-questions-about-back-doors-in-tech-products-idUSKBN27D1CS</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-byline-container-3H6dy&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Byline-byline-1sVmo ArticleBody-byline-10B7D&quot;&gt;By &lt;a class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__black-to-orange___23uc0 TextLabel__serif___3lOpX Byline-author-2BSir&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/journalists/joseph-menn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joseph Menn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ArticleBody-read-time-and-social-2VOIr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;TextLabel__text-label___3oCVw TextLabel__gray___1V4fk TextLabel__small-all-caps-spaced-out___3O9H4 ReadTime-read-time-1s3CG ArticleBody-read-time-29pGN&quot;&gt;9 Min Read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO (Reuters) - The U.S. National Security Agency is rebuffing efforts by a leading Congressional critic to determine whether it is continuing to place so-called back doors into commercial technology products, in a controversial practice that critics say damages both U.S. industry and national security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FILE PHOTO: FILE PHOTO: An aerial view of the National Security Agency (NSA) headquarters in Ft. Meade, Maryland, U.S. January 29, 2010. REUTERS/Larry Downing/File Photo/File Photo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The NSA has long sought agreements with technology companies under which they would build special access for the spy agency into their products, according to disclosures by former NSA contractor Edward Snowden and reporting by Reuters and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;These so-called back doors enable the NSA and other agencies to scan large amounts of traffic without a warrant. Agency advocates say the practice has eased collection of vital intelligence in other countries, including interception of terrorist communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The agency developed new rules for such practices after the Snowden leaks in order to reduce the chances of exposure and compromise, three former intelligence officials told Reuters. But aides to Senator Ron Wyden, a leading Democrat on the Senate Intelligence Committee, say the NSA has stonewalled on providing even the gist of the new guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“Secret encryption back doors are a threat to national security and the safety of our families – it’s only a matter of time before foreign hackers or criminals exploit them in ways that undermine American national security,” Wyden told Reuters. “The government shouldn’t have any role in planting secret back doors in encryption technology used by Americans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The agency declined to say how it had updated its policies on obtaining special access to commercial products. NSA officials said the agency has been rebuilding trust with the private sector through such measures as offering warnings about software flaws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“At NSA, it’s common practice to constantly assess processes to identify and determine best practices,” said Anne Neuberger, who heads NSA’s year-old Cybersecurity Directorate. “We don’t share specific processes and procedures.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Three former senior intelligence agency figures told Reuters that the NSA now requires that before a back door is sought, the agency must weigh the potential fallout and arrange for some kind of warning if the back door gets discovered and manipulated by adversaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The continuing quest for hidden access comes as governments in the United States, the United Kingdom and elsewhere seek laws that would require tech companies to let governments see unencrypted traffic. Defenders of strong encryption say the NSA’s sometimes-botched efforts to install back doors in commercial products show the dangers of such requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Critics of the NSA’s practices say they create targets for adversaries, undermine trust in U.S. technology and compromise efforts to persuade allies to reject Chinese technology that could be used for espionage, since U.S. gear can also be turned to such purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;In at least one instance, a foreign adversary was able to take advantage of a back door invented by U.S. intelligence, according to Juniper Networks Inc, which said in 2015 its equipment had been compromised. In a previously unreported statement to members of Congress in July seen by Reuters, Juniper said an unnamed national government had converted the mechanism first created by the NSA. The NSA told Wyden staffers in 2018 that there was a “lessons learned” report about the Juniper incident and others, according to Wyden spokesman Keith Chu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“NSA now asserts that it cannot locate this document,” Chu told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;NSA and Juniper declined to comment on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;Headline-headline-2FXIq Headline-black-OogpV ArticleBody-heading-3h695&quot;&gt;JUNIPER’S COMPROMISE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The NSA has pursued many means for getting inside equipment, sometimes striking commercial deals to induce companies to insert back doors, and in other cases manipulating standards - namely by setting processes so that companies unknowingly adopt software that NSA experts can break, according to reports from Reuters and other media outlets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The tactics drew widespread attention starting in 2013, when Snowden leaked documents referencing these practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Tech companies that were later exposed for having cut deals that allowed backdoor access, including security pioneer RSA, lost credibility and customers. Other U.S. firms lost business overseas as customers grew wary of the NSA’s reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;All of that prompted a White House policy review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“There were all sorts of ‘lessons learned’ processes,” said former White House cybersecurity coordinator Michael Daniel, who was advising then-president Barack Obama when the Snowden files erupted. A special commission appointed by Obama said the government should never “subvert” or “weaken” tech products or compromise standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The White House did not publicly embrace that recommendation, instead beefing up review procedures for whether to use newly discovered software flaws for offensive cyber operations or get them fixed to improve defense, Daniel and others said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The secret government contracts for special access remained outside of the formal review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“The NSA had contracts with companies across the board to help them out, but that’s extremely protected,” said an intelligence community lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The starkest example of the risks inherent in the NSA’s approach involved an encryption-system component known as Dual Elliptic Curve, or Dual EC. The intelligence agency worked with the Commerce Department to get the technology accepted as a global standard, but cryptographers later showed that the NSA could exploit Dual EC to access encrypted data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;RSA accepted a $10 million contract to incorporate Dual EC into a widely used web security system, Reuters reported &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-security-rsa-idUSBRE9BJ1C220131220&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in 2013. RSA said publicly that it would not have knowingly installed a back door, but its reputation was tarnished and the company was sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Juniper Networks got into hot water over Dual EC two years later. At the end of 2015, the maker of internet switches disclosed that it had detected malicious code in some firewall products. Researchers later determined that hackers had turned the firewalls into their own spy tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/idUSKBN0UN07520160109&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; by altering Juniper’s version of Dual EC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Juniper said little about the incident. But the company acknowledged to security researcher Andy Isaacson in 2016 that it had installed Dual EC as part of a “customer requirement,” according to a previously undisclosed contemporaneous message seen by Reuters. Isaacson and other researchers believe that customer was a U.S. government agency, since only the U.S. is known to have insisted on Dual EC elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Juniper has never identified the customer, and declined to comment for this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Likewise, the company never identified the hackers. But two people familiar with the case told Reuters that investigators concluded the Chinese government was behind it. They declined to detail the evidence they used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;The Chinese government has long denied involvement in hacking of any kind. In a statement to Reuters, the Chinese foreign ministry said that cyberspace is “highly virtual and difficult to trace. It is extremely irresponsible to make accusations of hacker attacks without complete and conclusive evidence. At the same time, we also noticed that the report mentioned that it was the U.S. intelligence agency - the National Security Agency - that created this backdoor technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;Headline-headline-2FXIq Headline-black-OogpV ArticleBody-heading-3h695&quot;&gt;NERVOUS COMPANIES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;Wyden remains determined to find out exactly what happened at Juniper and what has changed since as the encryption wars heat up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;This July, in previously unreported responses to questions from Wyden and allies in Congress &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/idUSKBN23H2C9&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, Juniper said that an unidentified nation was believed to be behind the hack into its firewall code but that it had never investigated why it installed Dual EC in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;“We understand that there is a vigorous policy debate about whether and how to provide government access to encrypted content,” it said in a July letter. “Juniper does not and will not insert back doors into its products and we oppose any legislation mandating back doors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Paragraph-paragraph-2Bgue ArticleBody-para-TD_9x&quot;&gt;A former senior NSA official told Reuters that many tech companies remain nervous about working covertly with the government. But the agencies’ efforts continue, the person said, because special access is seen as too valuable to give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div readability=&quot;4.8595041322314&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution-attribution-Y5JpY&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting by Joseph Menn; editing by Jonathan Weber and Edward Tobin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 13:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>oblib</dc:creator>
<og:title>Spy agency ducks questions about 'back doors' in tech products</og:title>
<og:description>The U.S. National Security Agency is rebuffing efforts by a leading Congressional critic to determine whether it is continuing to place so-called back doors into commercial technology products, in a controversial practice that critics say damages both U.S. industry and national...</og:description>
<og:image>https://static.reuters.com/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20201028&amp;t=2&amp;i=1539111638&amp;r=LYNXMPEG9R0YF&amp;w=800</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-security-congress-insight-idUSKBN27D1CS</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-security-congress-insight/spy-agency-ducks-questions-about-back-doors-in-tech-products-idUSKBN27D1CS</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>