<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Slack: An Apology and an Update</title>
<link>https://slackhq.com/an-apology-and-an-update</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://slackhq.com/an-apology-and-an-update</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Two days ago, we updated our system for applying location information to comply with U.S. trade embargoes and economic sanctions regulations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Soon after updating, we discovered that we made a series of mistakes and inadvertently deactivated a number of accounts that we shouldn’t have. We recognize the disruption and inconvenience this caused and we sincerely apologize to the people affected by our actions. In fact, we also apologize to the people whose accounts we&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;intended&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;to disable in order to comply with these regulations. We did not handle the communication well and in both cases we failed to live up to our own standards for courtesy and customer-centricity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We did not block any user based on their nationality or ethnicity. As is standard in the enterprise software industry, Slack uses location information principally derived from IP addresses to implement these required blocks. We do not collect, use, or possess any information about the nationality or ethnicity of our users.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We have restored access to most of the mistakenly blocked accounts, and we are working hard to restore any remaining users whose access was blocked in error. If you think we’ve made a mistake in blocking your access, please reach out to feedback@slack.com and we’ll review as soon as possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We would also like to notify our users that as we continue to update our systems over the next several weeks, we will soon begin blocking access to our service from IP addresses associated with an embargoed country. Users who travel to a sanctioned country may not be able to access Slack while they remain in that country. However, we will not deactivate their account and they will be able to access Slack when they return to countries or regions for which no blocking is required.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We acknowledge that we made several mistakes here. Our attempts to comply with these regulations were not well-implemented. In our communications, we did not treat our customers and other users with the respect they deserve. And finally, in the rush to understand the impact and begin the process of mitigation, we were slow to communicate what was happening. To everyone affected, we apologize. We’ll take the failures here as lessons we can use to improve our service and avoid similar mistakes in the future. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 01:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abraham</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>An Apology and an Update - Several People Are Typing</og:title>
<og:description>Two days ago, we updated our system for applying location information to comply with U.S. trade embargoes and economic sanctions regulations. Soon after updating, we discovered that we made a series of mistakes and inadvertently deactivated a number of accounts that we shouldn’t have. We recognize the disruption and inconvenience this caused and we sincerely …</og:description>
<og:url>https://slackhq.com/an-apology-and-an-update</og:url>
<og:image>https://slackhq.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/slack_rgb_social2.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://slackhq.com/an-apology-and-an-update</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Discord raises $150M, surpassing $2B valuation</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/21/gaming-chat-startup-discord-raises-150m-surpassing-2b-valuation/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/21/gaming-chat-startup-discord-raises-150m-surpassing-2b-valuation/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;Chatty gamers are apparently worth billions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://discordapp.com/&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;, the gaming chat startup with more than 200 million active users, announced Friday that it had secured $150 million in funding at a $2.05 billion valuation. The round was led by Greenoaks Capital with participation from Firstmark, Tencent, IVP, Index Ventures and Technology Opportunity Partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company announced this past April that they had raised $50 million in funding at a $1.65 billion valuation. With this latest bout of cash, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/discord&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;discord&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; has now pulled in more than $280 million in funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The influx of new money comes as the chat startup goes full speed ahead on one of its most ambitious offshoots to date, taking on games giant Valve with a gaming store meant to rival the ubiquitous Steam store. The company launched a global beta of the Discord Store in October; they recently announced that starting in 2019, they will be establishing a revenue split of 90/10 for developers that are self-publishing titles on the store, a margin much friendlier to indie devs than the 70/30 split on Steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company’s bread-and-butter remains its chat service, which brings voice and text communications to gamers looking to talk with teammates and fellow enthusiasts during and outside of gameplay. Discord isn’t the only service that offers this capability, but it is definitely one of the most popular with hundreds of millions of users coming to the app every month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We chatted with CEO Jason Citron at our most recent Disrupt SF event, where he talked about the opportunities available in the online games sales market and what challenges the company had up ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;embed-youtube embed breakout embed--video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bufnBzGy4eU?version=3&amp;amp;rel=1&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;autohide=2&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 22:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>sahin-boydas</dc:creator>
<og:title>Gaming chat startup Discord raises $150M, surpassing $2B valuation</og:title>
<og:description>Chatty gamers are apparently worth billions. Discord, the gaming chat startup with more than 200 million active users, announced Friday that it had secured $150 million in funding at a $2.05 billion valuation. The round was led by Greenoaks Capital with participation from Firstmark, Tencent, IVP, I…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/29582922657_f5ec4998e7_k.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/12/21/gaming-chat-startup-discord-raises-150m-surpassing-2b-valuation/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/21/gaming-chat-startup-discord-raises-150m-surpassing-2b-valuation/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>AT&amp;T will put a fake 5G logo on its 4G LTE phones</title>
<link>https://www.fiercewireless.com/5g/at-t-to-begin-upgrading-existing-lte-phones-to-5g-e</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.fiercewireless.com/5g/at-t-to-begin-upgrading-existing-lte-phones-to-5g-e</guid>
<description>&lt;div property=&quot;schema:articleBody&quot; readability=&quot;49.118219749652&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T confirmed to FierceWireless that it will soon begin changing the “LTE” indicator on some of its current Android phones to “5G E” in markets where the company now offers 4x4 MIMO, 256 QAM and other advanced LTE network technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“If they have one of the latest Android devices and it connects to a tower that’s enabled with 5G Evolution, they’ll soon see a “5G E” indicator pop up on their screen,” an AT&amp;amp;T spokesperson wrote in response to questions from FierceWireless. “Initially we’ll roll this out on a handful of devices, with more devices showing the indicator in spring 2019.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The operator didn’t immediately respond to questions about the total number of devices that would be affected by the change. However, potentially millions of existing LTE smartphone owners could eventually see their AT&amp;amp;T network status icon change from “LTE” to “5G E.” AT&amp;amp;T said its “5G Evolution” service will be commercially available in more than 400 markets by the end of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section role=&quot;article&quot; about=&quot;/node/358076&quot; class=&quot;node node--type-embed-promo node--view-mode-body-embed-promo clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;3.8712871287129&quot;&gt;&lt;header&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;FREE DAILY NEWSLETTER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;promo_content clearfix&quot; readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Like this story? Subscribe to FierceWireless!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wireless industry is an ever-changing world where big ideas come along daily. Our subscribers rely on FierceWireless as their must-read source for the latest news, analysis and data on this increasingly competitive marketplace. Sign up today to get wireless news and updates delivered to your inbox and read on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiercewireless.com/wireless/at-t-defends-use-5g-evolution-branding-for-lte-service-promises-theoretical-speeds-up-to-1&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; introduced the “5G Evolution” marketing label to cover markets where it offers advanced LTE network technologies like carrier aggregation, 4x4 MIMO, LAA and 256 QAM. Such technologies can dramatically improve the speeds available through LTE, and AT&amp;amp;T has argued that such technologies pave the way for eventual 5G services, though critics have argued that AT&amp;amp;T’s “5G Evolution” marketing moves only serve to sow confusion among consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RELATED: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiercewireless.com/wireless/at-t-defends-use-5g-evolution-branding-for-lte-service-promises-theoretical-speeds-up-to-1&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T defends use of ‘5G Evolution’ branding for LTE service, promises theoretical speeds up to 1 Gbps this year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T’s decision to change its “LTE” indicator to “5G E” has precedence. Sprint branded its WiMAX network as a 4G offering, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiercewireless.com/wireless/at-t-chides-t-mobile-for-misleading-4g-marketing-hspa&quot;&gt;while T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt; (and then later AT&amp;amp;T) both branded HSPA+ as 4G before the arrival of LTE. Those moves were notable considering the wireless industry widely regards LTE as the official 4G technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T’s “5G E” label will sit next to its “5G+” label, which the operator has applied to its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiercewireless.com/5g/at-t-launches-mobile-5g-teases-plans-15-gb-for-70-month&quot;&gt;mobile 5G service launching today in 12 cities&lt;/a&gt;. AT&amp;amp;T’s “5G+” label applies to transmissions in the operator’s millimeter-wave spectrum. (AT&amp;amp;T’s initial mobile 5G launch will transmit signals in its 39 GHz licensed spectrum band across 100 MHz of spectrum and 2x2 MIMO antennas.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RELATED: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiercewireless.com/5g/at-t-answers-5-questions-about-its-mobile-5g-service&quot;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T answers 5 questions about its mobile 5G service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For its part, Verizon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiercewireless.com/5g/verizon-s-cto-gives-forthcoming-network-a-new-name-5g-ultra-wideband&quot;&gt;has branded&lt;/a&gt; its 5G service as “5G Ultra Wideband.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;keywords-topics&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more on&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 20:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>devy</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://qtxasset.com/fiercewireless/1545409340/att-5ge.jpg?bvEFe4G2qLiWRm6LoVV.8gQ.vI2ZZ09M</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.fiercewireless.com/5g/at-t-to-begin-upgrading-existing-lte-phones-to-5g-e</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook open-sources a speech-recognition system and a machine learning library</title>
<link>https://code.fb.com/ai-research/wav2letter/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://code.fb.com/ai-research/wav2letter/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;WHAT THE RESEARCH IS:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new fully convolutional &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1812.06864&quot;&gt;approach&lt;/a&gt; to automatic speech recognition and &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1812.07625&quot;&gt;wav2letter++&lt;/a&gt;, the fastest state-of-the-art end-to-end speech recognition system available. The approach leverages convolutional neural networks (CNNs) for acoustic modeling and language modeling, and is reproducible, thanks to the toolkits we are releasing jointly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;HOW IT WORKS:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CNN architectures are competitive with recurrent architectures for tasks in which modeling long-range dependencies is important, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1612.08083&quot;&gt;language modeling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1711.04956&quot;&gt;machine translation&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://regmedia.co.uk/2016/09/09/wavenet.pdf&quot;&gt;speech synthesis&lt;/a&gt;. In end-to-end speech recognition, however, recurrent architectures are still more prevalent for both acoustic and language modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Facebook AI Research (FAIR) Speech team is sharing the first fully convolutional speech recognition system. From the waveform to the final word transcription, the learnable parts of the system are composed only of convolutional layers. This yields performance that’s competitive with that of recurrent architectures. &lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-12069 size-full&quot; data-src=&quot;https://code.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/fully_convolutional_ASR.png&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook AI Research (FAIR) Speech is sharing the first fully convolutional speech recognition system. From the waveform to the final word transcription, the learnable parts of the system are composed only of convolutional layers. This yields performance that's competitive with recurrent architectures.&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;416&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also releasing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebookresearch/flashlight&quot;&gt;flashlight&lt;/a&gt;, a fast, flexible standalone machine learning library designed by the FAIR Speech team and the creators of Torch and DeepSpeech. It features just-in-time compilation with modern C++, targeting both CPU and GPU backends for maximum efficiency and scale. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebookresearch/wav2letter/&quot;&gt;wav2letter++ toolkit&lt;/a&gt; is built on top of flashlight. We are releasing both frameworks jointly with this research to enable reproducibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WHY IT MATTERS:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;End-to-end speech recognition makes it easy to scale to multiple languages. Also, learning directly from raw speech is a promising avenue in settings where audio quality is highly variable. High-performance frameworks such as wav2letter++ enable fast iteration, which is often an important factor in successful research and model tuning on new data sets and tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;READ THE FULL PAPERS:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1812.07625&quot;&gt;Wav2letter++: The fastest open source speech recognition system&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1812.06864&quot;&gt;Fully Convolutional Speech Recognition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 20:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>runesoerensen</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Wav2letter++, the fastest open source speech system, and flashlight</og:title>
<og:description>Wav2letter++ is the fastest state-of-the-art end-to-end speech recognition system available. We're also releasing flashlight, a fast, flexible ML library.</og:description>
<og:url>https://code.fb.com/ai-research/wav2letter/</og:url>
<og:image>https://code.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/RIBred.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://code.fb.com/ai-research/wav2letter/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Burnout, stress lead more companies to try a four-day work week</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-world-work-fourdayweek/burnout-stress-lead-more-companies-to-try-a-four-day-work-week-idUSKBN1OG0GY</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-world-work-fourdayweek/burnout-stress-lead-more-companies-to-try-a-four-day-work-week-idUSKBN1OG0GY</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;(Corrects paragraph 4 to identify Perpetual Guardian as a trust company instead of an insurance company; corrects paragraph 13 to reflect that the study was conducted by Kronos and Future Workplace)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Emma Thomasson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BERLIN (Reuters) - Work four days a week, but get paid for five?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds too good to be true, but companies around the world that have cut their work week have found that it leads to higher productivity, more motivated staff and less burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is much healthier and we do a better job if we’re not working crazy hours,” said Jan Schulz-Hofen, founder of Berlin-based project management software company Planio, who introduced a four-day week to the company’s 10-member staff earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In New Zealand, trust company Perpetual Guardian reported a fall in stress and a jump in staff engagement after it tested a 32-hour week earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in Japan, the government is encouraging companies to allow Monday mornings off, although other schemes in the workaholic country to persuade employees to take it easy have had little effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britain’s Trades Union Congress (TUC) is pushing for the whole country to move to a four-day week by the end of the century, a drive supported by the opposition Labour party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TUC argues that a shorter week is a way for workers to share in the wealth generated by new technologies like machine learning and robotics, just as they won the right to the weekend off during the industrial revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It would reduce the stress of juggling working and family life and could improve gender equality. Companies that have already tried it say it’s better for productivity and staff wellbeing,” said TUC economic head Kate Bell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;OVERWORKED&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucie Greene, trends expert at consultancy J. Walter Thompson, said there was a growing backlash against overwork, underlined by a wave of criticism after Tesla (&lt;span id=&quot;”symbol_TSLA.O_0”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=TSLA.O&quot;&gt;TSLA.O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) boss Elon Musk tweeted that “nobody ever changed the world on 40 hours a week.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People are starting to take a step back from the 24-hour digital life we have now and realize the mental health issues from being constantly connected to work,” Greene said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent survey of 3,000 employees in eight countries including the United States, Britain and Germany found that nearly half thought they could easily finish their tasks in five hours a day if they did not have interruptions, but many are exceeding 40 hours a week anyway - with the United States leading the way, where 49 percent said they worked overtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There has been work creep. Because you always have the technology, you are always working, so people are getting burned out,” said Dan Schawbel, director of executive development firm Future Workplace, which conducted the survey with Kronos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schulz-Hofen, a 36-year-old software engineer, tested the four-day week on himself after realizing he needed to slow down following a decade of intense work launching Planio, whose tools allowed him to track his time in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t get less work done in four days than in five because in five days, you think you have more time, you take longer, you allow yourself to have more interruptions, you have your coffee a bit longer or chat with colleagues,” Schulz-Hofen said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I realized with four days, I have to be quick, I have to be focused if I want to have my free Friday.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schulz-Hofen and his team discussed various options before settling on everybody working Monday to Thursday. They rejected the idea of flexible hours because it adds administrative complexity, and were against a five-day week with shorter hours as it is too easy for overwork to creep back in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clients who call on a Friday hear a recorded message explaining why nobody is at the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20181217&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1336067632&amp;amp;r=LYNXMPEEBG0DJ&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;FILE PHOTO: Office workers take their lunch at a food court in Sydney, Australia, May 4, 2018. REUTERS/Edgar Su/File Photo&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;FILE PHOTO: Office workers take their lunch at a food court in Sydney, Australia, May 4, 2018. REUTERS/Edgar Su/File Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We got an unexpected reaction from customers. Most of our clients did not complain. They were just jealous,” Schulz-Hofen said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grey New York, an ad agency owned by WPP (&lt;span id=&quot;”symbol_WPP.L_1”&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=WPP.L&quot;&gt;WPP.L&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), launched a program in April to allow staff to work a four-day week for 85 percent of their full-time salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schawbel expects the idea to catch on in more companies and countries, but probably not his own: “I think America will be the last country to give us Monday mornings off because we’re so used to this way of working.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by Emma Thomasson, Editing by Rosalba O'Brien and Lauren Young&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 19:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>joeyespo</dc:creator>
<og:title>Burnout, stress lead more companies to try a four-day work week</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-world-work-fourdayweek-idUSKBN1OG0GY</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Work four days a week, but get paid for five?</og:description>
<og:image>https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20181217&amp;t=2&amp;i=1336067632&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXMPEEBG0DJ</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-world-work-fourdayweek/burnout-stress-lead-more-companies-to-try-a-four-day-work-week-idUSKBN1OG0GY</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Brave taking cryptocurrency donations “for me” without my consent</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/tomscott/status/1076160882873380870</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/tomscott/status/1076160882873380870</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Re: GDPR, I mean creators, not Brave users. If a domain owner, channel owner, or similar sends you a RTBF request, can those assigned donations be reverted and the records of which domain/channel/other personal identifier they were assigned to be removed?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 17:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>plusCubed</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/tomscott/status/1076160882873380870</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Electron 4.0.0</title>
<link>https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;blog-byline mt-2 mb-4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BinaryMuse&quot; class=&quot;author-link ml-3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/BinaryMuse.png?size=36&quot; alt=&quot;BinaryMuse&quot; class=&quot;avatar mr-2&quot;/&gt;BinaryMuse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Electron team is excited to announce that the stable release of Electron 4 is now available! You can install it from &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/&quot;&gt;electronjs.org&lt;/a&gt; or from npm via &lt;code&gt;npm install electron@latest&lt;/code&gt;. The release is packed with upgrades, fixes, and new features, and we can't wait to see what you build with them. Read more for details about this release, and please share any feedback you have as you explore!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large part of Electron's functionality is provided by Chromium, Node.js, and V8, the core components that make up Electron. As such, a key goal for the Electron team is to keep up with changes to these projects as much as possible, providing developers who build Electron apps access to new web and JavaScript features. To this end, Electron 4 features major version bumps to each of these components; Electron v4.0.0 includes Chromium &lt;code&gt;69.0.3497.106&lt;/code&gt;, Node &lt;code&gt;10.11.0&lt;/code&gt;, and V8 &lt;code&gt;6.9.427.24&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, Electron 4 includes changes to Electron-specific APIs. You can find a summary of the major changes in Electron 4 below; for the full list of changes, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/electron/electron/releases/tag/v4.0.0&quot;&gt;Electron v4.0.0 release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;disabling-the-remote-module&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#disabling-the-remote-module&quot;&gt;Disabling the &lt;code&gt;remote&lt;/code&gt; Module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You now have the ability to disable the &lt;code&gt;remote&lt;/code&gt; module for security reasons. The module can be disabled for &lt;code&gt;BrowserWindow&lt;/code&gt;s and for &lt;code&gt;webview&lt;/code&gt; tags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;hljs language-javascript&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; BrowserWindow({
  &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-attr&quot;&gt;webPreferences&lt;/span&gt;: {
    &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-attr&quot;&gt;enableRemoteModule&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-literal&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
  }
})


&amp;lt;webview src=&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;http://www.google.com/&quot;&lt;/span&gt; enableremotemodule=&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;&quot;false&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-name&quot;&gt;webview&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/api/browser-window&quot;&gt;BrowserWindow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/api/webview-tag&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;webview&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; Tag&lt;/a&gt; documentation for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;filtering-remoterequire--remotegetglobal-requests&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#filtering-remoterequire--remotegetglobal-requests&quot;&gt;Filtering &lt;code&gt;remote.require()&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;remote.getGlobal()&lt;/code&gt; Requests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature is useful if you don't want to completely disable the &lt;code&gt;remote&lt;/code&gt; module in your renderer process or &lt;code&gt;webview&lt;/code&gt; but would like additional control over which modules can be required via &lt;code&gt;remote.require&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a module is required via &lt;code&gt;remote.require&lt;/code&gt; in a renderer process, a &lt;code&gt;remote-require&lt;/code&gt; event is raised on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/api/app&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;app&lt;/code&gt; module&lt;/a&gt;. You can call &lt;code&gt;event.preventDefault()&lt;/code&gt; on the the event (the first argument) to prevent the module from being loaded. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/api/web-contents&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;WebContents&lt;/code&gt; instance&lt;/a&gt; where the require occurred is passed as the second argument, and the name of the module is passed as the third argument. The same event is also emitted on the &lt;code&gt;WebContents&lt;/code&gt; instance, but in this case the only arguments are the event and the module name. In both cases, you can return a custom value by setting the value of &lt;code&gt;event.returnValue&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;hljs language-javascript&quot;&gt;
app.on(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'remote-require'&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-params&quot;&gt;event, webContents, requestedModuleName&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;/span&gt;{
  
})


browserWin.webContents.on(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'remote-require'&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-params&quot;&gt;event, requestedModuleName&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;/span&gt;{
  
})&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a similar fashion, when &lt;code&gt;remote.getGlobal(name)&lt;/code&gt; is called, a &lt;code&gt;remote-get-global&lt;/code&gt; event is raised. This works the same way as the &lt;code&gt;remote-require&lt;/code&gt; event: call &lt;code&gt;preventDefault()&lt;/code&gt; to prevent the global from being returned, and set &lt;code&gt;event.returnValue&lt;/code&gt; to return a custom value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;hljs language-javascript&quot;&gt;
app.on(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'remote-get-global'&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-params&quot;&gt;event, webContents, requrestedGlobalName&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;/span&gt;{
  
})


browserWin.webContents.on(&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-string&quot;&gt;'remote-get-global'&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-function&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-params&quot;&gt;event, requestedGlobalName&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;/span&gt;{
  
})&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the following documentation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;javascript-access-to-the-about-panel&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#javascript-access-to-the-about-panel&quot;&gt;JavaScript Access to the About Panel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On macOS, you can now call &lt;code&gt;app.showAboutPanel()&lt;/code&gt; to programmatically show the About panel, just like clicking the menu item created via &lt;code&gt;{role: 'about'}&lt;/code&gt;. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/api/app?query=show#appshowaboutpanel-macos&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;showAboutPanel&lt;/code&gt; documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;controlling-webcontents-background-throttling&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#controlling-webcontents-background-throttling&quot;&gt;Controlling &lt;code&gt;WebContents&lt;/code&gt; Background Throttling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;WebContents&lt;/code&gt; instances now have a method &lt;code&gt;setBackgroundThrottling(allowed)&lt;/code&gt; to enable or disable throttling of timers and animations when the page is backgrounded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;hljs language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; win = &lt;span class=&quot;hljs-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; BrowserWindow(...)
win.webContents.setBackgroundThrottling(enableBackgroundThrottling)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/api/web-contents#contentssetbackgroundthrottlingallowed&quot;&gt;the &lt;code&gt;setBackgroundThrottling&lt;/code&gt; documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-more-macos-109-support&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#no-more-macos-109-support&quot;&gt;No More macOS 10.9 Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chromium no longer supports macOS 10.9 (OS X Mavericks), and as a result &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/electron/electron/pull/15357&quot;&gt;Electron 4.0 and beyond does not support it either&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;single-instance-locking&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#single-instance-locking&quot;&gt;Single Instance Locking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, to make your app a Single Instance Application (ensuring that only one instance of your app is running at any given time), you could use the &lt;code&gt;app.makeSingleInstance()&lt;/code&gt; method. Starting in Electron 4.0, you must use &lt;code&gt;app.requestSingleInstanceLock()&lt;/code&gt; instead. The return value of this method indicates whether or not this instance of your application successfully obtained the lock. If it failed to obtain the lock, you can assume that another instance of your application is already running with the lock and exit immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example of using &lt;code&gt;requestSingleInstanceLock()&lt;/code&gt; and information on nuanced behavior on various platforms, &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/api/app#apprequestsingleinstancelock&quot;&gt;see the documentation for &lt;code&gt;app.requestSingleInstanceLock()&lt;/code&gt; and related methods&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/api/app#event-second-instance&quot;&gt;the &lt;code&gt;second-instance&lt;/code&gt; event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;win_delay_load_hook&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#win_delay_load_hook&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;win_delay_load_hook&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building native modules for windows, the &lt;code&gt;win_delay_load_hook&lt;/code&gt; variable in the module's &lt;code&gt;binding.gyp&lt;/code&gt; must be true (which is the default). If this hook is not present, then the native module will fail to load on Windows, with an error message like &lt;code&gt;Cannot find module&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/tutorial/using-native-node-modules#a-note-about-win_delay_load_hook&quot;&gt;See the native module guide&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following breaking changes are planned for Electron 5.0, and thus are deprecated in Electron 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;nodejs-integration-disabled-for-nativewindowopen-ed-windows&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#nodejs-integration-disabled-for-nativewindowopen-ed-windows&quot;&gt;Node.js Integration Disabled for &lt;code&gt;nativeWindowOpen&lt;/code&gt;-ed Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in Electron 5.0, child windows opened with the &lt;code&gt;nativeWindowOpen&lt;/code&gt; option will always have Node.js integration disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;webpreferences-default-values&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#webpreferences-default-values&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;webPreferences&lt;/code&gt; Default Values&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating a new &lt;code&gt;BrowerWindow&lt;/code&gt; with the &lt;code&gt;webPreferences&lt;/code&gt; option set, the following &lt;code&gt;webPreferences&lt;/code&gt; option defaults are deprecated in favor of new defaults listed below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;table table-ruled table-full-width&quot;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Property&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Deprecated Default&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;New Default&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;contextIsolation&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;nodeIntegration&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;webviewTag&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;value of &lt;code&gt;nodeIntegration&lt;/code&gt; if set, otherwise &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note: there is currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/electron/electron/issues/9736&quot;&gt;a known bug (#9736)&lt;/a&gt; that prevents the &lt;code&gt;webview&lt;/code&gt; tag from working if &lt;code&gt;contextIsolation&lt;/code&gt; is on. Keep an eye on the GitHub issue for up-to-date information!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about context isolation, Node integration, and the &lt;code&gt;webview&lt;/code&gt; tag in &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/tutorial/security&quot;&gt;the Electron security document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electron 4.0 will still use the current defaults, but if you don't pass an explicit value for them, you'll see a deprecation warning. To prepare your app for Electron 5.0, use explicit values for these options. &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/api/browser-window#new-browserwindowoptions&quot;&gt;See the &lt;code&gt;BrowserWindow&lt;/code&gt; docs&lt;/a&gt; for details on each of these options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;webcontentsfindinpagetext-options&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0#webcontentsfindinpagetext-options&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;webContents.findInPage(text[, options])&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;medialCapitalAsWordStart&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;wordStart&lt;/code&gt; options have been deprecated as they have been removed upstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/app-feedback-program&quot;&gt;App Feedback Program&lt;/a&gt; we instituted during the development of Electron 3.0 was successful, so we've continued it during the development of 4.0 as well. We'd like to extend a massive thank you to Atlassian, Discord, MS Teams, OpenFin, Slack, Symphony, WhatsApp, and the other program members for their involvement during the 4.0 beta cycle. To learn more about the App Feedback Program and to participate in future betas, &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/blog/app-feedback-program&quot;&gt;check out our blog post about the program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the short term, you can expect the team to continue to focus on keeping up with the development of the major components that make up Electron, including Chromium, Node, and V8. Although we are careful not to make promises about release dates, our plan is release new major versions of Electron with new versions of those components approximately quarterly. &lt;a href=&quot;https://electronjs.org/docs/tutorial/electron-versioning&quot;&gt;See our versioning document&lt;/a&gt; for more detailed information about versioning in Electron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For information on planned breaking changes in upcoming versions of Electron, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/electron/electron/blob/master/docs/api/breaking-changes.md&quot;&gt;see our Planned Breaking Changes doc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 15:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gozzoo</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Electron 4.0.0 | Electron Blog</og:title>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://electronjs.org/blog/electron-4-0</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Raspberry Pi Pet Detector Camera Using Python, TensorFlow, and Twilio [video]</title>
<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gGqVNuYol6o</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gGqVNuYol6o</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;eow-description&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;I used TensorFlow and a Raspberry Pi to create a pet detector camera that watches the door and texts me when my cat wants to be let inside! This video explains how the code works, so you can use it as an example for your own object detection application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a Raspberry Pi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Famzn.to%2F2Iki3fb&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Famzn.to%2F2Iki3fb&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDcQ6TgYACITCNjR7a38st8CFZHDxAod120Gsyj4HUiqr6Kx7qaltYAB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://amzn.to/2Iki3fb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Get a Picamera: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Famzn.to%2F2rKxarh&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Famzn.to%2F2rKxarh&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDcQ6TgYACITCNjR7a38st8CFZHDxAod120Gsyj4HUiqr6Kx7qaltYAB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://amzn.to/2rKxarh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Handy Picamera + Pi case: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Famzn.to%2F2LxaUed&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Famzn.to%2F2LxaUed&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDcQ6TgYACITCNjR7a38st8CFZHDxAod120Gsyj4HUiqr6Kx7qaltYAB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://amzn.to/2LxaUed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---- Links mentioned in video ----&lt;br/&gt;Pet Detector Python code: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2FEdjeElectronics%2FTensorFlow-Object-Detection-on-the-Raspberry-Pi%2Fblob%2Fmaster%2FPet_detector.py&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2FEdjeElectronics%2FTensorFlow-Object-Detection-on-the-Raspberry-Pi%2Fblob%2Fmaster%2FPet_detector.py&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDcQ6TgYACITCNjR7a38st8CFZHDxAod120Gsyj4HUiqr6Kx7qaltYAB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/EdjeElectronics/Te...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Video tutorial on how to set up TensorFlow on the Raspberry Pi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=npZ-8Nj1YwY&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink spf-link&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDcQ6TgYACITCNjR7a38st8CFZHDxAod120Gsyj4HQ&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/npZ-8Nj1YwY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Twilio guide: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.twilio.com%2Fdocs%2Fsms%2Fquickstart%2Fpython&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.twilio.com%2Fdocs%2Fsms%2Fquickstart%2Fpython&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDcQ6TgYACITCNjR7a38st8CFZHDxAod120Gsyj4HUiqr6Kx7qaltYAB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://www.twilio.com/docs/sms/quick...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter: @EdjeElectronics &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2FEdjeElectronics&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2FEdjeElectronics&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDcQ6TgYACITCNjR7a38st8CFZHDxAod120Gsyj4HUiqr6Kx7qaltYAB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/EdjeElectronics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Music: Broke For Free - Something Elated&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fbrokeforfree.com%2F&quot; class=&quot;yt-uix-sessionlink&quot; data-url=&quot;/redirect?v=gGqVNuYol6o&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;redir_token=ZSZWps2G3PKD9Yn_Fb-3KXJ51XJ8MTU0NTU1MjA5NEAxNTQ1NDY1Njk0&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Fbrokeforfree.com%2F&quot; data-target-new-window=&quot;True&quot; data-sessionlink=&quot;itct=CDcQ6TgYACITCNjR7a38st8CFZHDxAod120Gsyj4HUiqr6Kx7qaltYAB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://brokeforfree.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 15:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>viniciosbarros</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gGqVNuYol6o</og:url>
<og:title>Raspberry Pi Pet Detector Camera Using Python, TensorFlow, and Twilio</og:title>
<og:image>https://i.ytimg.com/vi/gGqVNuYol6o/maxresdefault.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>I used TensorFlow and a Raspberry Pi to create a pet detector camera that watches the door and texts me when my cat wants to be let inside! This video explai...</og:description>
<og:type>video.other</og:type>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gGqVNuYol6o</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How ‘Baldur’s Gate’ Saved the Computer RPG</title>
<link>https://www.theringer.com/2018/12/21/18150363/baldurs-gate-bioware-1998-video-games</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theringer.com/2018/12/21/18150363/baldurs-gate-bioware-1998-video-games</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;GSib5s&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Art may largely be a matter of taste, but one conclusion is close to inarguable: 1998 was the best year ever for video games, producing an unparalleled lineup of revolutionary releases that left indelible legacies and spawned series and subcultures that persist today. Throughout the year,&lt;/em&gt; The Ringer&lt;em&gt;’s gaming enthusiasts will be&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/2018/8/29/17795406/1998-the-best-year-ever-for-video-games&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;paying tribute to the legendary titles turning 20 in 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;by replaying them for the umpteenth time or playing them for the first time, talking to the people who made them, and analyzing both what made them great and how they made later games greater. Our series rolls another 20 with the first great game by BioWare, the boundary-breaking role-playing epic&lt;/em&gt; Baldur’s Gate&lt;em&gt;, which debuted two decades ago Friday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;p-entry-hr&quot; id=&quot;o52HwD&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p-dropcap has-dropcap&quot; id=&quot;AaRK0j&quot;&gt;In late 1995, a small group of beginner game developers in Alberta who’d created a company called BioWare needed a new project. Their first title, a mech game called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shattered_Steel&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shattered Steel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, was nearing the end of development, and the tiny studio wanted to do something different. BioWare’s founders were weaned on tabletop role-playing games and digital equivalents like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wasteland_(video_game)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wasteland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so they decided that their second game should be a computer RPG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;camu44&quot;&gt;Considering industry trends at the time, this was an uncommon course for a Western developer. The video-game review site &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamerankings.com/&quot;&gt;GameRankings&lt;/a&gt; has indexed at least one review for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamerankings.com/browse.html?site=&amp;amp;cat=48&amp;amp;year=1995&amp;amp;numrev=2&amp;amp;sort=0&amp;amp;letter=&amp;amp;search=&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt; RPGs released in 1995. Of those 27, 21—including the top 13 by average review score—were made in Japan. The top of the list is littered with legendary Japanese developers: SquareSoft, Sega, Nintendo, Namco, Capcom. That was difficult company to crack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;RONqyZ&quot;&gt;“Everybody and their dog was convinced that Western RPGs were dead,” says BioWare cofounder &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TrentOster&quot;&gt;Trent Oster&lt;/a&gt;. “It was all gonna be Japanese RPGs. Nobody in the Western world knew how to make [RPGs] … there was just no hope.” If the Western RPG was dead, the Western &lt;em&gt;computer&lt;/em&gt; RPG was doubly dead: Every one of those top 13 RPGs from ’95 had come out on a console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;asGNG4&quot;&gt;Three years later, all of those illustrious Japanese studios also appeared on the 1998 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamerankings.com/browse.html?site=&amp;amp;cat=48&amp;amp;year=1998&amp;amp;numrev=2&amp;amp;sort=0&amp;amp;letter=&amp;amp;search=&quot;&gt;list&lt;/a&gt;. But close to the top, second only to Sega’s little-played &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/2018/1/29/16940902/1998-video-games-panzer-dragoon-saga-missing-masterpiece&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panzer Dragoon Saga&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a new name joined them: BioWare, the makers of &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ciiXtr&quot;&gt;The product of three exhausting and exhilarating years of labor by a team of roughly 15 people who didn’t know enough to be daunted by the task they undertook, &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; was a genre-stretching, disc-space-testing hybrid that broke new narrative, technical, and gameplay ground and established the identity of one of the past two decades’ most storied studios. “It just redefined expectations of what a role-playing game could be,” Oster says. “I think it really relaunched the whole concept of what a Western RPG is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hE4TOcrmlfY-vPOE52HXbLBK7xc=/0x0:640x480/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JglMSNawpxwv16qTo97rBtGFycg=/0x0:640x480/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5myYGenABD_Gz36kbVLUhbMAdks=/0x0:640x480/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ao4TmFwmCroFgYk5hiFYifBIje0=/0x0:640x480/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zRcJ7i_ufZE1yk8ovabANIlWTtw=/0x0:640x480/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tMEKOpoBMIQg0XQYPAw8o3M2o6o=/0x0:640x480/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/87X7H6p9CMmTq4cBs5wTyMXK4Ko=/0x0:640x480/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VRvEaWwATUN__kLuQaJ4A35HwYQ=/0x0:640x480/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wawZvqF6MIS2Vzall1X-4iy9lEI=/0x0:640x480/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-upload-width=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_czugv6sinoW5nDMa_dwVtjE9do=/0x0:640x480/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:640x480):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641737/Menu.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-dropcap has-dropcap&quot; id=&quot;Zzny7J&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; began in a basement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;yOWzT1&quot;&gt;Scott Greig, who became the first official BioWare employee, remembers how he heard about the company: An intern at the business where he was doing database work told him about some friends of his father’s, medical doctors who were getting into game-making. “I’m thinking, ‘Yeah, yeah, just a couple of guys in their basement,’” Greig says. That part, Greig discovered when he eventually met them in late 1995, turned out to be true: Ray Muzyka and Greg Zeschuk, two of the three newly graduated doctors who (along with three other associates) founded BioWare in February ’95, &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; working out of Zeschuk’s basement in Edmonton. But their desire to make games was serious, and they were already working on one. “It really was two guys in the basement making video games,” Greig says, “but they were two guys in the basement with a national contract with a real publisher.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UufCrW&quot;&gt;The company was looking for a lead programmer. “I was actually the only experienced game developer in the house,” says Oster, who would eventually join the &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; team as the head of the 3D art department after finishing &lt;em&gt;Shattered Steel&lt;/em&gt;. “And I mean, I had made one game. … It’s not like I knew the right way to do anything.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;BUthun&quot;&gt;Greig hadn’t made games except for his own enjoyment in high school, but he had programming chops, so BioWare brought him on. By the time he started in January ’96, the company had rented a small office space above a restaurant. BioWare was no longer subterranean, although it wasn’t exactly upscale. “I particularly remember having to hold the bathroom door closed with your foot when you were going in, because it didn’t actually latch,” Greig says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;i3S7bQ&quot;&gt;Although &lt;em&gt;Shattered Steel&lt;/em&gt; wasn’t out yet, BioWare wanted to create a showcase that would entice a publisher to invest in its RPG project, &lt;em&gt;Battleground: Infinity&lt;/em&gt;, which the company envisioned as an online game that would be based on ancient mythologies. Greig spent his first month cobbling together a tech demo. At that time, most game worlds were &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tile-based_video_game&quot;&gt;tile-based&lt;/a&gt; because of contemporary computers’ memory limitations. “If you look back to the &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; games, or pretty much any other role-playing game at this point,” Greig says, “the artists would make [tiles], ‘OK, here’s the corner of a room, here’s a part of a wall,’ and these were all laid out on a regular grid. And they would assemble the background by just reusing all these pieces.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5lxtPD&quot;&gt;BioWare’s inexperienced artists weren’t well-versed in the tile technique, so Greig experimented with Microsoft’s newly released &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DirectX&quot;&gt;DirectX&lt;/a&gt; software development kit and came up with a way to import a custom, full-screen, scrollable background that he’d painted in Photoshop. He called over Muzyka, with whom he’d been discussing training the artists in the tile-based method, and showed him his alternative method. Instead of piecing together tiles, Greig told Muzyka, “‘We [could] just paint whatever we want on here, and then we could just smoothly scroll around and have the characters walk on it.’ He looks at me and goes, ‘How many CDs will that be?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;cMV4ht&quot;&gt;Greig pulled out a calculator and did some math to estimate the storage requirements. “[I] said, ‘Oh, it probably won’t be more than four or five,’” he recalls. “And [Ray] goes, ‘All right. Hey, let’s do it.’ And that 10-minute conversation was basically the genesis of what ended up being &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; on the technical side.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;pQ70Yl&quot;&gt;A combination of new technology and a lack of skill and know-how had prompted BioWare to wander in a different direction, breaking a constraint that had hemmed in earlier games. It wouldn’t be the last time. “We were open to ideas that other people hadn’t actually tackled,” Greig says. “And it goes to show some of the power of actually having fresh ideas and inexperience in there, because we didn’t know that it couldn’t be done. So we just went ahead and did it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;wAsdpe&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nkJao67Drr4?rel=0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;BY9jdv&quot;&gt;The hacked-together demo didn’t turn many heads, but it did pique the interest of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feargus_Urquhart&quot;&gt;Feargus Urquhart&lt;/a&gt;, who had just formed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Isle_Studios&quot;&gt;Black Isle Studios&lt;/a&gt;, an internal RPG development team at Interplay Productions, BioWare’s publisher for &lt;em&gt;Shattered Steel&lt;/em&gt;. Interplay, which had developed &lt;em&gt;Wasteland&lt;/em&gt; and was one of the few Western studios to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stonekeep&quot;&gt;publish an RPG&lt;/a&gt; in 1995, had recently licensed the Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons IP from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TSR_(company)&quot;&gt;TSR, Inc.&lt;/a&gt; When Urquhart heard about BioWare’s pitch for &lt;em&gt;Battleground: Infinity&lt;/em&gt;, he realized that the studio’s RPG roots and Interplay’s lore were a match made in &lt;a href=&quot;https://forgottenrealms.fandom.com/wiki/Mount_Celestia&quot;&gt;Mount Celestia&lt;/a&gt;. “Part of [the demo’s] description was, ‘Oh, it’s kind of like D&amp;amp;D,’” says &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt;’s head writer, Lukas Kristjanson. “And Interplay had just acquired the rights and said, ‘Well, why don’t you &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; it D&amp;amp;D?’ And a whole bunch of geeks went, ‘Whaaaat?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;n9oxmz&quot;&gt;Out went ancient mythologies. In came the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Forgotten_Realms&quot;&gt;Forgotten Realms&lt;/a&gt;, a popular Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons fantasy setting. &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; was now a D&amp;amp;D game. BioWare just had to build it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/en5Q-xFtJHMWnSdVpraTw8SAi6k=/0x0:1432x805/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0ZqDv0fAtYNAJPHdNCd5fBbAHyc=/0x0:1432x805/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gn7SolO_s90X0ae46VgDvvNe-3Q=/0x0:1432x805/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iFDir7W--FFDDemTlwBZw_PUJPI=/0x0:1432x805/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SpQ379put3L32sgBL8UvxlmH5I4=/0x0:1432x805/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KHyq638DbjkH842YgHnf6G3I3LE=/0x0:1432x805/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bwbwIeZldl827B2Z1cEU1LhDKpg=/0x0:1432x805/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6Z2hZeMYmCWJXt8P3V-KQa5gtEk=/0x0:1432x805/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e_oV32lX6JAmSZa5PVAfBKXSpI8=/0x0:1432x805/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-upload-width=&quot;1432&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hAxBWZVil7QYCTc9xQnz7va6eCg=/0x0:1432x805/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:1432x805):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641730/image1.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;The BioWare team in the summer of 1997. &lt;cite&gt;Trent Oster&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-dropcap has-dropcap&quot; id=&quot;Nd8tH6&quot;&gt;“We were in unknown territory,” Greig says. The tech demo he’d designed was just the seed of what would grow into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.giantbomb.com/infinity-engine/3015-495/&quot;&gt;Infinity Engine&lt;/a&gt;, a platform featuring an isometric perspective and prerendered backgrounds that formed the backbone of &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; and its expansion and sequel, as well as Interplay’s &lt;em&gt;Planescape: Torment&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Icewind_Dale_(series)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Icewind Dale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “There was so much infrastructure that had to be built for the game engine, because everything had to be done from scratch,” Greig says, adding, “The movie equivalent is we had to build the camera before we could film our film.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;el9Fgn&quot;&gt;BioWare planned for &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; to be a blend of old and new. “It was kind of this examination of the old &lt;em&gt;Gold Box&lt;/em&gt; games in terms of their depth and their adherence to the [D&amp;amp;D] rules,” Oster says, referring to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gold_Box&quot;&gt;a series&lt;/a&gt; of D&amp;amp;D RPGs produced by Strategic Simulations, Inc. in the late ’80s and early ’90s. “But then bringing that forward into an almost real-time-strategy-style interface.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right c-float-hang&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;DYFmUO&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There was so much infrastructure that had to be built for the game engine, because everything had to be done from scratch. The movie equivalent is we had to build the camera before we could film our film.” —Scott Greig&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;H4nSb4&quot;&gt;Earlier RPGs, including the &lt;em&gt;Ultima&lt;/em&gt; games, had been difficult to control, making it complicated for players to select multiple members of their parties and tell them what to do. But Blizzard Entertainment had released &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warcraft:_Orcs_%26_Humans&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warcraft_II:_Tides_of_Darkness&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;II&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 1994 and 1995, respectively, and those two titles, along with Westwood Studios’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Command_%26_Conquer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Command &amp;amp; Conquer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; series, headlined a mid-’90s RTS boom based on mouse-first management rather than keyboard commands. BioWare borrowed that mouse-aided design, transplanting a new interface into an old genre where it was sorely needed. “Basically, you swipe the interface from a real-time-strategy game and plug it into a role-playing game,” Greig says. “That solved the party mechanics.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;bki6lC&quot;&gt;It &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; address a second problem: Mixing real-time management of up to five party members with the complexity of the D&amp;amp;D rule set made the action chaotic. “It became pretty obvious pretty quick that there was no way you were gonna be able to play the depths of D&amp;amp;D in real time without ever pausing the game,” Oster says. “That’s when we came up with the ‘pause and play’ plan.” That addition enabled players to stop in the middle of the game, queue up commands to their party, and then restart the real-time action. Although &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turns,_rounds_and_time-keeping_systems_in_games#Pausable_real-time&quot;&gt;didn’t invent&lt;/a&gt; this “active pause” approach, it did help popularize it. “When you play &lt;em&gt;Fallout&lt;/em&gt; to this day with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fallout.wikia.com/wiki/Vault-Tec_Assisted_Targeting_System&quot;&gt;V.A.T.S.&lt;/a&gt; system for the slow-motion targeting, I think you can trace the origins of all that back to the ‘pause and play’ idea,” Greig says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wtMgtE&quot;&gt;Those mechanics made &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; a technical improvement upon previous RPGs, but BioWare had to fill in that framework with story and character. Lead designer James Ohlen drew on his tabletop history to create some of &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt;’s computer companions, but the bulk of the writing fell to Kristjanson, another novice in the industry who became BioWare’s first full-time narrative crafter when he was hired in October ’96 after a chance encounter with a BioWare producer who was a friend of a friend. “I had an English degree and not much idea where to put it to use,” Kristjanson says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;TYEZqZ&quot;&gt;He soon put it to use more than he’d bargained for, producing an estimated 70 percent of the game’s 800,000 words, including dialogue, codex entries, and journals. “It was a beast,” Kristjanson says. Ohlen’s character concepts gave him somewhere to start, but they weren’t fully fleshed out. For example, Kristjanson recalls that in the case of &lt;a href=&quot;http://baldursgate.wikia.com/wiki/Minsc&quot;&gt;Minsc&lt;/a&gt;, a fan-favorite human ranger whom the player can recruit as a companion, “It was, ‘This guy has a head wound and a hamster.’ OK, what do we do with that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8T4Flq&quot;&gt;For BioWare’s band of longtime tabletop players, the enormity of the creative workload was leavened by the thrill of constructing a world in which thousands of other people would play. Kristjanson remembers talking to &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; programmer Mark Darrah—who now serves as the executive producer of BioWare’s &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt; series and its upcoming online action-RPG &lt;em&gt;Anthem&lt;/em&gt;—about the challenges the tight-knit team was confronting. “We were like, ‘How’s this gonna work?’” Kristjanson says. “And then, ‘Well, on tabletop it’s like this, on D&amp;amp;D it’s like this, and the last game I played it’s like this.’ We kind of looked at each other and went, ‘Holy shit. We get to figure this out?’ It’s crazy. We’re fans of this stuff, and we’re getting to build it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;s86guE&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bYoRmGHIxA4?rel=0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;hv2FcR&quot;&gt;For Kristjanson, the key to making the story sing was capturing the feeling of sitting around a kitchen table with a group of friends and bringing it to a computer game that was playable solo. “It’s all in character,” he says. “That was what we really realized early on. The fun of D&amp;amp;D is the controlled chaos of the party, the different personalities. Not just a pile of skills you throw at monsters, but the personalities that clash or flow with the story based on what you choose to do and who you choose to do it with.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8nE7dy&quot;&gt;The quality of &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt;’s dialogue, and the distinct identities of its 24 companions and hundreds of minor characters, set it apart from many of the trope-ridden titles that preceded it, whose appeal flowed much more from combat than from conversation. The game’s cast of non-player companions—many of whom, in a relative rarity for the era, were convincingly voiced—was a diverse group. Three of the five core party members were women (&lt;a href=&quot;http://baldursgate.wikia.com/wiki/Dynaheir&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; of whom was voiced by the prolific &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jennifer_Hale&quot;&gt;Jennifer Hale&lt;/a&gt;), and some story lines touch on sensitive subjects; when the protagonist encounters &lt;a href=&quot;http://baldursgate.wikia.com/wiki/Viconia_DeVir&quot;&gt;Viconia DeVir&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, she’s being persecuted because she’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://baldursgate.wikia.com/wiki/Drow&quot;&gt;drow&lt;/a&gt;, or dark-skinned elf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;NWFoQZ&quot;&gt;Although the fledgling BioWare wasn’t particularly diverse, Kristjanson—whose background lay in tabletop D&amp;amp;D, not the previous computer adaptations—sought to make the companions mirror his real-life companions, who had always been contrasting both in personality (including “the friend across the table who’s slightly gooned on Mountain Dew”) and in terms of race and gender. “You have this broad mix of everybody bringing their particular flavor of weird and great to the table, and that requires a huge spread of characters,” he says, adding, “They weren’t all just dudes like me. … That’s what I wanted to see in the game, because that’s part of what made it great.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p-dropcap has-dropcap&quot; id=&quot;0EpmgG&quot;&gt;Oster credits Greig’s database background for &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt;’s massive size. “Most of the other game developers looked first and foremost at it from a gaming/game-experience side, not ‘How do I represent data and access data in an effective manner,’” he says. “So we were just able to huck around huge volumes of assets.” As Greig had foretold, &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; filled five discs. According to user-submitted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/2016/8/25/16038806/video-game-length-playtimes-f7b8e38f949f&quot;&gt;playthrough lengths&lt;/a&gt; at the website &lt;a href=&quot;https://howlongtobeat.com/game.php?id=808&quot;&gt;How Long to Beat&lt;/a&gt;, a typical playthrough of the main story lasts 44.5 hours, while a “completionist” playthrough averages 106 hours. As in &lt;em&gt;Wasteland&lt;/em&gt;, Muzyka’s RPG touchstone, many scenarios could play out in more than one way, offering extra replay value. Compared with the typical game of the era, Oster says, “It’s just ridiculous when you analyze the scale of it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-left c-float-hang&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jfpuJGlGh7S5PKsJQCNH4qX-rF0=/0x0:800x813/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V5gYcdvn3sJS_Z3d069rRYaFpjI=/0x0:800x813/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3eW4NluLbRNifdnYhiVspQ63w-s=/0x0:800x813/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hXVkG38wKb69BTkuU8SRudauY9k=/0x0:800x813/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LkmW5XBT_3QlpX0aTW-2nzcVILk=/0x0:800x813/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8060Tb3-UC9Ley91N8GZ5qrdzgc=/0x0:800x813/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JcMO6JFhI9ternMu9_00t_s79fU=/0x0:800x813/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YwqMtOYFz6USlHeAVvuGERK8D0o=/0x0:800x813/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2wRm4aivt1Kt9RBe0QjxTLK68hA=/0x0:800x813/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-upload-width=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nXF5l3q_zEw_JRIaNxJkzWXs6FY=/0x0:800x813/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:800x813):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641727/Disc5.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;FZlvbC&quot;&gt;Because &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; was so big and the BioWare team, while sizable for the era, was small by modern standards, development was highly collaborative. “It wasn’t like, ‘OK, this was my job,’ and you just stuck to it,” Greig says. “You basically did whatever needed to get done, and there was lots of input from everybody around. … Even the junior quality-assurance tester guy had probably more influence on &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; than a senior producer does on some of the Triple-A game titles that are out right now.” Even though Greig was the lead programmer and wasn’t directly responsible for the story, he still read all of the Forgotten Realms sourcebooks to immerse himself in the setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;kXUghk&quot;&gt;That all-hands-on-deck ethos was partly attributable to the team’s enthusiasm for what they were making, and partly a reflection of the fact they were too new to the industry to be burned out. But it was also a by-product of BioWare biting off more than it could comfortably chew. “The general attitude was, ‘We’d like to do this, how hard could it be?’” Greig says. “But it turns out it’s really freaking hard to make video games.” So hard, in fact, that a more experienced staff likely would have set its sights a little lower. “I think the biggest asset of our inexperience was the fact we didn’t know how hard the work was gonna be and how much there was going to be,” Oster says. “We underestimated everything so profoundly that it sounded reasonable, when in that time and place it was actually quite an unreasonable thing to attempt to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;Au1OU9&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We underestimated everything so profoundly that it sounded reasonable, when in that time and place it was actually quite an unreasonable thing to attempt to do.” —Trent Oster&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3J00ED&quot;&gt;That breadth of content came at a cost to the developers, who spent roughly the last year of production in crunch mode and the last six months or so working seven days a week, 10-12 hours a day, and sometimes sleeping at their desks. “We’d work, we’d eat pizza, we’d work some more, and I swear after &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; came out, I wasn’t able to eat a slice of pizza for a year and a half,” Greig says. Although Oster notes that he and the rest of the team took it upon themselves to work those hours, out of belief in &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; and a sense of solidarity with their colleagues, that kind of crunch—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/2018/3/30/17179036/1998-video-games-starcraft-turns-20&quot;&gt;not uncommon&lt;/a&gt; among 1998’s standout titles—can be counterproductive and harmful and, despite the many other ways in which game-making has moved forward, remains a blight on the backstories of many &lt;a href=&quot;https://kotaku.com/inside-rockstar-games-culture-of-crunch-1829936466&quot;&gt;great titles&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;owD7Mo&quot;&gt;After logging all of those hours (and enduring multiple three-month delays), BioWare believed it might have a hit on its hands. For Interplay, though, &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; didn’t project to be a massive seller. The publisher’s previous D&amp;amp;D titles hadn’t been blockbusters, and neither &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; nor BioWare had a built-in brand, so Interplay wasn’t planning a full-court press. “They were doing their standard marketing thing, which at that point was, you take out a bunch of ads a couple months before the game comes out in some various magazines like &lt;em&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/em&gt; … and, that’s pretty much it,” Greig says. “We had been putting our heart and soul into this thing, and it’s like, ‘Oh, you’ve got to do something better than that.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;SUCHOX&quot;&gt;More out of unbridled enthusiasm than any coordinated marketing strategy, BioWare members began to talk up the game themselves, providing updates and answering questions on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usenet&quot;&gt;Usenet&lt;/a&gt; and message boards devoted to D&amp;amp;D. By the time the game came out, BioWare’s infectious, patient, and transparent posts had built up anticipation in the target market. Greig remembers one of the major trade magazines projecting &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; for 100,000 copies sold. Even internally, BioWare hoped for only 200,000, which would be enough to justify a sequel. Then the game came out. “It started to sell fairly well, and then it sold even better, and [then] the sales just took off,” Oster says. “And it was mostly from organic-style marketing—word of mouth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;zTntIf&quot;&gt;A press release on ship day &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20110727205647/http:/rpgvaultarchive.ign.com/archive/19981220.shtml&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; “a near frenzy” at “several mall-based stores” and quoted multiple sources testifying to frantic presale activity. &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; became the best-selling game in the two weeks following its release, moving &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/19990909093649/http:/interplay.com/press/bgno1.html&quot;&gt;175,000&lt;/a&gt; copies in that time and vindicating BioWare’s pre-release outreach. It topped &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20010224020250/http:/headline.gamespot.com/news/99_02/24_pc_interplay/index.html&quot;&gt;500,000&lt;/a&gt; by the end of February and hit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20120510051328/https:/www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/131493/baldurs_gate_ii_the_anatomy_of_a_.php&quot;&gt;1.5 million&lt;/a&gt; mark by May 2001. “This is a 100 percent standard procedure now for any game,” Greig says. “A key part of the marketing is engaging with the core audience and doing developer diaries, and they’ve got teams of people whose job is just to do this.” Inadvertently, BioWare had helped guide developers in how to sell games as well as how to make them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;jPw9jn&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; garnered Game of the Year and RPG of the Year honors from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baldur%27s_Gate#Critical_reviews&quot;&gt;multitude&lt;/a&gt; of outlets, and its 2000 sequel—which benefited from a more polished Infinity Engine that didn’t have to be built from scratch—was even &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baldur%27s_Gate_II:_Shadows_of_Amn#Critical_reviews&quot;&gt;more highly acclaimed&lt;/a&gt;. “&lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate II&lt;/em&gt; was about us actually, finally knowing how to make a game,” Oster says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;u8BKTf&quot;&gt;The team behind &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; went on to make many more. “When I got the job, a friend of my now-wife said, ‘Ha, gaming company. Well, that won’t last six months,’” Kristjanson says. “Because game companies were flaming out left and right.” Twenty-two years later, he’s still at BioWare, where some of his younger colleagues, like &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt; writer Sheryl Chee, cite &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; as influences. “Every now and then she brings it up that she played &lt;em&gt;BG I&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;BG II&lt;/em&gt; six times as a kid, and that was escape,” Kristjanson says. “I’m like, ‘This is weird.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;pKQbMx&quot;&gt;Although many of BioWare’s other early pioneers, including Greig and all of the cofounders, have since &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BioWare#2010s:_Muzyka_and_Zeschuk's_departure,_Mass_Effect_on_hiatus,_Anthem&quot;&gt;moved on&lt;/a&gt;, the company’s output over the past 20 years owes a debt to that first, formative RPG. “&lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; literally set up every game that BioWare ever made,” Oster says. “So, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Jade Empire&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dragon Age&lt;/em&gt;—they’re all kind of from that original DNA. If you pull back from all the flashy bits and all the high-end graphics and all the cinematic conversation, there’s a lot of similarities there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;d3DbZG&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S84cnghuGso?rel=0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;F6HYLF&quot;&gt;Oster still hasn’t quite quit the original. In 2009, he and another &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; alum, Cameron Tofer, founded a new studio, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beamdog.com/&quot;&gt;Beamdog&lt;/a&gt;, which now occupies the same office floor that BioWare did during the &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; days. In 2012, Beamdog developed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baldur%27s_Gate:_Enhanced_Edition&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate: Enhanced Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a remake published by Atari (which now owns the &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; license) that incorporated enhancements and additions and extended support to mobile platforms but started with the same code to preserve the familiar feel. “We approached it more as curators than reimagining it,” he says. “We didn’t want to rethink what &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; was. We wanted to make the best version of &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; that we could.” The &lt;em&gt;Enhanced Edition&lt;/em&gt; continues to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.beamdog.com/2018/08/updates-to-baldurs-gate-enhanced.html&quot;&gt;patched&lt;/a&gt;. “I still see areas where I think we can make things better,” Oster says. In 2016, his company produced an original expansion, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baldur%27s_Gate:_Siege_of_Dragonspear&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Siege of Dragonspear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which was set between the events of &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate I&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;II&lt;/em&gt; and represented the first original &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; game in more than 15 years, not counting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baldur%27s_Gate:_Dark_Alliance&quot;&gt;console spinoffs&lt;/a&gt;. Rumors are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcgamer.com/baldurs-gate-3-is-in-the-works-apparently/&quot;&gt;swirling&lt;/a&gt; about a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baldur%27s_Gate_(series)#Unfinished_games&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, although Oster says it’s not being made by Beamdog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;YOkVxG&quot;&gt;In a sense, an actual sequel seems extraneous, because so many spiritual sequels keep carrying the torch, from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pillars_of_Eternity&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pillars of Eternity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; series to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Divinity:_Original_Sin&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Divinity: Original Sin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; series to 2017’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Torment:_Tides_of_Numenera&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Torment: Tides of Numenera&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to 2018’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pathfinder:_Kingmaker&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pathfinder: Kingmaker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. All of those games were crowdfunded through Kickstarter, which has seen a sort of isometric boom as developers capitalize on players’ continued affection for the form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;8QYzht&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dG-4Gp3XNiw?rel=0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Ja1op9&quot;&gt;“The ones that have been successful haven’t tried to remake what we did, because when we made it we weren’t trying to make &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt;,” Kristjanson says, adding, “You can reduce that too much to, ‘Oh, this should be authentic D&amp;amp;D with the numbers.’ Well, even D&amp;amp;D isn’t authentic D&amp;amp;D. It’s every group has their house rule, and that house rule is because of the way that your particular collection of awesome weirdos wants to play it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;c-end-para&quot; id=&quot;xB4cck&quot;&gt;While writing for &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt;, Kristjanson learned that world-building is about asking questions more than it is about answering them. “For every time you answer a question, you should pose a couple more, because otherwise the world is just getting smaller instead of broadening out,” he says. Twenty years later, the world &lt;em&gt;Baldur’s Gate&lt;/em&gt; built is still expanding. “If you’re lucky, you get to take some of all this stuff that inspired you, all the stuff you thought was great, and you build something that’s worthy for someone else to build on whenever they come after you,” Greig says. “That is basically the best you can do as any type of artist.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 13:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bpierre</dc:creator>
<og:description>The genre-stretching game broke new narrative, technical, and gameplay ground and established the identity of one of the past two decades’ most storied video game studios</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5pWi7lrIoTx8MGd5BjamJG5KBdE=/0x215:3000x1786/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13641939/98Games_BaldursGate_NoBug_InterplayEntertainment_Getty_Ringer.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>How BioWare’s ‘Baldur’s Gate’ Saved the Computer RPG</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theringer.com/2018/12/21/18150363/baldurs-gate-bioware-1998-video-games</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theringer.com/2018/12/21/18150363/baldurs-gate-bioware-1998-video-games</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FCC fines Swarm $900K for unauthorized satellite launch</title>
<link>https://reuters.com/article/amp/idUSKCN1OJ2WT</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://reuters.com/article/amp/idUSKCN1OJ2WT</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON (Reuters) - Swarm Technologies Inc will pay a $900,000 fine for launching and operating four small experimental communications satellites that risked “satellite collisions” and threatened “critical commercial and government satellite operations,” the Federal Communications Commission said on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;PrimaryAsset_container&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s1.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20181220&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1337404661&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEEBJ1ZA&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) logo is seen before the FCC Net Neutrality hearing in Washington February 26, 2015. REUTERS/Yuri Gripas&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) logo is seen before the FCC Net Neutrality hearing in Washington February 26, 2015. REUTERS/Yuri Gripas&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The California-based start-up founded by former Google and Apple engineers in 2016 also agreed to enhanced FCC oversight and a requirement of pre-launch notices to the FCC for three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swarm launched the satellites in India last January after the FCC rejected its application to deploy and operate them, citing concerns about the company’s tracking ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It said Swarm had unlawfully transmitted signals between earth stations in the state of Georgia and the satellites for over a week. The investigation also found that Swarm performed unauthorized weather balloon-to-ground station tests and other unauthorized equipment tests prior to the satellites’ launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swarm aims to provide low-cost space-based internet service and plans eventually to use a constellation of 100 satellites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swarm won permission in August from the FCC to reactivate the satellites and said then it is “fully committed to complying with all regulations and has been working closely with the FCC,” noting that its satellites are “100 percent trackable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swarm co-founder and Chief Executive Officer Sara Spangelo said in a statement on Thursday that the company accepts the FCC decision “and appreciates the FCC’s ongoing support for Swarm’s mission.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, SpaceX launched three more satellites for Swarm on a Falcon 9 rocket after winning FCC approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FCC Commissioner Mike O’Rielly said the size of the penalty “is probably not significant enough to deter future behavior, but the negative press coverage is likely to prevent this company and others from attempting to do this again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Rielly said an initial fine negotiated by FCC staff was rejected by some commissioners, which led to reopening settlement talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting by David Shepardson; Editing by Dan Grebler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 13:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>daegloe</dc:creator>
<og:title>FCC fines Swarm $900,000 for unauthorized satellite launch</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-satellite-fine-idUSKCN1OJ2WT</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Swarm Technologies Inc will pay a $900,000 fine for launching and operating four...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s1.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20181220&amp;t=2&amp;i=1337404661&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEEBJ1ZA</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-satellite-fine/fcc-fines-swarm-900000-for-unauthorized-satellite-launch-idUSKCN1OJ2WT</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>