<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Facebook has removed all cross-posted tweets</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/28/facebook-has-removed-all-cross-posted-tweets/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/28/facebook-has-removed-all-cross-posted-tweets/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Update: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/how-cross-posted-tweets-disappeared-from-facebook-e65fd350-1898-4bc5-af0f-81e9614f5ec1.html&quot;&gt;Axios has a post&lt;/a&gt; explaining why the cross-posted tweets disappeared. Essentially, Twitter deleted its app from Facebook after Facebook stopped allowing cross-posts earlier this month, since without that feature it was basically useless. This unexpectedly caused old posts to disappear. TechCrunch also heard from a source with understanding of the situation that the deletion of the app took Facebook by surprise, as well as the fact that Twitter didn’t immediately tell them to restore the content.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook users are complaining the company has removed the cross-posted tweets they had published to their profiles as Facebook updates. The posts’ removal took place following the recent API change that &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/01/psa-cross-posting-tweets-to-facebook-no-longer-works-as-of-today/&quot;&gt;prevented&lt;/a&gt; Twitter users from continuing to automatically publish their tweets to Facebook. According to the affected parties, both the Facebook posts themselves, as well as the conversation around those posts that had taken place directly on Facebook, are now gone. Reached for comment, Facebook says it’s aware of the issue and is looking into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TechCrunch was alerted to the problem by a reader, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LawrenceMiller&quot;&gt;Lawrence Miller&lt;/a&gt;, who couldn’t find any information about the issue in Facebook’s Help Center. We’ve since confirmed the issue ourselves with several affected parties and confirmed it with Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the real-time nature of social media — and how difficult it is to pull up old posts — it’s possible that many of the impacted Facebook users have yet to realize their old posts have been removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, we only found a handful of public complaints about the deletions, so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;8.2473867595819&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;10.080139372822&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/facebook?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@facebook&lt;/a&gt; I used the Twitter for Facebook app for years, and I realize it's not working and isn't going to. But I just discovered all the Facebook updates it put have been deleted and dissappeared from my timeline! Is there a way to retrieve this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Omer Lev (@omerlev) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/omerlev/status/1033704078621257733?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.28125&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;8.8993055555556&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;A recent update to the Facebook Platform Policies ended the ability to automatically post Tweets to our Facebook profile or page and all of our previous Twitter posts were deleted by Facebook. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dfwwx?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#dfwwx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/txwx?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#txwx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/plano?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#plano&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/sAOsbdBjVO&quot;&gt;https://t.co/sAOsbdBjVO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Plano, Texas Weather (@PlanoWX) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PlanoWX/status/1032988001436094464?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 24, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;6.1309523809524&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;6.5396825396825&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;My post on Facebook via Twitter was deleted.&lt;br/&gt;Why?&lt;br/&gt;Can someone explain it? &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/twitter?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Tarin (@lestarindah499) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lestarindah499/status/1033750252598132736?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above: selected complaints from Twitter about the data loss&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1700396 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/Screen-Shot-2018-08-28-at-3.48.50-PM.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;485&quot; height=&quot;276&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above: a comment on TechCrunch following our post on the API changes &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of those who were impacted were very light Facebook users and had heavily relied on the cross-posting to keep their Facebook accounts active. As a result of the mass removals, their Facebook profiles are now fairly empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TechCrunch editor Matthew Panzarino is one of those here who was impacted. He points out that the ability to share tweets to Facebook was a useful way to reach people who weren’t on Twitter in order to continue a discussion with a different audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve had tweet cross-posting turned on for years, from the early days of it even existing. This just removed thousands of posts from my Facebook silently, with no warning,” Matthew told me. “Even though the posts didn’t originate on Facebook, I often had ongoing conversations about the posts once my Facebook friends (and audience) saw them. Many of them would never see them on Twitter either because they don’t follow me or they don’t use it,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s wild to have all of that context just vanish,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may recall, Facebook earlier this month &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/01/psa-cross-posting-tweets-to-facebook-no-longer-works-as-of-today/&quot;&gt;made a change to its API platform&lt;/a&gt; to prevent third-party apps from publishing posts to Facebook as the logged-in user. The change was a part of Facebook’s larger overhaul and lockdown of its API platform in the wake of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/cambridge-analytica/&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica scandal,&lt;/a&gt; where as many &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/04/technology/mark-zuckerberg-testify-congress.html&quot;&gt;as 87 million Facebook users&lt;/a&gt; had their data improperly harvested and shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, Facebook has been trying to plug up the holes in its platform to prevent further data misuse. One of the changes it made was to stop third-parties from being able to post to Facebook as the logged-in user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For existing apps, like Twitter, that permission was revoked on August 1, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-1700461&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/twitter-apps-screen.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;366&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above: Twitter’s cross-posting feature, on the day it was disabled by the Facebook API change&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the API changes, Twitter users were able to visit the “Apps” section from Twitter on the web, then authenticate with Facebook to have their tweets cross-posted to Facebook’s social network. Once enabled, the tweets would appear on the user’s page as a Facebook post they had published, and their friends could then like and comment on the post as any other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, the API changes should only have prevented Twitter users from continuing to cross-post their tweets to Facebook automatically. It &lt;em&gt;shouldn’t&lt;/em&gt; have also deleted the existing posts from Facebook users’ profiles and business users’ Facebook Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a breach of trust from a company that’s in the process of trying to repair a broken trust with its users across a number of fronts, including data misuse. Regardless of whatever new policy is in effect around apps and how they can post to Facebook, no one would have ever expected that Facebook would actually remove their old posts without warning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping that the problem is a bug that Facebook can resolve, and not something that will result in permanent data loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook tells us while it doesn’t have further information about the problem at this time, it should have more to share tonight or tomorrow about what’s being done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 01:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:title>Twitter’s deletion of its Facebook app caused old cross-posts to temporarily disappear</og:title>
<og:description>(Update: Axios has a post explaining why the cross-posted tweets disappeared. Essentially, Twitter deleted its app from Facebook after Facebook stopped allowing cross-posts earlier this month, since without that feature it was basically useless. This unexpectedly caused old posts to disappear. Tech…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/twitter-facebook-icons.png?w=711</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/08/28/facebook-has-removed-all-cross-posted-tweets/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/28/facebook-has-removed-all-cross-posted-tweets/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Some Facebook Employees Unite to Challenge Its ‘Intolerant’ Liberal Culture</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/28/technology/inside-facebook-employees-political-bias.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/28/technology/inside-facebook-employees-political-bias.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;45.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO — The post went up quietly on Facebook’s internal message board last week. Titled “We Have a Problem With Political Diversity,” it quickly took off inside the social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We are a political monoculture that’s intolerant of different views,” Brian Amerige, a senior Facebook engineer, wrote in the post, which was obtained by The New York Times. “We claim to welcome all perspectives, but are quick to attack — often in mobs — anyone who presents a view that appears to be in opposition to left-leaning ideology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Since the post went up, more than 100 Facebook employees have joined Mr. Amerige to form an online group called FB’ers for Political Diversity, according to two people who viewed the group’s page and who were not authorized to speak publicly. The aim of the initiative, according to Mr. Amerige’s memo, is to create a space for ideological diversity within the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The new group has upset other Facebook employees, who said its online posts were offensive to minorities. One engineer, who declined to be identified for fear of retaliation, said several people had lodged complaints with their managers about FB’ers for Political Diversity and were told that it had not broken any company rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;49.11294619073&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;45.775173148641&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Another employee said the group appeared to be constructive and inclusive of different political viewpoints. Mr. Amerige did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The activity is a rare sign of organized dissent within Facebook over the company’s largely liberal workplace culture. While the new group is just a sliver of Facebook’s work force of more than 25,000, the company’s workers have in the past appeared less inclined than their peers at other tech companies to challenge leadership, and most have been loyalists to its chief executive, Mark Zuckerberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;But over the past two years, Facebook has undergone a series of crises, including the &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/17/technology/indictment-russian-tech-facebook.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;spread of misinformation by Russians&lt;/a&gt; on its platform and the mishandling of users’ data. Facebook has also been accused of stifling conservative speech by President Trump and Senator Ted Cruz, Republican of Texas, among others. This month, the social network &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/06/technology/infowars-alex-jones-apple-facebook-spotify.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;barred the far-right conspiracy theorist Alex Jones&lt;/a&gt;, a move that critics seized on as further evidence that the company harbors an anti-conservative bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Within Facebook, several employees said, people have argued over the decisions to ban certain accounts while allowing others. At staff meetings, they said, some workers have repeatedly asked for more guidance on what content the company disallows, and why. Others have said Facebook, out of fear of being seen as biased, has let too many right-wing groups flourish on the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The dispute over employees’ political ideology arose a week before Sheryl Sandberg, Facebook’s chief operating officer, is scheduled to testify at a Senate hearing about social media manipulation in elections. A team helping Ms. Sandberg get ready for the hearing next Wednesday has warned her that some Republican lawmakers may raise questions about Facebook and biases, according to two people involved in the preparations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;34.34388185654&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;16.936708860759&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;On Tuesday, Mr. Trump again &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/28/business/media/google-trump-news-results.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=In%20Other%20News&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;module=Latest&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;brought up the issue of bias&lt;/a&gt; by tech companies with tweets attacking Google. In remarks later in the day, he widened his focus to include Twitter and Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Those companies “better be careful because you can’t do that to people,” Mr. Trump said. “I think that Google, and Twitter and Facebook, they are really treading on very, very troubled territory and they have to be careful. It is not fair to large portions of the population.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;42.072636433513&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;33.288239815527&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Facebook has long been viewed as a predominantly liberal company. Mr. Zuckerberg and Ms. Sandberg have donated to Democratic politicians, for example, and have supported issues such as immigration reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;The social network has sometimes struggled to integrate conservatives into its leadership. Palmer Luckey, the founder of Oculus, the maker of virtual reality goggles that Facebook acquired, was &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/06/04/business/oculus-palmer-luckey-new-start-up.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;pressured to leave the company last year&lt;/a&gt;, months after news spread that he had secretly donated to an organization dedicated to spreading anti-Hillary Clinton internet memes. And Peter Thiel, an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/10/16/technology/peter-thiel-donald-j-trump.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;outspoken supporter of Mr. Trump&lt;/a&gt;, has faced calls for his resignation from Facebook’s board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Zuckerberg publicly defended Mr. Thiel last year, saying that &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/mark-zuckerbergs-defense-of-peter-thiel-reveals-a-flawed-understanding-of-diversity-2017-3&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;he valued Mr. Thiel&lt;/a&gt; and that it was important to maintain diversity on the board. In an appearance before Congress this year, Mr. Zuckerberg responded to a question about anticonservative bias by saying he wanted Facebook to “be a platform for all ideas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;In May, Facebook announced that former Senator Jon Kyl, an Arizona Republican, would lead an &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/scoop-facebook-committing-to-internal-pobias-audit-1525187977-160aaa3a-3d10-4b28-a4bb-b81947bd03e4.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;inquiry&lt;/a&gt; into allegations of anticonservative bias on the social network. New employees also go through training that describes how to have respectful conversations about politics and diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;44.619582043344&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1h6whtw&quot; readability=&quot;35.303405572755&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Other Silicon Valley companies, including Google, have also experienced a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/08/08/technology/google-engineer-fired-gender-memo.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;wave of employee activism&lt;/a&gt; over diversity. If tech companies are willing to adjust their workplaces to make underrepresented groups more welcome, some employees argue, they should extend the same regard to those who do not fit the liberal-leaning Silicon Valley mold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Amerige, who started working at Facebook in 2012, said on his personal website that he followed philosophical principles laid out by the philosopher and writer Ayn Rand. He posted the 527-word memo about political diversity at Facebook on Aug. 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;On issues like diversity and immigration, he wrote, “you can either keep quiet or sacrifice your reputation and career.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;Mr. Amerige proposed that Facebook employees debate their political ideas in the new group — one of tens of thousands of internal groups that cover a range of topics — adding that this debate would better equip the company to host a variety of viewpoints on its platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-1i0edl6 e2kc3sl0&quot;&gt;“We are entrusted by a great part of the world to be impartial and transparent carriers of people’s stories, ideas and commentary,” Mr. Amerige wrote. “Congress doesn’t think we can do this. The president doesn’t think we can do this. And like them or not, we deserve that criticism.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-14jsv4e&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;28.38061465721&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;css-k8fkhk&quot; readability=&quot;8.1333333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Kate Conger and Sheera Frenkel on Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kateconger&quot;&gt;@kateconger&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sheeraf&quot;&gt;@sheeraf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interested in All Things Tech?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/newsletters/signup/TU&quot;&gt;Get the Bits newsletter&lt;/a&gt; delivered to your inbox weekly for the latest from Silicon Valley and the technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-3glrhn&quot; readability=&quot;8.0710659898477&quot;&gt;A version of this article appears in print on , on Page B1 of the New York edition with the headline: At Facebook, Workers Cite Intolerance By Liberals&lt;span&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytreprints.com/&quot;&gt;Order Reprints&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/pages/todayspaper/index.html&quot;&gt;Today’s Paper&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html?campaignId=48JQY&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>malachygr</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/28/technology/inside-facebook-employees-political-bias.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Dozens at Facebook Unite to Challenge Its ‘Intolerant’ Liberal Culture</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/08/29/business/29facebook1/29facebook1-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>In a rare sign of internal dissent, more than 100 employees have formed a group to agitate for better representation of conservative views.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/28/technology/inside-facebook-employees-political-bias.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How the Dutch created a casual biking culture</title>
<link>https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/8/28/17789510/bike-cycling-netherlands-dutch-infrastructure</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/8/28/17789510/bike-cycling-netherlands-dutch-infrastructure</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;rb491U&quot;&gt;In 2010, Chris and Melissa Bruntlett sold their cars and began transporting their family of four around Vancouver, BC, by bike. They noticed that bicyclists’ stories were not being told, so they started blogging about their carless lifestyle at the website of what would become their creative agency, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.modacitylife.com/&quot;&gt;Modacity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;XOJ6Lz&quot;&gt;Through cycling circles, they heard stories and saw pictures of cycling in Dutch cities, so they went to the Netherlands to check it out, visiting five cities to study cycling infrastructure, talk with local leaders, and share pictures, videos, and articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;xls5dt&quot;&gt;They ended up gathering enough material for a book, which was released Tuesday from Island Press: &lt;a href=&quot;https://islandpress.org/book/building-the-cycling-city&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Building the Cycling City: The Dutch Blueprint for Urban Vitality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a tour of Dutch bicycling culture that attempts to extract lessons that can be applied to other cities, including, yes, American cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ht7T0V&quot;&gt;I chatted with the Bruntletts by phone earlier this month about everything from how the Dutch have taken the concept of the protected bike lane and applied it to the intersection to the amazing Dutch cycling skills courses for kids. We even covered why the right wing in the Netherlands has to support more spending on cycling. Our conversation has been edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;UvVnt3&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Li14CM&quot;&gt;The American stereotype of the Netherlands is that they’ve got it all figured out; they do everything right. But your book makes it clear that everybody was not always on the same page. There were political battles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;oIlxTe&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;jULPNv&quot;&gt;One of the things we heard repeatedly when we got back was, “That would never work here, our city’s different.” We would always say, “well, every Dutch city is different!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;tt1xvT&quot;&gt;Rotterdam, for example, was completely obliterated during the Second World War and rebuilt in this post-war, modernist image — designing cities around the automobile, where people would live outside the city, commute by car into the city every day, and everyone would have more light and space and air. They’d be living happily in the suburbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;gaUzZ3&quot;&gt;It didn’t take long for Rotterdammers to realize this wasn’t the future they wanted. The spaces they were building were inhospitable to walking and cycling and public transit. Cycling rates were plummeting. There were more road fatalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;MXispe&quot;&gt;So, not just in Rotterdam, but in cities across the Netherlands in the ’70s, there was a real rejection of this car-centric urban planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;SOPqXn&quot;&gt;Some of them resisted better than others. In Rotterdam, they managed to reverse the tide and retrofit some of these spaces for other modes of transportation. But certainly a lot of Dutch cities made mistakes. In Utrecht, they paved over canals. In Amsterdam, they came just a single city council vote away from demolishing the Jewish quarter of their city to build a four-lane motorway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;FAGMq9&quot;&gt;So their status as a cycling nation wasn’t always a given. It took a lot of hard work, a certain degree of stubbornness, and forward-thinking politicians to get where they are. And even then, you know, the margins were really, really tight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rnVJThtpbiAu5cKvjlR6WhlpTl0=/0x0:4001x2660/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BnnEB095neAL8I7zwqfnT8i-3xs=/0x0:4001x2660/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rXm4OfO_-29zZz_Rlq9vBjoCtA8=/0x0:4001x2660/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DSfvaJjIJz7OkjMXOIlR2TjNycY=/0x0:4001x2660/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZNAmYDtszKllAx-YywCwZ-beCEY=/0x0:4001x2660/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WXPk5iXysLKVzCLqn9ivlu5kMsc=/0x0:4001x2660/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JgYbF1_MZD_1sp_pnFpy4ocQo_4=/0x0:4001x2660/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bEJkhhQaTJ0TCzaCJ8H2oAzxszs=/0x0:4001x2660/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Pr7ld_8E5Gznylqbqc2cP-gqvtQ=/0x0:4001x2660/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;dutch cyclists&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kK7EOZdfpPlDdtpF75cU8i3gufQ=/0x0:4001x2660/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:4001x2660)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620685/IMG_7022.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;Dutch cyclist. &lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;WqfpIt&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;gBzo5x&quot;&gt;The Dutch have this distinction between two kinds of cyclists that I thought was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;KF507b&quot;&gt;Melissa Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;YyZOQ5&quot;&gt;The Dutch have wielrenners, or “wheel runners” — the sporty cyclists — and they have a fietser, which is just “someone on a bike.” When you talk to somebody in the Netherlands about what makes biking so special, most of them will say, “What are you even talking about? It’s no different than when I get on the train or go for a walk.” You’re no more a cyclist than you are a pedestrian or a driver or a public transit user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qo4WMOXLkm5n15xZtzYA2Ly07Bc=/0x0:5131x3412/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I5Aj8YXPU_yCMEi6ytMo6OZLAcM=/0x0:5131x3412/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JCL2Jg3_y-CTqSj5Bxkagfe5EHE=/0x0:5131x3412/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sG4f3B1pTIX0zYAbCA1R-ws67Vk=/0x0:5131x3412/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xpI1WKDHg9X7qdu8t9MxA5IOsV0=/0x0:5131x3412/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HTCVakt4NLbt0il_WcfoUHf9Fko=/0x0:5131x3412/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qeXtX32N3LSRRZqkGUwdYQsW5d8=/0x0:5131x3412/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AV-POGBZEGwiiX8QWuN4zeez2Lc=/0x0:5131x3412/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8Uk5q37nZkT7UE_JbbYUNRZ4KgU=/0x0:5131x3412/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;dutch cyclists&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ase2d-bFD5c6c1MnzHbpgmvL3b8=/0x0:5131x3412/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:5131x3412)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620259/IMG_6489.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;Casual cyclists in the Netherlands. &lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;nHuxRI&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;sIMIEA&quot;&gt;In terms of bike infrastructure, I think most people in the US are primarily familiar with painted strips on the side of the road, those little “&lt;a href=&quot;https://nacto.org/publication/urban-bikeway-design-guide/bikeway-signing-marking/shared-lane-markings/&quot;&gt;sharrows&lt;/a&gt;.” What are the practical elements of infrastructure that make it safe for, say, an elderly fietser to go out biking in the Netherlands?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;Ux1PV8&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;CBiLje&quot;&gt;This is a critical point: The Dutch built environment treats people who ride bikes normally, everyday fietsers&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; with respect and dignity and gives them a wholly separate space to cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;vBWIHJ&quot;&gt;So the Dutch design manual classifies roads depending on the speed of the cars traveling in them. If there’s any major difference in speed, then full separation is required — concrete barriers, a grass median, planter boxes, or bollards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;118rOh&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;IrzIlL&quot;&gt;What is the speed threshold?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;jj83TV&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;HbynBN&quot;&gt;Anything where cars are traveling faster than 30 kph. So, what’s that, 19 mph?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;jwRU6W&quot;&gt;Mixing is permitted on streets where the cars are traveling slower than that. But the volume of cars needs to be fairly low, so that the cyclist still feels comfortable traveling on those streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;Iua9KI&quot;&gt;Melissa Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;zVI1sZ&quot;&gt;In those shared spaces, it’s usually cobblestone, or raised crosswalks, speed bumps where they’re needed. It’s very clearly delineated that cars are guests in these spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8Kol1z&quot;&gt;Cycle tracks are all paved with this easily identified red pavement, an inch-thick top coat of dyed red asphalt. It’s everywhere throughout the Netherlands — you know when you’re on a cycle track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3LFA6l&quot;&gt;They’ll do raised cycle tracks when speeds don’t go above 50 kph (30 mph), and then on highways or motorways, it will be an adjacent pathway, again with that trademark red, but completely separated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RR6BJWKiDCrFbcxTAQo5UDicr3M=/0x0:6016x4000/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vY13MLA6Bor91HjI286oOKyNwlI=/0x0:6016x4000/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VlWTghowd4ZEu6HPtXvC5CL8eh4=/0x0:6016x4000/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FPogSxLYcOYQroNseU6J-wCUFCg=/0x0:6016x4000/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gcpZ-_-uq6YGdbbJ5MhmJw70r84=/0x0:6016x4000/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yOE5PWHObWmsyNxw0vNaMBc8yGo=/0x0:6016x4000/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oA6ViJjdgNcT3dlXr7kPGwrdfeo=/0x0:6016x4000/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ujZduCYon0T7oiM8F6k2P_GR7_s=/0x0:6016x4000/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WmbZHxPJAK2Wq1BZDiD5M0OC0K0=/0x0:6016x4000/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;dutch cyclist&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8OdjNsEp0-YByOPFXmB_itu3e3c=/0x0:6016x4000/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12620849/IMG_5543.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;IOLjJu&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;54FoIO&quot;&gt;Say a little bit about intersections. I’m morbidly interested in intersections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;zGyQFI&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9uMSGf&quot;&gt;It’s one area we criminally underlook in North America. We build these protected bike lanes (if they’re protected at all) and then in an intersection you’re stuck in no man’s land. That’s where the vast majority of collisions occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Ycu5UG&quot;&gt;The Dutch have taken the concept of the protected bike lane and carried it through the intersection. More often than not, there is physical protection on the corners where there’s cars turning right or left. There’s often mid-block protection provided as well, so that you don’t feel exposed. The raised cycle track is also carried through the intersection. Through design, they’ve made the cycle track a priority — visually and physically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;lu9if7&quot;&gt;The cars know that they are to look out for bikes. They are treated almost as guests in the city, which is a complete 180 from how we function here in North America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;uUsbo2&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Idfr4X&quot;&gt;And you write that there are all-way, no-signs intersections?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;EquZI0&quot;&gt;Melissa Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;rzvXl2&quot;&gt;One of the things they started testing in the city of Groningen — which is in the north, and has some of the highest rates of cycling in the entire country — is having intersections where the cars have to wait and there’s a bicycle-only signal. You have bikes turning in six different directions, all moving at the same time, from every corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;cVZexl&quot;&gt;It sounds completely counterintuitive, but when we experienced it, it’s really just a matter of making eye contact. Everything is done through visual clues. We traveled through that intersection easily a dozen times during our trip there, with our children, and never once experienced any sort of collision. Maybe a couple of frustrated Dutch people because we were riding too slowly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B-wK_aoS0SHH9wLvtVfvT19TaQc=/0x0:6016x4000/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9sZcy4Tgv7uPakO5megNFxv0P60=/0x0:6016x4000/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wFVDf02PE4dJzub9ZuenprCHAEU=/0x0:6016x4000/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/heicT2Yt5SQeH_oyKrspV40ZEbc=/0x0:6016x4000/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GfgfYRZblq4jv4INCCxHL1FYSCo=/0x0:6016x4000/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MQjGipTMIdivmc3jhiM9UzYBwB0=/0x0:6016x4000/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SiaNbdxfdbKCA8U72H3nIF65QL8=/0x0:6016x4000/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PihXvnDNk1vZ_ChQ352d-VLhT7o=/0x0:6016x4000/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QPxypcKwSKzTa9HX8JUjD7W3cJU=/0x0:6016x4000/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;dutch cyclists&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EX2JRMQp3fxz0To6R-KeTgeHuJ0=/0x0:6016x4000/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621269/IMG_6409.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;This kind of mixed-used design, with no setback, is illegal almost everywhere in US cities. &lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;Zx2n0J&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;2jsInL&quot;&gt;I taught my kids to ride bikes, but there’s no real system set up for them to get education in it, and not that many safe places to ride. What do Dutch kids experience early on, in terms of bikes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;beWCcc&quot;&gt;Melissa Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ueLwIg&quot;&gt;The concept of cycling starts getting introduced to a lot of kids in preschool. They’ll run around on these push bikes. But the biggest education — while it’s not mandatory throughout the country, it’s done by most schools — is students around grade four or five, in the 10 and 11 age range, start taking cycling skills courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6YDkxg&quot;&gt;Between the ages of 11 and 12 they have to take a written exam to show that they understand the rules of the road. They also do a practical exam. So, every year, dozens or hundreds of Dutch students go out onto the street and travel on their routes to get to school, on a designated pathway. The Fietsersbond, which is their national cycling advocacy group, puts the kids right in real life situations, navigating their streets, knowing when to turn, how to signal, where to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5YMpW1&quot;&gt;After they complete this practical exam, they get a certificate saying, “I successfully passed the cycling skills program and can now responsibly ride through my city on my own.” It’s kinda neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-bL06vuzhJXExC1qp_9sfN6_sQc=/0x0:5900x3923/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sp_gTs2UzJcxqlR0I4WcwGMkl0A=/0x0:5900x3923/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/18lzhQMKulBRc25lTk_uIpckQaY=/0x0:5900x3923/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oQhx6FQFkxNII36Mu2JK1TaECNQ=/0x0:5900x3923/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XoJ3GugCJsDbk4LYdW-v-6cFhfA=/0x0:5900x3923/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G-NDUMA1hoQokdUKFxfxB1KaL10=/0x0:5900x3923/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wm3wokwT0V3vK1GrHzVjfHkZcBM=/0x0:5900x3923/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4myZjkH-YL3pv_y1V21BwJVSXV0=/0x0:5900x3923/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8UzNEuA5Md9aHumOX3492-ZlUWg=/0x0:5900x3923/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;wee dutch cyclists&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pZr-wjwTohB086pV-Zz75pxHaB8=/0x0:5900x3923/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:5900x3923)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621421/IMG_6937.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;Wee Dutch fietsers. &lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;IAWa1R&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;pc0tPI&quot;&gt;How do bikes fit in with public transit in the Netherlands?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;RQA8tp&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;D24HNN&quot;&gt;As Marco te Brömmelstroet, a professor at the University of Amsterdam, explained to us, the bike alone doesn’t replace the private automobile, and neither does public transit, but when you combine the two, that’s when the magic happens. Then the car becomes redundant in cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;xHyS7X&quot;&gt;It serves two goals. It increases the size of the catchment area for each station, so it’s feeding more customers into the public transit system. And it gives people a variety of options; they’re not dependent on one particular trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dgTdYP&quot;&gt;It’s creating this virtuous circle of sustainable transportation, where they have more people riding transit because the infrastructure is built to reach the stations. Cycling plays an important first-mile, last-mile role on these longer trips that may be 10, 15, 20 kilometers. That’s where you see replacement of car trips in cities: by capturing those mid-to-long trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;cOkRJe&quot;&gt;Melissa Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;inItUA&quot;&gt;And they’ve also introduced the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ns.nl/en/door-to-door/ov-fiets&quot;&gt;OV-Fiets&lt;/a&gt;, a rental bike, which is providing the last-mile solution. So 50 percent of people are coming to the station with their bike. They take their train, and on the other end, historically, they didn’t have anything to get them from the station to their next point of destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ni446p&quot;&gt;Now anyone who has their OV-chipkaart — the transit tap card they use for bus, trains, trams, and these OV-Fiets bikes — can pick up a bike from the train station, for €3.50 for every 24-hour period. They can have that bike all day, take it back to the train station, get on a train, and go back home to their other bike, all in one seamless trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rTzLBysJ-BVqql1p5V3jvscJ4No=/0x0:6016x4000/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gtCbcYNeG45_goNeekZxYKSBZ-w=/0x0:6016x4000/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MG78mnomFc8MwGQOzgWUjFPXARI=/0x0:6016x4000/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zPRLnEmQEISHTLtQmOtQnjSuYAY=/0x0:6016x4000/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Le-d0rj9s8R_n7yG9BcpajWIDJ4=/0x0:6016x4000/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u6d9GlmlbP-eGVZbcs_o-ACV-48=/0x0:6016x4000/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OqncL3LiiipiPi6DRfVuyYAsIso=/0x0:6016x4000/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k6mhhnSAUqaqTTYUaMLRPULFhhQ=/0x0:6016x4000/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/maUO65sm9vfPMKTwUgAGLObwDAQ=/0x0:6016x4000/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;dutch bike parking lots&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H_UgiuaOs7ALOVWCtdZ18Tke9RA=/0x0:6016x4000/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621605/IMG_5666.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;Very multi-modal. &lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;gsHcA7&quot;&gt;The National Rail [NV Nederlandse Spoorwege&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;] and ProRail, which are the two organizations managing this, have found in surveys that it’s actually replacing car trips, because people have an option at the other end. Unfortunately, they’ve been victims of their own success and can’t seem to keep up with the demand. They never have enough bikes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;tWrXQZ&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;t6Kdsk&quot;&gt;Did you see one of those giant automated bike garages the Dutch are famous for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;AavrKU&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;yq6Nfz&quot;&gt;One of the more spectacular products of this bike-train system is this sea of bicycles you see at any train station in the Netherlands. Step out of Amsterdam’s Grand Central — they had to build [a bike garage] over the canal because of the thousands and thousands of people that cycle to the train station every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;six3Oy&quot;&gt;Because of Utrecht’s size and location in the country, it is ground zero for this bike-train connection. They’re in the process of building something like 30,000 bike parking spots in the next 10 years. One such facility is 12,500 spaces. When it opens, either late this year or early next year, it will be the biggest bike-parking facility in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IBjTjKfA7A8OFFFTgeYzwJmerEw=/0x0:5916x3934/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mjDzg_RBLcrldrq87ma1fFJ5t58=/0x0:5916x3934/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JU532YkPjwsC64z-CF2ngebRM-A=/0x0:5916x3934/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ynElYrUdnPCzvukhOmRkul6CCTU=/0x0:5916x3934/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RyQOaIN5j-XDLYNVUgB5jQ7fc4Q=/0x0:5916x3934/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JmaoToddIlm-xw_KdAFmE203-Eg=/0x0:5916x3934/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/64u0gSyroxgs8uorZ8amK1VaVx4=/0x0:5916x3934/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qnrmu6vDNOr6I3cd76oCR4IyO84=/0x0:5916x3934/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LlkmXRNZHz76XXBhSmHqOl6Gsfg=/0x0:5916x3934/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;Dutch bike parking. &quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EAcXWobMWI-FSs6CuNE-GOW7ba8=/0x0:5916x3934/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:5916x3934)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619633/IMG_5384.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;Seas of bikes. &lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;qJVBby&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;OubnjY&quot;&gt;In the book, you stress the difference in Dutch bikes themselves. How are they different from US bikes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;XKoxgn&quot;&gt;Melissa Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;vgJKsC&quot;&gt;The first thing is, when the Dutch go into a shop to buy a bike, they’re buying a complete bicycle. Oftentimes in North America when we go into a bike shop, there’s a bike, but there’s no fenders, lights, racks, kickstand, bell, any of that kind of stuff. In the Netherlands, they don’t sell incomplete bikes because they need it to be practical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6jvM8o&quot;&gt;There, everyone, save maybe a small percentage of the population, rides these Dutch-style bikes, as they’ve come to be known (even though their origins are in England). You’re seated in an upright position, almost like you’re sitting on a stool or a chair. You’re forced to interact with people, because you can see them clearly. It just helps to breed that relaxed way of cycling. They don’t have to stress about looking up every time they have to turn. Signaling is a breeze. They’re largely single speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;qJuGCl&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;BDsUve&quot;&gt;We make a differentiation between the hunched-and-helmeted cyclist and the upright, bare-headed cyclist. Upright, everyday cycling, a form of walking-with-wheels, is far more broad, inclusive, accessible, and appealing to people of all ages and fitness levels. It isn’t just about getting from A to B as quickly as possible, it’s about enjoying the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UkbWsEKVnvcothWnkMiz7shxydc=/0x0:4037x2684/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VbyBP3gMDy4bc2vv6EE0qJ-h54o=/0x0:4037x2684/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l4QcjN85V2hFLGSFlcb8qrEII-E=/0x0:4037x2684/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mvdeecdWBBbGRwyAaLMGRUgfTT8=/0x0:4037x2684/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W8c9waoZlSEJQgqkwRQ-d7LaIiQ=/0x0:4037x2684/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A5c9w69seHufMR8IT872Aq2vdD4=/0x0:4037x2684/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tu9INPsM7DDRNArTCW-IsVPgyVc=/0x0:4037x2684/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TK8KIyaYjittaYxttauopMuEDC0=/0x0:4037x2684/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lo63upiqB2RQYEIv-hSpjsbfkSU=/0x0:4037x2684/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;dutch cyclist&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1sD9E_GILWhCYWZ3qJ7Sc4C8VwI=/0x0:4037x2684/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:4037x2684)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12621831/IMG_5896.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;An upright, unhelmeted Dutch rider. &lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;d4tWtL&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;hwkc8b&quot;&gt;In US cycling culture, bikes themselves — the materials, the brands — are often somewhat fetishized. Is that true in the Netherlands?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;cO6o1S&quot;&gt;Melissa Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Zf2bfe&quot;&gt;Not at all. Most of them will ride their bike until it falls apart. Their bikes are meant to be workhorses to last through all seasons, all kinds of beatings, because they live out on the street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8w0HvQ&quot;&gt;Most people we met still have their road bike that is lightweight, super-fast, clipped shoes, and all that, but that’s their weekend bike, when they go out and go for long rides, for sport and fitness. But the everyday bike, I mean, the image that most people have is of this black, beat up, vintage-looking Dutch bike — and that is literally what most of them ride around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;IFmoMe&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b8ob06&quot;&gt;The Dutch don’t wear bike helmets. How safe is it to ride a bike in the Netherlands?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;mj679Q&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;h66Unj&quot;&gt;We — like you — live in a place where helmets have been mandated by law, because they’ve been accepted as a commonsense safety device, normal as a seatbelt. But the Dutch show that [for them], safety in infrastructure, safety in slowing cars, and safety in numbers are all far more important than safety in body armor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;9VKIzZ&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3PmNNP&quot;&gt;Yeah, the US approach seems to be to up-armor the cyclist so that cars don’t have to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WNYMjtxuzR9yFoH0JqeLToyBxPc=/0x0:6016x4000/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R_h-ySq6Yeqtzq1jgR7PQydoHoM=/0x0:6016x4000/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sqEE3ENpuc6Kl9kVx5RKyEFpGNU=/0x0:6016x4000/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J3sgsp-hDgCkyHmlzMxiNY8AVoo=/0x0:6016x4000/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CIUtmMaqXAcm13x58exR7i0Yf5k=/0x0:6016x4000/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s1neDLgDVRJU-XTpYx-P6ratgio=/0x0:6016x4000/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b91LMvkGryfEumHrusNm_RauQ8s=/0x0:6016x4000/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/feyMCBBGE4RVgvYvN8MsjI_q7kc=/0x0:6016x4000/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/epoYWQP74k710_fAJgQ3Jko9qN8=/0x0:6016x4000/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;dutch cyclists&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bEzZVh--VKOvSSuMKLR1ZWBdSRI=/0x0:6016x4000/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:6016x4000)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622031/IMG_2988.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;Look Ma, no helmet! &lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;DrcO0B&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;roBfub&quot;&gt;Exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ij1VzT&quot;&gt;Less than 0.5 percent of Dutch cyclists wear helmets, which is one in 200 people on bikes. And that’s really just the sport cyclists. Virtually everybody else, from children to old people, doesn’t even think about helmets. It’s just not present in their culture, because they’ve ultimately decided that it’s far more important to build this culture of everyday cycling, and to build safe streets, instead of requiring people to protect themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;Lu5rgY&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;WaNzgw&quot;&gt;The Netherlands seems to be getting serious about long-distance bike corridors — bike highways. Are those getting used?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;thGrrW&quot;&gt;Melissa Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;J9mQ9K&quot;&gt;For sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;xYKmph&quot;&gt;For decades, the Dutch have had a country-wide network of bicycle trails. You can get from one city to another on a bike, no matter the distance. You could travel the whole country by bike if you wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;0ECCcD&quot;&gt;But what they started to realize in recent years is that, while that infrastructure exists, it isn’t very well-connected. So now they’re trying to find ways to make it a viable transportation option, an alternative to taking the motorway between two cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Os9u2X&quot;&gt;The greatest opportunity these are providing is for people in the growing e-bike market. You can travel further without having to break a sweat, and get from city to city on a very convenient, continuous path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;52ELWf&quot;&gt;The one we talk about in the book is the RijnWaalpad, which connects the city of Arnhem with the city of Nijmegen, about 14 to 15 kilometers. At no point on that trip do you ever have to put your foot down. You ride continuously, uninterrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;Q3BTVS&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;OkgQUd&quot;&gt;How are e-bikes and electric scooters and electric mopeds fitting into Dutch bike culture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;En1DmS&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;g0coSe&quot;&gt;The thing the Dutch have done well is classify these electric vehicles. Again, it comes down to the speed they’re capable of traveling. Regular e-bikes are speed-limited to [19 mph]. As long as you don’t exceed that speed, you’re able to use the regular bike infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UuG5ju&quot;&gt;If the bike is capable of going faster than that, it must utilize the streets and act like a car. There’s insurance requirements, licensing requirements, helmet mandates for those machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;iE6ZxV&quot;&gt;With the e-bike and electromobility in general, they’ve shown in the Netherlands, that they’re getting people to make better choices around personal transportation. They’re more likely to take their e-bike or scooter than an Uber or a taxi, or even the public transit system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dx9unb&quot;&gt;That little electric boost provides additional psychological help, and to encourage them to ride longer distances. So we are champions of electromobility, within reason. Cities still need to carefully regulate and react to the changes — I don’t think anybody foresaw, for example, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/8/27/17676670/electric-scooter-rental-bird-lime-skip-spin-cities&quot;&gt;scooter disruption&lt;/a&gt; that’s happened on our streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N1dDxIT5Ir-KhJarZkNhE0dkCno=/0x0:4279x2845/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aa6vjL_0Mt9Rw5Llu7yd1s6SCik=/0x0:4279x2845/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H2LxXcCqC-4yl2VdpipF9acFWkA=/0x0:4279x2845/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bZBWnirQ02S95Jz1NixEGvQ2o2Q=/0x0:4279x2845/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/URmIolRjpuL4OebL92nyMG8Z8Rg=/0x0:4279x2845/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5xMPzdQAiopM5MnJux3gek8dn1I=/0x0:4279x2845/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S6s3N4mtPxwBbnHtOsLHW6ZL7uE=/0x0:4279x2845/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rGcR7CBTc0Au-Rts6-k-OHLivGw=/0x0:4279x2845/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ew57XYdweAPnx7j06ASA47_KWy0=/0x0:4279x2845/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;dutch cyclist&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VwCK8Z_t4Y5BWk9aqlJSg8teJAU=/0x0:4279x2845/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:4279x2845)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12622313/IMG_7173.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;It takes all sorts (of bikes) in the Netherlands. &lt;cite&gt;Modacity&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;FueJIx&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;TO9orX&quot;&gt;Some US cities have had to deal with an &lt;a href=&quot;http://gothamist.com/2018/05/25/citi_bike_fury_flashback.php&quot;&gt;anti-bike lobby&lt;/a&gt;. Does that kind of sentiment or political force even exist at all in the Netherlands any more? Is there anyone pushing back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;tJJDj9&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;j012lQ&quot;&gt;Not that I’m aware. We had conversations with politicians there and they made it perfectly clear: Even the right-wing in the Netherlands has to support more spending on cycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;IEE9nB&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;nNhnLO&quot;&gt;Because of public pressure, public opinion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;PE0X0E&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;rUMWHN&quot;&gt;Exactly. It’s not a tenable or realistic position to win an election when probably 80 percent of the population cycles at least once a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;aSxSRg&quot;&gt;That’s not to say they aren’t also undermining the cause by building car parking and the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;fMiYeK&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;CuOocK&quot;&gt;So, pro-bike is settled, but anti-car maybe is not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;EQFk5w&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8AmmKS&quot;&gt;The Dutch still love their cars. They drive miles and miles, as much as neighboring countries. They’re having the same conversations as we are around the allocation of space, because they built all this space for cycling and it started to fill up. Now they’re trying to push for more space for cycling, and the exact same argument is being made, around loss of parking, loss of vehicle lanes. Here, we’re just arguing for any space,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dCaoa7&quot;&gt;David Roberts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;HnMuRE&quot;&gt;So it never ends? Every bit you take away from cars is a battle, forever?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;UimTpJ&quot;&gt;Chris Bruntlett&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;MVBFyH&quot;&gt;Exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jseliger</dc:creator>
<og:description>A chat with the authors of a new book on cycling in the Netherlands.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O1RO4gW2zDsRliK_-1SbokqJmjE=/0x3:5579x2924/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12619261/IMG_3142.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>No helmets, no problem: how the Dutch created a casual biking culture</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/8/28/17789510/bike-cycling-netherlands-dutch-infrastructure</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2018/8/28/17789510/bike-cycling-netherlands-dutch-infrastructure</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>NYC Mesh – community-owned network to replace your current internet connection</title>
<link>https://nycmesh.net/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://nycmesh.net/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Our network consists of Wi-Fi router “nodes”, “supernodes” and fiber spread throughout the city. The network connects directly to the internet backbone, so we do not rely on an ISP. All of our network nodes cooperate in the distribution of data, and the network can also function independently in case of emergencies or internet shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NYC Mesh is a neutral network that does not block or discriminate content. NYC Mesh does not collect, store, monitor, or log any user traffic or content that passes through our network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can connect whole buildings by wireless for speeds between 80 Mbps up to 1 Gbps, or by fiber at 20 Gbps (20,000 Mbps). The buildings we are currently planning include co-ops, a school and housing association buildings. Fiber involves an install fee and a monthly rental. For a quote, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:install@nycmesh.net&quot;&gt;email us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a network operator, please consider peering with our open network to provide bandwidth! (&lt;a href=&quot;https://nycmesh.net/peering&quot;&gt;Our peering policy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Our mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim to create an open, resilient, neutral network that serves both for daily internet use, and for emergency use during power outages or internet disruption, running software that helps our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=glW_S9bKAHk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nycmesh.net/assets/images/connect_thumb02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;How to connect to NYC Mesh&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;312&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;video by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.discobikini.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Christina Kelly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Get involved&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 18:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tonyztan</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://nycmesh.net/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DuckDuckGo Raises $10M</title>
<link>https://news.crunchbase.com/news/while-google-is-attacked-over-privacy-concerns-and-perceived-bias-duckduckgo-raised-10m/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.crunchbase.com/news/while-google-is-attacked-over-privacy-concerns-and-perceived-bias-duckduckgo-raised-10m/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content herald-entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google found itself in President Trump’s timeline being &lt;a href=&quot;https://money.cnn.com/2018/08/28/technology/donald-trump-google-rigged/index.html&quot;&gt;accused of biased search results&lt;/a&gt;. While the search giant denies those claims, Google has received more grounded criticism over how it handles user privacy and data. For &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/duck-duck-go&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;, it represents yet another opportunity to convert users, and now it has a tidy amount of cash from investors to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Crunchbase News on&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/crunchbasenews&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the only private search alternatives to Google, the privacy-focused DuckDuckGo quietly raised $10 million from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/omers-ventures#section-overview&quot;&gt;OMERS Ventures&lt;/a&gt; last week, a Canadian pension fund that has invested &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/search/funding_rounds/field/organizations/num_investments/omers-ventures&quot;&gt;in a number of startups&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchenginejournal.com/duckduckgo-receives-10m-financing-to-expand-global-impact/266199/&quot;&gt;Search Engine Journal,&lt;/a&gt; there was little need for the company to raise more money. DuckDuckGo, which had a last known &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/funding_round/duck-duck-go-series-unknown--5d9c6644&quot;&gt;raise of $3 million in 2011&lt;/a&gt;, has been profitable since 2014. However, the new funding could help DuckDuckGo expand its education-based campaigns concerning the privacy of search engines. The company has also developed a privacy app that &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/QNfnevM3gf&quot;&gt;blocks scripts from tracking visitors&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s possible more privacy-focused applications are in the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, $10 million is not a substantial amount of money when competing against Google. But for those looking for alternatives to Google, DuckDuckGo appears healthy and quite content with making &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-revenue-generation-model-for-DuckDuckGo/answer/Gabriel-Weinberg&quot;&gt;money off of keyword-based ads&lt;/a&gt; alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illustration Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://liannedias.com&quot;&gt;Li Anne Dias&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;herald-ad&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digiday has reported that Buzzfeed is testing a donation button on Buzzfeed News, which was recently spun out as its own entity. It's unclear whether...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growth stage investment fund, Lead Edge Capital has raised $520 million for its fourth fund. This fund brings LEC’s total assets under management to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 17:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>exotree</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>DuckDuckGo Raised $10M As Google Faces Privacy Concerns</og:title>
<og:description>DuckDuckGo raises money under the radar in the midst of Google's year of privacy and bias concerns. </og:description>
<og:url>https://news.crunchbase.com/news/while-google-is-attacked-over-privacy-concerns-and-perceived-bias-duckduckgo-raised-10m/</og:url>
<og:image>https://news.crunchbase.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/goog.gif</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.crunchbase.com/news/while-google-is-attacked-over-privacy-concerns-and-perceived-bias-duckduckgo-raised-10m/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Go 2 Draft Designs</title>
<link>https://go.googlesource.com/proposal/+/master/design/go2draft.md</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://go.googlesource.com/proposal/+/master/design/go2draft.md</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the Go 2 design process, we’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/go2draft&quot;&gt;published these draft designs&lt;/a&gt; to start community discussions about three topics: generics, error handling, and error value semantics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These draft designs are not proposals in the sense of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/s/proposal&quot;&gt;Go proposal process&lt;/a&gt;. They are starting points for discussion, with an eventual goal of producing designs good enough to be turned into actual proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the draft designs is accompanied by a “problem overview” (think “cover letter”). The problem overview is meant to provide context; to set the stage for the actual design docs, which of course present the design details; and to help frame and guide discussion about the designs. It presents background, goals, non-goals, design constraints, a brief summary of the design, a short discussion of what areas we think most need attention, and comparison with previous approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, these are draft designs, not official proposals. There are not associated proposal issues. We hope all Go users will help us improve them and turn them into Go proposals. We have established a wiki page to collect and organize feedback about each topic. Please help us keep those pages up to date, including by adding links to your own feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Error handling&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Error values&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generics&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 16:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>conroy</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://go.googlesource.com/proposal/+/master/design/go2draft.md</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Insured, but Still Owing $109K for a Heart Attack</title>
<link>https://khn.org/news/a-jolt-to-the-jugular-youre-insured-but-still-owe-109k-for-your-heart-attack/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://khn.org/news/a-jolt-to-the-jugular-youre-insured-but-still-owe-109k-for-your-heart-attack/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-body&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related partner-box top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;related-content&quot;&gt;This story also ran on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/08/27/640891882/life-threatening-heart-attack-leaves-teacher-with-108-951-bill&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;span class=&quot;replublish-story&quot;&gt;This story can be republished for free (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://khn.org/news/a-jolt-to-the-jugular-youre-insured-but-still-owe-109k-for-your-heart-attack/view/republish/&quot;&gt;details&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/news/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;15&quot; src=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/logo-npr.jpg&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;nosyndication&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: This story has an addendum reflecting the hospital’s latest settlement offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drew Calver took out his trash cans and then waved goodbye to his wife, Erin, as she left for the grocery store the morning that upended his picture-perfect life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes later, the popular high school history teacher and swim coach in Austin, Texas, collapsed in his bedroom from a heart attack. He pounded his fist on the bed frame, violent chest pains pinning him to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I thought I was dying,” the 44-year-old father recalled. He called out to the only other person in the house, his oldest daughter, Eleanor, now 7. Using his voice, he texted his wife, who was at the store with their youngest, Emory, now 6. A neighbor rushed him to the nearby emergency room at St. David’s Medical Center on April 2, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related pull-right&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;slab default-slab&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/send-us-your-medical-bills/&quot;&gt;Send Us Your Medical Bill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;slab-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;slab-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-813969 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/bill-envelope-side-smaller2.jpg?w=1350&amp;amp;h=620&quot; alt=&quot;Bill of the Month logo&quot; width=&quot;1350&quot; height=&quot;620&quot; srcset=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/bill-envelope-side-smaller2.jpg 1350w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/bill-envelope-side-smaller2.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=69 150w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/bill-envelope-side-smaller2.jpg?w=500&amp;amp;h=230 500w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/bill-envelope-side-smaller2.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=353 768w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/bill-envelope-side-smaller2.jpg?w=1270&amp;amp;h=583 1270w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1350px) 100vw, 1350px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have an exorbitant or baffling medical bill? Join the KHN and NPR’s Bill-of-the-Month Club and tell us about your experience. We’ll feature a new one each month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ER doctors confirmed the trauma to Calver’s heart and admitted him to the hospital’s cardiac unit. The next day, doctors implanted stents in his clogged “widow-maker” artery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heart attack was a shock for Calver, an avid swimmer who had competed in an Ironman triathlon just five months before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the surprise, even from his hospital bed, Calver asked whether his health insurance would cover all of this, a financial worry that accompanies nearly every American hospital stay. He was concerned because St. David’s is out-of-network on his school district health plan. The hospital told him not to worry and that they would accept his insurance, Calver said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hospital charged $164,941 for his surgery and four days in the hospital. Aetna, which administers health benefits for the Austin Independent School District, paid the hospital $55,840, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4777762-Calver-BOTM-Hospital-Charges.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;records show&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the difference of more than $100,000, with the hospital’s prior assurance, Calver believed he would not bear much, if any, out-of-pocket payment for his life-threatening emergency and the surgery that saved him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then the bills came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patient:&lt;/strong&gt; Drew Calver, 44, a high school history teacher and father of two in Austin, Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Bill:&lt;/strong&gt; $164,941 for a four-day hospital stay, including $42,944 for four stents and $10,920 for room charges. Calver’s insurer paid $55,840. The hospital billed Calver for the unpaid balance of $108,951.31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Provider:&lt;/strong&gt; St. David’s HealthCare, a large hospital system in central Texas. It’s run by HCA Healthcare, the nation’s largest for-profit hospital chain, and two nonprofit foundations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medical Treatment:&lt;/strong&gt; Emergency room treatment followed by four days in the hospital, most of it spent in the cardiac unit. During surgery, four stents were implanted to clear a blockage in his left anterior descending artery, the source of so-called widow-maker heart attacks, because they are so frequently deadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Gives:&lt;/strong&gt; St. David’s Medical Center is billing Calver for the $109,000 balance — an amount nearly twice his annual pay as a teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hospital’s billing company sent a notice June 26, urging him to take advantage of this “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4777829-Calver-BOTM-June-2018-Letter.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;FINAL opportunity to settle your balance.&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related inline&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;slab email-slab&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;email-signup&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;signup-text&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Email Sign-Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;slab-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to KHN’s free Morning Briefing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;“They’re going to give me another heart attack stressing over this bill,” Calver said. “I can’t pay this bill on my teacher salary, and I don’t want this to go to a debt collector.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of his heart attack, Calver fell victim to twin medical billing practices that increasingly bedevil many Americans, even as legislators have tried to protect them: surprise bills and balance billing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprise bills occur when a patient goes to a hospital in his insurance network but receives treatment from a doctor that does not participate in the network, resulting in a direct bill to the patient. They can also occur in cases like Calver’s, where insurers will pay for needed emergency care at the closest hospital — even if it is out-of-network — but the hospital and the insurer may not agree on a reasonable price. The hospital then demands that patients pay the difference, in a practice called balance billing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;side-by-side&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;alignleft wp-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;770&quot; height=&quot;513&quot; src=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_06_1350.jpg?w=770&amp;amp;h=513&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-khn-article-large size-khn-article-large&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The total bill for Drew Calver’s four-day hospital stay at St. David’s Medical Center in April 2017 was $164,941.&lt;span class=&quot;photo-credit&quot;&gt;(Callie Richmond for KHN)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;alignright wp-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;770&quot; height=&quot;513&quot; src=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_08_13501.jpg?w=770&amp;amp;h=513&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-khn-article-large size-khn-article-large&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;His insurer paid $55,840, leaving Calver responsible for the unpaid balance of $108,951.31.&lt;span class=&quot;photo-credit&quot;&gt;(Callie Richmond for KHN)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several states, including Texas (as well as New York, California and New Jersey) have passed laws to help shield consumers from surprise bills and balance billing, particularly for emergency care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://californiahealthline.org/news/for-millions-of-insured-californians-state-health-laws-dont-apply/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;a huge loophole&lt;/a&gt;: Those state-mandated protections typically don’t apply to people, like the Calver family, who get their health coverage from employers that are self-insured, meaning the companies or employers pay claims out of their own funds.  Federal law governs most of those health plans — and it does not include such protections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kff.org/report-section/ehbs-2017-section-10-plan-funding/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;60 percent&lt;/a&gt; of people with employer health benefits are covered by self-insured plans, but many don’t even know it, since employers typically hire an insurer to administer the plan and employees carry a card bearing the name of Blue Cross Blue Shield or another major insurer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_866039&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-866039&quot; src=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_01_1350.jpg?w=450&amp;amp;h=675&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; srcset=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_01_1350.jpg?w=450&amp;amp;h=675 450w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_01_1350.jpg?w=900&amp;amp;h=1350 900w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_01_1350.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=150 100w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_01_1350.jpg?w=333&amp;amp;h=500 333w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_01_1350.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=1151 768w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_01_1350.jpg?w=847&amp;amp;h=1270 847w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Drew Calver sits with his wife, Erin, and daughters Eleanor (left) and Emory (middle) in their Austin, Texas, home where he had a heart attack on April 2, 2017.&lt;span class=&quot;photo-credit&quot;&gt;(Callie Richmond for KHN)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This case “illustrates the dangers that even insured people face,” said Carol Lucas, an attorney in Los Angeles with experience in health care payment disputes. “The unfairness is especially acute when there is an emergency and the patient, who might ordinarily be completely compliant, has no say about the facility he winds up in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm-hospital-statement.pdf&quot;&gt;a statement&lt;/a&gt;, St. David’s HealthCare defended its handling of Calver’s bill and sought to blame the school district and Aetna for offering such a narrow network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While we did everything right in this particular situation, the structure of the patient’s insurance plan as a narrow network product placed a large portion of the financial responsibility directly on the patient because our hospital was not in-network,” the hospital said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patients experiencing an emergency are particularly at risk of landing at an out-of-network hospital. St. David’s said once ER patients are deemed stable, it tries to transfer them to an in-network facility. “However, this is not always possible because the patient’s health must come first,” the hospital said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This case also raises questions about the validity of the hospital’s charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industry analysts and consumer advocates say St. David’s has a reputation for exorbitant billing and for trying to collect big payouts as an out-of-network provider. “This is a well-known, problematic provider. We’ve seen multiple bills from them and they are always highly inflated,” said Dr. Merrit Quarum, chief executive of WellRithms, which scrutinizes medical bills for self-funded employers and other clients nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WellRithms reviewed Calver’s bill in detail at the request of Kaiser Health News and determined that a reasonable reimbursement would have been $26,985. That’s less than half &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4777764-Calver-BOTM-Aetna-EOB.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;what Aetna paid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healthcare Bluebook, which offers cost estimates for medical tests and treatments, arrived at a similar conclusion. It said a fair price for a hospitalization in Austin involving four heart stents would be about $36,800. St. David’s Medical Center charged four times that amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quarum and other analysts who reviewed the bill said several charges stood out, especially on the four stents, which were billed at $42,944. Coronary stents are typically metal mesh tubes implanted in arteries to improve blood flow. Most are coated with drugs to assist in healing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;St. David’s charged $19,708 apiece for two Synergy stents made by device giant Boston Scientific. Two other stents used were far cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The $20,000 price tag represents a significant markup of what U.S. hospitals typically pay themselves for stents. The median price paid by hospitals for the Synergy stent was $1,153 over the past year, according to the nonprofit research firm ECRI Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“St. David’s charge of over $19,000 for those stents is absolutely outrageous,” Quarum said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St. David’s declined to comment on its markup for the stents or what it actually paid the manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolution:&lt;/strong&gt; For now, Calver still faces a bill for $108,951.31, with none of the parties involved in his treatment or coverage providing significant redress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the hospital’s debt collector &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/4777791-Calver-BOTM-August-2018-Letter.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;sent the Calvers a letter Aug. 3&lt;/a&gt; demanding payment in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a reporter made inquiries, St. David’s said collection efforts were put on hold, and a hospital representative called Calver, offering to help him apply for a discount based on his income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a statement, St. David’s said “we work with all patients needing financial assistance to help determine their eligibility for this discount.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calver said that approach doesn’t address the balance billing or whether the charges were appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokeswoman for Aetna said “we are actively working to rectify the situation on behalf of the member.” But the health plan hasn’t shared any further details. The Austin school district declined to discuss this specific case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calver said the whole ordeal has been incredibly stressful for him and his wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am stuck in the middle of this convoluted, flawed system,” he said. “I’ve never owed a large amount like this or had credit card debt. What does it mean if this goes on my credit report?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_866064&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-866064&quot; src=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/calver_hospital.jpg?w=1003&amp;amp;h=752&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1003&quot; height=&quot;752&quot; srcset=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/calver_hospital.jpg 1003w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/calver_hospital.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=112 150w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/calver_hospital.jpg?w=500&amp;amp;h=375 500w, https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/calver_hospital.jpg?w=768&amp;amp;h=576 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1003px) 100vw, 1003px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Drew Calver’s daughters visit him at the hospital in April 2017 after his heart attack and resulting emergency surgery.&lt;span class=&quot;photo-credit&quot;&gt;(Courtesy of the Calver family)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Takeaway:&lt;/strong&gt; Faced with a surprise bill or a balance-billing situation, don’t rush to pay any medical bills you receive. First, let the insurance process play out completely so you’re sure what the health plan is paying the hospital and doctors — and what you ultimately might be responsible for, in terms of coinsurance or copayments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask for an itemized bill. Review the charges carefully and talk to your insurer, your employer and the hospital if the prices seem out of line. Arm yourself with estimates you can find online of the average prices charged in your area as you negotiate with all the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the bills keep coming, talk to your employer’s benefits department or the state insurance department about your legal protections. The situation will vary depending on the type of health insurance you have and the state you live in. Tell any debt collection agencies that may contact you that you are contesting the bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With any of these entities, you can always appeal to reason, with this argument: You had no choice but to go to an out-of-network hospital in the case of a life-threatening emergency, so the insurer and the hospital should work out payment and hold you harmless from financially crippling bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bill of the Month is a crowdsourced investigation by &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/news/tag/bill-of-the-month/&quot;&gt;Kaiser Health News&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/02/16/585549568/share-your-medical-bill-with-us&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt; that dissects and explains medical bills.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ashley Lopez, a reporter with NPR member station KUT in Austin, contributed to the audio story in this report.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;related partner-box bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;related-content&quot;&gt;This story also ran on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/08/27/640891882/life-threatening-heart-attack-leaves-teacher-with-108-951-bill&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;span class=&quot;replublish-story&quot;&gt;This story can be republished for free (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://khn.org/news/a-jolt-to-the-jugular-youre-insured-but-still-owe-109k-for-your-heart-attack/view/republish/&quot;&gt;details&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/news/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;45&quot; height=&quot;15&quot; src=&quot;https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/logo-npr.jpg&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story was produced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Kaiser Health News&lt;/a&gt;, which publishes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.californiahealthline.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;California Healthline&lt;/a&gt;, a service of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chcf.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;California Health Care Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-update&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: Monday, shortly after publication and broadcast of this story by Kaiser Health News and NPR, St. David’s said it was now willing to accept $782.29 to resolve the $108,951 balance because Drew Calver qualifies for its “financial assistance discount.” In a statement, the hospital said this offer was contingent on Calver submitting his application for a discount based on his household finances. Calver disputed that he owes any additional money to St. David’s and said this situation should have been resolved long before now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;meta-authors meta&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;author-name&quot;&gt;Chad Terhune:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cterhune@kff.org&quot;&gt;cterhune@kff.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/chadterhune&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@chadterhune&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;meta-tags&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Related Topics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;categories&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/topics/cost-and-quality/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Cost and Quality&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/topics/health-industry/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Health Industry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/topics/insurance/&quot; rel=&quot;category tag&quot;&gt;Insurance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tags&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/news/tag/bill-of-the-month/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Bill Of The Month&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/news/tag/emergency-medicine/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Emergency Medicine&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://khn.org/news/tag/hospitals/&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Hospitals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 16:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tim_sw</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>A Jolt To The Jugular! You’re Insured But Still Owe $109K For Your Heart Attack</og:title>
<og:url>https://khn.org/news/a-jolt-to-the-jugular-youre-insured-but-still-owe-109k-for-your-heart-attack/</og:url>
<og:description>A Texas teacher, 44, faces a “balance bill” of almost twice his annual salary for a heart attack he never expected to have.</og:description>
<og:image>https://kaiserhealthnews.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/botm_aug_10_1350.jpg?w=1200</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://khn.org/news/a-jolt-to-the-jugular-youre-insured-but-still-owe-109k-for-your-heart-attack/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zero-Day Vulnerability in Microsoft Windows Leaked on Twitter</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/SandboxEscaper/status/1034125195148255235</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/SandboxEscaper/status/1034125195148255235</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SandboxEscaper/status/1034125195148255235&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/SandboxEscaper/status/1034125195148255235&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17859589&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17859589&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 318&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 113&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 15:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tzury</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/SandboxEscaper/status/1034125195148255235</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Air-conditioners do great good, but at a high environmental cost</title>
<link>https://www.economist.com/international/2018/08/25/air-conditioners-do-great-good-but-at-a-high-environmental-cost</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.economist.com/international/2018/08/25/air-conditioners-do-great-good-but-at-a-high-environmental-cost</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;“AIR-CONDITIONING cannot be a grand success in the [American] South for the reason that the honest natives of the region recognise the natural summer heat as a welcome ally, in that it makes the inside of houses and offices agreeably uninviting.” In the annals of mistaken predictions, this one—made in 1935 by Clarence Cason, author of “90° in the Shade”—merits an honourable mention. In fact, air-conditioning soon became universal south of the Mason-Dixon line, turning the South into an engine of prosperity and even reshaping its politics by luring Republican migrants to a region that had once been a Democratic stronghold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stifling summer of 2018 in the northern hemisphere has been a banner season for air-conditioners and a reminder of how they have changed the world. Sales in France in the first three weeks of July were 192% higher than in the same period of 2017. In Japan, the government is helping schools install coolers. In Texas, on the orders of a judge, the state government has been putting them into prisons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form newsletter-form--inline&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;newsletter-form__message&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get our daily newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrade your inbox and get our Daily Dispatch and Editor's Picks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__container latest-updates-panel__container--blog-post&quot;&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__body&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Canada’s example of assisted dying refutes those who argue against it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Assisted dying would be damaging to those whose choices are not simple&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;What educated people from poor countries make of the “brain drain” argument&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Why the Mediterranean will eventually disappear&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-1.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Wood-burning stoves, the picturesque polluters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;latest-updates-panel__article-link&quot; readability=&quot;27&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;latest-updates-panel-card__title&quot;&gt;Ireland wrestles with Catholicism as the religion plunges in popularity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At current growth rates, according to the International Energy Agency (IEA), which advises national governments, 1bn air-conditioners will be installed globally in the next ten years. That would increase the world’s stock—1.6bn in 2016—by two-thirds (see chart). If you include refrigerators and systems that cool food, vaccines and data, the stock could be 6bn units in a decade. The growth in cooling will save lives, improve education and create wealth in the world’s hottest countries. But it brings huge environmental risks, warming the planet even as it cools people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;component-image blog-post__image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;component-image__img blog-post-article-image blog-post-article-image__slim&quot; srcset=&quot;/sites/default/files/imagecache/200-width/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png 200w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/300-width/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png 300w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/400-width/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png 400w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/640-width/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png 640w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/800-width/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png 800w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1000-width/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png 1000w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1200-width/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png 1200w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1280-width/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png 1280w, /sites/default/files/imagecache/1600-width/images/print-edition/20180825_IRC157.png 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 600px) 640px, calc(100vw - 20px)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee Kuan Yew, the first prime minister of Singapore, took the view that air-conditioning “changed the nature of civilisation by making development possible in the tropics… The first thing I did upon becoming prime minister was to install air-conditioners in buildings where the civil service worked. This was key to public efficiency.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;When China became cool&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1990 few Chinese households had air-conditioning. Twenty years later, the country had just under one unit per household. It now accounts for 35% of the world’s stock, compared with 23% for the United States. India and Indonesia are seeing rates of increase similar to China’s in the 1990s. The population of the 800km long southern coast of the Arabian Gulf increased from 500,000 in 1950 to 20m now, thanks to air-conditioned vertical palaces. At current rates, Saudi Arabia will be using more energy to run air-conditioners in 2030 than it now exports as oil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, only 8% of the 3bn people in the tropics have air-conditioning, compared with over 90% of households in America and Japan. But eventually, it will be near universal because so many trends are converging behind its spread: ageing, since old people are more vulnerable to heat stroke; urbanisation, since fields cannot be air-conditioned but offices and factories must be; and economic growth, since, after mobile phones, the middle class in emerging markets want fans or air-conditioners next. Even the proliferation of skyscrapers in the developing world’s megacities encourages air-conditioners. Because tall buildings have different air pressures at top and bottom, they usually have to be sealed, and cooled in summer. Shopping malls, open-plan offices and data-processing centres are all inconceivable without air-conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmentalists fret about this. An article in the &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; excoriated “the deluded world of air-conditioning”. Another in the &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; castigated buildings so cold in summer that “I could preserve dead bodies in the office.” Yet air-conditioning makes people, literally, healthier, wealthier and wiser. A study by Tord Kjellstrom of Australian National University found that, in South-East Asia, people without cooling could not work during 15-20% of working hours. It was too darned hot. Solomon Hsiang of the University of California, Berkeley calculated that, in the Caribbean and Central America, GDP falls by 1% for each degree above 26°C. In the tropics, cooling boosts productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for learning. A recent study in &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, a weekly journal, by Jose Guillermo Cedeño of Harvard University, followed two groups of college students in Boston during the summer of 2016. Those living in air-conditioned rooms did significantly better in a variety of cognitive tests than their peers in uncooled digs. Studies in Denmark showed that air-conditioning schools improved children’s ability to learn mathematics and languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most simply, cooling also saves lives. Western Europe suffered a withering heatwave in 2003; 11,000-17,000 more deaths than normal were attributed to it in France, mainly from cardiovascular and heart disease. There was a public outcry and the government brought in a range of reforms, including making air-conditioning mandatory in old-people’s homes. This year France has been even hotter than in 2003 but excess deaths so far seem to have been much lower: the health minister recently said the number of hospitalisations this summer has been only slightly greater than normal. Europe, it seems, is learning to cope. In Spain, according to a study by Joan Ballester of the Barcelona Institute for Global Health, heat-related deaths fell between 1980 and 2015, though average summer temperatures rose almost 1°C and there were more old people. In south-west Germany, says Stefan Muthers of the German Weather Service, 2003 and 2015 were the two warmest summers in the past 50 years; 1,700 people died in 2003 but the death toll in 2015 was almost 20% lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heatwaves take an even bigger toll in poor countries that are unable to protect themselves. The World Health Organisation (WHO) forecasts that, without adaptation (which is of course happening), over a quarter of a million extra deaths could be attributable to rising temperatures by 2050—about as many as the number of deaths in childbirth now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the definition of air-conditioning is widened to include cold chains for food, industrial processes or vaccines, the overall market increases—and so does its capacity for good. According to Toby Peters of Birmingham University in Britian, cooling for things such as industry, food and data storage uses only a little less energy than air-conditioning. Refrigerated transport is not far behind. These have as many benefits as cooling buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;Between farm and fork&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many developing countries, half the food crop is lost to rats and insects after harvest. Reducing that through refrigeration in storage or transport could do more to boost overall food availability than a new green revolution. In the process, it would also limit the greenhouse-gas emissions from wasted agricultural production. According to the WHO, 600m people fall ill at some point each year—and over 400,000 die—from eating contaminated food. A quarter of liquid vaccines are spoiled because they are not kept properly chilled. The death toll from diseases that could be vaccinated against but aren’t, says the WHO, is 1.5m a year, more than die in road accidents. Better cooling would reduce all these harms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as Homer Simpson, an American philosopher, said of alcohol, air-conditioning is the cause of, and solution to, many of life’s problems. In “Losing Our Cool”, a book from 2010, Stan Cox, an agricultural scientist, listed some of its damages: “emission of greenhouse gases…ozone-depleting chemicals [and] a lever to open ecologically vulnerable parts of the country to reckless growth.” He even blamed it for obesity caused (he said) by sitting around in artificially cooled refuges. A recent article in PLOS &lt;em class=&quot;Italic&quot;&gt;Medicine,&lt;/em&gt; by David Abel and colleagues at the University of Wisconsin-Madison, calculated that, by 2050, there will be 17,000 excess deaths in the eastern half of the United States from an increase of ozone and PM2.5 in the atmosphere (pollutants with a diameter of 2.5 microns or less). Air-conditioning, the authors think, will be responsible for almost 1,000 of those deaths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air-conditioners produce greenhouse gases in two ways. First, they are responsible for a share of the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; generated in the power stations that produce the electricity they run on. At the moment, according to the IEA, it takes about 2,000 TWhs (terawatt hours) of electricity to run all the world’s cooling machines for a year. This produces 4bn tons of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, 12% of the total. Without drastic improvements in air-conditioners’ efficiency, the IEA reckons, they will be burning up 6,000 TWhs by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On hot days in Riyadh, air-conditioners account for 70% of electricity demand during peak hours, usually the early evening. Peak hours matter because countries must build enough power stations to meet the maximum demand. But most of the time full capacity is not used, meaning firms earn nothing from it. So energy companies build peak capacity as cheaply as possible, which often means using coal or diesel. So demand for air-conditioning is pushing countries to build not just more power plants, but more polluting ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, air-conditioners use so-called “F gases” (such as hydrofluorocarbons, or HFCs) as refrigerants. When—as is common—the machines leak in use or on disposal, these gases escape, doing vast damage. HFCs trap between 1,000 and 9,000 times as much heat as the same amount of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, meaning they are much more potent causes of global warming. On this basis, Paul Hawken of Project Drawdown, a think-tank, calculates that improving air-conditioners could do more than anything else to reduce greenhouse gases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;xhead&quot;&gt;Hitting the fan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatih Birol, the head of the IEA, calls the insatiable energy demands of air-conditioning “one of the most critical blind spots in today’s energy debate”. Slowly, that blind spot is being opened up. In 2017, the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory in California, a research centre, calculated the extra carbon emissions that could be saved if air-conditioners were better. If HFCs were phased out and all units were as efficient as the best ones, the world could be spared around 1,000 average-sized (500MW capacity) power stations by 2030. There would be many more air-conditioning units, but each would use less energy. In India, this would save three times as much in carbon emissions as the prime minister’s much-vaunted plan to install 100 gigawatts of solar capacity by 2022. In China, it would save as much as eight Three Gorges dams (the largest dam in the world).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such gains will not be easy to achieve. A common way to improve energy efficiency is to impose minimum energy standards or energy codes for buildings. But these vary from country to country (they are stricter in Japan and Europe than in America, for example). And most poor, hot countries do not even have them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting rid of toxic refrigerant gases also depends on regulation, in this case an international agreement called the Kigali amendment (after the Rwandan capital where it was approved). The deal sets a timetable for phasing down the toxic gases. The trouble is that, to win the backing of tropical countries, the agreement allows them more than a decade to phase the gases out. Since air-conditioners often have a useful life of more than ten years, it could take until 2038 before the full effects of the Kigali amendment come into force—a long time to wait when demand for cooling is growing so fast. With the deal, argues Dan Hamza-Goodacre, boss of the Kigali Cooling-Efficiency Programme, a non-governmental organisation, air-conditioners can produce better health, higher productivity and more food while limiting the rise in global temperatures. In its absence, people cannot have those benefits without the environmental costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction (August 28th, 2018):&lt;/strong&gt; A previous version of this article misstated the name of Project Drawdown, a think-tank, as Project Download. This has been corrected. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 15:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lazerpants</dc:creator>
<og:description>The rapid growth in their use makes it urgent to limit the damage</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/print-edition/20180825_IRP001_0.jpg</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.economist.com/international/2018/08/25/air-conditioners-do-great-good-but-at-a-high-environmental-cost</og:url>
<og:title>Air-conditioners do great good, but at a high environmental cost</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.economist.com/international/2018/08/25/air-conditioners-do-great-good-but-at-a-high-environmental-cost</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Yahoo, Bucking Industry, Scans Emails for Data to Sell Advertisers</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/yahoo-bucking-industry-scans-emails-for-data-to-sell-advertisers-1535466959</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wsj.com/articles/yahoo-bucking-industry-scans-emails-for-data-to-sell-advertisers-1535466959</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix byline-wrap&quot;&gt;


    

        
    &lt;div class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;
    
    
        &lt;span&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;
    
              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Douglas MacMillan&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/7902&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://twitter.com/dmac1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@dmac1&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:douglas.macmillan@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;douglas.macmillan@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Douglas MacMillan&lt;/span&gt;, 
                  &lt;/div&gt;

              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Sarah Krouse&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8102&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://twitter.com/bysarahkrouse&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@bysarahkrouse&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:sarah.krouse@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;sarah.krouse@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Sarah Krouse&lt;/span&gt; and 
                  &lt;/div&gt;

              &lt;div class=&quot;author mobile-scrim hasMenu&quot; data-scrim=&quot;{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;author&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;header&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Keach Hagey&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;subhead&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.wsj.com/news/author/8296&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Biography&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;twitter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://twitter.com/keachhagey&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;@keachhagey&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;facebook&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://facebook.com/keach.hagey&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;keach.hagey&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;google&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://plus.google.com/104370531137368096163/posts&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Google+&amp;quot;},{&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;link&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;icon&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:Keach.Hagey@wsj.com&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Keach.Hagey@wsj.com&amp;quot;}]}&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/Person&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;name&quot; itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Keach Hagey&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;time class=&quot;timestamp&quot;&gt;
      Aug. 28, 2018 10:36 a.m. ET
    &lt;/time&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  

  &lt;div class=&quot;article-content &quot;&gt;



       






       




       &lt;p&gt;The U.S. tech industry has largely declared it is off limits to scan emails for information to sell to advertisers. 






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/AABA&quot;&gt;Yahoo&lt;/a&gt;
            

      &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/AABA?mod=chiclets&quot; class=&quot;media-object-chiclet down company-name&quot; data-channel=&quot;/quotes/zigman/92040767/composite&quot; data-symbol=&quot;AABA&quot; data-changepercent=&quot;-0.76&quot;&gt;
        AABA &lt;span&gt;-0.76%&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;

       still sees the practice as a potential gold mine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yahoo’s owner, the Oath unit of 






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/VZ&quot;&gt;Verizon Communications&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.,&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/VZ?mod=chiclets&quot; class=&quot;media-object-chiclet down &quot; data-channel=&quot;/quotes/zigman/262341/composite&quot; data-symbol=&quot;VZ&quot; data-changepercent=&quot;-0.36&quot;&gt;
        VZ &lt;span&gt;-0.36%&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;

       has been pitching a service to advertisers that analyzes more than 200 million Yahoo Mail inboxes and the rich user data they contain, searching for clues about what products those users might buy, said people who have attended Oath’s presentations as well as current and former employees of the company.&lt;/p&gt;




      &lt;div class=&quot;paywall&quot;&gt;






       




       &lt;p&gt;Oath said the practice extends to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/verizon-launches-new-ad-and-content-unit-as-yahoo-deal-completes-1497362908?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;AOL Mail, which it also owns&lt;/a&gt;. Together, they constitute the only major U.S. email provider that scans user inboxes for marketing purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The strategy bucks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebooks-next-privacy-challenge-less-data-to-target-ads-1532943001?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;a recent Silicon Valley trend toward more data privacy &lt;/a&gt;and shows an industry divided on where to draw the line between user protections and technologies that many advertisers crave.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/GOOGL&quot;&gt;Alphabet&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.’s&lt;/span&gt;


       &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-to-stop-reading-users-emails-to-target-ads-1498247136?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;Google, the most popular email provider with 1.4 billion users, said it stopped scanning messages in Gmail&lt;/a&gt; for ad targeting last year, citing user privacy. 






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/MSFT&quot;&gt;Microsoft Corp.,&lt;/a&gt;
            


       the former email leader, said it has never used email data for advertising.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yahoo’s practice began more than a decade ago and expanded over the years, said a person familiar with the matter. The company has increasingly looked for new ways to wring revenue out of its aging portfolio of web properties, which have stagnated in the era of smartphones and social networking.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/with-yahoo-deal-verizon-sets-sights-on-facebook-google-1469542028?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;Verizon created Oath last year, it envisioned the new unit as a future advertising rival&lt;/a&gt; to Google and 






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/FB&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.&lt;/span&gt;


       for its potential to marry data on Verizon’s vast pool of wireless subscribers with Yahoo’s highly trafficked online hubs, Verizon executives have said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oath owns dozens of popular websites, such as HuffPost and Yahoo Finance. It helps advertisers show messages on these sites as well as across the web, using a variety of ad-placement services.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;Email scanning has become one of the company’s most effective methods for improving ad targeting, said 




      Doug Sharp, 




       Oath’s vice president of data, measurements and insights. He said that the practice applies only to commercial emails in people’s accounts—from retailers, say, or mass mailings—and that users have the ability to opt out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Sharp said that being served ads is part of the trade-off users make in exchange for free online services, and that Yahoo’s research shows they prefer ads that are relevant to them. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“Email is an expensive system,” Mr. Sharp said. “I think it’s reasonable and ethical to expect the value exchange, if you’ve got this mail service and there is advertising going on.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He said Yahoo offers an ad-free email service for which customers pay $3.49 a month. It also scans the emails sent in that service. &lt;a href=&quot;https://aim.yahoo.com/aim/us/en/optout/?mod=article_inline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;Yahoo provides an opt-out option&lt;/a&gt; to users of both the free and paid services.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yahoo’s algorithms look for commercial emails and identify them using a database of commonly sent emails. The algorithms link certain types of emails to certain consumer preferences, and then place a “cookie,” a piece of tracking code, on that user’s computer to help advertisers show them messages in the future.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;Oath promises to give advertisers an edge by identifying groups of users who have bought certain products or services based on the receipts, travel itineraries and promotions in their inboxes, said Mr. Sharp. For example, he said, Yahoo’s system labels people who receive trade confirmations from online brokerage accounts as “investors” who can be targeted for finance-related advertisements.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h6&gt;Privacy questions&lt;/h6&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oath is testing the boundaries of what users may be comfortable sharing. Unlike with web-browsing habits and search histories, many users expect a greater degree of privacy when it comes to personal-communication tools such as email, said Lauren Gelman, an online-privacy lawyer and former executive director of Stanford Law School’s Center for Internet and Society.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google previously sold ads related to keywords in email messages. It used the information in personal and commercial email messages to show users relevant ads while they were looking at Gmail—not to target any users elsewhere on the web—a Google spokeswoman said.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;The scanning practice excluded paid users of Gmail, she said. Google and Oath said they prevented advertisers from targeting users based on certain sensitive categories of email, such as health conditions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google said it stopped targeting ads based on Gmail data last year, saying it wanted users to “remain confident that Google will keep privacy and security paramount.” &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google already collects so much data from its search engine that it no longer needed to rely on email data, said 




      Andreas Reiffen, 




       chief executive of digital-ad consultant Crealytics GmbH.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oath’s email scanning appears to go a step further than Google’s former system, by creating interest profiles of users based on the data in their email and using that intelligence to target them elsewhere on the web. Oath groups similar users together as an “audience” to which marketers can target ads, Mr. Sharp said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yahoo Mail users who receive frequent emails about driving for Lyft Inc. are sometimes placed into a “self-employed” audience, Mr. Sharp said. Some people who bought several plane tickets in the past year are labeled frequent travelers. A spokeswoman for Lyft declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;The cookies Oath places on users’ computers allow it to identify which audience they are part of and show them ads without ever providing any personally identifiable information to marketers, Mr. Sharp said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oath’s systems are designed to ignore personal messages and look for only commercial emails, which make up the vast majority of the messages that arrive in Yahoo Mail inboxes, Mr. Sharp said. Its algorithms strip out all personal information, such as names and email addresses.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At one point, Oath’s computers mistakenly labeled invitations to Indian weddings—which traditionally are sizable, multiday gatherings—as commercial emails, “because they end up as mass-mailed forms” to so many people, Mr. Sharp said. The company fixed that problem by looking for phrases common to wedding invitations and discarding any results.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In its privacy policy, Oath says all Yahoo Mail users may have portions of some emails reviewed by human employees. Oath employees may manually review sections of mass-mailed commercial emails that appear to be “boilerplate,” or the same for many users, the policy says.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A small number of users have explicitly opted in to letting human beings read all of their emails as a way to refine the algorithms and make sure no personal emails are being mislabeled, Mr. Sharp said. This is how the company discovered the Indian wedding problem, he said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h6&gt;Scanned receipts&lt;/h6&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oath uses receipts in Yahoo Mail inboxes as proof that an ad campaign convinced a user to buy a product, a person familiar with the matter said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yahoo has scanned email for years and included language in its privacy policy saying the company can scan and analyze all email messages. Over time, it added some detail to that disclosure, including an explanation of how it looks for mass-mailed commercial emails. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But Yahoo executives haven’t widely discussed the email-data collection, and many people never read the fine print. Some Yahoo Mail users only became aware of this practice when Oath emailed them in April with an update to its terms of service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In one message prompting users to respond, Yahoo gave two options: “I Accept,” or “I’ll do this later.” Users can opt out of all Yahoo ad personalization by visiting its “ad interest manager” page and clicking a button.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;The new privacy policy is “telling me all of my stuff is basically going to be rifled through and used however they want to use it,” said Lisa Bell Roden, 53, who lives in Ashburn, Va., and relies on the email service for her work with small businesses and entrepreneurs on media production. “That, to me, is rather off-putting,” she said, although she has no plans to close the Yahoo account.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The U.S. Federal Trade Commission requires companies to clearly disclose how they collect personal data in privacy policies. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/gdpr-has-companies-big-and-small-racing-to-comply-1527154200?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt;The EU’s new data-protection rules&lt;/a&gt; require companies to obtain users’ express consent for all data collection before they begin using a product or service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Sharp said the company changed its terms of service this year to comply with the European regulations. “It’s an odd thing, consent,” he said, “because I think the people who care about it are aware of it, and that’s as it should be.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yahoo paid $4 million in 2016 to settle a federal class-action lawsuit that claimed its scanning of email violated federal wiretap laws. Yahoo, which didn’t admit wrongdoing, agreed as part of the settlement terms to make a technical change: Rather than scanning emails while they are “in transit,” Yahoo now waits until they arrive in an inbox to scan them.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;Oath’s new privacy policy prevents users from filing class-action suits and instead requires them to pursue their grievances through arbitration or small-claims court.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Initially, Yahoo mined users’ emails in part to discover products they bought through receipts from e-commerce companies such as 






            &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotes.wsj.com/AMZN&quot;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;company-name-type&quot;&gt; Inc.,&lt;/span&gt;


       people familiar with the practice said. Yahoo salespeople told potential advertisers that about one-third of Yahoo Mail users were active Amazon customers, one of the people said. In 2015, Amazon stopped including full itemized receipts in the emails it sends customers, partly because the company didn’t want Yahoo and others gathering that data for their own use, someone familiar with the matter said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yahoo Mail, an email pioneer, struggled as users defected to Gmail. When 




      Marissa Mayer, 




       a former Google executive, joined Yahoo as CEO in 2012, she made email central to her strategy.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/yahoo-triples-estimate-of-breached-accounts-to-3-billion-1507062804?mod=article_inline&quot; class=&quot;icon none&quot;&gt; Yahoo’s reputation took a hit in 2016, when it said a data breach&lt;/a&gt; compromised many users’ privacy. Ms. Mayer, who left Yahoo after Verizon bought it, didn’t respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Verizon created Oath following its Yahoo and AOL acquisitions, putting former AOL head 




      Tim Armstrong




       in charge. Oath didn’t make Mr. Armstrong available for comment.&lt;/p&gt; 






       




       &lt;p&gt;In meetings with marketers, Oath representatives have acknowledged that many people use Yahoo Mail as their primary service for unwanted commercial email, one of the people who heard the pitch said. They indicated this is an advantage for advertisers who want to collect as much commercial data on users as possible, the person said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some Oath advertisers said the pool of potential Yahoo Mail users is too small to send highly targeted ads. Even out of tens of millions of users, only a small portion are likely to have bought specific items, one advertiser said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Others have raised questions about user privacy under Oath’s system. “I think the challenge of it,” said 




      Rob Griffin, 




       chief technology officer of digital-ad consultancy Tovo Labs, “is how do you monetize it without the icky factor?”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write to &lt;/strong&gt;Douglas MacMillan at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:douglas.macmillan@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;douglas.macmillan@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;, Sarah Krouse at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sarah.krouse@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;sarah.krouse@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt; and Keach Hagey at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:keach.hagey@wsj.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon &quot;&gt;keach.hagey@wsj.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;






      &lt;/div&gt;



  &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;p class=&quot;printheadline&quot;&gt;
      Appeared in the August 29, 2018, print edition as 'Yahoo, Bucking Industry, Scans Emails for Data to Sell.'
    &lt;/p&gt;




</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 14:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hemancuso</dc:creator>
<og:title>Yahoo, Bucking Industry, Scans Emails for Data to Sell Advertisers</og:title>
<og:description>The Web giant owned by Verizon analyzes more than 200 million inboxes for clues about what products people might buy—a practice much of Silicon Valley has declared off-limits.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.wsj.com/articles/yahoo-bucking-industry-scans-emails-for-data-to-sell-advertisers-1535466959</og:url>
<og:image>https://images.wsj.net/im-23619/social</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wsj.com/articles/yahoo-bucking-industry-scans-emails-for-data-to-sell-advertisers-1535466959</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>