<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Bill Gates has stepped down from Microsoft&amp;#039;s board</title>
<link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/microsoft-announces-change-to-its-board-of-directors-301023293.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/microsoft-announces-change-to-its-board-of-directors-301023293.html</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xn-location&quot;&gt;REDMOND, Wash.&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;xn-chron&quot;&gt;March 13, 2020&lt;/span&gt; /PRNewswire/ -- Microsoft Corp. today announced that Co-Founder and Technology Advisor &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Bill Gates&lt;/span&gt; stepped down from the company's Board of Directors to dedicate more time to his philanthropic priorities including global health, development, education, and his increasing engagement in tackling climate change. He will continue to serve as Technology Advisor to CEO &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Satya Nadella&lt;/span&gt; and other leaders in the company.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;span class=&quot;xn-chron&quot;&gt;June 27, 2008&lt;/span&gt;, Gates transitioned out of a day-to-day role in the company to spend more time on his work at the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation. He served as Microsoft's chairman of the board until &lt;span class=&quot;xn-chron&quot;&gt;February 4, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's been a tremendous honor and privilege to have worked with and learned from Bill over the years. Bill founded our company with a belief in the democratizing force of software and a passion to solve society's most pressing challenges. And Microsoft and the world are better for it. The board has benefited from Bill's leadership and vision. And Microsoft will continue to benefit from Bill's ongoing technical passion and advice to drive our products and services forward. I am grateful for Bill's friendship and look forward to continuing to work alongside him to realize our mission to empower every person and every organization on the planet to achieve more,&quot; said Microsoft CEO &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Satya Nadella&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;On behalf of our shareholders and the Board, I want to express my deep appreciation to Bill for all his contributions to Microsoft. As a member of the Board, he challenged us to think big and then think even bigger. He leaves an enduring legacy of curiosity and insight that serves as an inspiration for us all,&quot; said &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;John W. Thompson&lt;/span&gt;, Microsoft independent board chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Gates' departure, the Board will consist of 12 members, including John W. Thompson, Microsoft independent chair; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Reid Hoffman&lt;/span&gt;, partner at Greylock Partners; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Hugh Johnston&lt;/span&gt;, vice chairman and chief financial officer of PepsiCo; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Teri L. List-Stoll&lt;/span&gt;, executive vice president and chief financial officer of Gap, Inc.; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Satya Nadella&lt;/span&gt;, chief executive officer of Microsoft; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Sandra E. Peterson&lt;/span&gt;, operating partner, Clayton, Dubilier &amp;amp; Rice; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Penny Pritzker&lt;/span&gt;, founder and chairman, PSP Partners; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Charles W. Scharf&lt;/span&gt;, chief executive officer and president of Wells Fargo &amp;amp; Co.; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Arne Sorenson&lt;/span&gt;, president and CEO, Marriott International Inc.; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;John W. Stanton&lt;/span&gt;, chairman of Trilogy Equity Partners; &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Emma Walmsley&lt;/span&gt;, CEO of GlaxoSmithKline plc (GSK); and &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Padmasree Warrior&lt;/span&gt;, founder, CEO and president, Fable Group Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft (Nasdaq &quot;MSFT&quot; @microsoft) enables digital transformation for the era of an intelligent cloud and an intelligent edge. Its mission is to empower every person and every organization on the planet to achieve more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SOURCE Microsoft Corporation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://rt.prnewswire.com/rt.gif?NewsItemId=SF50289&amp;amp;Transmission_Id=202003131702PR_NEWS_USPR_____SF50289&amp;amp;DateId=20200313&quot;/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Related Links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Link to http://www.microsoft.com&quot; href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com&quot; class=&quot;linkOnClick&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 21:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>janvdberg</dc:creator>
<og:title>Microsoft announces change to its board of directors</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:description>/PRNewswire/ -- Microsoft Corp. today announced that Co-Founder and Technology Advisor Bill Gates stepped down from the company's Board of Directors to...</og:description>
<og:image>https://mma.prnewswire.com/media/24227/microsoft_corp_logo226_9217jpg.jpg?p=facebook</og:image>
<og:url>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/microsoft-announces-change-to-its-board-of-directors-301023293.html</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/microsoft-announces-change-to-its-board-of-directors-301023293.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>&amp;#039;Dead Sea Scrolls&amp;#039; at museum turn out to be forgeries</title>
<link>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/2020/03/museum-of-the-bible-dead-sea-scrolls-forgeries/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/2020/03/museum-of-the-bible-dead-sea-scrolls-forgeries/</guid>
<description>&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;On the fourth floor of the Museum of the Bible, a sweeping permanent exhibit tells the story of how the ancient scripture became the world’s most popular book. A warmly lit sanctum at the exhibit’s heart reveals some of the museum’s most prized possessions: fragments of the Dead Sea Scrolls, ancient texts that include the oldest known surviving copies of the Hebrew Bible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;But now, the Washington, D.C. museum has confirmed a bitter truth about the fragments’ authenticity. On Friday, independent researchers funded by the Museum of the Bible announced that all 16 of the museum’s Dead Sea Scroll fragments are modern forgeries that duped outside collectors, the museum’s founder, and some of the world’s leading biblical scholars. Officials unveiled the findings at an academic conference hosted by the museum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;“The Museum of the Bible is trying to be as transparent as possible,” says CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.museumofthebible.org/leadership&quot;&gt;Harry Hargrave&lt;/a&gt;. “We’re victims—we’re victims of misrepresentation, we’re victims of fraud.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;In a report spanning more than 200 pages, a team of researchers led by art fraud investigator &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artfraudinsights.com/colette_loll/&quot;&gt;Colette Loll&lt;/a&gt; found that while the pieces are probably made of ancient leather, they were inked in modern times and modified to resemble real Dead Sea Scrolls. “These fragments were manipulated with the intent to deceive,” Loll says.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;The new findings don’t cast doubt on the 100,000 real Dead Sea Scroll fragments, most of which lie in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imj.org.il/en/wings/shrine-book/dead-sea-scrolls&quot;&gt;the Shrine of the Book&lt;/a&gt;, part of the Israel Museum, Jerusalem. However, the report’s findings raise grave questions about &lt;a href=&quot;https://lyingpen.com/2020/01/13/a-list-of-70-unprovenanced-post-2002-dead-sea-scrolls-like-fragments/&quot;&gt;the “post-2002” Dead Sea Scroll fragments&lt;/a&gt;, a group of some 70 snippets of biblical text that entered the antiquities market in the 2000s. Even before the new report, some scholars believed that most to all of the post-2002 fragments were modern fakes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;“Once one or two of the fragments were fake, you know all of them probably are, because they come from the same sources, and they look basically the same,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uia.no/en/kk/profil/arsteinj&quot;&gt;Årstein Justnes&lt;/a&gt;, a researcher at Norway’s University of Agder whose &lt;a href=&quot;https://lyingpen.com/&quot;&gt;Lying Pen of Scribes&lt;/a&gt; project tracks the post-2002 fragments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot; class=&quot;clearfix&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 18:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<og:title>Exclusive: 'Dead Sea Scrolls' at the Museum of the Bible are all forgeries</og:title>
<og:description>Months of testing confirm earlier suspicions that the fragments were made in modern times. What happens next?</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/2020/03/museum-of-the-bible-dead-sea-scrolls-forgeries/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/content/dam/archaeologyandhistory/2020/03/dead-sea-scrolls/dead-sea-scrolls-testing-fragment-white1.ngsversion.1584144013126.adapt.1900.1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/2020/03/museum-of-the-bible-dead-sea-scrolls-forgeries/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>WWDC to Be Moved Online</title>
<link>https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=03132020a</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=03132020a</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;lighter article-date&quot;&gt;March 13, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;This June, WWDC20 brings a completely new online experience to millions of talented and creative developers around the world. Join us for a fully packed program — including Keynote and sessions — to gain early access to the future of Apple platforms and engage with Apple engineers. Dive into an exciting learning experience and discover how to create your most innovative apps yet using the latest Apple technologies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;article-text&quot;&gt;Stay tuned for details on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/wwdc20/&quot;&gt;WWDC20 website&lt;/a&gt;, by email, and in the &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/apple-developer/id640199958/&quot;&gt;Apple Developer app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>css</dc:creator>
<og:title>WWDC20. Coming this summer. - News - Apple Developer</og:title>
<og:description>This June, WWDC20 brings a completely new online experience to millions of talented and creative developers around the world. Join us for a fully packed program — including Keynote and sessions — to gain early access to the future of Apple platforms and engage with Apple engineers. Dive into an exciting learning experience and discover how to create your most innovative apps yet using the latest Apple technologies.Stay tuned for details on the WWDC20 website, by email, and in the Apple Developer app.</og:description>
<og:url>https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=03132020a</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=03132020a</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Slack account takeovers using HTTP Request Smuggling</title>
<link>https://hackerone.com/reports/737140</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://hackerone.com/reports/737140</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Browser not supported :( - HackerOne&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, user-scalable=yes, initial-scale=1&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;Content-Security-Policy&quot; content=&quot;default-src 'none'; base-uri 'self'; font-src 'self'; form-action 'none'; img-src 'self'; style-src 'self'&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; media=&quot;screen&quot; href=&quot;/assets/static_pages-a82409578e1edfb0c6ef16853b4f9b760c9407be98f7805ea598fb0e8bc1a382.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;not-supported non-boxless&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;23.340747330961&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;topbar&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackerone.com/&quot; class=&quot;topbar-logo&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;27&quot; height=&quot;32&quot; src=&quot;https://hackerone.com/assets/static_pages/logo-2ece2531df044c27fdb123146a12f674e6414ae8dbff01b24b22d3ed87324da6.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wrapper&quot; readability=&quot;8.4875444839858&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;status-page-image&quot; src=&quot;https://hackerone.com/assets/static_pages/batman-fb3629633550541f793df4606ccd843e996e63677ba8a0d5f744240764b3b5b0.gif&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;not-supported-intro&quot;&gt;You are visiting this page because we detected an unsupported browser. Your browser does not support security features that we require. We highly recommend that you update your browser. If you believe you have arrived here in error, please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@hackerone.com&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;. Be sure to include your browser version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;browsers-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;supported-intro&quot;&gt;These are the ones we recommend:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 15:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bartkappenburg</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://hackerone.com/browser-not-supported.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twilio releases open source video conferencing apps for iOS, Android and web</title>
<link>https://www.twilio.com/blog/open-source-video-apps-reactjs-ios-android</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.twilio.com/blog/open-source-video-apps-reactjs-ios-android</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Today we are excited to announce that we are open sourcing three video collaboration applications, one for iOS, one for Android, and a ReactJS one for the Web. Whether you are building a healthcare, education, or general video collaboration solution, these apps can accelerate development by providing you with a fully functioning video app that can be deployed to the cloud in minutes. In addition, they provide a canonical reference for developers building out their communication solutions by showcasing the Programmable Video capabilities. These applications are available today on Github under the Apache 2.0 license:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Twilio we strive to build a reliable, extensible platform so that our customers can build high quality communication experiences in their applications. Our Video SDKs provide the API building blocks for mobile and web developers to create custom communications experiences in their apps. We believe we can help our customers build better communications apps by producing these fully featured reference apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Image shows how the open source app renders across desktop, iPhone, and Android.&quot; class=&quot;richtext-image left&quot; height=&quot;429&quot; sizes=&quot;480px&quot; src=&quot;https://twilio-cms-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/images/Image_from_iOS_4.width-500.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://twilio-cms-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/images/Image_from_iOS_4.width-500.jpg 480w, https://twilio-cms-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/images/Image_from_iOS_4.width-1000.jpg 480w&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above image shows how the open source app renders across desktop, iPhone, and Android.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open Source Video Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team began implementing these applications as an internal means to exercise and validate the Programmable Video APIs. Over the years, we have found that the implementation and daily use of these applications provide valuable feedback for building a better Video platform. Additionally, we believe these applications can be helpful to developers embarking on building or enhancing their own Programmable Video apps. These apps are intended to accelerate development, provide a full reference of Programmable Video, and demonstrate best practices with easy-to-read code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How is this different from a Quickstart?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twilio uses quickstarts as a means to introduce developers to our Programmable Video SDKs. The quickstarts provide a simple and quick way for developers to build a reference app and familiarize themselves with the different capabilities of the platform with a minimal amount of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the purpose of these open source apps is to provide a more comprehensive demonstration of Programmable Video features such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Connecting to a Room and publishing audio &amp;amp; video tracks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screen sharing between participants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining participant bandwidth usage with Network Bandwidth Profile API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitoring network conditions with Network Quality API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These applications leverage a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twilio-labs/plugin-rtc&quot;&gt;Twilio CLI RTC plugin&lt;/a&gt; which supports quickly developing and deploying real-time communication applications using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twilio.com/docs/runtime&quot;&gt;Twilio Runtime&lt;/a&gt;. You can go from exploring an application’s source code to trying it out for yourself in 3 steps. The snippet belows shows an example of how to deploy the web application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 13:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>devinrader</dc:creator>
<og:title>Deploy your own video collaboration app in five minutes or less</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.twilio.com/blog/open-source-video-apps-reactjs-ios-android</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:image>https://twilio-cms-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/original_images/Copy_of_Product_Template_-_Video_2.png</og:image>
<og:description>Get a head start on your video app development with three new Twilio open sourced video collaboration applications for iOS, Android, and ReactJS for the Web.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.twilio.com/blog/open-source-video-apps-reactjs-ios-android</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Europe Wants a ‘Right to Repair’ Smartphones and Gadgets</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/12/world/europe/eu-right-to-repair-smartphones.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/12/world/europe/eu-right-to-repair-smartphones.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;LONDON — Hoping to replace that two-year-old smartphone in a few months? The European Union wants you to think twice about doing that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The bloc announced an ambitious plan on Wednesday that would require manufacturers of electronic products, from smartphones to tumble driers, to offer more repairs, upgrades and ways to reuse existing goods, instead of encouraging consumers to buy new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The “right to repair,” part of a wide-ranging &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/04/world/europe/eu-climate-law-greta-thunberg.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;policy package known as the Green Deal&lt;/a&gt; that was introduced this month, is the latest example of the European Union’s ambitions to promote more sustainable economic growth and to prevent waste. It extends standards brought in last year that put “right to repair” obligations on the manufacturers of some large appliances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The linear growth model of ‘take-make-use-discard’ has reached its limits,” Virginijus Sinkevicius, the union’s environment commissioner, told reporters in Brussels as he presented the “&lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/environment/circular-economy/pdf/new_circular_economy_action_plan.pdf&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Circular Economy Action Plan&lt;/a&gt;,” which includes the “right to repair” initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We want to make sure that products placed on E.U. market are designed to last longer, to be easier to repair and upgrade, easier to recycle and easier to reuse,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The plans are being put forward by the bloc’s executive arm, the European Commission. To become law, they would need to win the approval of the European Union’s Parliament and the governments of its 27 member states, a process experts say would take at least four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Mr. Sinckevicius said the proposal reflected a growing demand from consumers. According to the commissioner, surveys have found that two-thirds of European citizens want their electronic devices to serve them longer. They have also indicated support for clearer indications on a product’s life span, easier repairs or more readily available replacement parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Manufacturers like Apple take old iPhones back when consumers buy a new one, but the E.U. plan wants them to go one step further: If implemented, it would encourage consumers to buy less and to keep a product in use as long as possible, and encourage industries to consider recycling only when a device is no longer usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Environmental groups said the plan represented a shift from the European Union’s current policy, which is mostly based on recycling. A law passed in 2012 required countries to collect 65 tons of electronic waste for every 100 tons of goods put on sale by 2019, but members have not met such targets. Less than 40 percent of European electronic waste is recycled, according to E.U. estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;With the “right to repair,” upgrading a phone’s software, replacing the battery of a tablet, or buying a new display for a laptop instead of changing the whole device would become easier, said Jean-Pierre Schweitzer, from the European Environmental Bureau, a network of environmental citizens’ groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“We know people are ready for it,” said Mr. Schweitzer, who focuses on circular economy and product policy at the network. “The measures that the commission wants to take on products and repair are very, very good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The plan also includes measures to introduce a &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/17/business/european-union-phone-charger.html&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;common charger for smartphones&lt;/a&gt; — an effort that the European Union has long tried to implement, with little success — targets to reduce packaging, and a new framework to recycle batteries and textiles, among other measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Mr. Sinkevicius, the European commissioner, said the measures were essential if Europe was to meet its aim under the Green Deal: becoming a net zero emitter of greenhouse gases by 2050. “What we are trying to reach is a little bit different perception of the economic model,” he said this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But just as climate activists criticized the Green Deal as too vague, and for not setting a 2030 target, advocates like Mr. Schweitzer also faulted the European Commission for not setting broader, compulsory targets to reduce resource consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“It’s not all negative,” Mr. Schweitzer said. “But where do we want the economy to be in the next couple of years? How much do we want to reduce our material or water footprint? We’re missing the big picture.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-ew4tgv&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 10:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/12/world/europe/eu-right-to-repair-smartphones.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Europe Wants a ‘Right to Repair’ Smartphones and Gadgets</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/03/12/world/12eu-repair/EU-REPAIR-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>The European Union is seeking to help consumers fix or upgrade devices, rather than replace them, as part of a 30-year push to reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/12/world/europe/eu-right-to-repair-smartphones.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why the second wave of the 1918 Spanish flu was so deadly</title>
<link>https://www.history.com/news/spanish-flu-second-wave-resurgence</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.history.com/news/spanish-flu-second-wave-resurgence</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;m-detail-header mm-detail-header--in-content-well&quot;/&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;m-social mm-social--below-header&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-detail--body&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- tml-version=&quot;2&quot; --&gt;&lt;p&gt;The horrific scale of the 1918 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/world-war-i/1918-flu-pandemic&quot;&gt;Spanish flu&lt;/a&gt; pandemic is hard to fathom. The virus infected 500 million people worldwide and killed an estimated 20 million to 50 million victims— &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/news/spanish-flu&quot;&gt;that’s more&lt;/a&gt; than all of the soldiers and civilians killed during &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/world-war-i/world-war-i-history&quot;&gt;World War I&lt;/a&gt; combined. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/middle-ages/pandemics-timeline&quot;&gt;global pandemic &lt;/a&gt;lasted for two years, the vast majority of deaths were packed into three especially cruel months in the fall of 1918. Historians now believe that the fatal severity of the Spanish flu’s “second wave” was caused by a mutated virus spread by wartime troop movements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-b not-size-c not-size-d&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Spanish flu first appeared in early March 1918, it had all the hallmarks of a seasonal flu, albeit a highly contagious and virulent strain. One of the first registered cases was Albert Gitchell, a U.S. Army cook at Camp Funston in Kansas, who was hospitalized with a 104-degree fever. The virus spread quickly through the Army installation, home to 54,000 troops. By the end of the month, 1,100 troops had been hospitalized and 38 had died after developing pneumonia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-gallery-invite m-detail--body-item m-gallery-invite--landscape-slide&quot; phx-gallery=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;phx-gallery-image data-caption-html=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Boys wear bags of camphor around their necks around the time of the 1918-19 Spanish flu—an “old-wives’ method of flue-prevention,” &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://books.google.com/books?id=oE0EAAAAMBAJ&amp;amp;amp;pg=PA115&amp;amp;amp;lpg=PA115&amp;amp;amp;dq=%22camphor%22+around+the+neck+flu+prevention&amp;amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;amp;ots=_uCbKyifWV&amp;amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U32G7iTSJIEkucwflpQ8W6tztNIsA&amp;amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiumbqJk7bnAhVNj1kKHb2kD3MQ6AEwCnoECAgQAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;amp;q=%22camphor%22%20around%20the%20neck%20flu%20prevention&amp;amp;amp;f=false&amp;quot;&amp;gt;according&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to a December 1946 issue of &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Life&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; magazine.&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-full-height=&quot;1589&quot; data-full-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_2000%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_2000/MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3NDA1NjI0/gettyimages-515581890.jpg&quot; data-full-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-image-id=&quot;ci025cc549b0002738&quot; data-image-slug=&quot;GettyImages-515581890&quot; data-public-id=&quot;MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3NDA1NjI0&quot; data-source-name=&quot;Bettmann Archive/Getty Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;phx-gallery-image data-caption-html=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Spanish flu was a &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2862337/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;huge concern&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; for WWI military forces. Here, men gargle saltwater to prevent infection at the War Garden at Camp Dix (&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.militarybases.us/army/fort-dix/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;now Fort Dix&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;) in New Jersey, circa 1918.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Read more: &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.history.com/news/spanish-flu-deaths-october-1918&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Why October 1918 Was America's Deadliest Month Ever&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-full-height=&quot;1554&quot; data-full-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_2000%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_2000/MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MjA4NDc4/gettyimages-108882878.jpg&quot; data-full-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-image-id=&quot;ci025cc549a0002738&quot; data-image-slug=&quot;GettyImages-108882878&quot; data-public-id=&quot;MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MjA4NDc4&quot; data-source-name=&quot;PhotoQuest/Getty Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;phx-gallery-image data-caption-html=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;A woman wears a sci-fi-looking flu nozzle attached to a machine circa 1919. It’s not clear how it worked or if it had any health benefits.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-full-height=&quot;1465&quot; data-full-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_2000%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_2000/MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MTQzNDgw/gettyimages-2660331.jpg&quot; data-full-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-image-id=&quot;ci025cc54980002738&quot; data-image-slug=&quot;GettyImages-2660331&quot; data-public-id=&quot;MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MTQzNDgw&quot; data-source-name=&quot;Topical Press Agency/Getty Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;phx-gallery-image data-caption-html=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Donning a mask, a man uses a pump to spray an unknown “anti-flu” substance in the United Kingdom, circa 1920.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-full-height=&quot;1607&quot; data-full-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_2000%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_2000/MTcwMjI3ODA1MTM1NTc4Mzk4/gettyimages-613476274.jpg&quot; data-full-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-image-id=&quot;ci025cc549b0012738&quot; data-image-slug=&quot;GettyImages-613476274&quot; data-public-id=&quot;MTcwMjI3ODA1MTM1NTc4Mzk4&quot; data-source-name=&quot;Hulton-Deutsch Collection/Corbis/Getty Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;phx-gallery-image data-caption-html=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Professor Bordier of France’s University of Lyon apparently claimed that this machine could cure colds in minutes. This photo circa 1928 shows him demonstrating his own machine.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-full-height=&quot;1448&quot; data-full-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_2000%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_2000/MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3Mjc0MDE0/gettyimages-517387234.jpg&quot; data-full-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-image-id=&quot;ci025cc549c000251e&quot; data-image-slug=&quot;GettyImages-517387234&quot; data-public-id=&quot;MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3Mjc0MDE0&quot; data-source-name=&quot;Bettmann Archive/Getty Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;phx-gallery-image data-caption-html=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;People in London wear masks to avoid catching the flu circa 1932. This is a preventative method people still use around the world today.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-full-height=&quot;1406&quot; data-full-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_2000%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_2000/MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MjA5MDE2/gettyimages-2716720.jpg&quot; data-full-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-image-id=&quot;ci025cc54990012738&quot; data-image-slug=&quot;GettyImages-2716720&quot; data-public-id=&quot;MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MjA5MDE2&quot; data-source-name=&quot;Fox Photos/Getty Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;phx-gallery-image data-caption-html=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;People in England wear different-looking masks to prevent the flu circa 1932.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-full-height=&quot;1441&quot; data-full-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_2000%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_2000/MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MzQwMDg4/gettyimages-82090912.jpg&quot; data-full-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-image-id=&quot;ci025cc5499000251e&quot; data-image-slug=&quot;GettyImages-82090912&quot; data-public-id=&quot;MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MzQwMDg4&quot; data-source-name=&quot;Imagno/Getty Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;phx-gallery-image data-caption-html=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This baby’s parents had the right idea in this photo circa 1939. The flu can spread between people &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.cdc.gov/flu/about/disease/spread.htm&amp;quot;&amp;gt;up to six feet away&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, and because babies have a &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.cdc.gov/flu/highrisk/infantcare.htm&amp;quot;&amp;gt;high risk&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; of developing serious flu-related complications, it’s best for people who haven’t received flu shots to stay away.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Read more: &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.history.com/topics/middle-ages/pandemics-timeline&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Pandemics That Changed History&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-full-height=&quot;1462&quot; data-full-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_2000%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_2000/MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3Mjc0NTUy/gettyimages-3312859.jpg&quot; data-full-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-image-id=&quot;ci025cc5498000251e&quot; data-image-slug=&quot;GettyImages-3312859&quot; data-public-id=&quot;MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3Mjc0NTUy&quot; data-source-name=&quot;Harry Shepherd/Fox Photos/Getty Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;phx-gallery-image data-caption-html=&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;British actress Molly Lamont (far right) receives her “emergency flu rations” of oranges at Elstree Studios in London, circa 1940.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot; data-full-height=&quot;1430&quot; data-full-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_2000%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_2000/MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MTQyOTQy/gettyimages-3421496.jpg&quot; data-full-width=&quot;2000&quot; data-image-id=&quot;ci025cc54990002738&quot; data-image-slug=&quot;GettyImages-3421496&quot; data-public-id=&quot;MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3MTQyOTQy&quot; data-source-name=&quot;Fox Photos/Getty Images&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-gallery-invite--slides&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-gallery-invite--slide-container&quot;&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;m-gallery-invite--slide&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;m-gallery-invite--slide-image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_fit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Ch_406%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_620/MTcwMjI3ODA0ODY3NDA1NjI0/gettyimages-515581890.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GettyImages-515581890&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot;/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As U.S. troops deployed en masse for the war effort in Europe, they carried the Spanish flu with them. Throughout April and May of 1918, the virus spread like wildfire through England, France, Spain and Italy. An estimated three-quarters of the French military was infected in the spring of 1918 and as many as half of British troops. Luckily, the first wave of the virus wasn’t particularly deadly, with symptoms like high fever and malaise usually lasting only three days, and mortality rates were similar to seasonal flu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-a not-size-b&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-a not-size-c not-size-d&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-b not-size-c not-size-d&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How the Spanish Flu Got Its Name&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, it was during this time that the Spanish flu &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/news/why-was-it-called-the-spanish-flu&quot;&gt;earned its misnomer&lt;/a&gt;. Spain was neutral during World War I and unlike its European neighbors, it didn’t impose wartime censorship on its press. In France, England and the United States, newspapers weren’t allowed to report on anything that could harm the war effort, including news that a crippling virus was sweeping through troops. Since Spanish journalists were some of the only ones reporting on a widespread flu outbreak in the spring of 1918, the pandemic became known as the “Spanish flu.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reported cases of Spanish flu dropped off over the summer of 1918, and there was hope at the beginning of August that the virus had run its course. In retrospect, it was only the calm before the storm. Somewhere in Europe, a mutated strain of the Spanish flu virus had emerged that had the power to kill a perfectly healthy young man or woman within 24 hours of showing the first signs of infection. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late August 1918, military ships departed the English port city of Plymouth carrying troops unknowingly infected with this new, far deadlier strain of Spanish flu. As these ships arrived in cities like Brest in France, Boston in the United States and Freetown in South Africa, the second wave of the global pandemic began. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-b not-size-c not-size-d&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The rapid movement of soldiers around the globe was a major spreader of the disease,” says James Harris, a historian at Ohio State University who studies both infectious disease and World War I. “The entire military industrial complex of moving lots of men and material in crowded conditions was certainly a huge contributing factor in the ways the pandemic spread.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-a not-size-b&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-a not-size-c not-size-d&quot;/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Virus Killed the Young, Old and In-Between&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-detail--body-item m-detail--body-item-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;l-inline tml-image m-detail--tml-image--inline&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;phoenix-picture&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;picture class=&quot;is-waiting-to-load&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1240px) 700px, (min-width: 675px) 620px, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_380/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.webp 380w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_620/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.webp 620w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_1240/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.webp 1240w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_700/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.webp 700w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_1400/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.webp 1400w&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1240px) 700px, (min-width: 675px) 620px, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_380/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.jpg 380w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_620/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.jpg 620w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_1240/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.jpg 1240w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_700/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.jpg 700w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_1400/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.jpg 1400w&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;m-detail--tml-image m-image&quot; alt=&quot;1918 Flu&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/t_share/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_700/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.jpg&quot; height=&quot;1284&quot; width=&quot;2284&quot; srcset=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl url&quot;/&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/phoenix-picture&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;tml-image--caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Victims of the Spanish flu at a barracks hospital on the campus of Colorado Agricultural College, Fort Collins, Colorado, 1918.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;tml-image--attribution&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;American Unofficial Collection of World War I Photographs/PhotoQuest/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;From September through November of 1918, the death rate from the Spanish flu skyrocketed. In the United States alone, 195,000 Americans died from the Spanish flu in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/news/spanish-flu-deaths-october-1918&quot;&gt;just the month of October&lt;/a&gt;. And unlike a normal seasonal flu, which mostly claims victims among the very young and very old, the second wave of the Spanish flu exhibited what’s called a “W curve”—high numbers of deaths among the young and old, but also a huge spike in the middle composed of otherwise healthy 25- to 35-year-olds in the prime of their life. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“That really freaked out the medical establishment, that there was this atypical spike in the middle of the W,” says Harris. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ MORE: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/news/spanish-flu-deaths-october-1918&quot;&gt;Why October 1918 Was America's Deadliest Month Ever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only was it shocking that healthy young men and women were dying by the millions worldwide, but it was also &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; they were dying. Struck with blistering fevers, nasal hemorrhaging and pneumonia, the patients would drown in their own fluid-filled lungs. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-b not-size-c not-size-d&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only decades later were scientists able explain the phenomenon now known as “cytokine explosion.” When the human body is being attacked by a virus, the immune system sends messenger proteins called cytokines to promote helpful inflammation. But some strains of the flu, particularly the H1N1 strain responsible for the Spanish flu outbreak, can trigger a dangerous immune overreaction in healthy individuals. In those cases, the body is overloaded with cytokines leading to severe inflammation and the fatal buildup of fluid in the lungs. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;British military doctors conducting autopsies on soldiers killed by this second wave of the Spanish flu described the heavy damage to the lungs as akin to the effects of chemical warfare. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Lack of Quarantines Allowed Flu to Spread and Grow&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-detail--body-item m-detail--body-item-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;l-inline tml-image m-detail--tml-image--inline&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;phoenix-picture&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;picture class=&quot;is-waiting-to-load&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1240px) 700px, (min-width: 675px) 620px, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_380/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.webp 380w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_620/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.webp 620w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_1240/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.webp 1240w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_700/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.webp 700w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_1400/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.webp 1400w&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1240px) 700px, (min-width: 675px) 620px, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_380/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.jpg 380w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_620/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.jpg 620w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_1240/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.jpg 1240w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_700/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.jpg 700w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_1400/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.jpg 1400w&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;m-detail--tml-image m-image&quot; alt=&quot;1918 Flu, Walter Reed Hospital&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/t_share/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_700/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Mzgy/35b32f6f-2d26-4393-86a6-e6c586acb144.jpg&quot; height=&quot;3006&quot; width=&quot;5346&quot; srcset=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl url&quot;/&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/phoenix-picture&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;tml-image--caption&quot; itemprop=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A nurse checking on a patient at the Walter Reed Hospital Flu Ward during the influenza pandemic, circa 1918.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;tml-image--attribution&quot; itemprop=&quot;author&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Harris &amp;amp; Ewing/Underwood Archives/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harris believes that the rapid spread of Spanish flu in the fall of 1918 was at least partially to blame on public health officials unwilling to impose quarantines during wartime. In Britain, for example, a government official named Arthur Newsholme knew full well that a strict civilian lockdown was the best way to fight the spread of the highly contagious disease. But he wouldn’t risk crippling the war effort by keeping munitions factory workers and other civilians home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-b not-size-c not-size-d&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Harris’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/shm/advance-article/doi/10.1093/shm/hky119/5262288&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; onclick=&quot;return phoenixTrackClickEvent(this, event);&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;, Newsholme concluded that “the relentless needs of warfare justified incurring [the] risk of spreading infection” and encouraged Britons to simply “carry on” during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The public health response to the crisis in the United States was further hampered by a severe nursing shortage as thousands of nurses had been deployed to military camps and the front lines. The shortage was worsened by the American Red Cross’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/news/black-nurses-world-war-ii-truman-desegregation-military&quot;&gt;refusal to use trained African American nurses&lt;/a&gt; until the worst of the pandemic had already passed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ MORE: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/news/black-nurses-world-war-ii-truman-desegregation-military&quot;&gt;When Black Nurses Were Relegated to Care for German POWs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Medical Science Didn't Have the Tools&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But one of the chief reasons that the Spanish flu claimed so many lives in 1918 was that science simply didn’t have the tools to develop a vaccine for the virus. Microscopes couldn’t even see something as incredibly small as a virus until the 1930s. Instead, top medical professionals in 1918 were convinced that the flu was caused by a bacterium nicknamed “Pfeiffer’s bacillus.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-a not-size-b&quot;/&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-a not-size-c not-size-d&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a global flu outbreak in 1890, a German physician named Richard Pfeiffer found that all of his infected patients carried a particular strain of bacteria he called &lt;em&gt;H. influenzae&lt;/em&gt;. When the Spanish flu pandemic hit, scientists were intent on finding a cure for Pfeiffer’s bacillus. Millions of dollars were invested in state-of-the-art labs to develop techniques for testing for and treating &lt;em&gt;H. influenzae&lt;/em&gt;, all of it for naught&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-in-content-ad-row l-inline not-size-b not-size-c not-size-d&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This was a huge distraction for medical science,” says Harris. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By December 1918, the deadly second wave of the Spanish flu had finally passed, but the pandemic was far from over. A third wave erupted in Australia in January 1919 and eventually worked its way back to Europe and the United States. It’s believed that President &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/us-presidents/woodrow-wilson&quot;&gt;Woodrow Wilson&lt;/a&gt; contracted the Spanish flu during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/topics/world-war-i/treaty-of-versailles-1&quot;&gt;World War I peace negotiations&lt;/a&gt; in Paris in April 1919. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mortality rate of the third wave was just as high as the second wave, but the end of the war in November 1918 removed the conditions that allowed the disease to spread so far and so quickly. Global deaths from the third wave, while still in the millions, paled in comparison to the apocalyptic losses during the second wave. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;m-detail--body-item m-detail--body-item-inline&quot;&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;l-inline tml-image m-detail--tml-image--inline&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;&lt;phoenix-picture&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.historyvault.com/collections/world-war-1?cmpid=VAULT_articles_spanish-flu&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return phoenixTrackClickEvent(this, event);&quot; phx-track-id=&quot;image-click&quot;&gt;&lt;picture class=&quot;is-waiting-to-load&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1240px) 700px, (min-width: 675px) 620px, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_380/MTY4MjgxOTc3NzE4NjQ2MDM3/editorial-promo-700x200-svod-hvault-topics-wwi.webp 380w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_620/MTY4MjgxOTc3NzE4NjQ2MDM3/editorial-promo-700x200-svod-hvault-topics-wwi.webp 620w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_700/MTY4MjgxOTc3NzE4NjQ2MDM3/editorial-promo-700x200-svod-hvault-topics-wwi.webp 700w&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1240px) 700px, (min-width: 675px) 620px, calc(100vw - 40px)&quot; data-srcset=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_380/MTY4MjgxOTc3NzE4NjQ2MDM3/editorial-promo-700x200-svod-hvault-topics-wwi.jpg 380w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_620/MTY4MjgxOTc3NzE4NjQ2MDM3/editorial-promo-700x200-svod-hvault-topics-wwi.jpg 620w, https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_700/MTY4MjgxOTc3NzE4NjQ2MDM3/editorial-promo-700x200-svod-hvault-topics-wwi.jpg 700w&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;m-detail--tml-image m-image mm-image--link&quot; alt=&quot;HISTORY Vault&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/t_share/MTY4MjgxOTc3NzE4NjQ2MDM3/editorial-promo-700x200-svod-hvault-topics-wwi.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.history.com/.image/c_limit%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_700/MTY4MjgxOTc3NzE4NjQ2MDM3/editorial-promo-700x200-svod-hvault-topics-wwi.jpg&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; srcset=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl url&quot;/&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/phoenix-picture&gt;&lt;figcaption/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;m-detail--footer&quot;&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;m-detail--author-box&quot;/&gt;&lt;section class=&quot;m-social mm-social--below-content&quot;/&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 08:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>onetimemanytime</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.history.com/news/spanish-flu-second-wave-resurgence</og:url>
<og:title>Why the Second Wave of the 1918 Spanish Flu Was So Deadly</og:title>
<og:description>The first strain of the Spanish flu wasn’t particularly deadly. Then it came back in the fall with a vengeance.</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.history.com/.image/t_share/MTcwODc5MDQ3ODA1NDQ1Nzgz/4d62f159-d6e1-4315-bae8-08d8cb64e412.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.history.com/news/spanish-flu-second-wave-resurgence</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Linux Kernel Teaching</title>
<link>https://linux-kernel-labs.github.io/refs/heads/master/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://linux-kernel-labs.github.io/refs/heads/master/index.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;linux-kernel-teaching&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of lectures and labs Linux kernel topics. The lectures focus on theoretical and Linux kernel exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The labs focus on device drivers topics and they resemble “howto” style documentation. Each topic has two parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;a walk-through the topic which contains an overview, the main abstractions, simple examples and pointers to APIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a hands-on part which contains a few exercises that should be resolved by the student; to focus on the topic at hand, the student is presented with a starting coding skeleton and with in-depth tips on how to solve the exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This content is based on the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://ocw.cs.pub.ro/courses/so2&quot;&gt;Operatings Systems 2&lt;/a&gt; course from the Computer Science and Engineering Department, the Faculty of Automatic Control and Computers, University POLITEHNICA of Bucharest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get the latest version at &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://github.com/linux-kernel-labs&quot;&gt;http://github.com/linux-kernel-labs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started build the documentation from the sources after installing docker-compose on you host:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight-c&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tools&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labs&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;docker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then point your browser at &lt;strong&gt;Documentation/output/labs/index.html&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can build directly on the host (see tools/labs/docs/Dockerfile for dependencies):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight-c&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tools&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labs&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;toctree-wrapper compound&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Useful info&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 04:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>throwaway_7718</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://linux-kernel-labs.github.io/refs/heads/master/index.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>P3: Pandemic Prevention Platform (2017)</title>
<link>https://www.darpa.mil/program/pandemic-prevention-platform</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.darpa.mil/program/pandemic-prevention-platform</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The Pandemic Prevention Platform (P3) program aims to support military readiness and global stability through pursuit of novel methods to dramatically accelerate discovery, integration, pre-clinical testing, and manufacturing of medical countermeasures against infectious diseases. P3 confronts the reality that Department of Defense (DoD) personnel are not only deployed around the world for routine operations, but are often among the first responders to outbreaks of emerging or re-emerging disease with pandemic potential (e.g., Ebola). P3 aims specifically to develop a scalable, adaptable, rapid response platform capable of producing relevant numbers of doses against any known or previously unknown infectious threat within 60 days of identification of such a threat in order to keep the outbreak from escalating and decrease disruptions to the military and homeland. State-of-the-art medical countermeasures often take many months or even years to develop, produce, distribute, and administer. The envisioned P3 platform would cut response time to weeks and stay within the window of relevance for containing an outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P3 focuses on rapid discovery, characterization, production, testing, and delivery of efficacious DNA- and RNA-encoded medical countermeasures, a foundational technology pioneered by DARPA under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darpa.mil/program/autonomous-diagnostics-to-enable-prevention-and-therapeutics&quot;&gt;Autonomous Diagnostics to Enable Prevention and Therapeutics (ADEPT)&lt;/a&gt; program that provides the body with instructions on how to immediately begin producing protective antibodies against a given threat. The P3 program seeks to unlock the potential of these coded genetic constructs—establishing them as the basis for a threat-agnostic platform technology—by achieving and integrating breakthroughs in three key areas: novel approaches for the growth of viruses for use in testing and evaluation of countermeasures; rapid identification and maturation of protective antibodies to increase their potency; and novel technologies for the delivery of nucleic acid constructs into patients to encode the antibody of interest and produce a protective response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A principal benefit of the nucleic-acid-based approach to limiting the spread of infection is that genetic constructs introduced into the body would process quickly and not integrate into an individual’s genome. Similarly, the antibodies produced in response to treatment would only be present in the body for weeks to months. This is consistent with DARPA's intent to safely deliver transient immunity, halting the spread of disease by creating a firewall, and buying time for longer-term medical responses to be developed and deployed.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 23:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>hdivider</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.darpa.mil/program/pandemic-prevention-platform</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Court outlaws German Weather Service&amp;#039;s free weather app</title>
<link>https://www.dw.com/en/court-outlaws-german-weather-services-free-weather-app/a-52735502</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.dw.com/en/court-outlaws-german-weather-services-free-weather-app/a-52735502</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The German Weather Service (DWD) will no longer be allowed to provide general weather forecasts in a free mobile phone app after a federal court ruled in favor of a private firm on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Court of Justice (BGH) in Karlsruhe said the national meteorological service will only be permitted to offer extreme weather warnings for free and that a DWD app offering general weather forecasts must contain advertisements or be purchased by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;picBox full rechts&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;overlayLink&quot; href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/court-outlaws-german-weather-services-free-weather-app/a-52735502#&quot; link=&quot;/overlay/image/article/52735502/47613340&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/47613340_401.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Karlsruhe - Bundesgerichtshof (picture-alliance/dpa/S. Gollnow)&quot; alt=&quot;Karlsruhe - Bundesgerichtshof (picture-alliance/dpa/S. Gollnow)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The federal court ruled against the DWD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case came about when a lawsuit was filed by private provider WetterOnline against the DWD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unfair advantage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The private Bonn-based firm considered the DWD app anti-competitive as it put commercial providers at a disadvantage since they could not provide the information for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now, the DWD offered an application that could be used to retrieve not only severe warnings but also general forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The judges in Karlsruhe ruled in favor of the private firm as the German Weather Service, based in Offenbach, Hesse, had exceeded the legal mandate for its activities with this offer and wanted to limit the DWD's activities to protect private competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;longText&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery col3&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;imgTeaserL slideshow noDim&quot; data-id=&quot;52010970&quot; data-title=&quot;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&quot; data-date=&quot;20200302&quot; data-firstcategory=&quot;19990033&quot; data-secondcategory=&quot;19990021&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;slides&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;first&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/52605017_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Antarctica Melts Under Its Hottest Days on Record (Earth Observatory/ NASA)&quot; alt=&quot;Antarctica Melts Under Its Hottest Days on Record (Earth Observatory/ NASA)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A California day at the South Pole&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Antarctica, scientists measured temperatures on par with Los Angeles. In February, a record 18.3 degrees Celsius (64.9 degrees Fahrenheit) was measured at the Argentinean research station Esperanza Base in the north Antarctic. This was the highest temperature since measurements began there, according to NASA. The warm weather led to quickly developing melt ponds (pictured right).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/50335607_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Satellite view of Hurricane Dorian on the US coast (AFP/Rammb/Noaa/Ho)&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite view of Hurricane Dorian on the US coast (AFP/Rammb/Noaa/Ho)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More frequent and stronger storms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As oceans warm, the intensity of tropical cyclones will increase. The hurricane or typhoon season will last longer and there will be significantly more hurricanes, especially in the North Atlantic and the northeast Pacific. Extreme weather conditions will result in extremely destructive storms in the future, even in regions that have so far been spared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/50280094_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;People walking through flooded areas after Hurricane Dorian (picture alliance/AP Images/AP Photo/R. Espinosa) &quot; alt=&quot;People walking through flooded areas after Hurricane Dorian (picture alliance/AP Images/AP Photo/R. Espinosa) &quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rising sea levels and storm surges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oceans warm along with the rising temperatures of the Earth's atmosphere, albeit with a delay. This leads to a thermal expansion of the water masses, causing sea levels to rise further. The habitats and livelihoods of numerous coastal inhabitants — especially in poorer regions — will be lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;0.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/51899256_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A bushfire in Australia (Reuters/AAP Image/D. )&quot; alt=&quot;A bushfire in Australia (Reuters/AAP Image/D. )&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forest fires as a result of extreme weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there will be heavy precipitation and flooding in some places, extreme weather conditions elsewhere will cause very dry periods. Crop failures and devastating forest fires will be the result. The fire season will last much longer in many places, and the number of fires will increase dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/16059973_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A cod (by-nc-sa/Joachim S. Müller)&quot; alt=&quot;A cod (by-nc-sa/Joachim S. Müller)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;40&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Relocating entire ecosystems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warmer oceans will drive species, and eventually entire marine ecosystems, into colder regions. Fish and marine mammals will migrate toward the poles, just like land animals. The cod populations in the North Sea, for example, are already shrinking faster than can be explained by overfishing alone. Fishing regions further north could benefit from this development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/1733781_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Water snail Limacina&quot; alt=&quot;Water snail Limacina&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;40&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acidified seas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heating causes CO2 to dissolve directly in surface water, the pH value of seawater then decreases and the water &quot;acidifies.&quot; Mussels, starfish, corals, crabs and sea urchins lose their ability to form exoskeletons or endoskeletons in these conditions. This means that they will disappear, leading to unfiltered water and a lack of food for other marine life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/15188164_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Plankton as seen from a plane (picture alliance / dpa)&quot; alt=&quot;Plankton as seen from a plane (picture alliance / dpa)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Less plankton as fodder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the pH value decreases due to increased CO2 absorption, small algae aren't able to absorb as much iron. But plankton needs this mineral for strong growth. Since many phytoplankton species also form calcareous skeletons, they are likely to be affected by acidified water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;0.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/48232990_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;dead fish swimming in a river (picture-alliance/dpa/C. Schmidt)&quot; alt=&quot;dead fish swimming in a river (picture-alliance/dpa/C. Schmidt)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;37&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Oxygen decreases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warmer water stores less oxygen, so warming oceans lead to expanding areas that are oxygen-poor. In many rivers, lakes and lagoons, oxygen-poor &quot;death zones&quot; already exist where animals can't live because too little oxygen is dissolved in the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/19260691_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A fisherman walks on a beach blanketed with dead sardines in Tolten, Temuco, Chile, Sunday, May 15, 2016. (picture-alliance/AP Photo/F. Marquez)&quot; alt=&quot;A fisherman walks on a beach blanketed with dead sardines in Tolten, Temuco, Chile, Sunday, May 15, 2016. (picture-alliance/AP Photo/F. Marquez)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;38&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Explosive algae blooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In warm, oxygen-poor water, toxic algae bloom and can multiply explosively. Their poison kills fish and other sea creatures. Algae carpets are already threatening the fishing industry and tourism in many places. Here is a picture from Chile's coast, where red algae killed thousands of fish with their nerve poison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/48604788_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Bleached coral at the Great Barrier Reef (picture-alliance/dpa/D. Naupold)&quot; alt=&quot;Bleached coral at the Great Barrier Reef (picture-alliance/dpa/D. Naupold)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Empty white coral skeletons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warming oceans cause coral to lose not only its color but also its ability to reproduce, as a result of heavy coral bleaching. Coral reefs die off and provide no protection, no food and no hunting grounds for a variety of marine life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;hideBeforeLoad&quot; readability=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserImg&quot;&gt;&lt;img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.dw.com/image/4931110_303.jpg&quot; title=&quot;An image depicting changing currents in the Atlantic Ocean (NGDC)&quot; alt=&quot;An image depicting changing currents in the Atlantic Ocean (NGDC)&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;teaserContentWrap&quot; readability=&quot;39&quot;&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Catastrophes triggered by warming oceans&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changing ocean currents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the North Atlantic Current were to be interrupted by ocean warming, it would result in a severe cold spell throughout western and northern Europe. This is because the current ensures the continuous circulation of seawater as dense surface water sinks into deeper, cooler layers. The other oceanic currents would also be affected by such an interruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Author: Alexander Freund (fs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br class=&quot;clearfix&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jsi/sms (AFP, dpa)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dw.com/en/newsletter-registration/a-15718229&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;icon intern&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Each evening at 1830 UTC, DW's editors send out a selection of the day's hard news and quality feature journalism. You can sign up to receive it directly here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 22:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>4ad</dc:creator>
<og:description>WetterOnline has won its case against Germany's national weather service. The company sued the service over the anti-competitive nature of its free weather forecast app.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.dw.com/en/court-outlaws-german-weather-services-free-weather-app/a-52735502</og:url>
<og:title>Court outlaws German Weather Service's free weather app | DW | 12.03.2020</og:title>
<og:image>https://www.dw.com/image/47144478_304.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.dw.com/en/court-outlaws-german-weather-services-free-weather-app/a-52735502</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>