<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>LinkedIn is copying the contents of my clipboard on every keystroke</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/doncubed/status/1278757106468806656</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/doncubed/status/1278757106468806656</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t think this violates any specific laws but it definitely will make more people nervous when handling sensitive data on devices. 

Tik Tok responded to the issue saying that it is “triggered by a feature designed to identity repetitive, spammy behavior” 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 18:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dondonleroy</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/DonCubed/status/1278757106468806656</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zuckerberg: advertisers will be back to Facebook &amp;#039;soon enough&amp;#039;</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-53262860</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-53262860</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption full-width lead&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                &lt;img class=&quot;js-image-replace&quot; alt=&quot;Mark Zuckerberg in front of company logos&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1090A/production/_113205876_zuckneon.png&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;As the ads boycott grows, Mark Zuckerberg shows no sign of backing down. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;My guess is that all these advertisers will be back on the platform soon enough&quot; the Facebook chief executive has said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Campaigners accuse the tech firm of being too slow and reluctant to remove some hateful content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Zuckerberg added: &quot;We're not going to change our policies or approach on anything because of a threat to a small percent of our revenue.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The comments were made to Facebook staff at a private meeting last Friday, and were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/articles/zuckerberg-tells-facebook-staff-he-expects-advertisers-to-return-soon-enough?shared=55fd71efc87f385e&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;subsequently leaked to the Information news site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The social network has confirmed they are accurate and also announced a fresh development: its chief executive is to meet the organisers of the boycott - Stop Hate for Profit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It illustrates the concurrent ways Facebook is dealing with the matter. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    The educational group behind the TV show Sesame Street is among those who have said they will refrain from running ads on Facebook
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first is to be publicly conciliatory: offer smaller changes and hit home its message that hate has no place on the platform. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second is to privately play down the impact of the boycott: reassure advertisers and resist any fundamental changes to Facebook's business model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Balancing act&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday the firm's global affairs chief, Sir Nick Clegg, published an open letter to the ad world. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He attempted to assuage fears the company hadn't done enough to combat hate. Not surprisingly, he didn't echo his boss and add: &quot;You'll be back.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, of course companies have different internal- and external-facing messages. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this one in particular underlines the delicate tightrope that Facebook is trying to tread. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company is undoubtedly rattled by this boycott. According to a list compiled by its organisers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/u/1/d/1VSGhDwXm18yFf2BVCz0QJYFjCHrPhDuO-m5rCo0zoqI/htmlview&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;more than 600 brands are now involved&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week Facebook sent an email to companies and ad agencies assuring them it was doing all it could to remove hate speech. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This work is never finished, and we're proud of how our apps can help people come together, learn, and organize against hate and show their solidarity&quot; an email to one ad agency said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the boycott isn't hurting Facebook as much as you might think. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, Zuckerberg, in that same employee meeting, called the problem a &quot;reputational and a partner issue&quot; rather than a financial one. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And he has a point. The vast majority of companies are still advertising with Facebook. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take the UK for example. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the analytics company Pathmatics carried out a study into which companies were spending the most on Facebook ads seen in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They included:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Tesco&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Proctor &amp;amp; Gamble &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;BT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;Vodafone &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;American Express&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the exception of Microsoft, all of the top-10 spenders identified still appear to be advertising on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And thousands upon thousands of small-to-medium-sized businesses are doing likewise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Return to Washington&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One advertising executive sent me an expletive-riddled text yesterday, dismissing the idea its clients would stop advertising on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's that kind of message that gives Zuckerberg reason to be bullish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Areeq Chowdhury, from WebRoots Democracy, also believes the companies that have joined the boycott will come back. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The advertising being offered by these internet giants is unparalleled.&quot; he says. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The level of targeting they can achieve is not matched anywhere else, so I find it hard to believe that a lot of them will stop advertising in the long run.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That seems to be what the market thinks, too. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a dip in Facebook's share price, it's back to pretty much where it was last week. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, Facebook's strategy so far seems to be working. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The far greater worry is contagion - for example, if users started to leave Facebook and Instagram in large numbers in response to the boycott. But once again, there's little evidence of that happening. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Mr Zuckerberg last gave testimony to US lawmakers in October 2019
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, it was confirmed that Zuckerberg - along with Google's Sundar Pichai, Apple's Tim Cook and Amazon's Jeff Bezos - would testify before Congress in an antitrust hearing later this month. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the boycott continues to gather force, it could be an uncomfortable encounter, however secure Facebook may feel.&lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 17:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DarkContinent</dc:creator>
<og:title>Zuckerberg: Advertisers will be back 'soon enough'</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Facebook's chief dismisses claims in leaked comments that the ads boycott poses a financial threat.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-53262860</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1090A/production/_113205876_zuckneon.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-53262860</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MS will ban Forza players who add the confederate flag to their digital cars</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308677/microsoft-forza-player-ban-confederate-flag-hate-symbols</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308677/microsoft-forza-player-ban-confederate-flag-hate-symbols</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;A3vYXb&quot;&gt;If you play &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Forza Motorsport&lt;/em&gt;, you have some freedom to personalize cars in the game, even adding your own custom designs. One popular example: players have used the feature to recreate the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F0ssdKL1438&quot;&gt;General Lee&lt;/a&gt;, the 1969 Dodge Charger from &lt;em&gt;The Dukes of Hazzard&lt;/em&gt;, in almost every single Forza game &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZdHjm5UbKYc&quot;&gt;since at least 2007&lt;/a&gt;. But the General Lee famously includes the controversial confederate flag on its back — and Microsoft has just announced it will ban players who use that symbol (among others) in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;jVR2zV&quot;&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/forza_support/status/1276621666278232064?s=20&quot;&gt;statement posted on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; last Friday, Microsoft updated its enforcement guidelines to have a zero-tolerance policy for any player using the confederate flag or other symbols that represent “&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.forzamotorsport.net/hc/en-us/articles/360035563914-Forza-Enforcement-Guidelines&quot;&gt;notorious iconography&lt;/a&gt;,” including Nazi imagery and the rising sun, which can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/09/06/asia/japan-korea-olympics-rising-sun-flag-intl-hnk-trnd/index.html&quot;&gt;a symbol of Japanese imperialism&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft will not automatically ban players that create designs with these controversial images; instead, the original designer will need to be reported by &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.forzamotorsport.net/hc/en-us/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360004177714https://support.forzamotorsport.net/hc/en-us/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360004177714&quot;&gt;submitting a ticket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;dr0XwK&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/F0ssdKL1438?rel=0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media; accelerometer; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;X0DQcx&quot;&gt;While some players have &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.forzamotorsport.net/turn10_postsm1166222findlastpost_ONE-BIG-ANNOUNCEMENT-DUE-TO-LATEST-CONFEDERATE-FLAG-BAN-UPDATE.aspx#post1166321&quot;&gt;noticed the ban&lt;/a&gt;, it hasn’t sparked a significant backlash yet. Besides, if you want to turn your 1969 Dodge Charger into a General Lee, you don’t need a flag to do that. (Also, here’s the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.forzamotorsport.net/turn10_postst149065p2_KOOL-DESIGNS---PAINTS-BY-KoolIROCZ1967---One-Hot-Hog-and-11mm-Supervan-3.aspx?=&quot;&gt;General Bee&lt;/a&gt;.”) Even the real-life General Lee car &lt;a href=&quot;https://golfweek.usatoday.com/2020/06/16/bubba-watson-says-love-give-general-lee-to-museum/&quot;&gt;no longer wears the confederate flag&lt;/a&gt;; owner and pro golfer Bubba Watson says he had them removed in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;V38A2u&quot;&gt;In recent weeks, debates surrounding the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2015/6/24/8838429/confederate-flag-meaning-history&quot;&gt;modern display of the confederate flag&lt;/a&gt; have resurfaced amid protests in the US against systemic racism. Several institutions, which previously allowed displays of the flag, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2020/06/07/us/marine-corps-confederate-flag-trnd/index.html&quot;&gt;US Marine Corps&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2020/06/10/us/nascar-bans-confederate-flag-spt-trnd/index.html&quot;&gt;NASCAR&lt;/a&gt;, have banned the flag and depictions of it in its entirety, while lawmakers in Mississippi voted on Monday to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2020/06/28/politics/mississippi-flag-confederate-emblem/index.html&quot;&gt;remove the emblem from its state flag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 16:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bdz</dc:creator>
<og:description>No more General Lee in Forza games.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y4qCFU0s6nMg5l76SnfEehdcXYc=/0x13:614x334/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets/1336652/forza4carlist.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Microsoft will ban Forza players who add the confederate flag to their digital cars</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308677/microsoft-forza-player-ban-confederate-flag-hate-symbols</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308677/microsoft-forza-player-ban-confederate-flag-hate-symbols</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Abstract Wikipedia</title>
<link>https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Abstract_Wikipedia/June_2020_announcement</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Abstract_Wikipedia/June_2020_announcement</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;mw-parser-output&quot; readability=&quot;63.226962457338&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mw-pt-languages noprint&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other languages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Announcing_a_new_wiki_project.21_Welcome.2C_Abstract_Wikipedia&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-headline&quot; id=&quot;Announcing_a_new_wiki_project!_Welcome,_Abstract_Wikipedia&quot;&gt;Announcing a new wiki project! Welcome, Abstract Wikipedia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-editsection&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-editsection-bracket&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?title=Abstract_Wikipedia/July_2020_announcement&amp;amp;action=edit&amp;amp;section=1&quot; title=&quot;Edit section: Announcing a new wiki project! Welcome, Abstract Wikipedia&quot;&gt;edit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mw-editsection-bracket&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my honor to introduce Abstract Wikipedia, a new project that has been unanimously approved by the Wikimedia Foundation Board of Trustees. Abstract Wikipedia proposes a new way to generate baseline encyclopedic content in a multilingual fashion, allowing more contributors and more readers to share more knowledge in more languages. It is an approach that aims to make cross-lingual cooperation easier on our projects, increase the sustainability of our movement through expanding access to participation, improve the user experience for readers of all languages, and innovate in free knowledge by connecting some of the strengths of our movement to create something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our first new project in over seven years. Abstract Wikipedia was submitted as a project proposal by Denny Vrandečić in May of 2020 &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-1&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Abstract_Wikipedia/June_2020_announcement#cite_note-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; after years of preparation and research, leading to a detailed plan and lively discussions in the Wikimedia communities. We know that the energy and the creativity of the community often runs up against language barriers, and information that is available in one language may not make it to other language Wikipedias. Abstract Wikipedia intends to look and feel like a Wikipedia, but build on the powerful, language-independent conceptual models of Wikidata, with the goal of letting volunteers create and maintain Wikipedia articles across our polyglot Wikimedia world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project will allow volunteers to assemble the fundamentals of an article using words and entities from Wikidata. Because Wikidata uses conceptual models that are meant to be universal across languages, it should be possible to use and extend these building blocks of knowledge to create models for articles that also have universal value. Using code, volunteers will be able to translate these abstract “articles” into their own languages. If successful, this could eventually allow everyone to read about any topic in Wikidata in their own language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, this work will require a lot of software development, and a lot of cooperation among Wikimedians. In order to make this effort possible, Denny will join the Foundation as a staff member in July and lead this initiative. You may know Denny as the creator of Wikidata, a long-time community member, a former staff member at Wikimedia Deutschland, and a former Trustee at the Wikimedia Foundation &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-2&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Abstract_Wikipedia/June_2020_announcement#cite_note-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. We are very excited that Denny will bring his skills and expertise to work on this project alongside the Foundation’s product, technology, and community liaison teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to acknowledge that this is an experimental project, and that every Wikipedia community has different needs. This project may offer some communities great advantages. Other communities may engage less. Every language Wikipedia community will be free to choose and moderate whether or how they would use content from this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited that this new wiki-project has the possibility to advance knowledge equity through increased access to knowledge. It also invites us to consider and engage with critical questions about how and by whom knowledge is constructed. We look forward to working in cooperation with the communities to think through these important questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much to do as we begin designing a plan for Abstract Wikipedia in close collaboration with our communities. I encourage you to get involved by going to the project page and joining the new mailing list &lt;sup id=&quot;cite_ref-3&quot; class=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Abstract_Wikipedia/June_2020_announcement#cite_note-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. We recognize that Abstract Wikipedia is ambitious, but we also recognize its potential. We invite you all to join us on a new, unexplored path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katherine Maher (Executive Director, Wikimedia Foundation)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:CentralAutoLogin/start?type=1x1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 16:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>infodocket</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Abstract_Wikipedia/June_2020_announcement</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Estonian Electronic Identity Card: Security Flaws in Key Management</title>
<link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity20/presentation/parsovs</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity20/presentation/parsovs</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Open Access Media&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;description&quot; readability=&quot;11.447368421053&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USENIX is committed to Open Access to the research presented at our events. Papers and proceedings are freely available to everyone once the event begins. Any video, audio, and/or slides that are posted after the event are also free and open to everyone. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usenix.org/annual-fund&quot;&gt;Support USENIX&lt;/a&gt; and our commitment to Open Access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-bibtex-node field-type-node-reference field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bibtex-accordion&quot; readability=&quot;11.733333333333&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BibTeX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;bibtex-accordion-content&quot; readability=&quot;43.00283286119&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@inproceedings {247686,&lt;br/&gt;title = {Estonian Electronic Identity Card: Security Flaws in Key Management},&lt;br/&gt;booktitle = {29th {USENIX} Security Symposium ({USENIX} Security 20)},&lt;br/&gt;year = {2020},&lt;br/&gt;address = {Boston, MA},&lt;br/&gt;url = {https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity20/presentation/parsovs},&lt;br/&gt;publisher = {{USENIX} Association},&lt;br/&gt;month = aug,&lt;br/&gt;}&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 11:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dcbadacd</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity20/presentation/parsovs</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hundreds arrested as crime chat network cracked</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-53263310</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-53263310</guid>
<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;media-with-caption&quot; readability=&quot;-24&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;player-with-placeholder&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img class=&quot;media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image lead-video-placeholder&quot; src=&quot;https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p08jn4zf.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media playback is unsupported on your device&lt;/p&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-with-caption__caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Media caption&lt;/span&gt;The BBC's Tom Symonds is shown how a customised Android phone with EncroChat installed works&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;A top-secret communications system used by criminals to trade drugs and guns has been &quot;successfully penetrated&quot;, says the National Crime Agency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NCA worked with forces across Europe on the UK's &quot;biggest and most significant&quot; law enforcement operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Major crime figures were among over 800 Europe-wide arrests after messages on EncroChat were intercepted and decoded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than two tonnes of drugs, several dozen guns and £54m in suspect cash have been seized, says the NCA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the NCA was part of the investigation, it was initiated and led by French and Dutch police, and also involved Europol - the EU agency for law enforcement cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wil van Gemert, deputy executive director of Europol, told a press conference in the Hague that the hacking of the network had allowed the &quot;disruption of criminal activities including violent attacks, corruption, attempted murders and large-scale drug transports&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;NCA&lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Armed raids on properties resulted in more than 800 arrests across Europe
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NCA says the Europe-wide operation, which lasted over three months and involved police forces across the UK, has had the biggest impact on organised crime gangs it has ever seen, with 746 UK arrests, including two law enforcement officers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;story-body__unordered-list&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-48242157&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;UK organised crime 'chronic and corrosive'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;story-body__list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-49973186&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link&quot;&gt;Police arrest 13 over UK's 'biggest drug conspiracy' &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Metropolitan Police Commissioner, Dame Cressida Dick, whose force made 171 arrests and seized £13.3m in cash, described it as a &quot;game changer&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She said: &quot;This is just the beginning. We will be disrupting organised criminal networks as a result of these operations for weeks and months and possibly years to come.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nikki Holland, NCA director of investigations, said the operational team had described it &quot;as akin to cracking the enigma code&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;They see this as that significant in terms of getting that inside information, effectively having a person inside an organised crime group telling us what they're up to,&quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;'Criminal marketplace'&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;An estimated 60,000 people, among them up to 10,000 in Britain, subscribed to France-based EncroChat, which has now been taken down. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The system operated on customised Android phones and, according to its website, provided &quot;worry-free secure communications&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customers had access to features such as self-destructing messages that deleted from the recipient's device after a certain length of time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape has-caption full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
                 &lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image copyright&lt;/span&gt;
                 &lt;span class=&quot;story-image-copyright&quot;&gt;Essex Police &lt;/span&gt;
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
            &lt;figcaption class=&quot;media-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;off-screen&quot;&gt;Image caption&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;media-caption__text&quot;&gt;
                    Bank notes seized by Essex Police during the operation
                &lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was also panic wipe, where all the data on the device could be deleted by entering a four-digit code from the lock-screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NCA says the messaging system has been used as a &quot;criminal marketplace&quot; to co-ordinate the supply of Class A drugs across the world, and import weapons including assault rifles, sub-machine guns, shotguns, pistols and hand grenades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Law enforcement agencies began getting data from the site on 1 April after the encryption code is believed to have been cracked in March.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gangs are also believed to have used the handheld devices to plot attacks on rival groups, plan ways of enforcing drug debts and arrange for money to be laundered. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Threats to life detailed on the site included acid attacks and threats to chop off limbs.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dozens of organised crime groups have been dismantled, says the NCA, with the bulk of arrests in London and north-west England. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lockdown &quot;worked in our favour&quot;, says the agency, in that many more suspects were at home when they were raided.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of those arrested are said to form the &quot;middle tier&quot; of crime gangs while some are described as the &quot;Mr and Mrs Bigs&quot; of the underworld.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption body-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;story-body__crosshead&quot;&gt;Chat users realised 'too late'&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analysis by BBC technology reporter David Molloy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EncroChat sold encrypted phones with a guarantee of anonymity, with a range of special features to remove identifying information. The phones themselves cost roughly £900 (€1,000) each, with a subscription costing £1,350 (€1,500) for six months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Europol said that French police had discovered some of EncroChat's servers were located in the country, and that it was possible to put a &quot;technical device&quot; in place to access the messages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/z3emm3/encrochat-encro-hacked-encrypted-phones&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;rumours &lt;/a&gt;began to swirl about EncroChat being compromised by law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Netherlands' National Police said that users began to throw away their phones once the company became aware that messages were being intercepted - &quot;but it was too late&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police had already intercepted millions of messages, some of which have been acted on already - and others that may be used in the future. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;media-landscape no-caption body-width&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-and-copyright-container&quot;&gt;
                
                
                
                
                
            &lt;/span&gt;
            
        &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In London, those targeted in the Met operation, codenamed &quot;Eternal&quot;,  are alleged to include members of &quot;high-harm&quot; organised crime networks with longstanding links to violent crime and drug dealing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dame Cressida said: &quot;These people are in business to make enormous amounts of money. Many of them lead a very respectable lifestyle - and definitely a high-end lifestyle in fancy houses with big cars going to... clubs and restaurants, splashing the cash sometimes, but sometimes being very discreet about it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Met said that in June, its detectives identified a plot by an international drugs and firearms gang to shoot dead a member of a rival network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the force, it managed to prevent the shooting by arresting an individual for conspiracy to murder and seizing a loaded pistol, which was believed to be the planned murder weapon. &lt;/p&gt;
            </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 11:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bogle</dc:creator>
<og:title>Hundreds arrested as crime chat network cracked</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Police forces across Europe collaborated on the UK's &quot;most significant&quot; law enforcement operation.</og:description>
<og:url>https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-53263310</og:url>
<og:image>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p08jn4zf.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-53263310</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Go is boring, and that’s fantastic</title>
<link>https://www.capitalone.com/tech/software-engineering/go-is-boring/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.capitalone.com/tech/software-engineering/go-is-boring/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;71.763754045307&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I've been working as a professional software engineer for nearly 23 years, and I’ve been writing programs for about 38.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In that time, I've used a lot of languages. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; programming languages and learning about their new features and what changes they've made compared to the languages that came before them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you look at the past 10 years in programming languages, you’ll see lots of changes. C++, Java, Python, and JavaScript have gained new features, and new languages like Rust and Swift have changed rapidly since their introduction. This is all pretty exciting but it also feels like sometimes you can never catch up with all the ideas in all these languages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And then there's Go.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The best way to think about Go is to think about all the things that it &lt;em&gt;doesn't&lt;/em&gt; have.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; have a virtual machine or an LLVM-based compiler.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; have exceptions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; have user-defined implementation inheritance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; have overloading for functions, methods, or operators.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; have immutables.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; have enumerations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; have generics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And Go hasn’t added any major features since Go 1 was released in 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The one exciting thing that Go has is built-in concurrency support via goroutines, channels, and select. However, it is based on ideas from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~crary/819-f09/Hoare78.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;CSP, communicating sequential processes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;, which was first described in 1978.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;This doesn’t sound like a programming language from the 21st century, does it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And yet, Go is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2019/#most-loved-dreaded-and-wanted&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;the 3rd most wanted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;and (maybe not coincidentally)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2019/#technology-_-what-languages-are-associated-with-the-highest-salaries-worldwide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;the 3rd highest paying&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;language, according to Stack Overflow. Every startup in Silicon Valley is using Go to build their infrastructure. Docker, Kubernetes, etcd, Terraform, Vault, Consul, Traefik and lots of other cutting-edge projects are written in Go. So what's going on? Why is everyone interested in this &lt;em&gt;boring&lt;/em&gt; language?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-body-header grv-text__heading--medium grv-text--medium-large-light&quot;&gt;Why Software Engineering is the New Bridge Building&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;So before we answer that question, let's step back for a bit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; srcset=&quot;https://ecm.capitalone.com/WCM/tech/go-is-boring-1/thumbnail.png 60w, https://ecm.capitalone.com/WCM/tech/go-is-boring-1.png 740w&quot; alt=&quot;gateway of large rocks surrounded by grass&quot;/&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;grv-row&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-col--sm-4&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&quot;Arkadiko Mycenaean Bridge II&quot; (https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Arkadiko_Mycenaean_Bridge_II.JPG) by Flausa123 (https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?title=User:Flausa123&amp;amp;action=edit&amp;amp;redlink=1) is licensed under CC BY-SA 3.0 (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;64.125313283208&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlasobscura.com/places/arkadiko-bridge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Arkadiko Bridge in Argolis, Greece&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;. At just over 3,000 years old it's the oldest bridge in the world that's still standing today. Amazingly, it's still in use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now, why should we care about an old bridge? It's because there's a universal truth about software development that software engineers don't like to talk about too much.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We're really bad at writing software.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And I don't just mean that one person in the office who your manager sends out on coffee runs to reduce the bug count at crunch time. I mean everyone - me, you, and every famous developer you can think of.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;But the people who design and build bridges, they're great at it. Bridges get built on time, on budget, and last for dozens, hundreds, even thousands of years. Bridge building is, if you think about it, kind of &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt;. And bridges are such a common occurrence that they’re also incredibly boring. No one is amazed when a bridge works correctly, and everyone is kind of amazed when software does.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Unfortunately, the world is very dependent on software. It might even depend more on software than it does on bridges. So we have to get better at writing software far faster than we got good at building bridges.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-body-header grv-text__heading--medium grv-text--medium-large-light&quot;&gt;Everything We Know About Writing Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;33&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are a few things that we have learned in the last 60 years about writing programs where there is pretty much universal agreement:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We agree that it's better to find problems earlier rather than later.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We agree that people are &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt; at managing memory in programs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We agree that code reviews help find bugs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We agree that on any project that requires more than one person, communication costs dominate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-body-header grv-text__heading--medium grv-text--medium-large-light&quot;&gt;Hardware Isn’t Saving Us&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;25.245901639344&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We can combine these few things that we know with another truth that has settled in: computers aren't getting faster any more. At least not like they used to.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gotw.ca/publications/concurrency-ddj.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;During the 1980's and 1990's, CPUs got twice as fast every 1-2 years&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;. That's changed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; srcset=&quot;https://ecm.capitalone.com/WCM/tech/go-is-boring-2/thumbnail.png 60w, https://ecm.capitalone.com/WCM/tech/go-is-boring-2.png 778w&quot; alt=&quot;two squares with black text next to eachother&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;38.549509366637&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;When you look at single core performance,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://browser.geekbench.com/processors/2600&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://browser.geekbench.com/processors/2600&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;he fastest 2019 Core i9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;is less than twice as fast as&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://browser.geekbench.com/processors/662&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;the fastest 2011 Core i7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Instead of getting faster, we're adding more cores to CPUs.  When you look at multi-core performance, it's a little better, slightly more than 2x faster.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s not just CPU performance that is limiting us. Forrest Smith wrote a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forrestthewoods.com/blog/memory-bandwidth-napkin-math/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;fantastic blog post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;on the impact of RAM and RAM access patterns on performance. The highlights are:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;RAM is much slower than CPUs, and the gap is not getting better, even though CPUs aren't getting much faster.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;RAM might be random access, but if you actually use it that way, it's slow. You can read around 40 gigabytes per second from RAM on a modern Intel CPU if the data is sequential. If you do a random read, it’s a little less than half a gigabyte per second.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Code with lots of pointers is especially slow. Quoting Forrest: &lt;em&gt;“Sequentially summing values behind a pointer runs at less than 1 GB/s. Random access, which misses the cache twice, runs at just 0.1 GB/s. Pointer chasing is 10 to 20 times slower. Friends don't let friends use linked lists.”&lt;/em&gt; Ouch.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-body-header grv-text__heading--medium grv-text--medium-large-light&quot;&gt;Boring is the New Exciting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;36&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;So, given these few, precious things that we know about how to build software and the hardware that we have available to us, let's take another look at Go.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-body-header grv-text__heading--medium grv-text--medium-large-light&quot;&gt;Go and Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;79.416464050017&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finding Problems Earlier Rather Than Later&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Go language might lack features, but it ships with a great set of tools. Go's compiler is fast, and that fast compilation speed is considered a feature by the Go team. It lets you quickly see if your code compiles, and if it doesn't, it lets you see where the problems are. Testing is built into the standard library to encourage developers to test their code and find problems. Benchmarking and profiling and race checking are included out of the box, too. Very few languages ship with these tools and they make it easier to find problems quickly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Memory Management&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As we all know, Go has a garbage collector. You don't have to worry about keeping track of memory and that's a fantastic thing. Among compiled languages, garbage collection is rare. Rust's borrow checker is a fascinating way to get high performance and memory management, but it effectively turns the developer into the garbage collector, and that can be hard to use correctly. Swift's ARC can still leak memory if you make mistakes and forget to declare some references as weak. Now, Go's GC isn't as performant as these semi-automatic systems, and there are some situations where you need the extra speed, but in most cases it's certainly sufficient.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Code Reviews&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Code reviews are important if they are done well. In order to have an effective code review you need to make sure that the reviewers are focused on the right things. Low-quality code reviews spend time on things like formatting. Go helps here because there are no formatting arguments when reviewing Go code, because all Go code is formatted the way that go fmt says code should be formatted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And code reviews are a two-way street. If you want a review that works well, you need to make sure that other people can understand your code. Go programs are supposed to be simple, using a few well-understood constructs that haven't changed since the language was released. Because there are no exceptions, aspect-oriented programming, inheritance and method overriding, or overloading, it's very clear what code is calling what and where the values are returned. If you stay away from modifying package-level variables in Go it's very easy to see exactly how data is being modified. Since Go has changed so little, you can avoid the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoq.com/news/2015/01/lava-layer-antipattern/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;lava flow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoq.com/news/2015/01/lava-layer-antipattern/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;anti-pattern&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;, where you can tell exactly how old some code is based on when a feature it uses was introduced into the language.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Communication Costs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;How does Go help with this? We've already talked about how Go's simplicity, stability, and standard formatting makes it easier to communicate what your code is doing. And while that's part of it, there's something else as well. Go's implicit interfaces help teams write decoupled code. They are defined by the calling code to describe exactly what functionality is needed, which clarifies what your code is doing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-body-header grv-text__heading--medium grv-text--medium-large-light&quot;&gt;Go and Hardware&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;40.881656804734&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The decision to make Go a compiled language has paid off. Interpreted languages running in virtual machines seemed like a good idea when CPUs were getting faster every day. If your program wasn’t fast enough, just wait a year and it’ll be fine. That doesn’t work anymore. Compiling to native code is a lot less interesting than the latest virtual machine tricks, but it gives a big performance advantage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Let’s compare Go’s performance to some languages that run in Virtual Machines using microbenchmarks from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://benchmarksgame-team.pages.debian.net/benchmarksgame/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Benchmark Game&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;. First we’ll look at Python and Ruby compared to Go. Any percentage less than 100 means faster than Go, greater than 100% means slower:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; srcset=&quot;https://ecm.capitalone.com/WCM/tech/go-is-boring-table/thumbnail.png 60w, https://ecm.capitalone.com/WCM/tech/go-is-boring-table.png 1386w&quot; alt=&quot;table with black text and red and blue squares&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;40&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;That’s a lot of red. There’s one benchmark where Python is faster (oddly, it’s not only twice as fast as Go, it’s faster than every other language at this one test) and none where Ruby is. Except for that one case, both languages produce code that is between 17% slower and over 60 &lt;strong&gt;times&lt;/strong&gt; slower than Go.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Now let’s see how Java and JavaScript do:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; srcset=&quot;https://ecm.capitalone.com/WCM/tech/go-is-boring-table-2/thumbnail.png 60w, https://ecm.capitalone.com/WCM/tech/go-is-boring-table-2.png 1414w&quot; alt=&quot;table with black text and red and blue squares&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;61.740275284261&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;These languages are much closer to Go’s performance. JavaScript is faster than Go on one benchmark, slower on the others, but the worst case for JavaScript is about three times slower.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Java and Go are pretty close in performance. Java is faster than Go in four cases, about the same in two cases, and slower in four cases. The worst that Go does is about three times slower than Java, the best Go does is about 50% faster.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;What we are seeing is that the only VM that can keep up with Go is Java's.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/whitepaper-135217.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hotspot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;is amazing technology, but the fact that you need one of the best engineered pieces of software in the world in order to break even with a compiler that prioritizes compilation speed over optimization says something. And you pay a price for that amazing technology. The memory usage of Java applications is many, many times larger than Go applications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;There's a second advantage too. The garbage that garbage collectors manage are pointers that aren't in use. Unlike languages that hide their pointers, Go gives you control. It lets you avoid pointers and lay your data structures out in a way that allows fast RAM access. This also allows Go to use a simpler garbage collector because Go programs simply create less garbage. &lt;em&gt;Being boring is just less work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And as we all know, CPUs are making up for their lack of increased speed with more cores. So it's good to use a language that takes advantage of this.That's where Go's concurrency support comes in. Having language-level support for concurrency and a runtime library that schedules goroutines across multiple threads means that when you have multiple CPU cores, those threads can be mapped to those cores.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;article-body-header grv-text__heading--medium grv-text--medium-large-light&quot;&gt;I Do Not Want What I Haven’t Got&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;grv-text__body--normal&quot; readability=&quot;83.2101708383&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We have seen that Go focuses on the features and tooling that we know make it easier to create software and that better fit the memory and CPU architecture of modern computers. But what about the features that other languages have and Go doesn’t? Maybe Go developers are missing out and those features that Go doesn't have help developers write less buggy, easier to maintain code. Well, it turns out that as far as researchers can tell, that's not the case.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;A paper in 2017 called “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.cs.ucdavis.edu/~filkov/papers/lang_github.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;A Large Scale Study of Programming Languages and Code Quality in Github&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;” looked at 729 projects, 80 Million SLOC, 29,000 authors, 1.5 million commits, in 17 languages to try to answer the question: &lt;em&gt;What is the effect of programming languages on software quality?&lt;/em&gt; Their answer was that it makes little difference:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“It is worth noting that these modest effects arising from language design are overwhelmingly dominated by the process factors such as project size, team size, and commit size.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Another group of researchers took a second look at this data and did a reproduction study in 2019 called “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1901.10220.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the Impact of Programming Languages on Code Quality&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;”. What they found was even more surprising:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“Not only is it not possible to establish a causal link between programming language and code quality based on the data at hand, but even their correlation proves questionable.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;If programming language choice doesn’t matter, why choose Go? What these studies show is that process matters. Tooling, testing, performance, and ease of long-term maintenance are more important than trendy features. When properly used, Go’s built-in tooling supports better processes while providing time-tested features.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;This isn’t to say that new features are bad. Bridge building technology has certainly advanced over the centuries and millennia. But would you want to be the first to go over a bridge that was built with brand-new ideas and untested technology? You'd want to wait a little bit and have people test it out before you adopt it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The same is true for software. If we're going to build software infrastructure that's as reliable as bridges, we're going to need to use software technologies that are as well-tested and well-understood as those we use for physical infrastructure. That's why Go is mostly using features designed in the 1970s. We know they work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Go is boring, and that's fantastic. Let's all go out there and use it to build tomorrow's exciting applications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;***&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gopher Mascot Generated with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://urldefense.com/v3/__http:/Gopherize.me__;!!EFVe01R3CjU!IjyWo8esadqQE5IsseqfbP2yWKgMKU8lCZoOhpj0nl-yzB3uhLAv9mB6h-_tcY8113-k$&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gopherize.me&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rauhl</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:title>Go is Boring...And That’s Fantastic! | Capital One</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.www.capitalone.com/tech/software-engineering/go-is-boring//</og:url>
<og:description>Go is simple, reliable, and well-understood which makes it a great choice for your applications.</og:description>
<og:image>https://ecm.capitalone.com/WCM/tech/go-header/tablet.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.capitalone.com/tech/software-engineering/go-is-boring/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Sci-Hub Effect: Sci-Hub downloads lead to more article citations</title>
<link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.14979</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.14979</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;10.710526315789&quot;&gt;[Submitted on 26 Jun 2020 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.14979v1&quot;&gt;v1&lt;/a&gt;), last revised 29 Jun 2020 (this version, v2)]&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;descriptor&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt; Citations are often used as a metric of the impact of scientific publications. Here, we examine how the number of downloads from Sci-hub as well as various characteristics of publications and their authors predicts future citations. Using data from 12 leading journals in economics, consumer research, neuroscience, and multidisciplinary research, we found that articles downloaded from Sci-hub were cited 1.72 times more than papers not downloaded from Sci-hub and that the number of downloads from Sci-hub was a robust predictor of future citations. Among other characteristics of publications, the number of figures in a manuscript consistently predicts its future citations. The results suggest that limited access to publications may limit some scientific research from achieving its full impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 06:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lnyan</dc:creator>
<og:title>The Sci-hub Effect: Sci-hub downloads lead to more article citations</og:title>
<og:url>https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.14979v2</og:url>
<og:description>Citations are often used as a metric of the impact of scientific publications. Here, we examine how the number of downloads from Sci-hub as well as various characteristics of publications and their authors predicts future citations. Using data from 12 leading journals in economics, consumer research, neuroscience, and multidisciplinary research, we found that articles downloaded from Sci-hub were cited 1.72 times more than papers not downloaded from Sci-hub and that the number of downloads from Sci-hub was a robust predictor of future citations. Among other characteristics of publications, the number of figures in a manuscript consistently predicts its future citations. The results suggest that limited access to publications may limit some scientific research from achieving its full impact.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.14979</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Space Jam&amp;#039;s 1996 website is still alive</title>
<link>https://www.spacejam.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.spacejam.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spacejam.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.spacejam.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23709016&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23709016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 659&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 248&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 01:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>olingern</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.spacejam.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>DuckDuckGo browser seemingly sends domains a user visits to DDG servers</title>
<link>https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android/issues/527</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android/issues/527</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://avatars3.githubusercontent.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://github-cloud.s3.amazonaws.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;dns-prefetch&quot; href=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-/uy49LxdzjR0L36uT6CnmV1omP/8ZHxvOg4zq/dczzABHq9atntjJDmo5B7sV0J+AwVmv0fR0ZyW3EQawzdLFA==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/frameworks-feecb8f4bc5dce34742f7eae4fa0a799.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-0Dq+Bdp4xIEoUQ6d8RzDMUJdGejYZhWcZUh+JZDfYn/RCdp7u4QhKG8ABLNmvxL5YobdxQCLJaaacKNyIp8L2w==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/site-d03abe05da78c48128510e9df11cc331.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; media=&quot;all&quot; integrity=&quot;sha512-0qkCidPfjGd13b0fW6wxCDkXzbVws8nxr4qKcjzipVrgHdfSp2yLXje75iRFjmfBiEyvnrj+L1bIq64Cup9JeQ==&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/assets/github-d2a90289d3df8c6775ddbd1f5bac3108.css&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;Domains visited get leaked to DDG servers · Issue #527 · duckduckgo/Android · GitHub&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Android/app/src/main/java/com/duckduckgo/app/global/UriExtension.kt Line 60 in ed91c9e private const val faviconBaseUrlFormat = &amp;quot;https://icons.duckduckgo.com/ip3/%s.ico&amp;quot; This seems to be leaking all(?) the domains that users visit to you...&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;search&quot; type=&quot;application/opensearchdescription+xml&quot; href=&quot;/opensearch.xml&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;fluid-icon&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/fluidicon.png&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;fb:app_id&quot; content=&quot;1401488693436528&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;apple-itunes-app&quot; content=&quot;app-id=1477376905&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:image:src&quot; content=&quot;https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/342708?s=400&amp;amp;v=4&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@github&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:title&quot; content=&quot;Domains visited get leaked to DDG servers · Issue #527 · duckduckgo/Android&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:description&quot; content=&quot;Android/app/src/main/java/com/duckduckgo/app/global/UriExtension.kt Line 60 in ed91c9e private const val faviconBaseUrlFormat = &amp;amp;amp;quot;https://icons.duckduckgo.com/ip3/%s.ico&amp;amp;amp;quot; This seem...&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/342708?s=400&amp;amp;v=4&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:site_name&quot; content=&quot;GitHub&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:type&quot; content=&quot;object&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;Domains visited get leaked to DDG servers · Issue #527 · duckduckgo/Android&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android/issues/527&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;Android/app/src/main/java/com/duckduckgo/app/global/UriExtension.kt Line 60 in ed91c9e private const val faviconBaseUrlFormat = &amp;amp;quot;https://icons.duckduckgo.com/ip3/%s.ico&amp;amp;quot; This seems to be ...&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;assets&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;request-id&quot; content=&quot;C471:3C9A:9389E8:DB1F8F:5EFE836A&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;html-safe-nonce&quot; content=&quot;2442bf02f8d285caf2d563b2af213d2b771f34f9&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;visitor-payload&quot; content=&quot;eyJyZWZlcnJlciI6Imh0dHA6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvLnVrL3VybD9zYT10XHUwMDI2c291cmNlPXdlYlx1MDAyNmNkPTEiLCJyZXF1ZXN0X2lkIjoiQzQ3MTozQzlBOjkzODlFODpEQjFGOEY6NUVGRTgzNkEiLCJ2aXNpdG9yX2lkIjoiNDg5MTA2OTIzNTk4OTQ4MDI5OCIsInJlZ2lvbl9lZGdlIjoiaWFkIiwicmVnaW9uX3JlbmRlciI6ImlhZCJ9&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;visitor-hmac&quot; content=&quot;0569a199e50d56fcaace12fb77764b48e2d620c205b4268039cd03674fa9b9e1&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;hovercard-subject-tag&quot; content=&quot;issue:465768374&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;github-keyboard-shortcuts&quot; content=&quot;repository,issues&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;selected-link&quot; value=&quot;repo_issues&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;c1kuD-K2HIVF635lypcsWPoD4kilo5-jA_wBFyT4uMY&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;KT5gs8h0wvaagLKAVWq8bbeNwnZZK1r1XQysX3xurLU&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;ZzhVyEFwb7w3e0-uOTltm8Jsck2F5StVihD0exw2fsA&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-site-verification&quot; content=&quot;GXs5KoUUkNCoaAZn7wPN-t01Pywp9M3sEjnt_3_ZWPc&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-host&quot; content=&quot;collector.githubapp.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-app-id&quot; content=&quot;github&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-event-url&quot; content=&quot;https://collector.githubapp.com/github-external/browser_event&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-ga_id&quot; content=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;js-octo-ga-id&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;analytics-location&quot; content=&quot;/&amp;lt;user-name&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;repo-name&amp;gt;/issues/show&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;google-analytics&quot; content=&quot;UA-3769691-2&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta class=&quot;js-ga-set&quot; name=&quot;dimension10&quot; content=&quot;Responsive&quot; data-pjax-transient=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta class=&quot;js-ga-set&quot; name=&quot;dimension1&quot; content=&quot;Logged Out&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;hostname&quot; content=&quot;github.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;user-login&quot; content=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;expected-hostname&quot; content=&quot;github.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;enabled-features&quot; content=&quot;MARKETPLACE_PENDING_INSTALLATIONS,PRIMER_NEXT,ACTIONS_MANUAL_RUN&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;x-pjax-version&quot; content=&quot;4430c9a94a992f690eecc782107e0d27&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android/commits/develop.atom&quot; rel=&quot;alternate&quot; title=&quot;Recent Commits to Android:develop&quot; type=&quot;application/atom+xml&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;go-import&quot; content=&quot;github.com/duckduckgo/Android git https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android.git&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-user_id&quot; content=&quot;342708&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-user_login&quot; content=&quot;duckduckgo&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_id&quot; content=&quot;78869127&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_nwo&quot; content=&quot;duckduckgo/Android&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_public&quot; content=&quot;true&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_is_fork&quot; content=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_network_root_id&quot; content=&quot;78869127&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_network_root_nwo&quot; content=&quot;duckduckgo/Android&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;octolytics-dimension-repository_explore_github_marketplace_ci_cta_shown&quot; content=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-stats-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/stats&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;browser-errors-url&quot; content=&quot;https://api.github.com/_private/browser/errors&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;mask-icon&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/pinned-octocat.svg&quot; color=&quot;#000000&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;alternate icon&quot; class=&quot;js-site-favicon&quot; type=&quot;image/png&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;icon&quot; class=&quot;js-site-favicon&quot; type=&quot;image/svg+xml&quot; href=&quot;https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#1e2327&quot;/&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;manifest&quot; href=&quot;/manifest.json&quot; crossorigin=&quot;use-credentials&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body class=&quot;logged-out env-production page-responsive&quot; id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;42.943820224719&quot;&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;application-main&quot; data-commit-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; data-discussion-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot; data-issue-and-pr-hovercards-enabled=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/SoftwareSourceCode&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container-xl clearfix new-discussion-timeline px-3 px-md-4 px-lg-5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;repository-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-check-all-container&quot; data-pjax=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;signup-prompt p-4 text-center mb-4 rounded-1&quot; readability=&quot;31.129518072289&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;position-relative&quot; readability=&quot;9.578313253012&quot;&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; class=&quot;position-absolute top-0 right-0 btn-link link-gray&quot; data-action=&quot;click:signup-prompt#dismiss&quot; data-ga-click=&quot;(Logged out) Sign up prompt, clicked Dismiss, text:dismiss&quot;&gt;Dismiss&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;pt-2&quot;&gt;Join GitHub today&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;col-6 mx-auto&quot;&gt;GitHub is home to over 50 million developers working together to host and review code, manage projects, and build software together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot; data-ga-click=&quot;(Logged out) Sign up prompt, clicked Sign up, text:sign-up&quot; data-hydro-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;event_type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;authentication.click&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;payload&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;location_in_page&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;files signup prompt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;repository_id&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;auth_type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SIGN_UP&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;originating_url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android/issues/527&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;user_id&amp;quot;:null}}&quot; data-hydro-click-hmac=&quot;fb89c5a365dfd416b3df4c115204357b1da9112d810997a8e38fe382cef07262&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/join?source=prompt-issue-show&amp;amp;source_repo=duckduckgo%2FAndroid&quot;&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t perform that action at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash flash flash-warn flash-banner&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash-signed-in&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;You signed in with another tab or window. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android/issues/527&quot;&gt;Reload&lt;/a&gt; to refresh your session.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;js-stale-session-flash-signed-out&quot; hidden=&quot;&quot;&gt;You signed out in another tab or window. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android/issues/527&quot;&gt;Reload&lt;/a&gt; to refresh your session.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;details class=&quot;details-reset details-overlay details-overlay-dark lh-default text-gray-dark hx_rsm&quot; open=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 23:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>commotionfever</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/342708?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>Domains visited get leaked to DDG servers · Issue #527 · duckduckgo/Android</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android/issues/527</og:url>
<og:description>Android/app/src/main/java/com/duckduckgo/app/global/UriExtension.kt Line 60 in ed91c9e private const val faviconBaseUrlFormat = &amp;quot;https://icons.duckduckgo.com/ip3/%s.ico&amp;quot; This seems to be ...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/duckduckgo/Android/issues/527</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>