<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Apache Software Foundation joins GitHub open source community</title>
<link>https://github.blog/2019-04-29-apache-joins-github-community/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.blog/2019-04-29-apache-joins-github-community/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-featured mb-3 mb-md-9 pb-0 pb-md-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post-featured__image&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1194&quot; height=&quot;616&quot; src=&quot;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/apache-blog.png?fit=1194%2C616&quot; class=&quot;attachment-full size-full wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/apache-blog.png?w=1194 1194w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/apache-blog.png?w=300 300w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/apache-blog.png?w=768 768w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/apache-blog.png?w=1024 1024w, https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/apache-blog.png?w=804 804w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1194px) 100vw, 1194px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;post__content markdown-body col-12 col-md-10 mb-2 mb-md-4&quot; readability=&quot;64.21547277937&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today we’re excited to welcome the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://apache.org/foundation/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Apache Software Foundation (ASF)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;to GitHub. Apache is the world’s largest open source foundation, with over 200 million lines of code managed by an all-volunteer community of 730 members and 7,000 code contributors. Over their 20 year history, one billion lines of code have been committed across three million code commits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In 2016, Apache made the decision to start integrating GitHub’s repository and tooling with their own services. After solidifying the integration over the years, they decided to simplify how they work and move all Git projects to GitHub. As of February 2019, Apache’s migration to GitHub was complete, enabling all these projects with a simple platform to host and review code, collaborate on projects, and build software alongside 31 million developers around the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-the-transition&quot;&gt;Making the transition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We’ve been working with Apache to meet their needs and better support open source projects doing important work. We’re grateful to have such an impactful foundation migrate and grow directly on GitHub. With this transition completed, Apache can focus on building software and their community.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Whether we’re working with individual open source maintainers and contributors on some of the world’s largest open source foundations like Apache, GitHub’s mission is to be the home for all developers by supporting open source communities, addressing their unique needs, and helping open source projects thrive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;More details on this news can be found in the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://s.apache.org/7lio&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;press release&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re actively working with many different communities on their unique challenges and transition plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:opensource@github.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Contact us to get involved&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 11:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>moritzplassnig</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Apache Software Foundation joins GitHub open source community</og:title>
<og:description>We’re excited to welcome the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) to GitHub.</og:description>
<og:url>https://github.blog/2019-04-29-apache-joins-github-community/</og:url>
<og:image>https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/apache-blog.png?fit=1194%2C616</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.blog/2019-04-29-apache-joins-github-community/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Unauthorized access to Docker Hub database</title>
<link>https://success.docker.com/article/docker-hub-user-notification</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://success.docker.com/article/docker-hub-user-notification</guid>
<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;issue&quot;&gt;Issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, April 25th, 2019, we discovered unauthorized access to a single Docker Hub database storing a subset of non-financial user data. Upon discovery, we acted quickly to intervene and secure the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to update you on what we've learned from our ongoing investigation, including which Hub accounts are impacted, and what actions users should take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;resolution&quot;&gt;Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a brief period of unauthorized access to a Docker Hub database, sensitive data from approximately 190,000 accounts may have been exposed (less than 5% of Hub users). Data includes usernames and hashed passwords for a small percentage of these users, as well as GitHub and Bitbucket tokens for Docker autobuilds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We are asking users to change their password on Docker Hub and any other accounts that shared this password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For users with autobuilds that may have been impacted, we have revoked GitHub tokens and access keys. This means your autobuilds will fail, and we ask that you reconnect to your repositories and check security logs to see if any unexpected actions have taken place.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are enhancing our overall security processes and reviewing our policies. Additional monitoring tools are now in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;frequentlyaskedquestions&quot;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: What happened?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a brief period of unauthorized access to a Docker Hub database. During this time some sensitive data from approximately 190,000 accounts may have been exposed (less than 5% of Hub users). Data includes usernames and hashed passwords for a small percentage of users as well as GitHub and Bitbucket tokens for Docker autobuilds. All these tokens have been revoked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Were any of the Docker Official Images impacted by this incident?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Official Images have been compromised. We have additional security measures in place for our Official Images including GPG signatures on git commits as well as Notary signing to ensure the integrity of each image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: How do I know if I was impacted by this unauthorized access?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you directly received an email from Docker about this incident, you may have been impacted. If you have received a password reset link, your password hash was potentially exposed. We have invalidated it and sent you a password reset link as a precaution. If you are using autobuilds and your GitHub or Bitbucket repositories have been unlinked from Docker Hub, you will need to relink those repositories for autobuilds to work correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: What do I need to do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all Docker Hub users, there is no action required to preserve your security. A password reset link has been sent to any users who potentially had their password hash exposed. Users who have autobuilds who have had their GitHub or Bitbucket repositories unlinked will need to relink those repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Do I need to reset my password on Docker Hub?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. If your password hash was potentially exposed, we have invalidated your password and emailed you a reset password link. Even if you did not receive a password reset link, it’s never a bad idea to &lt;a href=&quot;https://id.docker.com/reset-password/?service=43f17c5f-9ba4-4f13-853d-9d0074e349a7&quot;&gt;change your password&lt;/a&gt; if you haven’t changed it in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Why did you delete my GitHub tokens before notifying me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revoking the tokens was done as soon as possible to protect users. At that point in time we were working on additional measures to secure the site. Once completed, communications were sent to all potentially impacted users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: If I relink my Docker Hub repository to a GitHub repository will I be at risk?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. Relinking your Docker Hub repository will create a new read-only deploy key to your GitHub or Bitbucket source repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: I can’t sign in to Docker Hub, have I been hacked?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have sent a password reset link to each user whose password hash may have been impacted. Please check your email to see if you have received a password reset link. If you have any concerns, please contact info@docker.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: I have never used the Docker Hub Autobuild feature. Why did I receive an email?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have linked your GitHub or Bitbucket account to Docker Hub in the past or your password hash was potentially exposed. If you did link your account to Docker Hub, we have unlinked it. If your password hash was potentially exposed, we have invalidated it and sent you a password reset link as a precaution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 01:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>yskchu</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://success.docker.com/article/docker-hub-user-notification</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ask HN: Are you put off building something because it already exists?</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19774997</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19774997</guid>
<description>&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.58823529411765&quot;&gt;&lt;td bgcolor=&quot;#FF6600&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr id=&quot;pagespace&quot; title=&quot;Ask HN: Are you put off building something because it already exists?&quot;&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;8.288920056101&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;fatitem&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; readability=&quot;5.8022440392707&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;athing&quot; id=&quot;19774997&quot; readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;votelinks&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19774997&quot; class=&quot;storylink&quot;&gt;Ask HN: Are you put off building something because it already exists?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;0.72289156626506&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot; id=&quot;score_19774997&quot;&gt;800 points&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=strimp099&quot; class=&quot;hnuser&quot;&gt;strimp099&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;age&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19774997&quot;&gt;14 hours ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;unv_19774997&quot;/&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/hide?id=19774997&amp;amp;goto=item%3Fid%3D19774997&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=Ask%20HN%3A%20Are%20you%20put%20off%20building%20something%20because%20it%20already%20exists%3F&amp;amp;sort=byDate&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&amp;amp;storyText=false&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&quot; class=&quot;hnpast&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=Ask%20HN%3A%20Are%20you%20put%20off%20building%20something%20because%20it%20already%20exists%3F&quot;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/fave?id=19774997&amp;amp;auth=2289b308b1634d0653bc340b1014178a29680f6d&quot;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19774997&quot;&gt;228 comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;15&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;Big market, check. Validated demand, check. Product or service exists, uh-oh.
&lt;p&gt;I set out to build a reverse address book. Instead of updating your address book with changes from everyone else, you update your own details and it pushes to everyone else. Turns out someone beat me to it and my inspiration evaporated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoom is a recent and great example of competing in a crowded market and winning. For you builders/founders out there, are you on a never ending quest to find something new/unique or do you prefer another quality in your idea to start a project?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/s.gif&quot; height=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;yclinks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&quot;&gt;Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsfaq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HackerNews/API&quot;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/security.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/bookmarklet.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/legal/&quot;&gt;Legal&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply to YC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hn@ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 01:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>strimp099</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19774997</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Custard Antenna</title>
<link>https://michaelcullen.name/2019/04/custard-antenna/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://michaelcullen.name/2019/04/custard-antenna/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, someone said of their ex-military antenna tuner “it would tune a bowl of custard if you asked it to” – this got me thinking, could I make my MFJ-971 antenna tuner literally tune a bowl of custard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been interested in strange antennas, having stumbled upon the K0S Strange Antenna Challenge many years ago. Sadly, the original website no longer seems to be around, however there are still references to it online, such as a post from the organiser, Erik Weaver N0EW, on eham: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eham.net/articles/10721&quot;&gt;https://www.eham.net/articles/10721&lt;/a&gt;. Essentially, it’s a special event station that uses only non-standard items as antennas. The example given was that of a tent pole: if you just stick the tent pole in the air, that’s not really a strange antenna since it’s just a bit of metal. If, however, you put the whole tent up in a tree, that’s a strange antenna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For quite a long time, I’ve been meaning to try out some unconventional antenna ideas, and this seemed like the perfect chance! It’s more than just a joke though, it’s also a good opportunity to learn something about antennas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Early Experiments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to start small, so I first conducted a small experiment with a pot of custard. I actually bought two: one to taste and the other to shove some wires in and try to tune. Good job as well – one of them turned out to be green and furry when I opened it, so I ended up eating one spoonful of the correctly coloured one, before proceeding to tune it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://michaelcullen.name/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Composite-custardtenna.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-95&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked! I managed to tune a pot of custard to the 20m band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Full Size Bowl&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that to satisfy the spirit of “tuning a bowl of custard” I needed a literal bowl of custard. I also wanted a relatively large amount of custard to give it the best chance of doing something interesting. I went to the local supermarket and bought a 4 litre bowl and a few 1kg boxes of custard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://michaelcullen.name/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1581_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-100&quot;/&gt;Three boxes of antenna fluid (aka custard)
&lt;p&gt;This sat around for a couple of weeks, generally getting in the way until I finally got around to trying to tune a bowl of custard. The other problem was I couldn’t quite believe how daft the thing I was about to do was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://michaelcullen.name/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Custardtenna-composite2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-98&quot;/&gt;Finely tuned dessert
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, one Saturday evening, I finally got chance to fill a bowl with custard and have a go. In the end I managed to get three boxes of custard into the bowl (I’d actually bought more, so I have some spare – more on that later) and tuned it up on 20m (14.15MHz to be specific – though it was flat across the band). Just out of interest, I hooked up my Yaesu FT-817ND and tried to receive some FT8. In case you haven’t come across it, FT8 is a digital mode designed for very weak signal reception. Some people hate it, but I really like how well it demonstrates band conditions, including how they change very quickly. Anyway, I figured if it was going to work on anything, it was FT8. To my surprise, after enabling the receiver’s preamp and turning up the RF gain, I was able to receive a signal from Greece – at one point the signal was -6dB which for FT8 is very much a decent signal! It’s worth mentioning here that on receive the ATU really doesn’t do much. But nonetheless, I was receiving FT8 on a bowl of custard! I did swap the custard out for a dummy load, but unsurprisingly, it did not receive anything – so at least on receive, the custard was not a complete dummy load. I do wonder if some of the pickup was on the wire feeding it, but the custard was definitely doing something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://michaelcullen.name/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1579.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-99&quot;/&gt;FT8 reception on custard
&lt;p&gt;In any case, the question was not if you could use custard to receive, but rather if it was possible to tune a bowl of custard to an acceptable SWR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did attempt to put about 30-40W of RF into the antenna system (bowl of custard + ATU) however nothing was picked up on PSKReporter, leading me to conclude that the bowl of custard was significantly inferior on transmit compared to receive. This came as absolutely no surprise of course, but I had to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of things I’d like to try next. The first is to repeat the experiment with a bowl of jelly, to see if it behaves any differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second experiment I would like to try, and the subject of the rest of this post, is to make a custard antenna that can at least vaguely usefully be used as an antenna. I want to make a contact of some form on an antenna made of custard!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial idea was to take some plastic guttering and make a custard dipole. The problem here though is supporting the guttering far enough above the ground for it to be usable as an antenna. My next thought was to use rigid plastic pipe, filled with custard, however I’m a little concerned that once filled with custard, the pipe could become too heavy to sensibly hold up. Since the length is probably more important than the diameter, I came up with the idea of using clear plastic tube – partly because it would look cooler if you could see the custard. Since custard is quite a thick material, I suspect I would need to use, maybe 15-16mm inside diameter tube to be reasonably sure of being able to fill it – and clear tube would be an advantage here since you would be able to see any air bubbles and squeeze them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think aiming for an antenna resonant on the 20m band is perhaps the best bet. I could maybe make something for VHF but that’s not as fun, and based on a very quick test I did, custard might actually be lossier above 30MHz or so. Higher HF bands aren’t really very usable at this low point in the solar cycle, and I think 5m or so of custard is probably just about achievable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few questions remaining about this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Should I use custard for the radials as well?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I could maybe fill some tube (perhaps thinner tube) with custard as radials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or maybe I could use jelly radials?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or maybe just wire? Is that cheating?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the velocity factor of custard? Not a question I ever thought I’d have, but one I should be able to approximately answer if I build this thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much would a 5m tube of custard weigh?
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Could a fibreglass pole support it or does it need some thing stronger?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much &lt;del&gt;antenna fluid&lt;/del&gt; custard do I need to fill the tube?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How lossy is custard as an antenna?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The answers to these questions (which no one has ever asked) will come in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 23:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>maxerickson</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-GB</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://michaelcullen.name/2019/04/custard-antenna/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Lorem Picsum – Lorem Ipsum but for photos</title>
<link>https://picsum.photos/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://picsum.photos/</guid>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Advanced Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may combine any of the options above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, to get a specific image that is grayscale and blurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;no-underline&quot; href=&quot;https://picsum.photos/id/870/200/300?grayscale&amp;amp;blur=2&quot;&gt;https://picsum.photos/id/870/200/300?grayscale&amp;amp;blur=2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To request multiple images of the same size in your browser, you need to add a random parameter to prevent the images from being cached&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;break-words&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;https://picsum.photos/200/300?random=1&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;img src=&quot;https://picsum.photos/200/300?random=2&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need a file ending, you can add &lt;code&gt;.jpg&lt;/code&gt; to the end of the url.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;break-words&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;no-underline&quot; href=&quot;https://picsum.photos/200/300.jpg&quot;&gt;https://picsum.photos/200/300.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 22:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>dmarby</dc:creator>
<og:title>Lorem Picsum</og:title>
<og:description>Lorem Ipsum... but for photos</og:description>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://picsum.photos/250/250</og:image>
<og:url>https://picsum.photos</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://picsum.photos/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thousands take to Hong Kong streets to protest new extradition laws</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hongkong-politics-extradition-idUSKCN1S405E</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hongkong-politics-extradition-idUSKCN1S405E</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;HONG KONG, April 28 (Reuters) - Tens of thousands of people marched on Hong Kong’s parliament on Sunday to demand the scrapping of proposed extradition rules that would allow people to be sent to mainland China for trial - a move which some fear puts the city’s core freedoms at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opponents of the proposal fear further erosion of rights and legal protections in the free-wheeling financial hub - freedoms which were guaranteed under the city’s handover from British colonial rule to Chinese sovereignty in 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranks of marchers snaked peacefully for more than three hours through the shopping and business districts of Causeway Bay and Wanchai, with thousands staying on into the evening outside the Legislative Council and government headquarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police said 22,800 people marched at the peak of the procession, but organizers estimated 130,000 turned out - making it one of the largest street protests in the city for several years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observers said the turnout dwarved an earlier protest against the plan last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veteran activist and former legislator Leung Kwok-hung said the government’s move risked removing Hong Kongers’ “freedom from fear”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hong Kong people and visitors passing by Hong Kong will lose their right not to be extradited into mainland China,” he said. “They would need to face an unjust legal system on the mainland.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some younger marchers said they were worried about traveling to the mainland after the move, which comes just as the government encourages young people to deepen ties with the mainland and promotes Hong Kong’s links with southern China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Law clerk Edward Wen, 45, said the difference in human rights standards between Hong Kong and the mainland was too great to bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You will be screwed as long as they put up a crime on your behalf,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The marchers’ chanted demands for Hong Kong Chief Executive Carrie Lam to step down echoed through the high-rise streets, with some protesters saying she had “betrayed” Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some sported yellow umbrellas - the symbol of the Occupy pro-democracy movement that paralyzed parts of Hong Kong for 11 weeks in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Image_container&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190428&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1381553982&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF3R07J&amp;amp;w=20&quot; aria-label=&quot;Demonstrators march during a protest to demand authorities scrap a proposed extradition bill with China, in Hong Kong, China April 28, 2019. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Image_caption&quot;&gt;

&lt;span&gt;Demonstrators march during a protest to demand authorities scrap a proposed extradition bill with China, in Hong Kong, China April 28, 2019. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed changes have sparked an unusually broad chorus of concern from international business elites to lawyers and rights’ groups and even some pro-establishment figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Patten, the last British governor of Hong Kong who handed the city back to Chinese rule in 1997, on Saturday described the move as “an assault on Hong Kong’s values, stability and security”, government-funded broadcaster RTHK reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LOOPHOLES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Lam and other government officials are standing fast by their proposals, calling them vital to plug long-standing loopholes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the changes, the Hong Kong leader would have the right to order the extradition of wanted offenders to China, Macau and Taiwan as well as other countries not covered by Hong Kong’s existing extradition treaties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a safeguard, such orders, to be issued case-by-case, could be challenged and appealed through the city’s vaunted legal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government officials have said no one at risk of the death penalty or torture or facing a political charge could be sent from Hong Kong. Under pressure from local business groups, they earlier exempted nine commercial crimes from the new provisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposals could be passed into law later in the year, with the city’s pro-democratic camp no longer holding enough seats to block the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government has justified the swift introduction of the changes by saying they are needed so a young Hong Kong man suspected of murdering his girlfriend in Taiwan can be extradited to face charges there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government’s assurances are not enough for Lam Wing-kee, a former Hong Kong political bookseller who said in 2016 he was abducted by mainland agents in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lam left Hong Kong for Taiwan last week, saying he feared being sent back to the mainland under the new laws and his experience showed he could have no trust in China’s legal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A group of 33 followers of Falun Gong, a religious sect banned in China, flew from Taiwan to Hong Kong on Saturday to join the march but were refused entry to Hong Kong, RTHK reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_container Slideshow_small Slideshow_standard&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Slideshow_preview-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;LazyImage_container LazyImage_dark&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20190428&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1381553976&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEF3R0DE&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Slideshow &lt;span class=&quot;Slideshow_count&quot;&gt;(8 Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday’s march comes amid renewed calls for deeper electoral reforms stalled five years ago after Occupy protests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four leaders of the movement were last week sentenced to jail terms ranging from eight to 16 months, part of a group of nine activists found guilty after a near month-long trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_container&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Attribution_attribution&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Attribution_content&quot;&gt;Reporting By Jessie Pang and Greg Torode; Additional reporting by Aleksander Solum and Clare Jim, Editing by Michael Perry, Richard Pullin and Dale Hudson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeContainer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;StandardArticleBody_trustBadgeTitle&quot;&gt;Our Standards:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;trustBadgeUrl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thomsonreuters.com/en/about-us/trust-principles.html&quot;&gt;The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:42:22 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>abc-xyz</dc:creator>
<og:title>Thousands take to Hong Kong streets to protest new extradition laws</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hongkong-politics-extradition-idUSKCN1S405E</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>Tens of thousands of people marched on Hong Kong's parliament on Sunday to ...</og:description>
<og:image>https://s3.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20190428&amp;t=2&amp;i=1381553982&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEF3R07J</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hongkong-politics-extradition-idUSKCN1S405E</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Software Projects and Heroes: Lessons Learned from GitHub Projects</title>
<link>https://arxiv.org/abs/1904.09954</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://arxiv.org/abs/1904.09954</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot; readability=&quot;28.362257792755&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;abs&quot; readability=&quot;12.351305812974&quot;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(Submitted on 22 Apr 2019)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;abstract mathjax&quot; readability=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;descriptor&quot;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt; A &quot;hero&quot; project is one where 80% or more of the contributions are made by the 20% of the developers. In the literature, such projects are deprecated since they might cause bottlenecks in development and communication. However, there is little empirical evidence on this matter. Further, recent studies show that such hero projects are very prevalent. Accordingly, this paper explores the effect of having heroes in project, from a code quality perspective. We identify the heroes developer communities in 1100+ open source GitHub projects. Based on the analysis, we find that (a) hero projects are majorly all projects; and (b) the commits from &quot;hero developers&quot; (who contribute most to the code) result in far fewer bugs than other developers. That is, contrary to the literature, heroes are standard and very useful part of modern open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;32.4&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Submission history&lt;/h2&gt;
From: Suvodeep Majumder [&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/show-email/f0c8a251/1904.09954&quot;&gt;view email&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[v1]&lt;/strong&gt; Mon, 22 Apr 2019 16:59:50 UTC (5,789 KB)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 17:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gmolau</dc:creator>
<og:title>Why Software Projects need Heroes (Lessons Learned from 1100+ Projects)</og:title>
<og:url>https://arxiv.org/abs/1904.09954v1</og:url>
<og:description>A &quot;hero&quot; project is one where 80% or more of the contributions are made by the 20% of the developers. In the literature, such projects are deprecated since they might cause bottlenecks in development and communication. However, there is little empirical evidence on this matter. Further, recent studies show that such hero projects are very prevalent. Accordingly, this paper explores the effect of having heroes in project, from a code quality perspective. We identify the heroes developer communities in 1100+ open source GitHub projects. Based on the analysis, we find that (a) hero projects are majorly all projects; and (b) the commits from &quot;hero developers&quot; (who contribute most to the code) result in far fewer bugs than other developers. That is, contrary to the literature, heroes are standard and very useful part of modern open source projects.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://arxiv.org/abs/1904.09954</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Darling – macOS Translation Layer for Linux</title>
<link>https://www.darlinghq.org</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.darlinghq.org</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.darlinghq.org/img/darling250.png&quot; alt=&quot;Darling&quot;/&gt; Darling is a translation layer that allows you to run unmodified macOS binaries on Linux. In its nature, it is similar to the well-known &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.winehq.org&quot;&gt;Wine project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, does not yet run macOS application with a GUI. For more information, review the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darlinghq.org/project-status&quot;&gt;Project Status&lt;/a&gt;. Developers are always welcome to join the project - take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darlinghq.org/developer-zone/low-hanging-fruit/&quot;&gt;Low Hanging Fruit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 17:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>pcr910303</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.darlinghq.org/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: 1MB – Free and easy static website hosting and database</title>
<link>https://1mb.site</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://1mb.site</guid>
<description>&lt;head&gt;&lt;meta charset=&quot;UTF-8&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;viewport&quot; content=&quot;width=device-width, user-scalable=no&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;theme-color&quot; content=&quot;#254cf5&quot;/&gt;&lt;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;1MB is a free and easy static website host.&quot;/&gt;&lt;title&gt;1MB&lt;/title&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Comfortaa:400,700|Roboto+Mono:400,700&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/boxicons@1.9.4/css/boxicons.min.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;link href=&quot;https://1mb.site/assets/?name=home.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot;/&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body id=&quot;readabilityBody&quot; readability=&quot;24.100598802395&quot;&gt;
&lt;header&gt;

&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;welcome&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Welcome to 1MB!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1MB is a free and easy static website host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section center&quot; readability=&quot;9.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card&quot; readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What is 1MB?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1MB is a free website host designed to make web development feel more approachable. You do not need to browse through complicated settings menus or juggle a bunch of server credentials here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can edit your site directly inside your browser. 1MB has a custom code editor with some useful features such as starter templates, live site previews, and themes. 1MB gets you online fast by letting you focus on coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/qsJJdYU.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section center&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Custom domains and SSL are free!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding a custom domain to your account is a quick process. SSL is automatically installed and renewed through Let's Encrypt completely free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Say hello to &lt;span&gt; https://&lt;/span&gt;your.domain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSL is one of the best ways to protect your website visitor's personal information and gain their trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section center&quot; readability=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card&quot; readability=&quot;11.555555555556&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Securely access a NoSQL database using nothing but JavaScript&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With permissions, enforced fields, and the ability to get the logged in 1MB username you can easily create a dynamic application. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.1mb.site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chat.1mb.site&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.1mb.site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;forum.1mb.site&lt;/a&gt; which are both applications that utilize a 1MB database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so/1mb/1MB-API-Documentation-e9f5f35586264cff92aa2211308957c7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the API documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section center&quot; readability=&quot;8.7106109324759&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card&quot; readability=&quot;12.581993569132&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Deploy however you want!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to deploy to your site via the command line run this command to install 1mb-cli:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;npm install --global 1mb-cli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your working directory run this command to deploy to your site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;1mb-cli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also deploy to your site using the API: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so/1mb/1MB-API-Documentation-e9f5f35586264cff92aa2211308957c7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read the API documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section center&quot; readability=&quot;5.4059405940594&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card&quot; readability=&quot;6.3069306930693&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Go Pro!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get more storage and other advanced functionality by upgrading to 1MB Pro: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pro.1mb.site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Learn More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/body&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 16:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>1mbsite</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://1mb.site/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The gig economy is quietly undermining a century of worker protections</title>
<link>https://qz.com/1556194/the-gig-economy-is-quietly-undermining-a-century-of-worker-protections/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://qz.com/1556194/the-gig-economy-is-quietly-undermining-a-century-of-worker-protections/</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;No kid ever dreamed of growing up and driving for Uber or styling for Stitch Fix. In part, that’s because none of those companies existed when most of today’s adults were young. It’s also because, besides its much-touted “flexibility,” the gig economy isn’t much of a place to build a career. Instead, over the course of less than a decade, the self-described “tech companies” that connect people to gig work have managed to erode hard-fought labor protections in place for a century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;In &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucpress.edu/book/9780520300569/hustle-and-gig&quot;&gt;Hustle and Gig&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; to be published in March by University of California Press, sociologist Alexandrea Ravenelle interviews 80 gig workers who are struggling, striving, and succeeding. She analyzes their stories in the context of US employment history and concludes that “for all its app-enabled modernity, the gig economy resembles the early industrial age…the sharing economy is truly a movement forward to the past.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;Although gig work was initially seen as a way to maximize worker freedom and create opportunities, it has, in its short history, proven corrosive. Ravenelle notes that a small percentage of people are making lots of money via side hustles, but they tend to be those who need it least. For example, she speaks to independent hoteliers in New York renting out rooms and apartments via AirBnB, including a corporate lawyer and a man with a chain of laundromats. Because they already had capital, have steady sources of income apart from their side gigs, and are willing to skirt rental laws, these two individuals are able to invest heavily in their “gigs” and create lucrative businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;Sadly, those who most need to work can find themselves trapped in a cycle of struggle. Ravenelle interviewed men and women signed up to do tasks on Task Rabbit—prior to its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2017/9/28/16377528/ikea-acquisition-taskrabbit-shopping-home-contract-labor&quot;&gt;acquisition by IKEA&lt;/a&gt;—and who drove for Uber, for example. They were not employees and so had no health insurance, workers’ compensation protections, employer contributions to Social Security and payroll taxes, paid time off, family leave protections, discrimination protections, or unemployment insurance benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;Sometimes, this gig work also requires an initial outlay of capital. (My own neighbor just traded in her old vehicle for a new car, taking on thousands of dollars in debt so that she can make extra money driving for Lyft.) At the very least, a potential worker needs a smartphone and wi-fi service. Ravanelle’s book boasts an image inside of a young man in a park panhandling for $30 to activate his phone service so that he can start picking up work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;Workers take gigs as they come and can’t afford to be too picky, despite the supposed liberty of being your own boss in the sharing economy. Platform algorithms are designed to downgrade those who aren’t always available, making it ever-harder to pick up gigs. All this ends up putting workers in dangerous situations, working for strangers without any protections from their employers. Uber, for example, offers email communications to drivers, a service that is not nearly as responsive as the taxi cab dispatcher, say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;The workers Ravenelle spoke to were hit on at work while in a stranger’s house; injured after taking strenuous moving jobs; found themselves delivering questionable packages containing illegal substances; and drove passengers involved in shady activities, fearing that a protest or refusal would end in violence. In all of these awkward situations, these “independent contractors” were forced to choose between a slew of bad options. They could turn down work when they needed the money and risk finding themselves scrambling more. They could take questionable tasks and hope that it all worked out, which it sometimes did. But that meant exposing themselves to the risk that they would end up hurt and financially responsible for their on-the-job injuries, which would also mean needing unpaid time off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;The availability of cheap labor also hasn’t escaped the notice of companies in need of a quick fix. Ravenelle spoke to workers who were doing manual labor, like filling coffee bags for a high-end roaster, that they picked up on an app. In other words,  businesses are also advertising tasks through the supposed peer-to-peer platforms, getting their temps through the new, cheaper system, rather than hiring workers directly. When Ikea acquired TaskRabbit in 2017, it was only making official a relationship that had been developing for years, as furniture buyers hired individuals to put together their Ikea designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;_7d6a7 quartz&quot;&gt;The costs of worker misclassification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;Companies can make more money and incur a lot less liability classifying workers as independent contractors, so they do. Technically, by issuing a 1099 to a gig worker instead of a W2 to an employee, the business is financially and socially distanced from the worker. It’s cheaper and easier than employing everyone who works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;But in the long run, Ravenelle argues, we will all lose as a result of this new structure. She notes that the government, and society as a whole, lose billions of dollars annually to worker misclassification, and writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;_9f6a5 quartz&quot; readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a cruel irony, workers in the sharing economy—hailed as the height of the modern workplace—find themselves without any of the worker protections enjoyed by their great-grandparents. Although workplace protections still exist for full-time and part-time employees, gig workers as independent contractors, are outside the social safety net of basic workplace protections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;From California to &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/11/lyft-drivers-sue-argue-that-theyre-employees-rather-than-contractors/&quot;&gt;Massachusetts,&lt;/a&gt; Uber and Lyft drivers, among others, have sued to be classified as employees. A California case was stymied in September when the Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals ruled that Lyft drivers had agreed by contract to settle disputes through arbitration, meaning the court didn’t even need to reach the classification question. Worker status was outside the court’s purview, it found, because Uber created a contract that made it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;But some drivers have opted out of the arbitration clause, and their cases may proceed. If they succeed in convincing the court they are employees and not contractors, this may signal the beginning of a much-needed reckoning with tech companies that have used the dated letter of the law to generate great profits at a cost to all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;_7d6a7 quartz&quot;&gt;How the gig economy creates economic insecurity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;There’s a hidden tax that corporations using contractors are paying for their cheap labor, so some companies see the upside of providing benefits. Ravenelle also speaks to founders who either switched from hiring contractors to employing workers, like the New York cleaning service MyClean, or decided doing so was the right thing to begin with, like the Hello Alfred errand-running service in Manhattan, which attempts to anticipate customer needs and therefore relies on a relationship between workers and consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;These companies argue that taking care of workers is good for business, although it does mean more administration and initial outlay. Loyal employees are happier, healthier, and do better work. They please customers and don’t need to be replaced or trained as often, which means business improves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;But these are rare examples, and their success is threatened by the existence of the many companies who abuse the system. Venture capitalists are more likely to pour money into businesses that can avoid employee liability, which makes it more difficult for responsible employers to compete. As Ravenelle notes, the “gig economy” is profoundly disrupting the deal between workers and businesses in the US, increasing economic insecurity and worker vulnerability and incentivizing investors and businesses to be bad social actors. She calls this “poor quality progress” that hides its regressive tendencies in friendly, unimpeachable language, terms like the “sharing economy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;a1dbe quartz&quot;&gt;It’s an empty promise, the sociologist argues: “The disruption offered by the sharing economy is simply a hustle.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 15:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>bsg75</dc:creator>
<og:description>Sociologist Alexandrea Ravanelle argues in her new book, &quot;Hustle and Gig,&quot; that all workers lose in the new marketplace.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/gigging.jpeg?quality=75&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1400</og:image>
<og:title>The gig economy is quietly undermining a century of worker protections</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://qz.com/1556194/the-gig-economy-is-quietly-undermining-a-century-of-worker-protections/</og:url>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://qz.com/1556194/the-gig-economy-is-quietly-undermining-a-century-of-worker-protections/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>