<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Bye Bye Mongo, Hello Postgres</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/info/2018/nov/30/bye-bye-mongo-hello-postgres</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/info/2018/nov/30/bye-bye-mongo-hello-postgres</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;At the Guardian, the majority of content - including articles, live blogs, galleries and video content – is produced in our in-house CMS tool, Composer. This, until recently, was backed by a Mongo DB database running on AWS. This database is essentially the “source of truth” for all Guardian content that has been published online – approximately 2.3m content items. We’ve just completed our migration away from Mongo to Postgres SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Composer, and its database, originally started their lives in Guardian Cloud – a data centre in the basement of our office near Kings Cross, with a failover elsewhere in London. Our failover procedures were put to the test rather harshly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/live/2015/jul/01/heatwave-live-britain-hottest-day-2015&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;one hot day in July 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Children play in the fountains outside the Hayward Gallery on the South Bank, London, enjoying the hot, sunny weather. Commissioned&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/48189c1117bb212716a843c9aceb74ef1387da1d/140_264_4547_2727/master/4547.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=4d59424a104be68eac5423aebc84124b&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Hot weather: good for fountain dancing, bad for data centres. Photograph: Sarah Lee/Guardian
&lt;p&gt;After this, the Guardian’s migration to AWS became that bit more urgent. We decided to purchase &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mongodb.com/products/ops-manager&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;OpsManager&lt;/a&gt; – Mongo’s database management software – along with a Mongo support contract – to help with the cloud migration. We used OpsManager to manage backups, handle orchestration and provide monitoring for our database cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to editorial requirements, we needed to run the database cluster and OpsManager on our own infrastructure in AWS rather than using Mongo’s managed database offering. This was non-trivial, as Mongo didn’t provide any tooling for getting set up easily on AWS – we needed to hand write the cloudformation to define all the infrastructure, and on top of that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/guardian/machine-images/tree/master/packer/resources/features/mongo24&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;we wrote hundreds of lines of ruby scripts&lt;/a&gt; to handle installation of monitoring/automation agents and orchestration of new DB instances. We ended up having to run knowledge sharing sessions about database management in the team – something we’d hoped OpsManager would make easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since migrating to AWS we’ve had two significant outages due to database problems, each preventing publication on theguardian.com for at least an hour. In both occasions neither OpsManager nor Mongo’s support agents were able to help us much, and we ended up solving the problem ourselves - in one case thanks to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sihil&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;member of the team&lt;/a&gt; picking up the phone from a desert on the outskirts of Abu Dhabi. Each of the issues could warrant a whole blog post in themselves, but the general take away points were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clocks are important – don’t lock down your VPC so much that NTP stops working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatically generating database indexes on application startup is probably a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database management is important and hard – and we’d rather not be doing it ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;An array of clocks.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/3f1ee5ce108720c858c673e56bfe19da53af8a50/0_130_5019_3011/master/5019.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=b64a067d690058739ad0beaffb08458a&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

When clocks get out of sync, networking becomes a nightmare. Photograph: Alamy Stock Photo
&lt;p&gt;OpsManager didn’t really deliver on its promise of hassle-free database management. For instance, actually managing OpsManager itself – in particular upgrading from OpsManager 1 to 2 – was very time consuming, and required specialist knowledge about our OpsManager setup. It also didn’t deliver on its “one-click upgrade” promise, due to changes in the authentication schema between different versions of Mongo DB. We lost at least two months of engineering time a year doing this database management work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these problems, combined with the hefty annual fee we were paying for the support contract and OpsManager, left us looking for an alternative database option, with the following requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimal database management required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encryption at rest supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A feasible migration path from Mongo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since all our other services are running in AWS, the obvious choice was DynamoDB – Amazon’s NoSQL database offering. Unfortunately at the time Dynamo didn’t support encryption at rest. After waiting around nine months for this feature to be added, we ended up giving up and looking for something else, ultimately choosing to use Postgres on AWS RDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But postgres isn’t a document store!” I hear you cry. Well, no, it isn’t, but it does have a JSONB column type, with support for indexes on fields within the JSON blob. We hoped that by using the JSONB type, we could migrate off Mongo onto Postgres with minimal changes to our data model. In addition, if we wanted to move to a more relational model in future we’d have that option. Another great thing about Postgres is how mature it is: every question we wanted to ask had in most cases already been answered on Stack Overflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a performance perspective, we were confident Postgres could cope – whilst Composer is a write-heavy tool (it writes to the database every time a journalist stops typing) – there are normally only a few hundred concurrent users – not exactly high performance computing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part two – two decades of content migrated, no downtime&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Postgres takes a bite out of mongo&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/ddd421d5de76ec12d96b8d741db76810b0561933/0_164_4667_2802/master/4667.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=b485e6bc572d5a5a40caa9ed6c37f8c8&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Postgres takes a bite out of mongo. Photograph: Bernd Thissen/AFP/Getty Images
&lt;h2&gt;Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most database migrations involve the same steps and ours was no exception. Here are the steps we took to migrate the database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create the new database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a way to write to the new database (new API).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a proxy that sends traffic to both the old and the new database, using the old one as primary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migrate records from the old database into the new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make the new database the primary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delete the old database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given that the database we were migrating powers our CMS, it was important the migration caused as little disruption as possible for our journalists. After all, the news never stops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work began on the new Postgres-powered API towards the end of July 2017. And so our journey begins. But to understand the journey we need to first understand where we started from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our simplified CMS architecture was something like this: a database, an API, and several apps talking to it (such as the web frontend). The stack was, and still is, built using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scala-lang.org/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Scala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scalatra.org/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Scalatra Framework&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://angularjs.org/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Angular.js&lt;/a&gt; and it is about four years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some investigation we concluded that before we could migrate existing content, we needed a way to talk to the new PostgreSQL database and still have the old API running as usual. After all, the Mongo database is our source of truth. It offered us a safety blanket while experimenting with the new API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the reasons why building on top of the old API wasn’t an option. There was very little separation of concern in the original API and MongoDB specifics could be found even at the controller level. As a result the task of adding another database type in the existing API was too risky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went down a different route instead and duplicated the old API. And this is how APIV2 was born. It was more or less an exact replica of the Mongo one and included the same endpoints and functionality. We used &lt;a href=&quot;https://tpolecat.github.io/doobie/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;doobie&lt;/a&gt;, a pure functional JDBC layer for Scala, added &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; for running locally and testing, and improved logging and separation of concerns. APIV2 was going to be a fast and modern API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of August 2017 we had a new API deployed that was using PostgreSQL as its database. But this was only the beginning. There are articles in the Mongo database that were first created over two decades ago and all of these needed to be moved to the Postgres database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Migrating to postgres for the winter&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/5c2a6f921775553760a8f2b4ca5249853aaf40dc/0_285_4272_2563/master/4272.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=cf435cf4e833206f73d42b1e5620d9c1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Migrating to postgres for the winter. Photograph: Anna-Maria Fjellström
&lt;h2&gt;Migration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to be able to edit any article on the site regardless of when they were published, so all articles exist in our database as the single “source of truth”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although all of the articles live in the Guardian’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://open-platform.theguardian.com/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Content API&lt;/a&gt; (CAPI), which powers the apps and website, getting the migration right was key as our database is the ‘source of truth’. If anything were to happen to the CAPI’s Elasticsearch cluster then we would reindex it from Composer’s database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, before turning off Mongo we had to be confident that the same request on the Postgres powered API and the Mongo-powered API would return identical responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this we needed to copy all content to the new Postgres database. This was done using a script that talked directly to the old and new APIs. The advantage of doing it this way was that the APIs already provided a well tested interface for reading and writing articles to and from the databases, as opposed to writing something that accessed the relevant databases directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic flow for the migration was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get content from Mongo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post content to Postgres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get content from Postgres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check that the responses from one and three are identical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A database migration has only really gone well if your end users are completely unaware that it has happened and a good migration script was always going to be an essential part of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind we needed a script that could:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make HTTP requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that after migrating a piece of content, the response from both APIs matched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop if there was an error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produce detailed logs to help diagnose issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart from the correct point after an error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We started off using &lt;a href=&quot;http://ammonite.io/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Ammonite&lt;/a&gt;. Ammonite allows you to write scripts in Scala, which is the primary language on our team. This was a good opportunity to experiment with something we’d not used before to see if it would be useful for us. Although Ammonite allowed us to use a familiar language there were downsides. Whilst Intellij now &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jetbrains.com/scala/2017/11/28/intellij-idea-scala-plugin-2017-3-lightbend-project-starter-ammonite-support-parallel-indexing-and-more/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;supports Ammonite&lt;/a&gt;, at the time it did not, which meant we lost autocomplete and automatic imports. It was also not possible to run an Ammonite script for an extended period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately Ammonite was not the right tool for the job and we used an sbt project instead to perform the migration. The approach we took allowed us to work in a language we were confident in and perform multiple ‘test migrations’ until we were confident to run it in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was unexpected was how useful this would be in testing the Postgres API. We found several subtle bugs and edge cases in the new API that we had not found before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to January 2017, and it was time to test a complete migration in CODE, our pre-production environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to most of our systems, the only similarity between CODE and PROD is the version of the application they are running. The AWS infrastructure backing the CODE environment was far less powerful than PROD simply because it receives far less usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a migration on CODE would help us to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimate how long a migration on PROD would take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assess what impact, if any, a migration would have on performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to get an accurate measurement of these metrics, we had to match the two environments. This involved restoring a backup of the PROD mongo database into CODE and updating the AWS backed infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migrating just over 2m items of content was going to take a long time, certainly more than office hours. So we ran the script in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNU_Screen&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;screen sessio&lt;/a&gt;n overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to measure the progress of the migration, we shipped structured logs (using markers) to our ELK stack. From here, we could create detailed dashboards, tracking the number of articles successfully migrated, the number of failures and the overall progress. Additionally, these were displayed on a big screen near the team to provide greater visibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Dashboard showing progress of the migration&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a0d724443096cfcc93f93006a950812ed4759e7d/0_71_3360_1533/master/3360.png?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=a58ab04ef4bd196acaf2e1b70ab5b8a7&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Dashboard showing progress of the migration Photograph: Editorial Tools/Guardian
&lt;p&gt;Once the migration had finished, we employed the same techniques to check each document in Postgres matched Mongo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Part three – Proxy and running in production&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Mongo to Postgres migration: the proxy&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/44cb77a97c4dcdbcf58e736214f10306b2d8f4e8/0_265_2725_1635/master/2725.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=8806ad5bfb8f52353c1d26ecd32d4f4f&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Mongo to Postgres migration: the proxy. Photograph: Maria Livia Chiorean
&lt;h2&gt;Proxy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the new Postgres-powered API was running we needed to test it with real life traffic and data access patterns to ensure it was reliable and stable. There were two possible ways to achieve this: update each client that talks to the Mongo API to talk to both APIs; or run a proxy that’ll do this. We wrote a proxy in Scala using &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.akka.io/docs/akka/2.5/stream/index.html&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Akka Streams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proxy was fairly simple in its operation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accept traffic from a load balancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forward the traffic to the primary api and return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronously forward the same traffic to the secondary api.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculate any difference between the two responses and log them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the start, the proxy was logging a lot of differences between the responses of the two APIs, surfacing some very subtle but important behavioural differences in the APIs that needed to be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Structured logging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we do logging at the Guardian is by using an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/elk-stack&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;ELK&lt;/a&gt; stack. Using Kibana gave us the flexibility to surface logs in a way that would be most useful to us. Kibana uses the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/6.x/query-dsl-query-string-query.html#query-string-syntax&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;lucene query syntax&lt;/a&gt; that is fairly easy to learn. But we soon realised that filtering out logs or grouping them was not possible in the current setup. For example, we weren’t able to filter out logs sent as a result of GET requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution was to send more structured logs to Kibana rather than sending only a message. One log entry contains multiple fields, like the timestamp, the name of the app that sent the log or the stack. Adding new fields programmatically is very easy. These structured fields are called markers and they can be implemented using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/logstash/logstash-logback-encoder&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;logstash-logback-encoder&lt;/a&gt; library. For each request we extracted the useful information (eg path, method, status code) and created a map with the additional information we needed to log. Have a look at the example below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-scala&quot;&gt;import akka.http.scaladsl.model.HttpRequest
import ch.qos.logback.classic.{Logger =&amp;gt; LogbackLogger}
import net.logstash.logback.marker.Markers
import org.slf4j.{LoggerFactory, Logger =&amp;gt; SLFLogger}

import scala.collection.JavaConverters._

object Logging {
 val rootLogger: LogbackLogger = LoggerFactory.getLogger(SLFLogger.ROOT_LOGGER_NAME).asInstanceOf[LogbackLogger]

 private def setMarkers(request: HttpRequest) = {
   val markers = Map(
     &quot;path&quot; -&amp;gt; request.uri.path.toString(),
     &quot;method&quot; -&amp;gt; request.method.value
   )
   Markers.appendEntries(markers.asJava)
 }

 def infoWithMarkers(message: String, akkaRequest: HttpRequest) =
   rootLogger.info(setMarkers(akkaRequest), message)
}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The additional structure in our logs allowed us to build useful dashboards and add more context around our diffs, which helped us identify some of the smaller inconsistencies between the APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Replicating traffic and proxy refactoring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having migrated content into the CODE database we ended up with an almost exact replica of the PROD database. The major difference was CODE had no traffic. For replicating real traffic into the CODE environment we used an open-source tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://goreplay.org/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;GoReplay&lt;/a&gt; (gor). It’s very easy to set up and it’s customisable to suit your requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As all traffic coming into our APIs was hitting the proxy first it made sense to install gor on the proxy boxes. See below how to download gor on your box and how to start capturing traffic on port 80 and send it to another server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wget https://github.com/buger/goreplay/releases/download/v0.16.0.2/gor_0.16.0_x64.tar.gz

tar -xzf gor_0.16.0_x64.tar.gz gor

sudo gor --input-raw :80 --output-http http://apiv2.code.co.uk&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything worked fine for a while, but very soon we experienced an outage on production when the proxy became unavailable for a couple of minutes. Upon investigation we found all three boxes on which the proxy was running cycled at the same time. Our suspicion was that gor was using too many resources and was causing the proxy to fall over. On further investigation we found in the AWS Console that the boxes had been regularly cycling, but not at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going any deeper, we tried to find a way to still run gor, but this time without putting any more pressure on the proxy. The solution came from our secondary stack for Composer. This stack is only used in case of emergency and it has our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/info/developer-blog/2016/dec/05/testing-in-production-how-we-combined-tests-with-monitoring&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;production monitoring tool&lt;/a&gt; constantly running tests against it. Replaying traffic from this stack to CODE at double the speed worked without any issues this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new findings raised a lot of questions. The proxy had been built with the idea that it would only exist temporarily, so it perhaps hadn’t been as carefully designed as other apps. Also, it was built using &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.akka.io/docs/akka-http/current/&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Akka Http&lt;/a&gt;, which none of the team members had used before. The code was messy and full of quick fixes. We decided to start a big refactoring job to improve readability that included using for comprehensions instead of the growing nested logic we had before, and adding even more logging markers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were hoping that by taking time to understand how everything worked and by simplifying the logic we’d be able to stop the boxes from cycling. But this didn’t work. After about two weeks of trying to make the proxy more reliable we were starting to feel like we were falling deeper and deeper down a rabbit hole. A decision had to be made. We agreed to take the risk and leave it as it was it was better to spend the time on the actual migration than trying to fix a piece of software that was going to be gone in a month’s time. We paid for this decision by going through two more production outages, each lasting about two minutes, but overall it was the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to March 2017 and we had now finished migrating CODE, with no detrimental impact on performance of the API or user experience in the CMS. We could now start to think about decommissioning the proxy in CODE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first stage of this was to change the priorities of the APIs, so that the proxy talked to Postgres first. As previously mentioned this was configuration based. However there was one complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Composer sends messages on a Kinesis stream when a document has been updated. In order to avoid message duplication, only one API should send these messages. The APIs have a flag in configuration for this; the value was true for the Mongo backed API and false for the Postgres backed one. Simply changing the proxy to talk to Postgres first wasn’t enough as the message wouldn’t get sent on the Kinesis stream until the request reached Mongo too. This was too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this, we created HTTP endpoints to change the config in memory across all instances in the load balancer instantaneously. This allowed us to very quickly switch which API was primary without needing to edit a config file and redeploy. Additionally, this could be scripted, reducing human interaction and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now all requests were going to Postgres first and API2 was talking to Kinesis, the change could be made permanent via config and a redeploy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next stage was to remove the proxy entirely and get clients to solely talk to the Postgres API. As there are numerous clients, updating each of them individually wasn’t really viable. Therefore, we pushed this up to the DNS. That is, we created a CNAME in DNS that, at first, pointed to the proxy’s ELB and would change to point to the API ELB. This allowed a single change to be made rather than updating each individual client of the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was now time to migrate PROD. Although slightly scary because, well, it’s production. The process was relatively simple as everything was based on configuration. Additionally, as we add a stage marker to the logs, it was also possible to repurpose the previously built dashboards simply by updating the Kibana filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Switching off the proxy and MongoDB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten months and 2.4m migrated articles later, we were finally in a position to switch off all the Mongo related infrastructure. But first, the moment we’d all been waiting for: kill the proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Logs showing the scaling down of the Flexible API Proxy&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/53bfd0107a6d069ac575513ed3f6b0ccb0db0597/0_0_2250_1350/master/2250.png?width=300&amp;amp;quality=85&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=747be933676582f9fb9295f87a386794&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Logs showing the scaling down of the Flexible API Proxy. Photograph: Editorial Tools/Guardian
&lt;p&gt;This small piece of software caused us so many issues we couldn’t wait to turn it off! All we needed to do was update the CNAME record to point directly at the APIV2 load balancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team gathered around one computer. The switch was one click away. No one was breathing anymore. Complete silence. Click! And the change was out. Nothing broke! We all relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly, deleting the old MongoDB API was another challenge. While frantically deleting old code we found that our integration tests have never been changed to use the new API. Everything turned red quickly. Fortunately, most of the issues were configuration related and therefore easy to fix. But there were a couple of issues with the PostgreSQL queries that were caught by the tests. Trying to think of things we could have done to avoid this error, we realised that when starting a big piece of work you also have to accept that you’re going to make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything that came afterwards worked smoothly. We detached all the Mongo instances from OpsManager and then terminated them. The only thing left to do was celebrate. And get some sleep.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 17:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>philliphaydon</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/info/2018/nov/30/bye-bye-mongo-hello-postgres</og:url>
<og:description>In April the Guardian switched off the Mongo DB cluster used to store our content after completing a migration to PostgreSQL on Amazon RDS. This post covers why and how</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/4842b3009287b04d043eb1b627ee8fa5e6e77096/0_19_3817_2289/master/3817.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;s=26ad28d56fb8b1130e12cd61112ab28c</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Bye bye Mongo, Hello Postgres | Digital blog</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/info/2018/nov/30/bye-bye-mongo-hello-postgres</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Go Modules in 2019</title>
<link>https://blog.golang.org/modules2019</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.golang.org/modules2019</guid>
<description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/modules2019&quot;&gt;Go Modules in 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;19 December 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_1.&quot;&gt;What a year!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 was a great year for the Go ecosystem, with package management as one of our major focuses. In February, we started a community-wide discussion about how to integrate package management directly into the Go toolchain, and in August we delivered the first rough implementation of that feature, called Go modules, in Go 1.11. The migration to Go modules will be the most far-reaching change for the Go ecosystem since Go 1. Converting the entire ecosystem—code, users, tools, and so on—from GOPATH to modules will require work in many different areas. The module system will in turn help us deliver better authentication and build speeds to the Go ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is a preview of what the Go team is planning relating to modules in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_2.&quot;&gt;Releases&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go 1.11, released in August 2018, introduced &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/doc/go1.11#modules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;preliminary support for modules&lt;/a&gt;. For now, module support is maintained alongside the traditional GOPATH-based mechanisms. The &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; command defaults to module mode when run in directory trees outside GOPATH/src and marked by &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; files in their roots. This setting can be overridden by setting the transitional environment variable &lt;code&gt;$GO111MODULE&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;on&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;off&lt;/code&gt;; the default behavior is &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt; mode. We’ve already seen significant adoption of modules across the Go community, along with many helpful suggestions and bug reports to help us improve modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go 1.12, scheduled for February 2019, will refine module support but still leave it in &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt; mode by default. In addition to many bug fixes and other minor improvements, perhaps the most significant change in Go 1.12 is that commands like &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;run&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;x.go&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;rsc.io/2fa@v1.1.0&lt;/code&gt; can now operate in &lt;code&gt;GO111MODULE=on&lt;/code&gt; mode without an explicit &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim is for Go 1.13, scheduled for August 2019, to enable module mode by default (that is, to change the default from &lt;code&gt;auto&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;on&lt;/code&gt;) and deprecate GOPATH mode. In order to do that, we’ve been working on better tooling support along with better support for the open-source module ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_3.&quot;&gt;Tooling &amp;amp; IDE Integration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the eight years that we’ve had GOPATH, an incredible amount of tooling has been created that assumes Go source code is stored in GOPATH. Moving to modules requires updating all code that makes that assumption. We’ve designed a new package, &lt;a href=&quot;https://godoc.org/golang.org/x/tools/go/packages&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;golang.org/x/tools/go/packages&lt;/a&gt;, that abstracts the operation of finding and loading information about the Go source code for a given target. This new package adapts automatically to both GOPATH and modules mode and is also extensible to tool-specific code layouts, such as the one used by Bazel. We’ve been working with tool authors throughout the Go community to help them adopt golang.org/x/tools/go/packages in their tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this effort, we’ve also been working to unify the various source code querying tools like gocode, godef, and go-outline into a single tool that can be used from the command line and also supports the &lt;a href=&quot;https://langserver.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;language server protocol&lt;/a&gt; used by modern IDEs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition to modules and the changes in package loading also prompted a significant change to Go program analysis. As part of reworking &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;vet&lt;/code&gt; to support modules, we introduced a generalized framework for incremental analysis of Go programs, in which an analyzer is invoked for one package at a time. In this framework, the analysis of one package can write out facts made available to analyses of other packages that import the first. For example, &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;vet&lt;/code&gt;’s analysis of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://golang.org/pkg/log/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;log package&lt;/a&gt; determines and records the fact that &lt;code&gt;log.Printf&lt;/code&gt; is a &lt;code&gt;fmt.Printf&lt;/code&gt; wrapper. Then &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;vet&lt;/code&gt; can check printf-style format strings in other packages that call &lt;code&gt;log.Printf&lt;/code&gt;. This framework should enable many new, sophisticated program analysis tools to help developers find bugs earlier and understand code better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_4.&quot;&gt;Module Index&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important parts of the original design for &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt; was that it was &lt;em&gt;decentralized&lt;/em&gt;: we believed then—and we still believe today—that anyone should be able to publish their code on any server, in contrast to central registries such as Perl’s CPAN, Java’s Maven, or Node’s NPM. Placing domain names at the start of the &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt; import space reused an existing decentralized system and avoided needing to solve anew the problems of deciding who can use which names. It also allowed companies to import code on private servers alongside code from public servers. It is critical to preserve this decentralization as we shift to Go modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralization of Go’s dependencies has had many benefits, but it also brought a few significant drawbacks. The first is that it’s too hard to find all the publicly-available Go packages. Every site that wants to deliver information about packages has to do its own crawling, or else wait until a user asks about a particular package before fetching it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working on a new service, the Go Module Index, that will provide a public log of packages entering the Go ecosystem. Sites like godoc.org and goreportcard.com will be able to watch this log for new entries instead of each independently implementing code to find new packages. We also want the service to allow looking up packages using simple queries, to allow &lt;code&gt;goimports&lt;/code&gt; to add imports for packages that have not yet been downloaded to the local system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_5.&quot;&gt;Module Authentication&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt; relies on connection-level authentication (HTTPS or SSH) to check that it is talking to the right server to download code. There is no additional check of the code itself, leaving open the possibility of man-in-the-middle attacks if the HTTPS or SSH mechanisms are compromised in some way. Decentralization means that the code for a build is fetched from many different servers, which means the build depends on many systems to serve correct code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Go modules design improves code authentication by storing a &lt;code&gt;go.sum&lt;/code&gt; file in each module; that file lists the cryptographic hash of the expected file tree for each of the module’s dependencies. When using modules, the &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; command uses &lt;code&gt;go.sum&lt;/code&gt; to verify that dependencies are bit-for-bit identical to the expected versions before using them in a build. But the &lt;code&gt;go.sum&lt;/code&gt; file only lists hashes for the specific dependencies used by that module. If you are adding a new dependency or updating dependencies with &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;-u&lt;/code&gt;, there is no corresponding entry in &lt;code&gt;go.sum&lt;/code&gt; and therefore no direct authentication of the downloaded bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For publicly-available modules, we intend to run a service we call a &lt;em&gt;notary&lt;/em&gt; that follows the module index log, downloads new modules, and cryptographically signs statements of the form “module M at version V has file tree hash H.” The notary service will publish all these notarized hashes in a queryable, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.certificate-transparency.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Certificate Transparency&lt;/a&gt;-style &lt;a href=&quot;http://static.usenix.org/event/sec09/tech/full_papers/crosby.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tamper-proof log&lt;/a&gt;, so that anyone can verify that the notary is behaving correctly. This log will serve as a public, global &lt;code&gt;go.sum&lt;/code&gt; file that &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt; can use to authenticate modules when adding or updating dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aiming to have the &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; command check notarized hashes for publicly-available modules not already in &lt;code&gt;go.sum&lt;/code&gt; starting in Go 1.13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_6.&quot;&gt;Module Mirrors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the decentralized &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt; fetches code from multiple origin servers, fetching code is only as fast and reliable as the slowest, least reliable server. The only defense available before modules was to vendor dependencies into your own repositories. While vendoring will continue to be supported, we’d prefer a solution that works for all modules—not just the ones you’re already using—and that does not require duplicating a dependency into every repository that uses it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Go module design introduces the idea of a module proxy, which is a server that the &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; command asks for modules, instead of the origin servers. One important kind of proxy is a &lt;em&gt;module mirror&lt;/em&gt;, which answers requests for modules by fetching them from origin servers and then caching them for use in future requests. A well-run mirror should be fast and reliable even when some origin servers have gone down. We are planning to launch a mirror service for publicly-available modules in 2019. JFrog’s GoCenter and Microsoft’s Athens projects are planning mirror services too. (We anticipate that companies will have multiple options for running their own internal mirrors as well, but this post is focusing on public mirrors.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One potential problem with mirrors is that they are precisely man-in-the-middle servers, making them a natural target for attacks. Go developers need some assurance that the mirrors are providing the same bits that the origin servers would. The notary process we described in the previous section addresses exactly this concern, and it will apply to downloads using mirrors as well as downloads using origin servers. The mirrors themselves need not be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aiming to have the Google-run module mirror ready to be used by default in the &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; command starting in Go 1.13. Using an alternate mirror, or no mirror at all, will be trivial to configure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_7.&quot;&gt;Module Discovery&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we mentioned earlier that the module index will make it easier to build sites like godoc.org. Part of our work in 2019 will be a major revamp of godoc.org to make it more useful for developers who need to discover available modules and then decide whether to rely on a given module or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;TOC_8.&quot;&gt;Big Picture&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This diagram shows how module source code moves through the design in this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.golang.org/modules2019/code.png&quot; width=&quot;374&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before, all consumers of Go source code—the &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; command and any sites like godoc.org—fetched code directly from each code host. Now they can fetch cached code from a fast, reliable mirror, while still authenticating that the downloaded bits are correct. And the index service makes it easy for mirrors, godoc.org, and any other similar sites to keep up with all the great new code being added to the Go ecosystem every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited about the future of Go modules in 2019, and we hope you are too. Happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;By Russ Cox&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 15:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>baijum</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.golang.org/modules2019</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>MailChimp deleted my account with no warning</title>
<link>https://blog.rongarret.info/2018/12/mailchimp-deleted-my-account-with-no.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.rongarret.info/2018/12/mailchimp-deleted-my-account-with-no.html</guid>
<description>[See update at the bottom of the post.]&lt;p&gt;I make and sell a security product called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sc4.us/hsm/index.html&quot;&gt;SC4-HSM&lt;/a&gt; which, among other things, acts as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/solutions/fido-u2f/&quot;&gt;FIDO U2F key&lt;/a&gt;.  A few days ago I was contacted by an independent security researcher named Christian Reitter saying (correctly) that he had discovered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.trezor.io/details-about-the-security-updates-in-trezor-one-firmware-1-7-2-3c97adbf121e&quot;&gt;security flaw&lt;/a&gt; that impacted a wide range of such keys.  It turned out that the SC4-HSM is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; impacted by the flaw, so I waited for the information embargo period to end and went to send out a notice to my mailing list letting my customers know all was well and they didn't need to worry.  I keep my mailing list on MailChimp.  I don't use the account very often, but every time I have used it I have had no problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, however, when I went to log in to my account, I was met with the following message:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This account has been deactivated. To continue using Mailchimp, please create a new account with a new username. If you have questions, please contact compliance@mailchimp.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I went to my web site to see what a customer would experience if they tried to sign up for my list, and the result was the most unhelpful error message I have ever seen on the web (and that's saying something):&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Ojf-0w0gA6Y/XBhPzyaga3I/AAAAAAAABWs/o7kZ24ReSj4jJRa-FeCLW5bI_ggrbIhCgCK4BGAYYCw/s1600/Untitled.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Ojf-0w0gA6Y/XBhPzyaga3I/AAAAAAAABWs/o7kZ24ReSj4jJRa-FeCLW5bI_ggrbIhCgCK4BGAYYCw/s400/Untitled.png&quot; width=&quot;322&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Remember, this is what one of &lt;em&gt;my prospective customers&lt;/em&gt; would see.  Such a person may or may not have a MailChimp account, most likely not, so what would be the point of going to a dashboard?  Assuming that button actually took you to a dashboard.  Which it doesn't.)&lt;p&gt;I was shocked.  As I said, I don't use my account very much, but I know it was active as of November 26 (three weeks ago) because someone signed up for my mailing list that week and I received a notification about that.  I went back through my mail archives to see if a warning or notification about this had gotten spam-filtered somehow.  Nope.  Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the situation is this: MailChimp shut down my account without even &lt;em&gt;notifying&lt;/em&gt; me, let alone warning me that this was about to happen.  At the same time, they turned the link on my site that prospective customers use to sign up for my mailing list into a dead link, and cut off my access to the existing list so I can no longer contact my existing customers.  The only way to contact MailChimp is by email (they don't have a phone number AFAICT).  I sent them an inquiry about this but they have not responded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As if all that were not bad enough, there appears on the face of it to be no way to re-activate my account.  The only option given in the error message is  &quot;To continue using Mailchimp, please create a new account with a new username.&quot;  If I take this error message at face value, my mailing list is gone forever.  WTAF MailChimp?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really don't like to resort to public shaming, but this really is unacceptable.  Even if I do manage to get my account and/or mailing list back somehow, I don't see how I can ever rely on MailChimp for anything mission critical.  Pulling the rug out from under me like this is something you only get to do once.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: MailChimp just now (as of 12/19 9:12 AM PST) reinstated my account.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 14:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>lisper</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://blog.rongarret.info/2018/12/mailchimp-deleted-my-account-with-no.html</og:url>
<og:title>MailChimp deleted my account with no warning or notification</og:title>
<og:description>[See update at the bottom of the post.] I make and sell a security product called the SC4-HSM  which, among other things, acts as a FIDO U...</og:description>
<og:image>https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Ojf-0w0gA6Y/XBhPzyaga3I/AAAAAAAABWs/o7kZ24ReSj4jJRa-FeCLW5bI_ggrbIhCgCK4BGAYYCw/w1200-h630-p-k-no-nu/Untitled.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.rongarret.info/2018/12/mailchimp-deleted-my-account-with-no.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>With trust destroyed, Facebook is haunted by old data deals</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/19/all-out-of-faithbook/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/19/all-out-of-faithbook/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;featured__span-first-words&quot;&gt;As Facebook colonized&lt;/span&gt; the rest of the web with its functionality in hopes of fueling user growth, it built aggressive integrations with partners that are coming under newfound scrutiny through a deeply reported &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/18/technology/facebook-privacy.html&quot;&gt;New York Times investigation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;span&gt;Some of what Facebook did was sloppy or unsettling, including forgetting to shut down APIs when it cancelled its Instant Personalization feature for other sites in 2014, and how it used contact syncing to power friend recommendations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But other moves aren’t as bad as they sound. &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; did provide Spotify and Netflix the ability to access users messages, but only so people could send friends songs or movies via Facebook messages without leaving those apps. And Facebook did let Yahoo and Blackberry access people’s News Feeds, but to let users browse those feeds within social hub features inside those apps. These partners could only access data when users logged in and connected their Facebook accounts, and were only approved to use this data to provide Facebook-related functionality. That means &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/spotify&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;spotify&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; at least wasn’t supposed to be rifling through everyone’s messages to find out what bands they talk about so it could build better curation algorithms, and there’s no evidence yet that it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully Facebook has ditched most of these integrations, as the dominance of iOS and Android have allowed it to build fewer, more standardized, and better safeguarded access points to its data. And it’s battened down the hatches in some ways, forcing users to shortcut from Spotify into the real Facebook Messenger rather than giving third-parties any special access to offer Facebook Messaging themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-large wp-image-1615241&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/facebook-custom-audiences-certification-consent1.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;370&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most glaring allegation &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/12/facebooks-partners/&quot;&gt;Facebook hasn’t adequately responded&lt;/a&gt; to yet is that it used data from Amazon, Yahoo, and Huawei to improve friend suggestions through People You May Know — perhaps its creepiest feature. The company needs to accept the loss of growth hacking trade secrets and become much more transparent about how it makes so uncannily accurate recommendations of who to friend request — as &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/amazon-and-facebook-reportedly-had-a-secret-data-sharin-1831192148&quot;&gt;Gizmodo’s Kashmir Hill&lt;/a&gt; has documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, Facebook has admitted to missteps, with its Director of Developer Platforms and Program&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt; Konstantinos Papamiltiadis writing “we shouldn’t have left the APIs in place after we shut down instant personalization.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In others, we’ll have decide where to draw the line between what was actually dangerous and what gives us the chills at first glance. You don’t ask permission from friends to read an email from them on a certain browser or device, so should you worry if they saw your Facebook status update on a &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/blackberry&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;blackberry&quot;&gt;Blackberry&lt;/a&gt; social hub feature instead of the traditional Facebook app? Well that depends on how the access is monitored and meted out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underlying question is whether we trust that Facebook and these other big tech companies actually abided by rules to oversee and not to overuse data. Facebook has done plenty wrong, and after repeatedly failing to be transparent or &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/25/nowhere-to-go/&quot;&gt;live up to its apologies&lt;/a&gt;, it doesn’t deserve the benefit of the doubt. For that reason, I don’t want it giving any developer — even ones I normally trust like Spotify — access to sensitive data protected merely by their promise of good behavior despite financial incentives for misuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s former chief security officer Alex Stamos &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexstamos/status/1075298459064758275&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that “allowing for 3rd party clients is the kind of pro-competition move we want to see from dominant platforms. For ex, making Gmail only accessible to Android and the Gmail app would be horrible. For the NY Times to try to scandalize this kind of integration is wrong.” But countered that by noting that “integrations that are sneaky or send secret data to servers controlled by others really is wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if Spotify and &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/netflix&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;netflix&quot;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; didn’t abuse the access Facebook provided, there’s always eventually a Cambridge Analytica. Tech companies have proven their word can’t necessarily be trusted. The best way to protect users is to properly lock down the platforms with ample vetting, limits, and oversight &lt;span&gt;so there won’t be gray areas that require us to put our faith in the kindness of businesses.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 14:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ihsoj</dc:creator>
<og:title>With trust destroyed, Facebook is haunted by old data deals</og:title>
<og:description>As Facebook colonized the rest of the web with its functionality in hopes of fueling user growth, it built aggressive integrations with partners that are coming under newfound scrutiny through a deeply reported New York Times investigation. Some of what Facebook did was sloppy or unsettling, includ…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Facebook-Haunted.png?w=740</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/12/19/all-out-of-faithbook/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/19/all-out-of-faithbook/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What I learned in ten years of blogging</title>
<link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/starting-a-blog/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://ferrucc.io/posts/starting-a-blog/</guid>
<description>&lt;header class=&quot;mt4 w-100 mw7&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;f6 b helvetica tracked&quot;&gt;POSTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;time class=&quot;f6 mv4 dib tracked&quot; datetime=&quot;2018-12-15T20:57:56+01:00&quot;&gt;December 15, 2018&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m 21, but I’ve been blogging for almost 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I grew up doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I’ve written on the internet has reached millions of people. Most of what I’ve written is in Italian, but I was also quite successful when writing in english. My Quora profile, reached 400k people in three months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through blogging I had the opportunity to travel the world, getting free tickets to all the biggest music festivals (Ultra, Tomorrowland.. you name it), getting promos from the Majors and interviewing my favorite artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the numbers of my first blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://edmnews.it&quot;&gt;EDMnews.it&lt;/a&gt; these are the only ones I could find as my other domains expired 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ferrucc.io/starting-a-blog/edmnews-views.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually as I didn’t have time to blog anymore and my personal interests moved away from EDM the website got assimilated into &lt;a href=&quot;https://thisisedm.it&quot;&gt;This is EDM&lt;/a&gt; which was a Google News source and had more than 100k pageviews a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was because of my Wordpress websites that I was pushed towards learning how to code. Without blogging, I wouldn’t be who I am today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that it’s still among the best ways to get your message out there and meet interesting people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-m-now-opening-up-the-kimono&quot;&gt;👘 I’m now opening up the kimono.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;here-s-all-i-know-about-blogging&quot;&gt;Here’s all I know about Blogging:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;No one has time to read your article, write the first lines like they’re a TLDR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design of your site is irrelevant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To start out you don’t need any software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define your audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out where your audience is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For SEO don’t write short articles (&amp;gt;2000 words)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One well researched article is better than a lot of mediocre content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend half of the time writing, half promoting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend 50% of the writing time actually writing, the rest tweaking, reading and illustrating. Details are important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spill all your secrets. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t be worried about the fact that you’ll run out of content, you won’t.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no rules, slowly craft your unique style.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back in your old posts and link them to newer ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a Newsletter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do what everyone else is afraid to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to people asking for things or offering tips.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carefully crafting something timeless that really penetrates your readers minds is hard, but worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time when you read something you already know everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10% of the time things are different, you feel like a switch turns on in your head and suddenly see things differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I find content that makes me feel this way I’ll refresh the page of the website every day to check if I missed something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel hooked, like an addict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what we’re going for.. getting unsolicited messages like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;14&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This was illuminating, it opened up a world of possibilities in my mind.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve always thought this, but didn’t have the courage to write it down, thanks for doing it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Your words made me finally what’s the big deal about X, thanks”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive in and learn how to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-audience&quot;&gt;🕵️‍♂️ The Audience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first step&lt;/strong&gt; when starting out a blog is figuring out who’s your audience. Most people I know skip this step, but it’s essential. It’s easy to blurt out some words and share them on your social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s much harder to create articles that resonate with the people you want to reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain how to do this I’ll show you how I’m doing it right now for this personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until now I used this blog to help me think, but for the new year I decided to treat it more seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is my goal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that it’s a “personal” blog doesn’t mean that it’s about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact it means its about what I can offer to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;strong&gt;first practical tip&lt;/strong&gt; is related to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your about page in your blog has to be about how you can help and what people can expect from you. Then eventually about you..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But let’s be honest, no one gives a shit about you, or me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is my audience?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re starting a blog for your company you have to see who your customers generally are, or which customers would be your ideal audience and cater to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a description of who my realistic reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;13&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your name is Vincent, you are a 30yo generalist from France, you don’t work long hours for your day job. You’ve spent some time working remotely, but are now stable in the US. You’ve started more projects than you can count, and some were successful. You’re interested in anything that is not ordinary and you are a contrarian by nature. You don’t shy away from an argument and never get offended. You aren’t really interested in retiring, you’re more interested in experimenting than anything else. Some people perceive you as a bit of a dick you couldn’t care less.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you defined your audience you have &lt;del&gt;to figure out if it’s large enough.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Come on, it’s the internet, don’t worry about it it’s big enough.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact if it seems big enough for you, I’d consider to niche down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-name&quot;&gt;📌 The name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next step is to &lt;strong&gt;pick a name&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s not important, just make sure it’s something you like and that it’s not too generic or impossible to remember. Don’t spend more than a day on this and once you find a name sleep at least one night over it before settling for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case I picked my name Ferruccio as the domain name, because my name is extremely rare and I already owned the domain &lt;a href=&quot;https://ferrucc.io&quot;&gt;ferrucc.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside is that Americans have no clue on how to say it, but I’m okay with this. It’s certainly easier to remember than certain Indian names (🧐 talking about you Chamath Palihapitiya).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-style&quot;&gt;💅 The Style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The styling of your blog, as in how it looks doesn’t really count too much at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your writing style on the other hand makes all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on who your audience is, you have to adjust the tone of your conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example as I picked someone much older and experienced then me as a target audience it would make no sense if I had a “know it all” tone. My audience isn’t native english speakers so I won’t be complicating my language and I’ll limit my vocabulary in an effort to be as clear and accessible as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you really want to make something unique one thing you can do is have custom illustrations in your style. Having a coherent style for illustrations in your blog can be something that makes people remember about you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than big corporate blogs &lt;a href=&quot;https://waitbutwhy.com/&quot;&gt;Wait But Why&lt;/a&gt; does this very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are bad at drawing learn how to use something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sketchapp.com/&quot;&gt;Sketch&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still coming up with a design style for the illustrations on this website, but I think it’s going to be something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ferrucc.io/starting-a-blog/chat.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ferrucc.io/starting-a-blog/tree.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a little obsessed with design, but illustrations are only one of the things you can do to stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a coder you can try and make your posts interactive with small programs inside of them or interactive visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great example of this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nealagarwal&quot;&gt;Neal Agarawall&lt;/a&gt;’s blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://neal.fun/&quot;&gt;Neal.fun&lt;/a&gt;. Look at this lottery simulator he made, that visually explains you why gambling is a bad idea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ferrucc.io/starting-a-blog/powerball.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is this &lt;a href=&quot;https://lab-cryptotrend.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;blockchain simulator&lt;/a&gt; (in Italian) I created as a promotional product for an Italian cryptocurrency blog I created a while back and grew to 10k uniques in a month. I was also creating unique illustrations for that one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have any of the above skills either learn them by doing or feel free to keep everything simple sticking with text content. To prove the point that you don’t need to do any of these things here are some ugly blogs with great content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the Gwern blog looks like: &lt;img src=&quot;https://ferrucc.io/starting-a-blog/gwern-ugly.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not really important to have any illustrations, but the fact that I can make them and express my messages visually helps me stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So find something unique you can do, and add it to your site! &lt;strong&gt;An idea that requires no particular skills for example is to add an audio version of your posts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-writing-process&quot;&gt;📝 The Writing Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having figured out all the basics for your blog you’re ready to jump to the writing part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to do this is to Brainstorm a couple of Titles that your audience and ideally also you find interesting and start writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title doesn’t really have to describe what the content of the article is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good way to pick titles is using the content from &lt;a href=&quot;https://ferrucc.io/posts/old-school-marketers/&quot;&gt;“The First Hundred Million”&lt;/a&gt; which is a book from the 1920s by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E._Haldeman-Julius&quot;&gt;Julius Haldeman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously your article can’t be completely off topic, but your goal with it has to be to captivate and inform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on where your target audience hangs out you also have to figure out how your articles should be. For instance if your target readers are on a subreddit you can write posts in the 700-800 word range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be successful on search engines though you might want to make your content much longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s some data that shows the ideal word count: &lt;img src=&quot;https://ferrucc.io/starting-a-blog/shares-data.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see articles in the &amp;gt;1000 words range get much more shares than shorter content. Over the 3000 words mark looks like the reward for (word count)/(shares) starts to decrease, but there are no strict rules, do how you see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you can’t ignore is that longer content clearly correlates to more organic traffic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ferrucc.io/starting-a-blog/hubspot.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my suggestions if you want your blog to grow is to write long content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although keep in mind that this correlation could also be due to external factors. &lt;em&gt;Maybe to write longer articles on average more research is required&lt;/em&gt;, ensuring a higher quality of content and thus more shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have no clue on how to write a blog post you can run a search for articles you like targeted to the audience and deconstruct them trying to figure out a recurring theme or template structure you can follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your blog posts are going to be a personal thing so I don’t think I can give other suggestions that can help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand if you are starting a company blog a good tip is to write content related to what your product does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example my friends at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boxysuite.com&quot;&gt;Boxy Suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; make Google Apps that are native apps for Mac OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also recently decided to start a blog for their company to attract more customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their case the goal of the blog is to be found by Gmail power users. So their blog posts will be content like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“10 Gmail shortcuts to maximize productivity”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The best Chrome extensions for Gmail”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of your posts sometimes it’s also a good idea to qualify yourself as an expert, showing some context on why you’re talking about something and why people should listen to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something you can do and that can help in many cases, but it doesn’t mean you &lt;strong&gt;have&lt;/strong&gt; to do this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fixing-your-drafts&quot;&gt;🔨 Fixing your Drafts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you finished writing wait for a day and start reading everything you wrote fixing typos, trimming out useless words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a sentence doesn’t add any value remove it. If a sentence is too long split it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve readability highlight important words with &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;italics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it’s also good practice to have a couple of short paragraphs that lead to a longer one, like I just did here. Avoid long sentences and long paragraphs, they’re not easy on the eyes of the reader and will cause people to scroll through your content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve finished your post. Sleep another night over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post it the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you feel sick at reading it the n-th time you’ve likely done a great job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you identified your audience, you also know where your audience hangs out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repost your article on the platforms that allow it, like Medium and subreddits in your niche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share your content on Social Media and even text it to the friends you have that might care about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another must, is to collect emails of your readers. If someone gets on your website and leaves, they’ll likely never come back, unless you manage to get your hands on their email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An email is important because it gives you direct contact with people and reduces the impact on your audience of any algorithm change by large media companies or social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also start reaching out to people with blogs similar to yours and pitch them guest posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guest posts are a great opportunity to tap in wider audiences and gain backlinks to your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips-from-my-friends&quot;&gt;Tips from my friends:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I want to make this article the best resource out there on blogging I decided to reach out to some people I admire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some awesome tips from my friends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pat-walls-https-twitter-com-thepatwalls-of-starter-story-https-www-starterstory-com&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thepatwalls&quot;&gt;Pat Walls&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.starterstory.com/&quot;&gt;Starter Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19,470 uniques in November 2018 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.starterstory.com/&quot;&gt;Starter Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t do any keyword research. Most of my content is interviews, so I have other people write the content. This allows me to make much more of it because I don’t have to do all of the hard work of writing. Most of my work is to make sure the content is good and work with the writer to make it better. I promote mainly on Reddit and social media. On Reddit I post “case studies” that are mostly reposts of my blog content to a subreddit as a self post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that my content has a recurring format is a double edged sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👍 It allowed me to systemize the content creation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👎 It also hurts my growth though as people get tired of the same format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hugo-di-francesco-https-twitter-com-hugo-df-of-code-with-hugo-https-codewithhugo-com&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hugo__df&quot;&gt;Hugo Di Francesco&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://codewithhugo.com/&quot;&gt;Code with Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0-12k Unique users/month in 7 months&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing ads isn’t bad, as long as there’s nothing you can do instead of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basing everything around ads will make you focus purely on volume, not quality of traffic. The issue with trying for a “let’s get another 100,000 users on the site” is that, 100,000 is harder than 10 or 100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got anything to sell, sell it, an advertiser paying you means they value the attention more than whatever amount of money they’re spending (never mind all the wasted $$ in middlemen and fees).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Value your audiences attention, get the ad money but use it as a crutch until you’ve got better things to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;kp-https-twitter-com-thisiskp-of-kp-http-thisiskp-com&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thisiskp_&quot;&gt;KP&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://thisiskp.com/&quot;&gt;KP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;gt;1000 posts written over the years - 18k unique users a year on his new blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you use momentum as a hack for consistency. Create a simple routine with a clear recurring cue. My cue was “8:30am” every day and the hack I used was to “open my laptop and type 1 complete sentence. Since this was such an achievable goal, it became so easy to stick with the habit. Of course, I wrote way more than 1 sentence but it’s a great way to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ad on your website means the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone through a platform (that generally keeps 50% of the money) is paying 2x what it’s giving to you to promote a product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These people aren’t dumb, they’re doing it because they’re expecting a return on investment. To my knowledge they’ve been doing it for more than 30 years and still haven’t stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that these ads are effective even if they’re poorly targeted and sold at what seems to you as an inflated price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my suggestion here is simple. You know your reader better than any advertiser, so sell them something you know they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked about this with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hugo__df&quot;&gt;Hugo Di Francesco&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://codewithhugo.com/&quot;&gt;Code with Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and he told me that for him on most of his site ads make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s why: “Advertisers took on the risk. I de-risked the user interaction. I make money without having to build trust and sell something”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is the writer of an article that you found useful, surely has more trust than an advertiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact after talking with Hugo, we realised together that his strategy works well on posts that aren’t related to things he’s selling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On posts that are related to things he’s selling, instead of a generic ad, he fills that space with an ad for himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ferrucc.io/starting-a-blog/hugo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren’t any rules in blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can take some cues from what I learned over the years, or ignore everything and do things your own way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact if you’re breaking the rules email me a link to your posts. I’m constantly looking for inspiration and fascinated by people that change the rules and still get results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not getting results, reread this post and figure out what you’re doing wrong.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;aside class=&quot;w-30-l mt6-l&quot;/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 13:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>0xferruccio</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://ferrucc.io/starting-a-blog/secrets.png</og:image>
<og:title>Everything I've learned in 10 years of Blogging</og:title>
<og:description>What I've written on the internet has reached millions of people and today I'm opening up the kimono, here's all I know about blogging.</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://ferrucc.io/posts/starting-a-blog/</og:url>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://ferrucc.io/posts/starting-a-blog/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>LibreRouter: Powering community networks with free and open hardware</title>
<link>https://blog.apnic.net/2018/12/18/librerouter-powering-community-networks-with-free-and-open-hardware/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://blog.apnic.net/2018/12/18/librerouter-powering-community-networks-with-free-and-open-hardware/</guid>
<description>&lt;img width=&quot;555&quot; height=&quot;202&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/logo_from_datasheet_banner-555x202.png&quot; class=&quot;attachment-featuredImageLarge size-featuredImageLarge wp-post-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/logo_from_datasheet_banner.png 555w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/logo_from_datasheet_banner-300x110.png 300w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/logo_from_datasheet_banner-206x75.png 206w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/logo_from_datasheet_banner-256x93.png 256w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 555px) 100vw, 555px&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Community networks have become vital in enabling unserved or underserved communities to access the online information and services they need. Typically, community network infrastructure is built on consumer grade off-the-shelf hardware, which has its firmware flashed, hacked and modified to serve the needs of a community network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This kind of modification became much more difficult in the wake of a 2014 &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.documentcloud.org/documents/2339685/fcc-software-security-requirements.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;United States Federal Communications Commission (FCC) regulation&lt;/a&gt; [PDF] that required wireless infrastructure vendors to secure their products against any software modification. The regulation has since been rolled back, but while in effect it had a global impact, with many manufacturers implementing this protection, even on devices used outside the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to this software lockdown, &lt;a href=&quot;https://librerouter.org/team&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;a group of hackers and engineers with experience in deploying community networks&lt;/a&gt; around the globe got together and decided that they should build their own router. And so, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://librerouter.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;LibreRouter&lt;/a&gt; project was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/500mts_test_medium.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-25465&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/500mts_test_medium.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Librerouter in testing&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/500mts_test_medium.jpg 460w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/500mts_test_medium-225x300.jpg 225w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 1 — The LibreRouter in testing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addressing community needs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team saw the LibreRouter project as an opportunity to address the particular needs of community networks, while also addressing the shortcomings of off-the-shelf devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicolás Pace, member of Argentina’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://altermundi.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;AlterMundi&lt;/a&gt; and member of the Liberouter team, says that this was an opportunity for communities to design a router that fit their needs. “Don’t design from the computer desk, design from the community on. Because it’s their need that you need to fulfil, not the manufacturer’s need”. From their work within communities, the team identified some guiding principles. They are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Approachability&lt;/strong&gt;: To enable geek-free wireless mesh networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;: To be able to scale without impacting speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robustness&lt;/strong&gt;: Devices should be rock solid. Especially in remote areas, taking a device to be repaired is a lengthy and involved process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affordability&lt;/strong&gt;: Routers will be sold for an affordable price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The router also needed to be suited to the conditions of rural communities, such as remoteness, limited digital skills, limited or no electricity, low budgets, and limited line of sight and/or available spectrum allocation. Nicolás  also identified cultural specifics as a consideration: “Who runs the community? Who owns infrastructure? [Is it] managed by one or by many or by everyone? Also, what do they want to do with the infrastructure?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the project progressed, the team identified reparability as an additional key requirement, especially when networks are built in areas that are difficult to reach and where resources are scarce. “If they do break, the devices need to be repairable by the communities, with parts that are available to them”, Nicolás says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The hardware – LibreRouter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these requirements in mind, the team designed LibreRouter as an open hardware device, meaning that users can learn how it works and make modifications as they wish. Nicolás explains: “the most common case would be if it breaks, they can understand why it’s broken and repair it and search for replacement parts and replace them”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With proprietary hardware, “the designs were still available more or less, because you could reverse engineer them, or because they were structurally simple to figure them out… but having the blueprints allows innovation”, he adds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/librerouter_prototype.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-25461&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/librerouter_prototype.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Librerouter prototypes&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/librerouter_prototype.jpg 730w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/librerouter_prototype-300x144.jpg 300w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/librerouter_prototype-600x288.jpg 600w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/librerouter_prototype-624x299.jpg 624w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 2 — The latest prototype of the Librerouter.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LibreRouter hardware features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;2 x multiple-input multiple-output (MIMO) 2×2 5 Ghz radios, with power amplification for long-range point-to-point links. The radios are capable of 300 Mbps throughput without degradation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 2.4 Ghz radio for client devices/hotspot capability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mini PCIe ports for expansion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lightning protection hardware, capable of withstanding five to six lightning strikes before replacement is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powered by battery, solar or mains power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Future plans for the router include a TV White Space (TVWS) frequency shifter and a low-bandwidth high-gain radio for the creation of a low-power control lane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full hardware specifications can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://librerouter.org/media/documents/librerouter_specifications_v6.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; [PDF].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software – LibreMesh, LimeApp and LibreNet6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LibreRouter runs the &lt;a href=&quot;https://libremesh.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;LibreMesh&lt;/a&gt; software, which is layered on top of &lt;a href=&quot;https://openwrt.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;OpenWRT&lt;/a&gt;. LibreMesh creates mesh networks using a two-layered architecture, featuring &lt;a href=&quot;https://libremesh.org/howitworks.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Better Approach To Mobile Adhoc Networking  – Advanced (BATMAN-ADV) and BMX6 routing protocols&lt;/a&gt;.  The aim of LibreMesh is to simplify mesh network configuration, including automation of IP address assignment and mesh DNS configuration. Since it’s open source, LibreMesh may also be modified or customized by anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LibreMesh-powered networks may be monitored and managed using the LimeApp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot-from-2018-05-24-22-12-50.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-25463&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot-from-2018-05-24-22-12-50.png&quot; alt=&quot;Librerouter mesh&quot; srcset=&quot;https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot-from-2018-05-24-22-12-50.png 625w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot-from-2018-05-24-22-12-50-300x298.png 300w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot-from-2018-05-24-22-12-50-600x596.png 600w, https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/screenshot-from-2018-05-24-22-12-50-624x620.png 624w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 625px) 100vw, 625px&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 3 — The Libremesh software simplifies mesh network configuration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LibreNet6 is a VPN that can interconnect LibreMesh-powered networks. It is expected that this feature will be particularly useful in allowing members of the community to provide remote assistance and troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supply and demand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LibreRouter is currently a prototype, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://librerouter.org/article/first-outdoor-radio-and-antenna-test/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;has performed well in tests so far&lt;/a&gt;. Prototype LibreRouters are currently being used in community networks in Mexico, Argentina, Canada and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent survey of interest was taken, and the LibreRouter received interest from over 40 communities worldwide, including community networks in Thailand, Singapore and India. Based on the survey results, the LibreRouter team expect a demand for over 2,500 routers in the next two years. A promising start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Want to get involved?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get involved in the LibreRouter project by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;rw-rating-table rw-ltr rw-left&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;Rate this article&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;views-disclaimer&quot;&gt;The views expressed by the authors of this blog are their own and do not necessarily reflect the views of APNIC. Please note a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.apnic.net/?p=395&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; applies to this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 12:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>xuande</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>LibreRouter: Powering community networks with free and open hardware | APNIC Blog</og:title>
<og:description>The LibreRouter project has developed an open source, open hardware router, customized to the needs of community-run networks.</og:description>
<og:url>https://blog.apnic.net/2018/12/18/librerouter-powering-community-networks-with-free-and-open-hardware/</og:url>
<og:image>https://blog.apnic.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/logo_from_datasheet_banner.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://blog.apnic.net/2018/12/18/librerouter-powering-community-networks-with-free-and-open-hardware/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Python gets a new governance model</title>
<link>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/775105/5db16cfe82e78dc3/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/775105/5db16cfe82e78dc3/</guid>
<description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;90%&quot; cellspacing=&quot;5&quot; readability=&quot;4.1829745596869&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;11.154598825832&quot;&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Welcome to LWN.net&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following subscription-only content has been made available to you by an LWN subscriber. Thousands of subscribers depend on LWN for the best news from the Linux and free software communities. If you enjoy this article, please consider accepting the trial offer on the right. Thank you for visiting LWN.net!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;Form&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; readability=&quot;1.2016574585635&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;3.6049723756906&quot;&gt;&lt;td readability=&quot;4.8066298342541&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Free trial subscription&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try LWN for free for 1 month: no payment or credit card required. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Promo/slink-trial2-2/claim&quot;&gt;Activate your trial subscription now&lt;/a&gt; and see why thousands of readers subscribe to LWN.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Jake Edge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;December 18, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in late October, when we &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/769178/&quot;&gt;looked in&lt;/a&gt; on the Python governance question, which came about due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/759654/&quot;&gt;resignation of Guido van Rossum&lt;/a&gt;, things seemed to be mostly set for a vote in late November. There were six Python Enhancement Proposals (PEPs) under consideration that would be ranked by voters in a two-week period ending December 1; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Instant-runoff_voting&quot;&gt;instant-runoff voting&lt;/a&gt; would be used to determine the winner. In the interim, though, much of that changed; the voting period, winner-determination mechanism, and number of PEPs under consideration are all different. But the voting concluded on December 16 and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/python-governance-vote-december-2018-results/546&quot;&gt;winner has been declared&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-8016/&quot;&gt;PEP 8016&lt;/a&gt; (&quot;The Steering Council Model&quot;), which was added to the mix in early November, came out on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right around the time of our previous article, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/python-governance-electoral-system/290&quot;&gt;new thread&lt;/a&gt; was started on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/c/committers&quot;&gt;Python committers Discourse instance&lt;/a&gt; to discuss the pros and cons of various voting systems. Instant-runoff voting fell out of favor; there were concerns that it didn't truly represent the will of the electorate, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Instant-runoff_voting#2009_Burlington_mayoral_election&quot;&gt;seen&lt;/a&gt; in a Burlington, Vermont mayoral election in 2009, for example. The fact that it was put in place by fiat under a self-imposed deadline based on in-person conversations at the core developer sprint, rather than being hashed out on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/&quot;&gt;Discourse instance&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-committers&quot;&gt;python-committers mailing list&lt;/a&gt; may have also been a factor. As Nathaniel J. Smith &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/python-governance-electoral-system/290/21&quot;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm particularly concerned by all this rhetoric about how the deadline is fixed and everyone has to get in line. I want to be done soon too! But trying to steamroller other core devs like this, and acting like some core devs get to resolve disagreements like this by pure fiat, is a really unhealthy precedent. I feel like some of us are so concerned about making sure it &lt;em&gt;looks&lt;/em&gt; like we can work together, make decisions, and hold a legitimate vote, that they're undermining our ability to &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; work together, make decisions, or hold a legitimate vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Stufft put together a &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/python-governance-electoral-system/290/40&quot;&gt;lengthy summary&lt;/a&gt; of many of the different voting systems along with their good and bad attributes. No one had any interest in using &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plurality_voting&quot;&gt;plurality voting&lt;/a&gt;&quot; (also known as &quot;first past the post&quot;), but opinions differed on other possibilities. Eventually, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-8001/&quot;&gt;PEP 8001&lt;/a&gt; (&quot;Python Governance Voting Process&quot;) was changed to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Condorcet_method&quot;&gt;Condorcet method&lt;/a&gt; to determine the winner. A tie or cycle, which are both possible—though unlikely—under the Condorcet method, would result in a re-vote among the tied options. Condorcet has been used by Debian and other projects for many years, which is part of the reason consensus formed around that method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The winner&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, Condorcet led to an election where the results were clear without any real ambiguity about them. As Tim Peters, who was one of the more active developers in the voting-methodology discussion, &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/python-governance-vote-december-2018-results/546/9&quot;&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;&lt;span&gt;Not only was there a flat-out Condorcet ('beats all') winner, but if we throw that winner out, there's also a flat-out Condorcet winner among the 7 remaining - and so on, all the way down to 'further discussion'.&lt;/span&gt;&quot; Given that the pool of voters was fairly small, 94, and that only 62 people actually voted, there could have been some far messier outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps not surprising that a late entrant into the election was the clear winner. Smith and Stufft authored the PEP; it likely benefited from the discussion of the other PEPs and the changes that were made to them along the way. It also doesn't hurt that it is explicitly intended to be boring, simple, and flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with most of the other proposals, PEP 8016 creates a council. Various sizes were proposed in the other PEPs, but the steering council of PEP 8016 consists of five people elected by the core team. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-8016/#membership&quot;&gt;definition&lt;/a&gt; of the core team is somewhat different than today's core developers or committers. The PEP explicitly states that roles other than &quot;developer&quot; could qualify for the core team. Becoming a member of the team simply requires a two-thirds majority vote of the existing members—and no veto by the steering council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The veto is not well specified in the PEP and was the subject of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/pep-8016-the-steering-council-model/394/34&quot;&gt;question&lt;/a&gt; during the discussion process. &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/pep-8016-the-steering-council-model/394/35&quot;&gt;According to Smith&lt;/a&gt;, that idea came from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/internals/organization/&quot;&gt;Django governance document&lt;/a&gt;, which was a major influence on the PEP. It is hoped that it would never have to be used, &quot;&lt;span&gt;but there are situations when the alternatives are even worse&lt;/span&gt;&quot;. There is also an escape hatch if it turns out that a core team member needs to be removed; a super-majority of four council members can vote to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The steering council&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The council is imbued with &quot;&lt;span&gt;broad authority to make decisions about the project&lt;/span&gt;&quot;, but the goal is that it uses that authority rarely; it is meant to delegate its authority broadly. The PEP says that the council should seek consensus, rather than dictate, and that it should define a standard PEP decision-making process that will (hopefully) rarely need council votes to resolve. It is, however, the &quot;&lt;span&gt;court of final appeal&lt;/span&gt;&quot; for decisions affecting the language. But the council cannot change the governance PEP; that can only happen via a two-thirds vote of the core team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mandate for the council is focused on things like the quality and stability of Python and the CPython implementation, as well as ensuring that contributing to the project is easy so that contributions will continue to flow into it. Beyond that, maintaining the relationship between the core team and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/psf/&quot;&gt;Python Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt; (PSF) is another piece of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steering council members will serve for the length of single Python feature release; after each release, a new council will be elected. Candidates must be nominated by a core team member; &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Approval_voting&quot;&gt;approval voting&lt;/a&gt;&quot; will be used to choose the new council. Each core team member can anonymously vote for zero to five of the candidates; the five with the highest total number of votes will serve on the new council, with ties decided by agreement between the tied candidates or by random choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some conflict-of-interest rules as well: &quot;&lt;span&gt;While we trust council members to act in the best interests of Python rather than themselves or their employers, the mere appearance of any one company dominating Python development could itself be harmful and erode trust.&lt;/span&gt;&quot; So no more than two council members can be from the same company; if a third person from the company is elected, they are disqualified and the next highest vote-getter moves up. If the situation arises during the council's term (e.g. a change in employer or an acquisition), enough council members must resign to ensure this makeup. Vacancies on the council (for this or any other reason) will be filled by a vote of the council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event of core team dissatisfaction with the council, a no-confidence vote can be held. A member of the core team can call for such a vote; if any other member seconds the call, a vote is held. The vote can either target a single member of the council or the council as a whole. If two-thirds of the core team votes for no confidence, the councilperson or council is removed. In the latter case, a new council election is immediately triggered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the other PEPs specified things such as how PEPs would be decided upon or placed various restrictions on who could serve on the council. Victor Stinner's &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/comparison-of-the-7-governance-peps/392&quot;&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt; of the seven proposals gives a nice overview of the commonalities and differences between them. Many were fairly similar at a high level, most obviously varying on the size of the council, though there are other substantive differences, of course. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-8010/&quot;&gt;PEP 8010&lt;/a&gt; (&quot;The Technical Leader Governance Model&quot;), which more or less preserved the &quot;benevolent dictator&quot; model, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-8012/&quot;&gt;PEP 8012&lt;/a&gt; (&quot;The Community Governance Model&quot;), which did not have a central authority, were both something of an outlier. It is interesting to note that 8012 came in second in the voting, while 8010 was one of the least favored governance options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Another election&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is council elections. There are two phases, each of which will last two weeks; first is a nomination period, followed by the actual voting. Van Rossum has not ridden off into the sunset as some might have thought; he was active in some of the threads leading up to the governance election and was the first to &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/organizing-the-council-elections/549&quot;&gt;start organizing the council election&lt;/a&gt;. He asked that the process start after the new year to give folks some time to relax over the holidays. Smith &lt;a href=&quot;https://discuss.python.org/t/organizing-the-council-elections/549/4&quot;&gt;agreed&lt;/a&gt;, noting that starting on January 6 would lead to the actual vote starting January 20 and a council elected on February 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the process has gone fairly smoothly since Van Rossum stepped down and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/759756/&quot;&gt;first steps toward new governance&lt;/a&gt; were taken back in July. There would seem to be plenty of good candidates for the council, many of whom were active in the governance discussions. The first incarnation of the council will have lots of things to decide, including the PEP approval process, but it won't have all that much time to do so. Instead of the usual 18-month cycle, the council will serve an abbreviated term until &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0569/&quot;&gt;Python 3.8 is released&lt;/a&gt;, which is currently scheduled for October 2019. The council elected after that should have a full 18 months, unless, of course, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/755224/&quot;&gt;release cadence is shortened&lt;/a&gt;. It will all be interesting to watch play out; once again, stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;Form&quot; readability=&quot;1.2534246575342&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;2.5068493150685&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you like this article?&lt;/strong&gt; Please accept our &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Promo/slink-trial2-2/claim&quot;&gt;trial subscription offer&lt;/a&gt; to be able to see more content like it and to participate in the discussion.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr width=&quot;60%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Login/?target=/Articles/775105/&quot;&gt;Log in&lt;/a&gt; to post comments)</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 11:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>OrangeTux</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/775105/5db16cfe82e78dc3/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook gave Spotify and Netflix access to users’ private messages</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/18/18147616/facebook-user-data-giveaway-nyt-apple-amazon-spotify-netflix</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/18/18147616/facebook-user-data-giveaway-nyt-apple-amazon-spotify-netflix</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;Qwma6L&quot;&gt;What to make of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/18/technology/facebook-privacy.html&quot;&gt;the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;’ latest story about Facebook’s broad data-sharing agreements&lt;/a&gt;? The story, which draws on internal documents describing the company’s partnerships, reports on previously undisclosed aspects of business partnerships with companies including Apple, Amazon, Microsoft, Spotify, and Netflix. In some cases, companies had access to data years after it was supposed to have been cut off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;B2unxy&quot;&gt;Here’s how the story is framed by reporters Gabriel J.X. Dance, Michael LaForgia, and Nicholas Confessore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9sQhc9&quot;&gt;The documents, as well as interviews with about 50 former employees of Facebook and its corporate partners, reveal that Facebook allowed certain companies access to data despite those protections. They also raise questions about whether Facebook ran afoul of a 2011 consent agreement with the Federal Trade Commission that barred the social network from sharing user data without explicit permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;YPt6ss&quot;&gt;In all, the deals described in the documents benefited more than 150 companies — most of them tech businesses, including online retailers and entertainment sites, but also automakers and media organizations. Their applications sought the data of hundreds of millions of people a month, the records show. The deals, the oldest of which date to 2010, were all active in 2017. Some were still in effect this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;URxU8p&quot;&gt;The story, which builds on reporting earlier this year from both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/06/03/technology/facebook-device-partners-users-friends-data.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=RelatedCoverage&amp;amp;pgtype=Article&amp;amp;region=Footer&quot;&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-gave-some-companies-access-to-additional-data-about-users-friends-1528490406&quot;&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, describes a variety of data-sharing partnerships, some of which users were likely unaware of. They include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;Om9rk2&quot;&gt;Giving Apple access to users’ Facebook contacts and calendar entries, even if they had disabled data sharing, as part of a partnership that still exists. Apple told the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; it was unaware that it had special access, and of the data described would never leave the user’s device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;IvSnIz&quot;&gt;Giving Amazon the names and contact information of users, in a partnership that is currently being wound down. Amazon wouldn’t discuss how it used the data other than to say it had used it “appropriately.” On Twitter, &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;’s Kashmir Hill speculated that Amazon &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kashhill/status/1075219155295580165&quot;&gt;may have used the data to fight review fraud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;Rt5MKZ&quot;&gt;Giving Bing, the Microsoft search engine, access to see names and other profile information of a user’s friends. Microsoft said it has since deleted the data. Facebook says that only user data set to “public” was accessible to Microsoft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;Hp3TOR&quot;&gt;Giving Spotify, Netflix, and the Royal Bank of Canada the ability to read users’ private Facebook messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;alpdTZ&quot;&gt;The access described in the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; story falls into three types of Facebook partnerships. The first are what Facebook calls “integrations,” and they refer to custom-built apps that Facebook built for OEMs like BlackBerry. Because they were integrated with phone operating systems, they require a broad exchange of data with OEMs. They’ve gotten a lot of attention this year, but I think most users would reasonably assume that their personal data was being exchanged with the phone manufacturer in those cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;rcDXny&quot;&gt;The second type of partnerships, which is represented by the Bing deal, are part of a now-defunct program called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/facebook-instant-personalization-how-to-disable-it-and-why/&quot;&gt;instant personalization&lt;/a&gt;.” This feature, which launched in 2010, opted every Facebook user in by default. It allowed all of its partners to personalize their own services using whatever Facebook knew about you and was willing to share. Yelp, for example, would show visitors which of their Facebook friends used the site when they visited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wm9s4w&quot;&gt;The program drew significant criticism when it launched, and it was eventually killed off in 2014. But according to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, Bing continued to have access to the data through 2017, and two other companies still had access this summer. On one hand, this was all public data — friends’ names, hometowns, and anything else they marked public. On the other hand, Facebook’s failure to shut down data access here is reminiscent of the failure &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/10/17165130/facebook-cambridge-analytica-scandal&quot;&gt;that sparked the Cambridge Analytica data privacy scandal&lt;/a&gt;: a company said it had deleted a bunch of user data turned out to have instead used it in an attempt to influence the 2016 presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5RRNQ3&quot;&gt;The final type of partnerships are essentially one-off deals that Facebook made over the years. The scariest-sounding of them all was a deal Facebook made with companies including Spotify, Netflix, and the Royal Bank of Canada in which partners were granted read and write access to users’ Facebook messages. This was the result of a broadly written API, launched in 2010 as part of an early (pre-Messenger) effort to build a messaging platform. In Spotify’s case, for example, the company plugged into your chat window to send songs to your friends. It seems possible that a rogue employee made mischief in someone’s messages, but the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; story doesn’t include any examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;IsESMK&quot;&gt;There are other worrisome details in the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; story, including reports that Yahoo and the Russian search company Yandex both retained access to user data years after it was supposed to have been cut off. Collectively, they speak to an indifference toward data security that flies in the face of recent Facebook pronouncements on the subject — most notably, chief marketing officer Carolyn Everson’s statement last week that privacy “&lt;a href=&quot;https://digiday.com/social/facebooks-carolyn-everson-privacy-foundation-company/&quot;&gt;is the foundation of our company&lt;/a&gt;.” Everson made her comments on the same day that Facebook opened a pop-up kiosk in New York City’s Bryant Park where users could ask questions about how their data is used on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5vWszO&quot;&gt;Presumably, they would have had more questions to ask if they had access to the list of 150 companies that had been making data partnerships with Facebook over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;n1Xi9R&quot;&gt;In response to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;’ report, the company acknowledged it had more work to do to regain user trust. It also highlighted some of the benefits of data sharing, including the ability to create more personalized experiences on other sites and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;FXK6xh&quot;&gt;“Facebook’s partners don’t get to ignore people’s privacy settings, and it’s wrong to suggest that they do,” said Steve Satterfield, director of privacy and public policy at Facebook, in an email. “Over the years, we’ve partnered with other companies so people can use Facebook on devices and platforms that we don’t support ourselves. Unlike a game, streaming music service, or other third-party app, which offer experiences that are &lt;em&gt;independent&lt;/em&gt; of Facebook, these partners can only offer specific Facebook features and are unable to use information for independent purposes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dgUNYA&quot;&gt;The company &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2018/12/facebooks-partners/&quot;&gt;also published a blog post responding to the story in further detail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9kSgzo&quot;&gt;Netflix told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;AZSsf6&quot;&gt;“Over the years we have tried various ways to make Netflix more social. One example of this was a feature we launched in 2014 that enabled members to recommend TV shows and movies to their Facebook friends via Messenger or Netflix. It was never that popular so we shut the feature down in 2015. At no time did we access people’s private messages on Facebook, or ask for the ability to do so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;QATrqK&quot;&gt;I find it helpful to read the allegations in the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;’ story chronologically, starting with the integration deals, continuing with the one-off agreements, and ending with instant personalization. Do so and you read a story of a company that, after some early success growing its user base by making broad data-sharing agreements with one set of companies — OEMs — it grew more confident, and proceeded to give away more and more, often with few disclosures to users. By the time “Instant personalization” arrived, it was widely panned, and never met Facebook’s hopes for it. Shortly after it was wound down, Facebook would take action against Cambridge Analytica, and once again began placing meaningful limitations on its API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9ovIhF&quot;&gt;Then basically nothing happened for three years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;qhZyBj&quot;&gt;Whatever is happening, it’s happening ... now. It has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/28/17914524/facebook-bug-50-million-affected-security-token-access-view-as-feature&quot;&gt;only two months since the largest data breach in Facebook’s history&lt;/a&gt;. It has been only five days since the last time &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/14/18140771/facebook-photo-exposure-leak-bug-millions-users-disclosed&quot;&gt;Facebook announced a significant data leak&lt;/a&gt;. It has been only two days since I said I would be taking the rest of the year off of writing this newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;uGdmfG&quot;&gt;It has only been a few hours since &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cher/status/1074941152279769088&quot;&gt;Cher announced she was quitting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;DR73Y0&quot; readability=&quot;7.5668789808917&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; readability=&quot;8.5127388535032&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;WONT USE GOOGLE,GETTING RID OF FACEBOOK ACCOUNT I DIDNT KNOW I HAD.WOULD GET RID OF TWITTER IF IT WASN’T 4 ❤️ OF YOU.THESE COMPANIES HAVE NO ALLEGIANCE TO,OR ❤️OF ANYTHING BUT MONEY . THEY MIGHT AS WELL BE CONSPIRING WITH RUSSIA TO DESTROY OUR DEMOCRACY.&lt;br/&gt;WHERES❤️OF&lt;/p&gt;
— Cher (@cher) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cher/status/1074941152279769088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 18, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ghdSE3&quot;&gt;Here are two last things to chew over as we think about this story in the coming days. One, it’s now clear that a data partnership with Facebook can create reputational risks for the companies making the deals. Every company named in the report will be held account for the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;’ findings, and they better have good and thorough answers when shareholders, lawmakers, and reporters start asking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wUf9hM&quot;&gt;Two, it’s amazing how much oxygen we all have given to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/14/18140146/does-facebook-sell-data-debate-volume-infinity&quot;&gt;the false notion that Facebook sells your data&lt;/a&gt; — when the real story was the data they were giving away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;AZNkGN&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 19th, 2:52AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to include comment from Netflix and a blog post from Facebook.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 11:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>staz</dc:creator>
<og:description>Partnerships with tech giants went way further than previously disclosed, says new report</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RjpjdR4FyTBVgpn1mvkThpnF29Y=/0x146:2040x1214/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12793301/acastro_180828_1777_facebook_0001.0.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Facebook gave Spotify and Netflix access to users’ private messages</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/18/18147616/facebook-user-data-giveaway-nyt-apple-amazon-spotify-netflix</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/18/18147616/facebook-user-data-giveaway-nyt-apple-amazon-spotify-netflix</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What I learned from reading a thousand emergency room bills</title>
<link>https://www.vox.com/health-care/2018/12/18/18134825/emergency-room-bills-health-care-costs-america</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.vox.com/health-care/2018/12/18/18134825/emergency-room-bills-health-care-costs-america</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;rPuwfu&quot;&gt;For the past 15 months, I’ve asked Vox readers to &lt;a href=&quot;http://erbills.vox.com&quot;&gt;submit emergency room bills&lt;/a&gt; to our database. I’ve read lots of those medical bills — 1,182 of them, to be exact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;lqITho&quot;&gt;My initial goal was to get a sense of how unpredictable and costly ER billing is across the country. There are millions of emergency room visits every year, making it one of the more frequent ways we interact with our health care system — and a good window into the health costs squeezing consumers today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fOjfuh&quot;&gt;I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/2/27/16936638/er-bills-emergency-room-hospital-fees-health-care-costs&quot;&gt;my project&lt;/a&gt; focused on one specific charge: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2016/5/13/11606760/emergency-facility-fees-american-health-care&quot;&gt;the facility fee&lt;/a&gt;. I found this charge for walking through an emergency room’s doors could be as low as $533 or well over $3,000, depending on which hospital a patient visited and how severe her case was. I also learned that the price of this charge had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/health-care/2017/12/4/16679686/emergency-room-facility-fee-monopolies&quot;&gt;skyrocketed&lt;/a&gt; in recent years, increasing much faster than other medical prices for no clear reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;JeoFQk&quot;&gt;But given the volume and diversity of bills I received, I’ve learned so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wYCKW0&quot;&gt;I’ve read emergency room bills from all 50 states and the District of Columbia. I’ve looked at bills from big cities and from rural areas, from patients who are babies and patients who are elderly. I’ve even submitted one of my own emergency room bills for an unexpected visit this past summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img srcset=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gs_qBMC_bV7v3_YNmoMtbjD0LYo=/0x0:1080x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MaVLOKIpXzewlIufwa7VXLLfD-k=/0x0:1080x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/14m71fdjb9c3B3QTcBPhzcvW-8Y=/0x0:1080x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1oLyoPdDRE1LWYiMJ-T0LdTu70I=/0x0:1080x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/imIBjUmmzo3WYw3yUAiF9vyvRUc=/0x0:1080x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S3_C0JucucJw3u5BbCRnyXQbBAk=/0x0:1080x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4d1zgl7oOrfceSxAUD6xPiBj6ng=/0x0:1080x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GhCfrinR7LQD0I5lPH_eH6AVDgA=/0x0:1080x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uwkhhLBoJMm1LcLm43MSFkWokmI=/0x0:1080x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg 1920w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-upload-width=&quot;1080&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AWOVvVCRBfbD0gMYPrTAU6xKjrQ=/0x0:1080x1080/1200x0/filters:focal(0x0:1080x1080):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625037/ER_Bills_map.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Graphic: Javier Zarracina, Kavya Sukumar/Vox&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;toDjxA&quot;&gt;Some of the patients I read about come in for the reasons you’d expect: a car accident, pains that could indicate appendicitis or a heart attack, or because the ER was the only place open that night or weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;17qbQO&quot;&gt;Some come in for reasons you’d &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; expect. Like the little girl who swallowed a coin to hide it from her sister, the 12-year-old boy who was hit by a home run ball at a professional baseball game (who, incidentally, was given a $60 ibuprofen at the local children’s hospital), and the adult who ate an entire bag of chocolate candy … without realizing it was edible marijuana. Rest assured, they are all fine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;Se70jp&quot;&gt;In so many ways, patients find themselves in a vulnerable position during these encounters with the health care system. The result is often high — and unpredictable — bills. Hospitals are not transparent about the cost of their services, their prices vary wildly from one ER to another, and it’s hard to tell which doctors are covered by insurance (even if the hospital itself is covered). In many cases, patients can’t be certain what they owe until they receive a bill in the mail, sometimes weeks or months later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;22X1wX&quot;&gt;I’ve also learned that there is a lot of interest in fixing these types of situations. Since we started this project, multiple senators have introduced bills to prevent surprise emergency room bills — &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/10/29/18018098/hassan-emergency-room-bill&quot;&gt;including one directly inspired by our project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;xJdaFY&quot;&gt;I’ll stop collecting emergency room bills on December 31. But before I do that, I wanted to share the five key things I’ve learned in my year-long stint as a medical bills collector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;p71VbZ&quot;&gt;1) The prices are high — even for things you can buy in a drugstore&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;JQa2nf&quot;&gt;One bill that left an impression on me came from a woman seen in the emergency room the day after her wedding. Her eye was irritated from the fake eyelashes she’d worn the night before, and she worried that her cornea might have been scratched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;x6nmCl&quot;&gt;The providers checked out her eye, squeezed in some eyedrops, and sent her home. She later got a bill that charged $238 for those eyedrops, a generic drug called ofloxacin. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodrx.com/floxin&quot;&gt;According to GoodRX&lt;/a&gt;, a website that tracks drug prices, an entire vial of this drug can be purchased at a retail pharmacy for between $15 and $50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UUG8HL&quot;&gt;This is something that I saw over and over again reading emergency room bills: high prices for items that a patient could have picked up at a drugstore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;EO6frj&quot;&gt;I see this a lot, for example, with pregnancy tests. They happen in emergency rooms for good reason: Doctors often need to know whether a woman is pregnant to determine her course of care. But the prices I’ve seen for pregnancy tests are really high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;oORmpt&quot;&gt;The bills in our database include a $236 pregnancy test delivered in Texas, a $147 pregnancy test in Illinois, and a $111 test in California. The highest price I saw? A $465 pregnancy test at a Georgia emergency room. For that amount, you could buy 84 First Response tests on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;CvObQx&quot;&gt;Or look at the price of a common antibiotic ointment called bacitracin (you might know it better by its brand name, Neosporin). The bills in our database show that one hospital in Tennessee charged a patient a pretty reasonable $1 for bacitracin — while another hospital in Seattle charged $76 for the exact same ointment. Since prices aren’t made public, it was impossible for these (or any) patients to know whether they were at a hospital that charges $1 for a squirt of antibiotic ointment or one that charges 76 times that amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4HjXTD&quot;&gt;These bills submitted to our database were in situations where there was not a life-threatening emergency, where a provider presumably could have sent the patient to a place where their drug is available cheaper, often over the counter. But that doesn’t seem to happen. Perhaps emergency room providers don’t know the price of the care they provide, either. Instead, patients are getting drugstore items in the emergency room at a significant markup — and paying higher bills as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;oFinPl&quot;&gt;2) Going to an in-network hospital doesn’t mean you’ll be seen by in-network doctors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;GkAvIX&quot;&gt;On January 28, 34-year-old Scott Kohan woke up in an emergency room in downtown Austin, Texas, with his jaw broken in two places, the result of a violent attack the night before. Witnesses called 911, which dispatched an ambulance that brought him to the hospital while he was unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;k3rJKv&quot;&gt;Kohan, who submitted his bill to our database, ended up needing emergency jaw surgery. The hospital where he was seen was in network; he Googled this on his phone right after regaining consciousness. But the jaw surgeon who saw him wasn’t. Kohan ended up with a $7,924 bill from the surgeon, which was only reversed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2018/5/23/17353284/emergency-room-doctor-out-of-network&quot;&gt;after I wrote about his bill&lt;/a&gt; in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;dJqygI&quot;&gt;Kohan’s case is something I see regularly in our database: patients who end up with big bills because they went to an in-network hospital but were seen by an out-of-network doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;rzKwkB&quot;&gt;Here’s how that happens: When doctors and hospitals join a given health insurance plan’s network, they agree to specific rates for their services, including everything from a routine physical to a complex surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;vpPgPL&quot;&gt;Doctors typically end up out of network when they can’t come to that agreement — when they think the insurance plan is offering rates that are too low but the insurer argues that the doctor’s prices are simply too high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;nYPT2J&quot;&gt;Unless states have laws regulating out-of-network billing — and most don’t — patients often end up stuck in the middle of these contract disputes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;Ti55oz&quot;&gt;Academic research has shown that most of these types of bills actually originate from a small number of hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7CReAL&quot;&gt;These bills “aren’t randomly sprinkled throughout the nation’s hospitals,” one &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/24/upshot/the-company-behind-many-surprise-emergency-room-bills.html&quot;&gt;New York Times article from July 2017&lt;/a&gt; noted. “They come mostly from a select group of E.R. doctors at particular hospitals. At about 15 percent of the hospitals, out-of-network rates were over 80 percent, the study found.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;nSlKXE&quot;&gt;These surprise bills appear to be especially common in Texas, where Kohan lives. As many as 34 percent of emergency room visits lead to out-of-network bills in Texas — way above the national average of 20 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;BoWyqi&quot;&gt;And, much like the bills with high prices, these bills are really hard to prevent. Out-of-network doctors won’t often mention that they don’t accept the patient’s insurance; they might not even know. And patients often have little choice about where to receive their care — like Kohan, who needed emergency jaw surgery due to his attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;q424Fa&quot;&gt;3) You can be charged just for sitting in a waiting room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;poqbCI&quot;&gt;Before I started reporting this project, I knew from my decade as a health care reporter that America has sky-high medical prices. But what I didn’t know was that patients can face steep bills even if they &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; see a doctor or have their ailment treated. They can decline treatment and still end up with a hefty fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;O5z0m1&quot;&gt;I learned about this from a bill sent to me by Jessica Pell. She told me about going to an emergency room in New Jersey after she fell and cut her ear. She was given an ice pack but no other treatment. She never received a diagnosis. But she did get a bill for $5,751.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;8PAzwR&quot;&gt;“It’s for the ice pack and the bandage,” Pell said of the fee. “That is the only tangible thing they could bill me for.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;7LV8iJ&quot;&gt;After I saw Pell’s bill, I started looking through our database and finding similar bills from other patients. They all ended up with significant medical bills, in the hundreds or thousands of dollars. These fees were often on top of additional fees from another health care provider where they ultimately did receive treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;kPWyK9&quot;&gt;This is all due to the key fee I’ve been investigating this year: the ER facility fee. This is the fee that ERs charge for walking in the door and seeking care, something akin to a cover charge at a bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;USdoxP&quot;&gt;Hospital executives often argue that these fees help them keep the lights on and doors open for whatever emergency might come in, anything from a stubbed toe to a stroke patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;EwEBFB&quot;&gt;But experts who study emergency billing question how these fees are set and charged, noting that they are seemingly arbitrary, varying widely from one hospital to another. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/health-care/2017/12/4/16679686/emergency-room-facility-fee-monopolies&quot;&gt;Vox analysis&lt;/a&gt; of these fees, published last year, shows that the prices rose 89 percent between 2009 and 2015 — rising twice as fast as overall health care prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wzMFcP&quot;&gt;“It is having a dramatic effect on what people spend in a hospital setting,” says Niall Brennan, the executive director of the Health Care Cost Institute, which provided the data for that analysis. “And as we know, that has a trickle-down effect on premiums and benefits.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;88gZhh&quot;&gt;4) It is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hard for patients to advocate for themselves in an emergency room setting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;lTGlI9&quot;&gt;Since I started working on this project, one of the questions I get most frequently is: How do I avoid a surprise ER bill? Or how can I get my ER bill lowered?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;gwXScA&quot;&gt;I wish I had a good answer, but I don’t. Patients are usually at the mercy of the hospital when it comes to ER billing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;cdqvBk&quot;&gt;I have talked to some patients who have successfully negotiated down their emergency room bills. Most of those people applied for financial aid, requested a prompt pay discount, or found an error on their bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;IFCqdh&quot;&gt;Some especially savvy patients have even had luck arguing that their facility fee charge was coded incorrectly — that the hospital used a billing code that should be reserved for really intense, complex visits when their visit was actually pretty simple. I’ve noticed that these patients tend to have a doctor in their family who can help them make this type of argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;iBq3E7&quot;&gt;Most patients who have successfully negotiated down a bill tell me it wasn’t easy. Erin Floyd from Florida told me about her experience reducing two of her daughter’s bills — one by 90 percent and one by 45 percent — through a combination of financial aid and prompt care discounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;lqlZDm&quot;&gt;On the one hand, she was happy to have the bills lowered. In total, she ended up saving $4,369. On the other hand, the whole process was exhausting. There were lots of phone calls and faxes involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;AYJCOQ&quot;&gt;“I spent at least three hours on the phone working on this,” she says. “I was scanning, faxing, emailing, all while I was at work.” Over email, she described it as an “incredibly stressful and long process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;MykfQP&quot;&gt;And then there are, &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2018/10/surprise-billing-health-care-journalism.html&quot;&gt;as Slate has noted&lt;/a&gt;, patients who have had their bills reversed after journalists wrote about them. Our project, for example, has resulted in $45,107 in medical bills being reversed after Vox began inquiring about those charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Bd21Im&quot;&gt;But for all of investigative journalism’s merits, reporters writing about medical bills isn’t a great solution for the health care system’s woes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;AJJkMw&quot;&gt;What stands out to me is that in all these cases, it’s essentially the hospital that gets to decide whether it wants to negotiate or reverse a bill. And if a hospital says no? If it won’t change the facility fee code, or doesn’t offer a prompt payment discount? The patient is essentially stuck. The hospital has the trump card: It can send the bill to a collection agency, a move that could devastate a patient’s credit. In those situations, there isn’t anything a patient can do to stop them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a35sBZ&quot;&gt;5) Congress wants to do something about the issue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;wGIL0b&quot;&gt;As more journalists write about ER bills, there is a growing outcry on Capitol Hill — and more senators on both sides of the aisle who want to do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;leBius&quot;&gt;There are now two proposals in Congress that would make the types of bills I write about a thing of the past. One comes from Sen. Maggie Hassan (D-NH) and another from a bipartisan group of senators including Sens. Bill Cassidy (R-LA) and Claire McCaskill (D-MO).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;DCj8JU&quot;&gt;While the two bills aim to do the same thing (prevent surprise bills in the emergency room), they take different policy approaches. The Cassidy-McCaskill proposal essentially bars out-of-network providers from billing patients directly. Instead, they would have to seek payment from the health insurer, who would be required to pay a price similar to local market rates. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/21/17887692/voxcare-surprise-er-bills-senate&quot;&gt;I’ve written in greater detail about how this works&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;qcmSng&quot;&gt;Will either of these bills become law? It’s hard to tell. On the one hand, the safest bet with Congress is often inaction. But this issue seems to be gaining momentum. Just this week, for example, a large coalition of health plans and consumer advocates put out a statement supporting federal action on the issue. What’s more, there is bipartisan interest in working on this — making it the rare issue that just might bring Democrats and Republicans together on health care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;p-entry-hr&quot; id=&quot;a5tbLH&quot;/&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;UKeC3q&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join the conversation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;Lxt4Ol&quot;&gt;Are you interested in more discussions around health care policy? Join our &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2lbzgPq&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for conversation and updates.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 10:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jedwhite</dc:creator>
<og:description>A $5,571 bill to sit in a waiting room, $238 eyedrops, and a $60 ibuprofen tell the story of how emergency room visits are squeezing patients.</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-ycfdQWT7CV7qM0TeLc7Saq3Snw=/668x0:3204x1328/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13625035/ER_project_year.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>&quot;I read 1,182 emergency room bills this year. Here’s what I learned.&quot;</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.vox.com/health-care/2018/12/18/18134825/emergency-room-bills-health-care-costs-america</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.vox.com/health-care/2018/12/18/18134825/emergency-room-bills-health-care-costs-america</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Writing copy for landing pages</title>
<link>https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/landing-page-copy</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/landing-page-copy</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, there’s the landing page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s often a company’s first impression: a digital introduction to an organization, the problem it tackles, and the solutions it offers. The sophistication of landing pages can vary. Some companies use their homepage as a landing page. Others create specific pages that target discrete customer profiles and move them through a marketing funnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landing pages also take various forms depending on the growth stage of a company. But that’s one of the common missteps that I see: landing pages prioritize the story of the startup, rather than the journey &lt;em&gt;of the customer&lt;/em&gt; with the startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landing page copy improves the more customers see themselves in it. Rethink and revise your landing page by &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/landing-page-copy#the-foundational-elements-of-effective-landing-page-copy&quot;&gt;building it around three elements&lt;/a&gt;. If that’s too much effort and you’re looking for fast fixes, the following tips will improve your current landing page copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus copy on them.&lt;/strong&gt; Landing pages often say “we offer” or “our solution,” which focuses on the wrong thing—your company, not your customers. Go through each sentence in your copy and rewrite it to address your customers. One way to do this is to begin with the word “you.” Another tip is to start your sentence with a verb. Focusing on them nearly guarantees that your copy will address—and speak to—your visitor. Here’s a good example of what this looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/modern_fertility.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;modern fertility screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only possible exception to leading with “you” in your copy is if you’re a service business, where prospects want to see what you do differently as a service provider. That’s often expressed as “we” language. But it doesn’t have to be. It just very often is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add pattern, texture, and shine to a block of copy.&lt;/strong&gt; Accurate, succinct, and grammatically correct copy can still feel flat. Patterns, texture, and shine can add another dimension to your copy, making it more engaging and memorable. Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;9.354435483871&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply a pattern to a sentence.&lt;/strong&gt; Patterns may be used to subtly reference a logo or map out a theme. Take a logistics company that transports goods by railway. Perhaps it not only wants to deliver a message, but also simulate a train with a pattern of evenly spaced dots in a horizontal line. To mimic that visual, rewrite landing page copy to link only words of similar length, such as three- or four-letter words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vary sentence length and formatting to create texture.&lt;/strong&gt; Texture can make copy feel more conversational, natural, and engaging. To create texture, write a smooth, polished sentence and juxtapose it with a more staccato sentence. Throw in some short sentences. More. More. And maybe one more. And then add a sentence that goes a lot longer, using clauses to lure your reader along. Then stop. The result? Texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;3.81598062954&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Include a glossy word or two for shine.&lt;/strong&gt; Polish might mean swapping in a few new words. Find a bland word in your copy, and replace it with a more dazzling synonym. Take the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collectiveretreats.com/&quot;&gt;Collective Retreats&lt;/a&gt; landing page copy below. Instead of “Find destinations without losing luxury,” try “Explore extraordinary destinations without sacrificing luxury.” The bright adjective and stronger verbs adds punch to the copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/collective_retreats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;collective retreats screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Defang objections with an “even if” clause.&lt;/strong&gt; If you can anticipate what might keep someone from believing your claim or assertion, undercut that opposition by acknowledging it. It’ll hint that you understand their fear, uncertainty, and doubt—and suggest that your solution takes those considerations into account. The formula is simple: “[Claim] even if [objection].” A very simple example is: “Be creative even if you’re not creative.” Here’s an “even if” clause in the wild:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/woorank.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;woorank screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limit each sentence to one idea.&lt;/strong&gt; Sentences have the capacity to carry a lot of information, but your reader cannot. Your readers depend on periods, question marks, and even exclamation marks to give their brains a short rest—just enough of a reprieve to absorb information before moving on. The more you help readers with information digestion, the more appetite they’ll have to read on. So edit every sentence to have just one thought. Not two. Not three. Apple is skilled at this technique, but even it has opportunities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/apple_tv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;apple tv screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take its copy for Apple TV 4K. Most of the sentences don’t qualify as sentences, but they absolutely follow the rule. Here’s the one that doesn’t: “Apple TV 4K lets you watch movies and shows in amazing 4K HDR—and now it completes the picture with immersive sound from Dolby Atmos.” This sentence merges two distinct features. The average reader would be better able to take in the information if that sentence was broken in two:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;Apple TV 4K lets you watch movies and shows in amazing 4K HDR. It’s got immersive sound from Dolby Atmos. Streams your favorite channels live. Has great content from apps like Netflix, Amazon Prime Video, and ESPN. And thanks to Siri, you can control it all with just your voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a landing page that’s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; your homepage.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve recently created a website for your company, your landing page might be your homepage, but they’re two different creatures. A landing page is designed to convert prospects into customers. It speaks to visitors looking for something specific, features content relevant to that particular item, and contains a call-to-action customized to that precise offering. On the other hand, a homepage serves a broad audience, features widely-relevant content, and may not have an immediate CTA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More sophisticated companies will route visitors who, say, search for products for large companies to a page geared toward enterprises rather than a homepage with general information. If you have a website with more than one page—or a more advanced information architecture and sitemap—consider linking to the page on your site that best addresses a visitor’s intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the spoiler: landing page copy is never done. Like your company, it will—and should—evolve over time. It’s an iterative process, and can always be improved. There are hundreds of copywriting formulas (many of them documented &lt;a href=&quot;https://copyhackers.com/2015/10/copywriting-formula/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) that can help you craft a headline, draft bullets, or structure a CTA. But if you don’t have the fundamentals down, the improvement will be incremental, not game-changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy for a high-performing landing page has three foundational qualities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It delivers a convincing first impression for the startup.&lt;/strong&gt; At a fundamental level, this involves direct, specific, and grammatically-correct copy. That level of precision and professionalism sets expectations and raises the bar for future engagements with a company’s product and team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It considers the maturity of the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Every market—like every company—is in its own stage of development. Companies in highly mature markets can use short copy, because most visitors already get the ins-and-outs of the solution or category (e.g. disposable razors). Their focus should be on product differentiators, the brand story, and who’s using it. If a market is still emerging (e.g. cryptocurrency in 2018) customers likely need more information, because a company is not only educating about its solution, but also helping define the category more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It reflects the customer’s stage of awareness.&lt;/strong&gt; Effective landing page copy mirrors customer comprehension, which is layered and includes: how well a customer understands the challenge the company addresses (e.g. data privacy), what’s at stake (e.g. personal data and/or compliance), the changing landscape (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/guides/general-data-protection-regulation&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt;), and tools that help (e.g. a specific product).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, great copy demonstrates that a company grasps how aware customers are of the market, its pain points, and potential solutions. The best copy does all that &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; signals that the company is clued into precisely how aware the customers are of &lt;em&gt;themselves&lt;/em&gt;. Here are the five stages of awareness for any visitor to your landing page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most aware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors totally understand your solution and likely believe it’s a top contender for them. They just needs nudging. Purchases happen here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product-aware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors are learning about your product. Free trials, demos, and purchases happen here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution-aware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors are considering solutions to their pain or problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem-aware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors are feeling pain or dealing with a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unaware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors haven’t experienced a need that would drive them to your solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Landing page copy reflects the customer if you can answer “yes” to the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the language accessible and does it mirror a visitor’s stage of awareness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the copy move them from where they are to where they want to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are visitors prompted to take action once they become Product-aware or Most aware?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every landing page should &lt;strong&gt;deliver a convincing first impression, consider the maturity of the market,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;reflect the customer’s stage of awareness&lt;/strong&gt;. The best way to see how the absence or presence of these elements alter a landing page is to review real-life examples. So, with the three foundational elements in mind, I’ve evaluated the landing pages of nine companies—from member management software to a vegan candy brand to a court date notification service. Here goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-impression-make-an-accurate-trust-building-and-lasting-introduction&quot;&gt;First impression: make an accurate, trust-building, and lasting introduction.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapwing.com&quot;&gt;Kapwing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does&lt;/strong&gt;: Modern editor for videos, GIFs, and images&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landing Page Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;: Copy that’s short, but vague&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix to Apply&lt;/strong&gt;: Get specific—but, first, scroll down&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/kapwing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kapwing screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headline—”Creativity made easy”— raises this question: Are people who’d use this solution &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; creative? The phrase suggests that it’s hard for your audience to be creative. Is that true?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page falls victim to the myth that copy must be kept short at all costs. Many startups write three- or four-word headlines that try to say everything. It reduces the elevator pitch to a hiccup. Along the way, we tell ourselves we’re being succinct because we understand that being succinct is good when it comes to communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But are you being succinct or are you being vague? Worse, are you sacrificing a clear message for a short one? Your headline is prime real estate. Let it do some real work—it’s made for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think back to your last ten conversations with a customer or prospect. (If you haven’t had at least ten, &lt;a href=&quot;https://copyhackers.com/2018/05/how-to-listen/&quot;&gt;do that first&lt;/a&gt;.) At what point in the conversation did they perk up? That’s the fodder for a good headline—at least one that’s worth testing. That’s what should top your landing page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With headlines, don’t take rich, nuanced feedback from customers and whittle it down to the smallest possible version. Instead listen. Write down what you hear. And put it on the page. You’ll clean it up so it’s on brand and persuasive, but it shouldn’t be boiled down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concern in boiling it down is that you’ll get too vague. Kapwing’s tools run the gamut. They make memes, add subtitles to video, create montages and more. If you’re the marketing team, the temptation is to look at everything Kapwing does, plot it in a Venn diagram, and promote the overlapping part: the quality that all features, uses cases and outputs have in common. That’s likely how “Creativity made easy” emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s how mediocre headlines surface—and it happens surprisingly often, even to the most copy-savvy startups. Many founders use more effective headlines in their verbal elevator pitches or elsewhere in copy. That’s the case for Kapwing; the better options for a headline are further down in the copy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tasks that take hours in iMovie take minutes in Kapwing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;No install. No passwords. No technical tutorials. It works on every OS, on your phone, and your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bring on the memes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Creative jobs that take hours in iMovie take just minutes in Kapwing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either copy expresses the ease of being creative in Kapwing in a specific, compelling way—and serve as entry points to its other suite of tools. These messages should lead the page as a headline. Hidden headline copy happens to many businesses. It’s not that companies can’t generate good headlines; they’ve likely just buried them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webgazer.io/&quot;&gt;WebGazer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; Free website monitoring&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landing Page Challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; We-focused copy&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix to Apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &quot;The Rule of You&quot;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This headline works, as long as visitors arrive on the page knowing what WebGazer is and does. The copy might suffice if this is a retargeting page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if it’s not? Let’s start with the phrase: “We help you keep your business running.” The very first word (“we”) is a problem. We-focused copy is an issue—almost without fail. It communicates from the perspective of the company, not the customer. It’s the equivalent of a person introducing themselves and dominating the airspace with their story. Correct “we-focused” copy by rewriting every sentence to begin with the word “you” or a verb. Here’s how WebGazer can change three sentences on its landing page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;We-focused copy&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;You-focused copy&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;We monitor your sites without a rest, see what we have done today yourself.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;You can rest easy. Because we’ll monitor your site without rest.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;WebGazer checks if your website is up as it should be and notifies you if anything goes wrong.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Keep your online business running without interruption. WebGazer monitors it night and day. And notifies you if anything goes wrong.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;We help you keep your business running.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;How would you know if your website was suddenly down?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.influencekit.com/&quot;&gt;InfluenceKit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; Automated reporting for sponsored content&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landing Page Challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; A timely call to action&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix to Apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://copyhackers.com/2015/10/copywriting-formula/#AIDA)[%20framework](https://copyhackers.com/2015/10/copywriting-formula/#AIDA&quot;&gt;AIDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/influence_kit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;influence kit screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first impression is how much is &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; with this landing page copy. It reads well and follows some of the strongest copywriting better practices, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removing distracting calls to action (e.g. no global navigation)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hooking visitors immediately with a highly desirable benefit (why they should care)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expanding on the benefit with product-specific support (how the product does it)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formatting copy for maximum readability (the three paragraphs of body copy under “You have a blog?” is a manageable column to read instead of spanning the width of the page, which is extremely fatiguing for the reading eye.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a voice that is present but not overwhelming (With few exceptions, they’ve used their voice in crossheads only, minimizing ‘interruptions’ in how readers process information.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading with “you” wherever possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making sentences short, and easy to consume&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The landing point copy has done so much right—the challenge is that it hasn’t cashed in on it. After making a convincing argument to the prospect, it forgets to end with a CTA. The AIDA framework can help outline this progression and missed opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIDA: Attention, Interest, Desire, Action.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab their attention&lt;/strong&gt;. In this case, InfluenceKit starts to build trust and empathy by clearly articulating the problem many bloggers face: demonstrating value from content. The copy reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;...it’s really hard proving to brands how much value you’re delivering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build up their interest in the subject&lt;/strong&gt;. Here, the copy deepens that understanding by elaborating on the problem, causing readers to nod along and more fully recognize themselves in the challenge. This shared understanding builds further interest. The copy continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;Yes, it’s about the content, but it’s also about knowing how many lives were impacted by what you created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;We all like to know where our money's going (dang you Target!!). Brands are just like us; they want to know what they're getting for their investment. Reporting impressions is the industry standard for internet marketing, and up until now, bloggers have been a black hole of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;Your blog is more than just pretty pictures, you have real influence. You know it, and we know it, and together we’re going to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn that casual interest into a direct desire&lt;/strong&gt; for them to add the solution to their lives. The solution that’s offered is succinct and clear. The copy reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;Show Your Real Influence with Powerful and Dynamic Reports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call them to action.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s a CTA, but it’s in the wrong place. It’s buried beneath a list of integrations, the four-step process to set-up InfluenceKit, an infographic on the two types of bloggers, and a Meet-the-Team section. Finally, there’s a call to action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;Ready to Prove Your Value &amp;amp; Make More Money? Request Access Now. (Secret handshake to follow)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The copy has sufficiently made a case for action by the end of the four-part “How Does InfluenceKit Work?” section. Here, I’d expect—and encourage—a &lt;em&gt;closer&lt;/em&gt; section, featuring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A restatement of the value prop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick bullet list of results generated by the solution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A powerful screenshot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A CTA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A testimonial from a blogger or sponsor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A data point about average results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps InfluenceKit is a newer company, which is why there’s no data yet for how it’s paying off. But there’s power in being new. I’d suggest the founders share their own story and results thanks to InfluenceKit—being transparent all along that they’re the founders—to demonstrate that others can also benefit. Part of making a lasting first impression is creating a window for not only a prospect to relate, but act, and interact. That turns an impression into a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;market-maturity-reflect-the-state-of-your-market-in-your-copy&quot;&gt;Market maturity: reflect the state of your market in your copy.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nombacandies.com/&quot;&gt;Nomba&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; Digital-first vegan candy brand&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landing Page Challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; The model to try or demo&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix to Apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Map your market over your first customer engagement&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/nomba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;nomba screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “Try Now” language at the top of the landing page—and throughout the site—is confusing. But what’s more puzzling is the idea of a trial for this product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the mainstream consumer, trials are not typical in the world of buying candy. By offering a trial, you’ve effectively taken a super-sophisticated market of buyers—people who’ve bought candy, understand buying candy, and just wanna get vegan candy—and introduced doubt. Suddenly visitors are asking small questions that escalate into bigger concerns:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does a trial mean in the world of candy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try food that’s shipped to me? Do I ship it back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I get a sample or a full-sized product?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait. Is this a subscription I’ll have to work to get out of?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I even &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; spicy candy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And just like that, they’re gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your visitors go from wanting to give this spicy vegan candy a shot to hitting the back button and feeling relief that they got out of there as quickly as they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nomba’s copy has a new challenge: it needs to deal with the “problem” of prospective customers not understanding the trial model for a food item. Here’s how it can do that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, know that you have to address the problem.&lt;/strong&gt; But you &lt;em&gt;do not have to go into great detail&lt;/em&gt; to address it. After all, this is a $5 treat or $15 investment in sugar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, ask: what’s the easiest, quickest way is to address the problem?&lt;/strong&gt; Often, it’s in naming. Sometimes product features are better explained by renaming them and pricing tiers are better explained by re-labeling each tier. In this case, the &lt;em&gt;trial&lt;/em&gt; may be better grokked by renaming it to &lt;em&gt;sample pack&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;sampler&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the “Try Now” CTA could become any of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the Sampler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample Nomba&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample It&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nomba should keep that new language consistent throughout each product page and checkout to avoid further confusion. Any startup that offers demos or trials to win customers should craft their copy with not only their customer, but their existing market in mind. The market part of product/market fit also matters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://eve.io/&quot;&gt;Eve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does&lt;/strong&gt;: Event management software&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landing Page Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;: Overemphasis on the solution, not the problem&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix to Apply&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://copyhackers.com/2015/10/copywriting-formula/#PAS&quot;&gt;PAS framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/eve.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;eve screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prospects for event management software may already recognize the need for a solution, but if not, this landing page needs more education on the challenges of planning events. After all, there’s a lot of complexity in running events: multiple stakeholders, shifting timelines, numerous vendors, and changing agendas. The list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The landing page starts out relatively strong with a benefit-driven headline and a product-level value proposition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;The easier way to plan events.&lt;br/&gt;Eve allows your entire team to plan, execute and review your events, all in one place — without changing your existing workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading with a value proposition is the standard choice for SaaS companies. That’s fine, but a lot of marketers struggle with what should go next on the page. For a product like eve—where it’s easy for the prospect and the whole world to minimize the pain of event planning until you’re two days away from the event and panicking—I’d recommend moving swiftly from discussing the value prop to outlining and fleshing out the problem eve solves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem like that’s accomplished with the first crosshead under the hero:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;Easy software to end event stress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that crosshead leads with the solution (“easy software”) when it ought to focus entirely on the pain (“event stress”). The PAS—or Problem, Agitation, Solution—framework helps lay out copy in a way that it zeroes in on the driving force behind choosing a painkiller solution like eve: the pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest advice is choosing copy that doesn’t glide over that pain. So swap this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;&quot;How hard could it be to plan and coordinate a live event?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;&quot;How hard could it be to plan and coordinate a two-day conference with 20 speakers from around the globe and 500 attendees?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first option is safe. The second option is sticky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too often we try to boil everything down to its safest version. And we sacrifice specific, sticky copy that might actually hook and convert actual prospects. It’s not our fault. Everyone we know is writing safe copy. If we go bold, we’re taking a risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test it and see, but my encouragement is to go for it. Rare is the business that makes waves today without either 1) a huge marketing budget to overcome their safe messaging or 2) a memorable way of connecting with people. Endeavor to be uncomfortably specific with your prospects. It shows you’re in touch with the precise pain felt by the professionals in your market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scribendi.com/&quot;&gt;Scribendi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; Editing and proofreading services for English documents&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landing Page Challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; Understanding scale and results&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix to Apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Visualize—don’t just display—data&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/scribendi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;scribendi screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the copy on this page is strong. But copy is not always words, but numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further down the page, there is some impressive proof of impact on clients served, words proofread and editors in action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/scribendi_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;scribendi2 screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are striking figures, but they also come with complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I’m sure I’m not the only person who misread 1.6B as 1.6M. That sounds like a lot, but how many documents does that mean? Is it 10,000+ ESL papers for academics or 100,000 essays for undergraduates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suggest keeping the data as is, but adding in a visual that shows the scale of the achievement. Here’s one way to back into a compelling visual via a quick calculation: 1.6B words is actually 6.4M pages. That’s 318,939 millimeters. That’s 1,046 feet. That’s amazing. That’s more than half the size of the CN Tower in Canada—or insert your local landmark relevant to your audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help your prospects visualize the work you’ve done—and don’t be afraid to reference something &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; your market to make the case &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; your market. Numbers are good. But I believe the saying goes: whoever draws a picture wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;customer-awareness-map-your-customers-awareness&quot;&gt;Customer awareness: map your customers’ awareness.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joinit.org/&quot;&gt;Join It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; Member management software&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landing Page Challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; Assumes visitor is solution-aware&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix to Apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Shift to the mindset of a solution-aware prospect&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/join_it.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;join it screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This headline—Membership Management Software—is great for search engine optimization (SEO), but it’s so technical that it’s jarring, especially as the first three bold words on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a headline like “Membership Management Software” to work, its prospects need to be sophisticated and “solution-aware.” Here’s where that stacks on the five stages of awareness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most aware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors totally understand your solution and likely believe it’s a top contender for them. They just need nudging. Purchases happen here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product-aware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors are learning about your product. Free trials, demos and purchases happen here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution-aware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors are considering solutions to their pain or problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem-aware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors are feeling pain or dealing with a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unaware.&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors haven’t experienced a need that would drive them to your solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If prospects are solution-aware, they’re actively seeking “membership management software” and would easily call it that. However, Join It is eliminating a segment of prospects by only addressing solution-aware visitors. By finessing headlines and copy to match the &lt;em&gt;problems or state of mind&lt;/em&gt; of prospects, Join It can open its aperture to capture more potential customers. Here’s how that might look with tweaks to copy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Solution-aware prospect’s state of mind on arrival&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Corresponding headline copy&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;I’ve heard that membership management software can help me automate all the community stuff I’m struggling with&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Now You Can Automate Community Engagement with Easy Membership Management Software&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;I need membership management software that does this big list of stuff&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fast-Growing Organizations Need Membership Management Software That:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Brings your community together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works intuitively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automates your tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scales as you grow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;I’m thinking of switching from X membership management software, which I don’t like because of Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Put an End to Y with Easy Membership Management Software That Scales&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Should I be terrified of all the work that’s about to come when I introduce a membership management solution in my organization?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;small&gt;Membership management software&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br/&gt;How Much Easier Would Growing Your Business Be If You Could &lt;strong&gt;Automate Your Community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;A shift from solution-aware language to the state-of-mind of a prospect may seem like you’re downshifting to a problem-aware visitor. This stage of visitor might seem further from a product-aware prospect, where a sale can occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But given the market maturity for membership management software, Join It will open its top-of-the-funnel to more prospects if it makes its headline more accessible to more visitors. And it’ll still be relatable to solution-aware and product-aware prospects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://parkpnp.com/us/&quot;&gt;Parkpnp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; Marketplace for unused or underutilized parking spaces&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landing Page Challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; Incorrect assumptions about the visitor&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix to Apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://copyhackers.com/2015/10/copywriting-formula/#PAS&quot;&gt;The Rule of One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/park_pnp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;park pnp screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;A key part of customer awareness is understanding the context and drive for their visit—all of which should be reflected in the copy and experience of a page. That nuance can be the difference between a visitor identifying you as a hero in their lives—or a villain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Parkpnp, context and drive are pivotal factors for its solution. An app that allows you to find a parking space might be used in advance of an anticipated painful parking experience, such as major sporting events. But it’s more likely to be used in the heat of the moment, when the pain for a prospect is most visceral and distractions abound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, most people will use Parkpnp when they are driving their cars looking for a place to park in a busy area. Their pain is high. Their motivation to solve the pain is high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They need a hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your site a hero or a villain in that moment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current hero section copy and experience sets up the solution to be more the villain than the hero. First, it puts work on the user’s plate by asking for an address—which holds true on both mobile and desktop. But perhaps more glaringly, it makes assumptions about what “perfect” means to the user. In fact, &lt;em&gt;perfect parking&lt;/em&gt; could mean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s near where I am now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s closest to my final destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s available now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s available regularly / always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It allows overnight parking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the cheapest option in the vicinity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It accepts credit card payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s patrolled by security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has extra-wide parking spots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t require parallel parking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s got special needs access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The word “perfect” is trying to cover all manner of desires in the headline for this page. But perfect for User A may not be perfect for User B. This is where the business needs to make a decision: What’s the primary prospect’s top definition of &lt;em&gt;perfect parking&lt;/em&gt; in the moment they use the solution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question gets to the heart of what copywriters call the Rule of One, which holds that you are always writing a landing page with the following four points identified first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all parts of the Rule of One, your One Reader is the most important. You can’t write an effective page without first identifying your One Reader. Once you know your One Reader well, you know what pains drive them, what benefits they’re looking for, what offer they’re most likely to respond best to, what kinds of social proof will move them—the list goes on. You do not have to get incredibly detailed on your One Reader, but you do have to know them well enough to look at the above list of definitions of &lt;em&gt;perfect parking&lt;/em&gt; and know which one they would choose if they could only choose one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one they would use is the one you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Parkpnp, if the One Reader defines &lt;em&gt;perfect parking&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;parking that’s near where I am now&lt;/em&gt;, the headline would change and so would the CTA. Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th/&gt;
&lt;th&gt;From...&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;To...&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Headline&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FIND YOUR PERFECT PARKING SPACE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FIND AN AVAILABLE PARKING SPACE NEARBY NOW&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Primary CTA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Field: Where would you like to park?&lt;br/&gt;Button: Find Parking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Button: Find Parking Near Me Now&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Subordinate CTA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Button: Find Parking Nearby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Link: Find Parking for a Future Date, Event, or Long-Term Need&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s how your site goes from being a villain to being a hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if your One Reader would define &lt;em&gt;perfect parking&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;parking near my work that doesn’t cost half my paycheck&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;safe parking for my daughter who’s away at college&lt;/em&gt;—that is, if they’re planning for future parking needs—the headline and experience would change accordingly, of course. You don’t have to get that specific. But if you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; get that specific in your headline, you’re more likely to convert your visitor. The alternative is writing a headline that serves a huge range of audiences. But, be forewarned: a hero to all is a boring character—and more likely to be ineffectual for the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ecourtdate.com/&quot;&gt;eCourt Date&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it does:&lt;/strong&gt; Timely, digital court date reminders&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landing Page Challenge:&lt;/strong&gt; Unclear who the user is&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fix to Apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &quot;Ideal for&quot; statement&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d37ugbyn3rpeym.cloudfront.net/atlas-guides/landing-page-copy-guide/e_court_date.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;e court date screenshot&quot; class=&quot;expandable&quot;/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the first—and most important—question about eCourt Date’s landing page: do people land on this page and know if the service is meant for them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the cleanest, easiest ways to optimize your copy is to use an “ideal for” statement. That statement can appear anywhere on your site, but it’s best that it appears closer to the top of your landing page. That’s especially true for a service like eCourt Date, where the user is unclear. It might be for lawyers, police officers, the court, defendants and plaintiffs—maybe even those serving jury duty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whichever one it is, put that on the page in an ideal-for statement, like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;Ideal for lawyers with criminal and DUI cases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it’s for more than one user, that’s fine. Put those names on the page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;Ideal for criminal lawyers, traffic cops, and courthouse administrators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, the headline and subhead in the hero have context and communicate the service more clearly. To enhance the copy, take a few extra steps. Answer why it matters and add proof that you’ve done it. This rule is known as “So What”/”Prove it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the copy might look with those two elements addressed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;indented-copy&quot;&gt;Ideal for busy courthouse administrators&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send Court Date Reminders.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce Failure to Appear Rates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Notify defendants about court dates and other legal events. So you save up to 20 hours per month of court staff time. Reduce court no-shows by 33%. And humanize the defendant experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bolster this copy with testimonials from previously frustrated and now happy court staff or judges. These improvements all stem from articulating the ideal user for the service at the onset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Landing page copy is an underleveraged, powerful tool. Done right, it builds brand, engenders trust, and sells product—to anyone with an internet connection, on their schedule. But it’s not automatic. Landing page copy must deliver a convincing first impression, consider the maturity of the market, and reflect the customer’s stage of awareness. It must meet prospects where they are and get them to where they—and the business—want them to be. Once it does, hand waves became high fives, and high fives turn into handshakes—and conversions can happen without much human intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t overthink where you should start. Just get started. A landing page can—and must—always improve. If you have limited time and resources, run through &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/landing-page-copy#quick-wins-for-better-landing-page-copy&quot;&gt;the quick wins&lt;/a&gt; to make tweaks that generate outsized gains. If you have more time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/landing-page-copy#the-foundational-elements-of-effective-landing-page-copy&quot;&gt;revamp your copy&lt;/a&gt; to orient around making a lasting impression, the maturity of the market, and customer awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;disclaimer&quot; readability=&quot;4.0941176470588&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Landing page copy is only one channel to the customer. Get &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/email-marketing-ecommerce&quot;&gt;tips on email marketing&lt;/a&gt;, or hone your cold emails and calls with &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/starting-sales#how-should-you-communicate-with-customers&quot;&gt;this guide on finding your first customers&lt;/a&gt;. If there’s a related topic you wish we’d cover, drop us a line at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:atlas@stripe.com&quot;&gt;atlas@stripe.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/atlas/guides&quot; class=&quot;common-Link common-Link--arrowL&quot;&gt;Return to guides&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 07:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>HeinZawHtet</dc:creator>
<og:title>Stripe Atlas: Writing copy for landing pages</og:title>
<og:url>https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/landing-page-copy</og:url>
<og:description>Write copy that delights visitors, persuades prospects, and wins customers.</og:description>
<og:image>https://stripe.com/img/v3/atlas/guide/social.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://stripe.com/atlas/guides/landing-page-copy</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>