<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>Facebook crawls links in PDFs you send in Messenger</title>
<link>https://twitter.com/vah_13/status/1187755829371555840</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://twitter.com/vah_13/status/1187755829371555840</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/vah_13/status/1187755829371555840&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/vah_13/status/1187755829371555840&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21363383&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21363383&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 394&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 128&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 13:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>ortekk</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://mobile.twitter.com/vah_13/status/1187755829371555840</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tesla’s new Solar Roof costs less than a new roof plus solar panels</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/25/teslas-new-solar-roof-costs-less-than-a-new-roof-plus-solar-panels-aims-for-install-rate-of-1k-per-week/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/25/teslas-new-solar-roof-costs-less-than-a-new-roof-plus-solar-panels-aims-for-install-rate-of-1k-per-week/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/tesla-motors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;tesla-motors&quot;&gt;Tesla&lt;/a&gt; has launched the third iteration of its solar roof tile for residential home use, which it officially detailed in a blog post on Friday and in a call with media. Tesla CEO &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/person/elon-musk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;elon-musk&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt; kicked off the call with some explanatory remarks on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/solarroof&quot;&gt;V3 Solar Roof&lt;/a&gt;, and then took a number of questions. The company says it’ll begin installations in the coming weeks (Musk says some installations have already begun) and that it hopes to ramp production to as many as 1,000 new roofs per week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla’s solar roof tiles — which are designed to look just like normal roof tiles when installed on a house, while doubling as solar panels to generate power — are something of a work-in-progress. The company is still tinkering with the product three years &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/28/these-are-teslas-stunning-new-solar-roof-tiles-for-homes/&quot;&gt;after announcing the concept&lt;/a&gt;, having done trial installations with two different iterations so far. “Versions one and two we were still figuring things out,” said Elon Musk &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/tesla-solar-roof-version-3-is-coming-elon-musk-says-2019-10&quot;&gt;on an earnings call earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;, adding that he thinks “version three is finally ready for the big time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla’s Solar &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/roof&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;roof&quot;&gt;Roof&lt;/a&gt; website now includes a pricing estimator, which lists $42,500 as the total price for the average 2,000 square-foot home, with 10kW solar panels. It also lists $33,950 as the price after an $8,550 federal tax incentive. You can also enter your address and get an updated estimate that takes into account local costs and incentives, and add on any Powerwalls (with three as the default for a 2,000 square-foot roof).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The solarglass roof is not going to make financial sense for somebody who has a relatively new roof, because this is itself a roof, that has integrated solar power generation,” Musk explained. He went on to note that Tesla has managed with this version three product to achieve a price point that is “less than what the average roof costs, plus the solar panels” that you would add on top of said roof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Figuring out how to install it effectively is very non-trivial. And we’re actually going to have […] ‘installathons,’ ” Musk said, which will pit two teams against each other to see who can roof one of two similar-sized/designed roofs faster. Musk reiterated later that there’s “quite a bit of R&amp;amp;D just in the installation process itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk also said that while it’s hiring and training specialized installers at first, the plan is to ultimately expand installations to any third-party contractors as well. On the call, he and the Tesla team discussed how they focused on getting the installation time down to where it’s faster than installing traditional shingles, plus solar panels on top of that. Musk added that his ultimate goal is to install the solar glass tiles even faster than comparative shingles. This is a significant change from version two of the solar roof, Musk later said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re doing installations as fast as we possibly can, starting in the next few weeks,” Musk said about availability, adding that the goal is to “get to 1,000 roofs per week” sometime in “the next several months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/09/24/tesla-solar-roof-tiles-where-are-they.html&quot;&gt;report from CNBC&lt;/a&gt; from September 2018 found that Tesla still hadn’t performed many actual installations of its solar roof tile, despite the two-year gap between announcement and the date of their investigation, and a January announcement about the initiation of solar roof tile production at Tesla’s Buffalo-based Gigafactory. During the company’s annual general shareholder meeting in June, Musk said that the third iteration of the tile was being worked on, and while he didn’t detail the actual number of installations, he did say that they were in progress in eight different states across the U.S. at that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musk addressed some of the production delays to date, addressing the installation complexity of previous generations, but also citing the Tesla Model 3 production ramp, which he said “really stripped resources from solar for a year or a year-and-a-half.” Now that Model 3 production is in a good place, Musk said that that has unblocked significantly some of the company’s ability to focus on this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total addressable market that Musk sees for this product is somewhere on the order of 100 million houses worldwide, and Musk stressed that the company does indeed intend to make this available worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at launch there will be only one available look for the Solar Roof, the Tesla CEO also said that the company will roll out additional variants as quickly as it can, including tiles that resemble clay and other alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tiles and roof installation carry a warranty of 25 years, which includes their protective weatherization (including 130 MPH wind resistance) and their power generation capability. On balance, the Solar Roof provides more energy generation than a similarly sized roof retrofitted with traditional tiles, though individually, the tile’s power-gathering cells themselves are less energy-efficient than a traditional solar cell. The Solar Roof is better performing, however, because it covers more surface area of a home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 12:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>prostoalex</dc:creator>
<og:title>Tesla’s new Solar Roof costs less than a new roof plus solar panels, aims for install rate of 1K per week – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>Tesla has launched the third iteration of its solar roof tile for residential home use, which it officially detailed in a blog post on Friday and in a call with media. Tesla CEO Elon Musk kicked off the call with some explanatory remarks on the V3 Solar Roof, and then took a number of questions. [&amp;…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/SR-Hero_2880x1800.jpg?w=746</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/10/25/teslas-new-solar-roof-costs-less-than-a-new-roof-plus-solar-panels-aims-for-install-rate-of-1k-per-week/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/25/teslas-new-solar-roof-costs-less-than-a-new-roof-plus-solar-panels-aims-for-install-rate-of-1k-per-week/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An Illustrated Guide to Useful Command Line Tools</title>
<link>https://www.wezm.net/technical/2019/10/useful-command-line-tools/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.wezm.net/technical/2019/10/useful-command-line-tools/</guid>
<description>&lt;header readability=&quot;1.1590909090909&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published on &lt;time datetime=&quot;2019-10-26T14:11:22+11:00&quot;&gt;Sat, 26 October 2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://boyter.org/posts/my-list-of-useful-command-line-tools/&quot;&gt;a similar post by Ben Boyter&lt;/a&gt; this a list of useful command line tools that I use. It’s not a list of every tool I use. These are tools that are new or typically not part of a standard POSIX command line environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post is a living document and will be updated over time. It should be obvious that I have a &lt;strong&gt;strong&lt;/strong&gt; preference for fast tools without a large runtime dependency like Python or node.js. Most of these tools are portable to *BSD, Linux, macOS. Many also work on Windows. For OSes that ship up to date software many are available via the system package repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About my CLI environment:&lt;/strong&gt; I use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zsh.org/&quot;&gt;zsh&lt;/a&gt; shell, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsd.it/shop/fonts/pragmatapro/&quot;&gt;Pragmata Pro&lt;/a&gt; font, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chriskempson/base16&quot;&gt;base16 default dark&lt;/a&gt; color scheme. My prompt is generated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edkolev/promptline.vim&quot;&gt;promptline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Alacritty &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alacritty is fast terminal emulator. Whilst not strictly a command line tool, it does host everything I do in the command line. It is the terminal emulator in use in all the screenshots on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/jwilm/alacritty&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;alt &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; is a tool for finding the alternate to a file. E.g. the header for an implementation or the test for an implementation. I use it paired with Neovim to easily toggle between tests and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ alt app/models/page.rb
spec/models/page_spec.rb
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/uptech/alt&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;bat &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bat&lt;/code&gt; is an alternative to the common (mis)use of &lt;code&gt;cat&lt;/code&gt; to print a file to the terminal. It supports syntax highlighting and git integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/bat.png&quot; alt=&quot;bat screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/sharkdp/bat&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;chars &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;chars&lt;/code&gt; shows information about Unicode characters matching a search term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/chars.png&quot; alt=&quot;chars screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/antifuchs/chars&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;dot &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dot&lt;/code&gt; is a dotfiles manager. It maintains a set of symlinks according to a mappings file. I use it to manage &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wezm/dotfiles&quot;&gt;my dotfiles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/dot.png&quot; alt=&quot;dot screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/ubnt-intrepid/dot&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;dust &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dust&lt;/code&gt; is an alternative &lt;code&gt;du -sh&lt;/code&gt;. It calculates the size of a directory tree, printing a summary of the largest items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/dust.png&quot; alt=&quot;dust screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/bootandy/dust&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;exa &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;exa&lt;/code&gt; is a replacement for &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; with sensible defaults and added features like a tree view, git integration, and optional icons. I have &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; aliased to &lt;code&gt;exa&lt;/code&gt; in my shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/exa.png&quot; alt=&quot;exa screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://the.exa.website/&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;eva &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;eva&lt;/code&gt; is a command line calculator similar to &lt;code&gt;bc&lt;/code&gt;, with syntax highlighting and persistent history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/eva.png&quot; alt=&quot;eva screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/NerdyPepper/eva&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;fd &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;fd&lt;/code&gt; is an alternative to &lt;code&gt;find&lt;/code&gt; and has a more user friendly command line interface and respects ignore files, like &lt;code&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt;. The combination of its speed and ignore file support make it excellent for searching for files in git repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/fd.png&quot; alt=&quot;fd screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/sharkdp/fd&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;hexyl &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hexyl&lt;/code&gt; is a hex viewer that uses Unicode characters and colour to make the output more readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/hexyl.png&quot; alt=&quot;hexyl screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/sharkdp/hexyl&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;jq &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-C-%23444444&quot; alt=&quot;Language: C&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt; is kind of like &lt;code&gt;awk&lt;/code&gt; for JSON. It lets you transform and extract information from JSON documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/jq.png&quot; alt=&quot;jq screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://stedolan.github.io/jq/&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;mdcat &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mdcat&lt;/code&gt; renders Markdown files in the terminal. In supported terminals (not Alacritty) links are clickable (without the url being visible like in a web browser) and images are rendered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/mdcat.png&quot; alt=&quot;mdcat screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/lunaryorn/mdcat&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;pass &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-sh-%2389e051&quot; alt=&quot;Language: sh&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pass&lt;/code&gt; is a password manager that uses GPG to store the passwords. I use it with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/passff/passff&quot;&gt;passff&lt;/a&gt; Firefox extension and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mssun/passforios&quot;&gt;Pass for iOS&lt;/a&gt; on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/pass.png&quot; alt=&quot;pass screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/lunaryorn/mdcat&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Podman &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-Go-%2300ADD8&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Go&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;podman&lt;/code&gt; is an alternative to Docker that does not require a daemon. Containers are run as the user running Podman so files written into the host don’t end up owned by root. The CLI is largely compatible with the &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; CLI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/podman.png&quot; alt=&quot;podman screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://podman.io/&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Restic &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-Go-%2300ADD8&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Go&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;restic&lt;/code&gt; is a backup tool that performs client side encryption, de-duplication and supports a variety of local and remote storage backends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://restic.net/&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;ripgrep &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ripgrep (&lt;code&gt;rg&lt;/code&gt;) recursively searches file trees for content in files matching a regular expression. It’s extremely fast, and respects ignore files and binary files by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/ripgrep.png&quot; alt=&quot;ripgrep screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;shotgun &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;shotgun&lt;/code&gt; is a tool for taking screenshots on X.org based environments. All the screenshots in this post were taken with it. It pairs well with &lt;code&gt;slop&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ shotgun $(slop -c 0,0,0,0.75 -l -f &quot;-i %i -g %g&quot;) eva.png
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/neXromancers/shotgun&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;skim &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;skim&lt;/code&gt; is a fuzzy finder. It can be used to fuzzy match input fed to it. I use it with Neovim and zsh for fuzzy matching file names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/skim.png&quot; alt=&quot;skim screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/lotabout/skim&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;slop &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-C%2B%2B-%23f34b7d&quot; alt=&quot;Language: C++&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;slop&lt;/code&gt; (Select Operation) presents a UI to select a region of the screen or a window and prints the region to stdout. Works well with &lt;code&gt;shotgun&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ slop -c 0,0,0,0.75 -l -f &quot;-i %i -g %g&quot;
-i 8389044 -g 1464x1008+291+818
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/naelstrof/slop&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Syncthing &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-Go-%2300ADD8&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Go&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncthing is a decentralised file synchronisation tool. Like Dropbox but self hosted and without the need for a central third-party file store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://syncthing.net/&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;tig &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-C-%23444444&quot; alt=&quot;Language: C&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;tig&lt;/code&gt; is a ncurses TUI for git. It’s great for reviewing and staging changes, viewing history and diffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/tig.png&quot; alt=&quot;tig screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://jonas.github.io/tig/&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;titlecase &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;titlecase&lt;/code&gt; is a little tool I wrote to format text using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/2008/05/title_case&quot;&gt;title case format described by John Gruber&lt;/a&gt;. It correctly handles puctuation, and words like iPhone. I use it to obtain consistent titles on all my blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ echo 'an illustrated guide to useful command line tools' | titlecase
An Illustrated Guide to Useful Command Line Tools
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I typically use it from within Neovim where selected text is piped through it in-place. This is done by creating a visual selection and then typing: &lt;code&gt;:!titlecase&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/wezm/titlecase&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Universal Ctags &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-C-%23444444&quot; alt=&quot;Language: C&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universal Ctags is a fork of exuberant ctags that is actively maintained. &lt;code&gt;ctags&lt;/code&gt; is used to generate a &lt;code&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; file that &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; and other tools can use to navigate to the definition of symbols in files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;$ ctags --recurse src
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;http://ctags.io/&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;watchexec &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;watchexec&lt;/code&gt; is a file a directory watcher that can run commands in response to file system changes. Handy for auto running tests or restarting a development web server when source files change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;# run command on file change
$ watchexec -w content cobalt build

# kill and restart server on file change
$ watchexec -w src -s SIGINT -r 'cargo run'
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/watchexec/watchexec&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;z &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-sh-%2389e051&quot; alt=&quot;Language: sh&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;z&lt;/code&gt; tracks your most used directories and allows you to jump to them with a partial name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/z.png&quot; alt=&quot;z screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rupa/z&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;zola &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-rust-%23dea584&quot; alt=&quot;Language: Rust&quot;/&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;zola&lt;/code&gt; is a full-featured very fast static site compiler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/cli/zola.png&quot; alt=&quot;zola screenshot&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;action-button action-button-ghost&quot; href=&quot;https://www.getzola.org/&quot;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/images/lobsters.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; class=&quot;lobsters&quot;/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lobste.rs/s/pven1z/illustrated_guide_some_useful_command&quot;&gt;Discuss on Lobsters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21363121&quot;&gt;Discuss on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;left&quot;/&gt;
✦
&lt;hr class=&quot;right&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous Post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wezm.net/technical/2019/04/lobsters-tui/&quot;&gt;What I Learnt Building a Lobsters TUI in Rust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 11:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>signa11</dc:creator>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.wezm.net/technical/2019/10/useful-command-line-tools/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bruno Simon – 3D Curriculum</title>
<link>https://bruno-simon.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://bruno-simon.com/</guid>
<description>[unable to retrieve full-text content]
&lt;p&gt;Article URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bruno-simon.com/&quot;&gt;https://bruno-simon.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21362200&quot;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21362200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points: 233&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Comments: 41&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 07:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>laurentdc</dc:creator>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:url>https://bruno-simon.com</og:url>
<og:title>Bruno Simon - Creative developer</og:title>
<og:description>Creative developer living in Paris, freelancer, former lead developer at Immersive Garden, former developer at Uzik and teacher.</og:description>
<og:image>https://bruno-simon.com/social/share-1200x630.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://bruno-simon.com/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hitman hires hitman who hires hitman who hires hitman who hires hitman</title>
<link>https://metro.co.uk/2019/10/23/hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-tells-police-10971438/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://metro.co.uk/2019/10/23/hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-tells-police-10971438/</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap&quot;&gt;

&lt;img width=&quot;644&quot; height=&quot;387&quot; data-rsz=&quot;shrink&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/metro.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PRI_91404333.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;zoom=1&amp;amp;resize=644%2C387&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;The final hitman was insulted at the money he had been offered (Picture: AFP)&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10970994 size-full&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
The final hitman was insulted at the money he had been offered (Picture: AFP)
&lt;p&gt;Five hitmen have been jailed for attempted murder after each one avoided carrying out the contract themselves so they could make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese businessman Tan Youhui was looking for a hitman to take out a competitor, Wei Mou, and was willing to pay 2 million yuan (£218,000) to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hitman that Mr Youhui hired decided to offer the job to another hitman for half the original price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second hitman then subcontracted to another hitman, who then subcontracted to a fourth, who gave the job to a fifth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, hitman number five was so incensed at how much the value of the contract had fallen, that he told the target to fake his own death, which eventually led to the police finding out about the plot, Beijing News reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The businessman and the hapless assassins were all convicted of attempted murder by the court in Nanning, Guangxi, following a trial that lasted three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-slot-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-slot-label-container&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-slot-label&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-slot-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-slot-label-container&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-slot-label&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original dispute occurred in 2013, when Wei decided to sue real estate developer Youhui.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap&quot;&gt;

&lt;img data-orig-id=&quot;wp-image-10970996&quot; data-orig-w=&quot;&quot; data-orig-h=&quot;&quot; data-max-width=&quot;540&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;303&quot; data-rsz=&quot;shrink&quot; src=&quot;https://metro.co.uk/wp-content/themes/metro-parent/img/fallback.png&quot; data-src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/metro.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PRI_91220895.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;zoom=1&amp;amp;resize=540%2C303&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; alt=&quot;gov website http://nnzy.chinacourt.gov.cn/article/detail/2019/10/id/4562340.shtml&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-10970996&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
he businessman and the hapless assassins were all convicted of attempted murder by the court in Nanning, Guangxi, China (Picture: Nanning Intermediate People’s Court)
&lt;p&gt;Worried he would lose the lengthy court battle, Tan hired a hitman named Xi Guangan to kill Mr Wei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Xi contacted another hitman, Mo Tianxiang offering him half the original sum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mo then decided to contact a third hitman, Yang Kangsheng, who quoted an upfront price of 270,000 Yuan (£29,775) to carry out the hit, with 500,000 (£55,140) Yuan to be handed over once it was done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://metro.co.uk/2019/10/26/man-dies-of-heart-attack-mid-air-on-british-airways-flight-10989308/&quot; data-track=&quot;in-content-link/1/thumbnail/auto-cat/&quot; data-track-destination=&quot;10989308&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail-link&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/metro.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PRI_92098722.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;crop=142px%2C0px%2C2221px%2C1665px&amp;amp;resize=200%2C150&amp;amp;zoom=1&amp;amp;ssl=1&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; data-rsz=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://metro.co.uk/wp-content/themes/metro-parent/img/fallback.png&quot; alt=&quot;A British Airways aeroplane takes off from the runway at Heathrow Airport's Terminal 5 in west London, on September 13, 2019. (Photo by Tolga Akmen / various sources / AFP) (Photo credit should read TOLGA AKMEN/AFP/Getty Images)&quot; class=&quot;thumbnail-link-image&quot;/&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mor-title&quot;&gt;Man dies of heart attack mid-air on British Airways flight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Yang Kangsheng passed it on to another hitman, Yang Guangsheng, for a further reduced fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contract finally came to the fifth hitman, Ling Xiansi, who eventually told the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tan, who hired the original hitman, was jailed for five years, while Xi, the first hitman, was sentenced to three years and six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang Kangsheng and Yang Guangsheng were sentenced to three years and three months, Mo was sentenced to three years, and Ling was sentenced to two years and seven months.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;article-below-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-slot-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-slot-label-container&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-slot-label&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;ad-slot-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-slot-label-container&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ad-slot-label&quot;&gt;Advertisement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 05:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>occamschainsaw</dc:creator>
<og:title>Hitman hires hitman who hires hitman who hires hitman who hires hitman</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://metro.co.uk/2019/10/23/hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-tells-police-10971438/</og:url>
<og:description>A businessman and the hapless assassins he hired were all convicted of attempted murder.</og:description>
<og:image>https://i2.wp.com/metro.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PRI_91404333_1571934133.jpg?quality=90&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;crop=1&amp;zoom=1&amp;ssl=1</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://metro.co.uk/2019/10/23/hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-hires-hitman-tells-police-10971438/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microsoft Wins Pentagon’s $10B Contract</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/25/technology/dod-jedi-contract.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/25/technology/dod-jedi-contract.html</guid>
<description>&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;SAN FRANCISCO — The Department of Defense on Friday &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Contracts/Contract/Article/1999639/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;awarded a $10 billion technology contract&lt;/a&gt; to Microsoft over Amazon in a contest that was closely watched after &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/18/us/politics/trump-amazon-defense-department-contract.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;President Trump ramped up his criticism of Amazon’s founder, Jeff Bezos, and said he might intervene&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The 10-year contract for the Joint Enterprise Defense Infrastructure, known as JEDI, had set off a showdown among Amazon, Microsoft, IBM, Oracle and Google for the right to transform the military’s cloud computing systems. The acrimonious process involved intense lobbying efforts and legal challenges among the rivals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The contract has an outsize importance because it is central to the Pentagon’s efforts to modernize its technology. Much of the military operates on 1980s and 1990s computer systems, and the Defense Department has spent billions of dollars trying to make them talk to one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The decision was a surprise because &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/02/us/politics/amazon-pentagon-contract-trump.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon had been considered the front-runner&lt;/a&gt;, in part because it had built cloud services for the Central Intelligence Agency. But that was before Mr. Trump became publicly hostile to Mr. Bezos, who also owns The Washington Post. The president often refers to the newspaper as the “Amazon Washington Post” and has accused it of spreading “fake news.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In public, Mr. Trump said there were other “great companies” that should have a chance at the contract. But a speechwriter for former Defense Secretary Jim Mattis says &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2019/10/23/syria-disagreement-with-trump-used-pretext-mattiss-departure-pentagon-chief-new-book-says/&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in a book&lt;/a&gt; scheduled for publication next week that Mr. Trump had wanted to foil Amazon and give the contract to another company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The issue quickly became radioactive at the Pentagon. The new defense secretary, Mark T. Esper, at first said he wanted to &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/01/us/politics/amazon-pentagon-contract.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;take several months to review the issue&lt;/a&gt; and then, a few days ago, recused himself from the bidding. He said he could not participate because his son worked for IBM, one of the competitors for the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;As recently as this month, the betting was that Microsoft would, at most, get only part of the contract and that the Pentagon would use multiple suppliers for its cloud services, as do many private companies. Microsoft was considered in the lead for other government cloud programs, including an intelligence contract; only recently has Microsoft opened enough classified server facilities to be able to handle data on the scale of the Pentagon contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“The acquisition process was conducted in accordance with applicable laws and regulations,” the Defense Department said in a statement on Friday. “All offerors were treated fairly and evaluated consistently with the solicitation’s stated evaluation criteria.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Microsoft did not immediately have a comment. Amazon, which calls its cloud platform Amazon Web Services, or AWS, said in a statement that it was surprised by the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“AWS is the clear leader in cloud computing, and a detailed assessment purely on the comparative offerings clearly led to a different conclusion,” Drew Herdener, a spokesman for Amazon, said. “We remain deeply committed to continuing to innovate for the new digital battlefield where security, efficiency, resiliency and scalability of resources can be the difference between success and failure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The award to Microsoft is likely to fuel suspicions that Mr. Trump may have weighed in privately as well as publicly against Amazon. Experts on federal contracting said it would be highly improper for a president to intervene in the awarding of a contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Price Floyd, a former head of public affairs at the Pentagon who consulted briefly for Amazon, said he thought Mr. Trump’s vocal criticism of Amazon would give it ample grounds to protest the award to Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“He’s the commander in chief, and he hasn’t been subtle about his hostility toward Amazon,” Mr. Floyd said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Microsoft’s win has implications for the cloud computing industry, in which businesses rent space on technology companies’ server computers, giving them cheap and fast access to storage and processing. Amazon has long been the dominant player, with about 45 percent of the market, trailed by Microsoft with around 25 percent, said Daniel Ives, an analyst for Wedbush Securities who has closely followed the JEDI saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Landing the JEDI contract puts Microsoft in a prime position to earn the roughly $40 billion that the federal government is expected to spend on cloud computing over the next several years, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Losing the bid is also a hit to the reputation of Amazon, which decided last year to open &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/13/business/national-landing-amazon-va.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;a large outpost in Northern Virginia&lt;/a&gt; that will eventually employ at least 25,000 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Unifying information in the cloud has obvious benefits for the Pentagon as the military moves to greater use of remote sensors, semiautonomous weapons and, ultimately, artificial intelligence. It is particularly crucial now that United States Cyber Command has been elevated to the equivalent of Central Command, which runs operations in the Middle East, or the Northern Command, which defends the continental United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But some critics of the process argued that such a large contract should not be awarded to a single company, while proponents said using only one provider would eliminate glitches in military systems and streamline communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The initial reaction on Friday from some lawmakers was positive, mostly because the long-delayed contract had finally been issued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Representative Jim Langevin, a Rhode Island Democrat who has immersed himself in cyber issues, suggested the military was finally catching up with private industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“Advanced general-purpose cloud is the industry norm, and it’s past time the Department of Defense had access to these capabilities,” said Mr. Langevin, the chairman of the Armed Services Subcommittee on Intelligence and Emerging Threats and Capabilities. “I look forward to continuing to use my position in Congress to increase access to next-generation technologies that support our war fighters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;But Senator Mark Warner, a Democrat of Virginia, &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MarkWarner/status/1157341554346008576&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;said on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that it was “important that we maintain a fair &amp;amp; competitive process” and that “for the President to use the power of his office to punish critics in the media would be a complete abuse of power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;Amazon, Microsoft, IBM, Oracle and Google began battling for the JEDI contract more than a year ago. &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-10-08/google-drops-out-of-pentagon-s-10-billion-cloud-competition&quot; title=&quot;&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google dropped out&lt;/a&gt; last October without submitting a formal bid, saying the military work conflicted with its corporate principles, which preclude the use of artificial intelligence in weaponry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;The Pentagon said in April that only &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/10/technology/amazon-microsoft-jedi-pentagon.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Amazon and Microsoft met its technical requirements&lt;/a&gt; for fulfilling the contract. In &lt;a class=&quot;css-1g7m0tk&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/20/technology/military-contract-deap-ubhi.html?module=inline&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;an unsuccessful legal challenge, Oracle&lt;/a&gt; alleged that Amazon had biased the process in its favor by hiring Defense Department employees to work on the bidding process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;In August, the Defense Department’s inspector general announced that it had assembled a team to review the JEDI process. But while that was underway, Mr. Trump raised his objections. The process froze, and Pentagon officials said time was being wasted — which would ultimately put the United States at a military disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;“In 20 years of covering tech, I’ve never seen a battle for any type of contract reach this level of nastiness,” Mr. Ives said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;css-exrw3m evys1bk0&quot;&gt;He said he saw the ferocity of the contest mainly as a response to Amazon’s enormous success as the pioneer of cloud computing, which is now the foundation of much of the digital infrastructure of private industry. He said Amazon’s revenue from federal government contracts, about $200 million in 2014, had reached $2 billion this year, much of it from the C.I.A. and other intelligence agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;css-o6xoe7&quot; aria-label=&quot;companion column&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;false&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 23:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>aaronbrethorst</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/25/technology/dod-jedi-contract.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Microsoft Wins Pentagon’s $10 Billion JEDI Contract, Thwarting Amazon</og:title>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2019/10/25/business/25jedi/25jedi-facebookJumbo-v2.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>Amazon was considered a front-runner for the cloud computing project before President Trump began criticizing the company’s founder, Jeff Bezos.</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/25/technology/dod-jedi-contract.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Don Valentine has died</title>
<link>https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/remembering-don-valentine/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/remembering-don-valentine/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/b0b63a16ef62d208f38bd7deefb0a4ce4ea35f99/a8390/img/c/don-valentine-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Don Valentine (4)&quot; title=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Valentine, founder of Sequoia Capital and one of the generation of leaders who forged Silicon Valley, died today aged 87 at his home in Woodside, California. He shaped Sequoia and left his imprint not just on his family and friends and those who worked with him, or the many philanthropic institutions that have invested with Sequoia Capital, but also on the Founders and leaders of some of the most significant technology companies of the later part of the twentieth century. Our deepest sympathies go to Rachel, his wife of 58 years, his three children, Christian, Mark and Hilary, and seven grandchildren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’s life is woven into the fabric of Silicon Valley. Born in New York in 1932, he studied chemistry at Fordham University before moving to Southern California in the mid 1950s to join the burgeoning aerospace industry where he became a sales engineer with Raytheon. Understanding that the epicenter of the young semiconductor industry lay further north, he moved to the San Francisco peninsula to join Fairchild Semiconductor, a spawning ground for several later spinoffs – including Intel, Advanced Micro Devices and National Semiconductor - which, in turn, helped power the growth of the mini-computer, personal computer and inter-networking industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seven years at Fairchild, where he helped build the most competitive salesforce in the semiconductor industry, he joined National Semiconductor as its founding VP of Sales and Marketing. During the time Don spent at National, the company became known for the sales and operational prowess which made it a leading supplier of analog circuitry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at National, Don started making personal investments in technology companies and his sideline interest captured the attention of the privately-held Capital Group – one of the earliest managers of mutual funds. Together with Capital, Don established Capital Management Services which formed its first $3 million venture capital fund in 1974.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first fund made seminal investments in Atari, the pioneering videogame company started by Nolan Bushnell, and in Apple Computer, a company started by a onetime Atari employee, Steve Jobs, and his high school friend, Steve Wozniak. Don served on the Boards of both Atari and Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These early investments put what later became known as Sequoia Capital on the map. Don’s choice of name for our partnership was in keeping with the man. It conveyed the longevity and strength of the tallest of redwoods with the humility of someone who refrained from putting his own name on our business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don was Sequoia’s driving force and central figure until the mid-1990s – a period associated with the formation of many enduring companies which bore his hallmark. These included Oracle, LSI Logic, Microchip Technology, Linear Technology and Network Appliance. The company of which he was proudest, Cisco Systems, made much of the plumbing for the internet and his service as Chairman from the time of Sequoia’s original investment in 1987 spanned three decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don also nurtured two companies whose business plans and formation occurred within Sequoia’s office – Electronic Arts and Sierra Semiconductor. The former became a mainstay of the videogame business while the latter led to the creation, with the Government of Singapore, of Chartered Semiconductor which, as a manufacturing company, helped change the complexion of the global semiconductor industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond Sequoia, Don’s fondness for rainswept Scottish golfing vacations, Pebble Beach, the Oakland Raiders and the accomplishments of Tom Brady were apparent. For many years he was a devoted supporter of the Stanford School of Engineering and helped orchestrate the Stanford Engineering Venture Fund which became a model for universities across the nation. He was also a keen supporter of medical research. Less well known was his affection for the San Francisco Opera (where he was a longtime member of the Guild) and the San Francisco Symphony where he served as a member of the Board of Governors and an enthusiastic backer of its leader, Michael Tilson Thomas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his later years Don was a ready source of advice for those who stopped by his office and, unlike most former leaders, resisted the temptation to criticize decisions which he considered misguided or to meddle in the business. Ever curious he relished spending time with young people brimming with ideas about the future. His family and friends and those who spent decades working with him harbor a trove of affectionate memories of the quirks and habits of a man who favored green ink, never drank coffee, listened carefully, understood the virtues of silence, built the foundation on which so many have the good fortune to stand, and insisted that the ultimate test for every startup was a thoughtful answer to his perpetual question about its quest, “Who cares?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DTV&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest in Peace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don's family asks that in lieu of flowers, donations be made to the Donald T. Valentine Memorial Fund at Stanford University. Gifts can be directed to the Donald T. Valentine Memorial Fund at Stanford, payable to Stanford University, c/o Trish Gerber, Office of Development, Stanford University, 326 Galvez Street, Stanford CA 94305, (650) 736-4020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details of the celebration of Don's life will be circulated in due course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 21:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>gatsby</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://www.sequoiacap.com/img/c/don-valentine-4_w650_q80.png</og:image>
<og:title>Sequoia - Remembering Don Valentine</og:title>
<og:description>Don Valentine, founder of Sequoia Capital and one of the generation of leaders who forged Silicon Valley, died today aged 87 at his ...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/remembering-don-valentine/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Indian startups have raised a record $11.3B this year</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/23/india-tech-startups-fundraise/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/23/india-tech-startups-fundraise/</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot;&gt;With two months of 2019 still to go, Indian tech startups are already having their best year as a record amount of capital flows into the local ecosystem in a major rebound since the darkened funding environment of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unlisted tech startups in India have raised $11.3 billion this year, a substantial jump from last year’s $10.5 billion fundraise, research firm Tracxn told TechCrunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year’s fundraise, the largest sum for the local ecosystem in any year, further moves the nation’s burgeoning startup space on a path of steady growth. Since 2016, when tech startups accumulated just $4.3 billion — down from $7.9 billion the year before — flow of capital has increased significantly in the ecosystem. In 2017, Indian startups raised $10.4 billion, according to Tracxn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startups with consumer-facing offerings including financial services have attracted most of the venture capital this year — about $8.2 billion, Tracxn said. Following that is retail startups that have bagged about $2.3 billion and those that offer enterprise services, with $1.5 billion. (There is some overlap of startups whose offerings fall under more than one category.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors’ growing appetite for equity in India’s startups shows that the local ecosystem is maturing, said Dev Khare, a partner at VC fund &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/lightspeed-venture-partners&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;lightspeed-venture-partners&quot;&gt;Lightspeed Venture Partners&lt;/a&gt;. In an interview with TechCrunch, Khare noted that in 2014 and 2015, startups were largely focused on building e-commerce solutions and replicating ideas that worked in Western markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But today, they are tackling a wide-range of categories and opportunities and building some solutions that have not been attempted in any other market,” he said. He attributes much of this change to the arrival of telecom operator Reliance Jio and some government efforts, such as introduction of GST taxation system for businesses and introduction of UPI payments infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jio, a three-year-old telecom operator run by India’s richest man, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/person/mukesh-ambani&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;person&quot; data-entity=&quot;mukesh-ambani&quot;&gt;Mukesh Ambani,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/12/reliance-jio-broadband-blockchain-iot-microsoft/&quot;&gt;has disrupted the market with incredibly low-cost mobile data&lt;/a&gt;. The low-cost data meant that overnight, tens of millions of Indians were able to come online for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, alongside a cash crunch created by New Delhi in late 2016, led to a sudden explosion in &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/06/pratilipi-a-youtube-for-writers-storytelling-platform-in-india-raises-15-million/&quot;&gt;demand for content&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/12/hotstar-disneys-indian-streaming-service-sets-new-global-record-for-live-viewership/&quot;&gt;and services&lt;/a&gt;, including mobile wallets that created a massive opportunity for local startups to innovate, Khare said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial services firm &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/paytm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;paytm&quot;&gt;Paytm,&lt;/a&gt; which has raised more than $2 billion to date, has more than 200 million registered users in India, while Google Pay has &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/18/google-pay-job-business-india/&quot;&gt;amassed over 67 million active customers&lt;/a&gt; in less than two years of its existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Khare said more people than ever in India today are willing to work at a startup. Citing Lightspeed’s internal research, he said in 2010, only 10% of founders of startups that had reached a Series A financing round had worked at a startup before. That figure went up to 36% in 2014 and ballooned to 70% last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some other promising signals as well: Of the top 150 Indian startups that raised capital in the first half of this year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://themorningcontext.com/women-led-startups-in-india/&quot;&gt;17.3% of them were either led or co-led by women&lt;/a&gt;, Indian news outlet The Morning Context reported on Wednesday, citing data from research firm Venture Intelligence. This is a massive jump from last year, when just 10% of startups counted women as their founder or co-founder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A trend that appears to continue from the last several years is concentration of funds in a smaller number of startups. So far, tech startups in India have participated in 872 financing rounds, compared to 924 last year, and 1,141 in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that number, as well as total fundraise amount, could change substantially by the end of the year as many more startups prep to close new financing rounds. &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/zomato&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;zomato&quot;&gt;Zomato,&lt;/a&gt; Swiggy and Paytm alone are expected to close rounds worth as much as $3 billion in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a fascinating turnaround for the nation, which just 10 years ago had a very small startup ecosystem. In a recent interview with TechCrunch, &lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://crunchbase.com/organization/paytm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;paytm&quot;&gt;Paytm&lt;/a&gt; founder and CEO Vijay Shekhar Sharma recounted the early days of One97, the parent firm of Paytm, and how difficult it was for him to raise a few hundred thousand dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 19:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jmsflknr</dc:creator>
<og:title>Indian startups have raised a record $11.3B this year – TechCrunch</og:title>
<og:description>With two months of 2019 still to go, Indian tech startups are already having their best year as a record amount of capital flows into the local ecosystem in a major rebound since the darkened funding environment of 2016. The unlisted tech startups in India have raised $11.3 billion this year, a sub…</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/GettyImages-1158428016.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2019/10/23/india-tech-startups-fundraise/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/23/india-tech-startups-fundraise/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>My company sold for $100M and I got zilch – how can that be?</title>
<link>https://medium.com/help-me-heidi/my-company-sold-for-100-million-and-i-got-zilch-how-can-that-be-f7be0563f1f8</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://medium.com/help-me-heidi/my-company-sold-for-100-million-and-i-got-zilch-how-can-that-be-f7be0563f1f8</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;2289&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;Dear Former Millionaire:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;1384&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;I feel your pain. I really do. I’ve always thought it unfortunate that common practice is to tell employees share amounts and strike prices, but not give them all the other numbers needed to help them evaluate what their options will end up being worth. For what it’s worth, I encourage all the companies I work with to be more transparent. I guess yours wasn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;f5ca&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;There are probably multiple issues at play here, but I’m going to guess the biggest one is your preference overhang. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3c1f&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;When venture capitalists buy equity, they typically do not buy the same shares employees get, which are common shares. They buy preferred shares. You can even guess from the name that these are somehow better. After all, if you were given the option of something &lt;em class=&quot;hb&quot;&gt;preferred&lt;/em&gt; or something &lt;em class=&quot;hb&quot;&gt;common&lt;/em&gt;, which would you take? There are all sorts of reasons this is so, including the obligation VCs have to protect the downside of investing the money they get from their Limited Partners — who are often entities like pension funds and school endowments. There are also some advantages to common shareholders by having two classes of stock — for example, this allows the company to price your common stock options at less than what the VCs pay because they have different attributes and, therefore, different values. (You can read more about preferred versus common &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.priorilegal.com/legal-for-industries/startup/common-vs-preferred-stock-in-startups&quot; class=&quot;fu cf hn ho hp hq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;c6f4&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;The principal benefit of preferred shares for those who own them is that they get their money out first if the company is sold. While common practice is they get the same out that they put in, it is not unheard of for some of that money to carry a multiple, 2x or even more (meaning they might get two times or more their money out first), especially if the company had to raise money at a time when no one wanted to put any in without additional downside protection. Point is, this is the market, and it has been that way for a long time, and there is nothing inherently wrong with these terms. But if you don’t know about it, it sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3edf&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;Most employees think that, if they own 1% of a company sold for $100 million, they will get $1 million. But that’s not the whole equation. What they will really get is the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;974f&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;Sales price minus legal fees minus carve-out minus banker fees minus preferred overhang, then that remainder is divvied up by percent of company-owned. (Whether the preferred stock is participating or not creates a further wrinkle which you can read about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startupcompanylawyer.com/2007/06/15/what-is-the-difference-between-non-participating-preferred-stock-and-participating-preferred-stock/&quot; class=&quot;fu cf hn ho hp hq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but for now, this captures most of what you need.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;79be&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;The “easiest” way for your 1% to be worth nothing is to have that preferred overhang be a lot of money since all the other things in the equation usually do not end up being more than about 15–20% of the total value being received in the sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3268&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;And often that preferred overhang is a lot. If you raised multiple rounds (&lt;strong class=&quot;gp hc&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;hb&quot;&gt;regardless of the valuation of those rounds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and if you raised more than your company is now being sold for, you will get nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3e92&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;This might be easier to understand by example, so let me paint a hypothetical picture from what you’ve told me about your situation that would result in your goose egg payout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4f00&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;Let’s say your company raises a $2 million seed round, a $15 million Series A, and then a $50 million Series B. These have standard 1x preferences, meaning they will get their money out first in any sale of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5395&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;Then the company runs into problems, and no new investors are willing to come in. The board decides to start a sale process since the company is unprofitable and so cannot exist without new capital. But the company only has enough money to cover payroll for sixty days — not enough time to find a buyer and get a sale done. To increase the time they have to find a buyer, the existing investors offer an additional $10 million in a loan, or “bridge note” — but in exchange they will only put that in if they can get a 2x preference, in other words, they will get the first $20 million of any sale proceeds for doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;a4be&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;Four more months pass, and the company secures two competing bids to buy the company, the highest being $100 million. So they agree to sell for $100 million. The lawyers and bankers get paid $3 million for their work. Certain key employees were incentivized with a “ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fenwick.com/FenwickDocuments/Carving-Up-the-Pie.pdf&quot; class=&quot;fu cf hn ho hp hq&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;carve-out&lt;/a&gt; “ in order to stay through the transaction and make sure it would happen, they get 10% of the deal, or $10 million. The seed, Series A, and Series B investors get their money back, or $67 million, and the bridge note would be paid $20 million. So, $3 plus $10 plus $67 plus $20 equals $100 million — &lt;strong class=&quot;gp hc&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;hb&quot;&gt;and zero for all common shareholders, including you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;b7a8&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;Again, let me emphasize, this is not inherently unfair. When I raised capital as an entrepreneur about a million years ago, I sold preferred shares too. I even had the preferred overhang number on the wall in my office, to remind me how much money would have to go out the door before I or my team could make a single penny when the company finally got sold. The problem is most companies hide it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;5765&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;In fact, one of my kids was recently interviewing at a startup and I told her to ask about the preferred overhang — she said the interviewer looked at her like she was asking about his sex life! She didn’t get a call-back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;9ef3&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;Sadly, while I can explain to you why you have ended up in this predicament, I can’t tell you how to fix it, at least not for this at-bat. However, I hope this explanation helps you go into your next endeavor with eyes open and hopefully with better data. You can actually find out the preference stack for many companies by simply Googling “how much money has company X raised?” While that won’t give you any indication if the money was raised at other than a 1x, it will at least give you the ballpark preference overhang number. Even better, just ask what it is. But, be prepared for offended glares and raised eyebrows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;af8b&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;Wishing you better outcomes in your future&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;3832&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gp hc&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;hb&quot;&gt;— Heidi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;fb1d&quot; class=&quot;gn go ep ba gp b gq gr gs gt gu gv gw gx gy gz ha&quot;&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;gp hc&quot;&gt;&lt;em class=&quot;hb&quot;&gt;Send me questions at HelpmeHeidi@threshold.vc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 19:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rmason</dc:creator>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>My company sold for $100 million and I got Zilch. How can that be?</og:title>
<og:description>Dear Heidi:</og:description>
<og:url>https://medium.com/help-me-heidi/my-company-sold-for-100-million-and-i-got-zilch-how-can-that-be-f7be0563f1f8</og:url>
<og:image>https://miro.medium.com/max/1200/1*6G_YubFAdsqg2fLVkmgLGw@2x.png</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://medium.com/help-me-heidi/my-company-sold-for-100-million-and-i-got-zilch-how-can-that-be-f7be0563f1f8</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>We tested Europe’s new lie detector for travelers and triggered a false positive</title>
<link>https://theintercept.com/2019/07/26/europe-border-control-ai-lie-detector/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://theintercept.com/2019/07/26/europe-border-control-ai-lie-detector/</guid>
<description>&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;208&quot; readability=&quot;45&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;They call it&lt;/u&gt; the Silent Talker. It is a virtual policeman designed to strengthen Europe’s borders, subjecting travelers to a lie detector test before they are allowed to pass through customs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to your arrival at the airport, using your own computer, you log on to a website, upload an image of your passport, and are greeted by an avatar of a brown-haired man wearing a navy blue uniform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What is your surname?” he asks. “What is your citizenship and the purpose of your trip?” You provide your answers verbally to those and other questions, and the virtual policeman uses your webcam to scan your face and eye movements for signs of lying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the interview, the system provides you with a QR code that you have to show to a guard when you arrive at the border. The guard scans the code using a handheld tablet device, takes your fingerprints, and reviews the facial image captured by the avatar to check if it corresponds with your passport. The guard’s tablet displays a score out of 100, telling him whether the machine has judged you to be truthful or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person judged to have tried to deceive the system is categorized as “high risk” or “medium risk,” dependent on the number of questions they are found to have falsely answered. Our reporter — the first journalist to test the system before crossing the Serbian-Hungarian border earlier this year — provided honest responses to all questions but was deemed to be a liar by the machine, with four false answers out of 16 and a score of 48. The Hungarian policeman who assessed our reporter’s lie detector results said the system suggested that she should be subject to further checks, though these were not carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travelers who are deemed dangerous can be denied entry, though in most cases they would never know if the avatar test had contributed to such a decision. The results of the test are not usually disclosed to the traveler; The Intercept obtained a copy of our reporter’s test only after filing a data access request under European privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-wrap align-center width-fixed&quot; data-reactid=&quot;209&quot; readability=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;210&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-article-large wp-image-260876&quot; src=&quot;https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2019/07/guard-photo-1000-1564076275.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;amp;q=90&amp;amp;w=1000&amp;amp;h=907&quot; alt=&quot;guard-photo-1000-1564076275&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The iBorderCtrl project’s virtual policeman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption source&quot;&gt;Image: iBorderCtrl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;211&quot; readability=&quot;43.556195965418&quot;&gt;The virtual policeman is the product of a project called iBorderCtrl, which involves security agencies in Hungary, Latvia, and Greece. Currently, the lie detector test is voluntary, and the pilot scheme is due to end in August. If it is a success, however, it may be rolled out in other European Union countries, a potential development that has attracted controversy and media coverage across the continent.
&lt;p&gt;IBorderCtrl’s lie detection system was developed in England by researchers at Manchester Metropolitan University, who say that the technology can pick up on “micro gestures” a person makes while answering questions on their computer, analyzing their facial expressions, gaze, and posture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An EU research program has pumped some 4.5 million euros into the project, which is being managed by a consortium of 13 partners, including Greece’s Center for Security Studies, Germany’s Leibniz University Hannover, and technology and security companies like Hungary’s BioSec, Spain’s Everis, and Poland’s JAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers at Manchester Metropolitan University believe that the system could represent the future of border security. In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/6215340-Intelligent-Deception-Detection-Through-Machine.html&quot;&gt;academic paper&lt;/a&gt; published in June 2018, they stated that avatars like their virtual policeman “will be suitable for detecting deception in border crossing interviews, as they are effective extractors of information from humans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Newsletter-shortcode Newsletter-shortcode-layout-full&quot; data-reactid=&quot;212&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Newsletter-shortcode-container&quot; data-reactid=&quot;214&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;Newsletter-shortcode-headline&quot; data-reactid=&quot;215&quot;&gt;Join Our Newsletter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;Newsletter-shortcode-subhead&quot; data-reactid=&quot;216&quot;&gt;Original reporting. Fearless journalism. Delivered to you.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Newsletter-shortcode-link-cta&quot; data-reactid=&quot;218&quot;&gt;I’m in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;221&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, some academics are questioning the value of the system, which they say relies on pseudoscience to make its decisions about travelers’ honesty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ray Bull, professor of criminal investigation at the University of Derby, has assisted British police with interview techniques and specializes in methods of detecting deception. He told The Intercept that the iBorderCtrl project was “not credible” because there is no evidence that monitoring microgestures on people’s faces is an accurate way to measure lying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They are deceiving themselves into thinking it will ever be substantially effective and they are wasting a lot of money,” said Bull. “The technology is based on a fundamental misunderstanding of what humans do when being truthful and deceptive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, following the refugee crisis and a spate of terrorist attacks in France, Belgium, Spain, and Germany, police and security agencies in Europe have come under increasing political pressure to more effectively track the movements of migrants. Border security officials on the continent say they are trying to find faster and more efficient new ways, using artificial intelligence, to check the travel documents and biometrics of the more than 700 million people who annually enter the EU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;Pullquote Pullquote--right&quot; data-reactid=&quot;222&quot; readability=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They are wasting a lot of money.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div data-reactid=&quot;224&quot; readability=&quot;70.475224476222&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Commission — the EU’s executive branch — has set aside a &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_IP-18-4106_en.htm&quot;&gt;proposed €34.9 billion&lt;/a&gt; for border control and migration management between 2021 and 2027. Meanwhile, in September last year, European lawmakers agreed to establish a new automated system that will screen nationals from visa-free third countries — including the United States — to establish whether or not they should be allowed to enter the EU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, a visa-free traveler who, for whatever reason, has not been able to submit an application in advance will not be granted entry into the Schengen zone, an area covering 26 countries in Europe where travelers can move freely across borders without any passport checks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBorderCtrl is one technology designed to strengthen the prescreening process. But transparency activists say that the project should not be rolled out until more information is made available about the technology — such as the algorithms it uses to make its decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, researchers at the Milan-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hermescenter.org/&quot;&gt;Hermes Center for Transparency and Digital Human Rights&lt;/a&gt; used freedom of information laws to obtain &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/public/search/projectid:41912-iBorderCtrl&quot;&gt;internal documents&lt;/a&gt; about the system. They received hundreds of pages; however, they were heavily redacted, with many pages completely blacked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The attempt to suppress debate by withholding the documents that address these issues is really frightening,” said Riccardo Coluccini, a researcher at the Hermes Center. “It is absolutely necessary to understand the reasoning behind the funding process. What is written in those documents? How does the consortium justify the use of such a pseudoscientific technology?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A study produced by the researchers in Manchester tested iBorderCtrl on 32 people and said that their results showed the system had 75 percent accuracy. The researchers noted, however, that their participant group was unbalanced in terms of ethnicity and gender, as there were fewer Asian or Arabic participants than white Europeans, and fewer women than men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giovanni Buttarelli, head of the EU’s data protection watchdog, told The Intercept that he was concerned that the iBorderCtrl system might discriminate against people on the basis of their ethnic origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are we only evaluating possible lies about identity or we are also trying to analyze some of the person’s somatic traits, the edges of the face, the color of the skin, the cut of the eyes?” Buttarelli said. “Who sets the parameters to establish that a certain subject is lying or not lying?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for iBorderCtrl declined to answer questions for this story. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iborderctrl.eu/Frequently-Asked-Questions&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; for the project acknowledges that the lie detection system will “have an impact on the fundamental rights of travellers” but says that, because the test is currently voluntary, “issues with respect to discrimination, human dignity, etc. therefore cannot occur.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The reporting for this story was supported by the Investigative Journalism for Europe grant and the Otto Brenner Foundation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 19:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>rchaudhary</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://theintercept.com/2019/07/26/europe-border-control-ai-lie-detector/</og:url>
<og:description>4.5 million euros have been pumped into the virtual policeman project meant to judge the honesty of travelers. An expert calls the technology “not credible.”</og:description>
<og:image>https://theintercept.imgix.net/wp-uploads/sites/1/2019/07/lie-illustration-01-1564006566.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;q=90&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1200&amp;h=800</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>We Tested Europe’s New Lie Detector for Travelers — and Immediately Triggered a False Positive</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://theintercept.com/2019/07/26/europe-border-control-ai-lie-detector/</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>