<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="css/feed.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#">
<channel>
<atom:link rel="self" href="http://192.168.1.4/fivefilters/makefulltextfeed.php?url=hnrss.org%2Fnewest%3Fpoints%3D200&amp;max=10&amp;links=preserve&amp;exc=" />
<atom:link rel="alternate" title="Source URL" href="http://hnrss.org/newest?points=200" />
<atom:link rel="related" title="Subscribe to feed" href="http://www.subtome.com/#/subscribe?feeds=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D&amp;back=http%3A%2F%2F192.168.1.4%2Ffivefilters%2Fmakefulltextfeed.php%3Furl%3Dhnrss.org%252Fnewest%253Fpoints%253D200%26max%3D10%26links%3Dpreserve%26exc%3D" />
<title>Hacker News: Newest</title>
<link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newest</link>
<description>Hacker News RSS</description>
<item>
<title>The dots do matter: how to scam a Gmail user</title>
<link>https://jameshfisher.com/2018/04/07/the-dots-do-matter-how-to-scam-a-gmail-user</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://jameshfisher.com/2018/04/07/the-dots-do-matter-how-to-scam-a-gmail-user</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;I recently received an email from Netflix which nearly caused caused me to add my card details to someone else’s Netflix account. Here I show that this is a new kind of phishing scam which is enabled by an obscure feature of Gmail called “the dots don’t matter”. I then argue that the dots &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; matter, and that this Gmail feature is in fact a misfeature. Finally I’ll suggest some ways the Gmail team can combat such scams in future. But first, I’ll show you the email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/518b13acc741c4dbb2565050913c93da4be9e65d/5ca90/assets/2018-04-07/email.png&quot; alt=&quot;email from Netflix&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Odd,” I thought, “but OK, I’ll check.” The email is genuinely from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;netflix.com&lt;/code&gt;, so I clicked through to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/simplemember/editcredit?locale=en-GB&quot;&gt;an “Update your credit or debit card” page&lt;/a&gt;, which is genuinely hosted on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;netflix.com&lt;/code&gt;. No phishing here. But hang on, the “Update” page showed my declined card as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**** 2745&lt;/code&gt;. A card number I don’t recognize. Checking my records, I’ve never seen this card number. What’s going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally realized that this email is to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;james.hfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;. I normally use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jameshfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;, with no dots. You might think this email should have bounced, but instead it reached my inbox, because &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/mail/answer/7436150?hl=en&quot;&gt;“dots don’t matter in Gmail addresses”&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone accidentally adds dots to your address when emailing you, you’ll still get that email. For example, if your email is johnsmith@gmail.com, you own all dotted versions of your address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;john.smith@gmail.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jo.hn.sm.ith@gmail.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;j.o.h.n.s.m.i.t.h@gmail.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix does not know about this Gmail “feature”. Externally, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jameshfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;james.hfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; are different identities, and should have their own Netflix accounts. I signed up for Netflix account &lt;em&gt;N1&lt;/em&gt; backed by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jameshfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; in 2013. But in September 2017, someone, let’s call her “Eve”, created a new Netflix account &lt;em&gt;N2&lt;/em&gt;, backed by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;james.hfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eve has access to account &lt;em&gt;N2&lt;/em&gt; because she set its password when signing up, but I also have access to the account because I own &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;james.hfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;, and so I can follow the password reset process for this account. I did so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eve loves her TV! She’s watched 587 titles in six months, all from her “Android Device” in Alabama. She watched three seasons of &lt;em&gt;Trailer Park Boys&lt;/em&gt; over a single day in October. She consumed nearly every day until 22nd March, when Netflix put her account “on hold” due to payment failure. Eve had paid for these shows. She paid $13.99 every month for her Premium plan, until February when her card &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**** 2745&lt;/code&gt; (also billed to Huntsville, Alabama) was declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this was all a mistake? Perhaps Eve is actually &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitepages.com/name/James-Fisher/Huntsville-AL&quot;&gt;one of the twelve James Fishers in Huntsville, AL&lt;/a&gt;, and perhaps he typed his email address in wrong when he signed up months ago. Netflix doesn’t do any email address verification when you sign up; you can start watching shows straight away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps this was not a mistake but a &lt;em&gt;scam&lt;/em&gt;. I was almost fooled into perpetually paying for Eve’s Netflix access, and only paused because I didn’t recognize the declined card. More generally, the phishing scam here is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hammer the Netflix signup form until you find a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; address which is “already registered”. Let’s say you find the victim &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jameshfisher&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a Netflix account with address &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;james.hfisher&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign up for free trial with &lt;a href=&quot;https://getfinal.com/&quot;&gt;a throwaway card number&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After Netflix applies the “active card check”, cancel the card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait for Netflix to bill the cancelled card. Then Netflix emails &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;james.hfisher&lt;/code&gt; asking for a valid card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hope Jim reads the email to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;james.hfisher&lt;/code&gt;, assumes it’s for his Netflix account backed by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jameshfisher&lt;/code&gt;, then enters his card &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**** 1234&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the email for the Netflix account to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;eve@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;, kicking Jim’s access to this account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Netflix free forever with Jim’s card &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**** 1234&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where is the security flaw here? Some would say it’s Netflix’s fault; that Netflix should verify the email address on sign up. But using someone else’s address on signup only cedes control of the account to that person. Others would say that Netflix should disallow the registration of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;james.hfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;, but this would force Netflix and every other website to have insider knowledge of Gmail’s canonicalization algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, the blame lies with Gmail, and specifically Gmail’s “dots don’t matter” feature. The scam fundamentally relies on the Gmail user responding to an email with the assumption that it was sent to their canonical address, and not to some other address from their infinite address set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Gmail power users might claim: “The dots-don’t-matter feature is great. I get ownership of an infinite set of email addresses!” But firstly, no one &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt; this infinite set of email addresses. Those who &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want infinite addresses already have the “plus labelling” feature: I also own &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jameshfisher+spam@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jameshfisher+work@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; et cetera. Plus labelling is a similar feature, but with similar scam potential, although with some legitimate use cases. But I have certainly never wanted &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;j.ame.s.h.fis.h.e.r@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;, and John Smith never wanted &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jo.hn.sm.ith@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;. I have never asked someone for her email address only for her to reply, “it’s &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jane.doe@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;, but feel free to add the dot wherever you like.” Each Gmail user has &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; email address that they think of as theirs; all the others are mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do Gmail users not want these extra addresses, most are not even aware that they &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; these addresses. I’m sure my parents are unaware that they own an infinite set of email addresses. They won’t know this, because Google have never told them, and this is not how email works anywhere else. Even the most technically minded Gmail power user refers to “my email address”, not to “my infinite set of email addresses”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even those Gmail users who are aware of their infinite set of addresses are probably unaware of the scams that this exposes them to. We teach people about “phishing” due to emails &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; dodgy email addresses, but we don’t teach people anything about phishing due to emails &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; dodgy addresses. Nevertheless, the result is the same: the victim loses money to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even in the rare case that a Gmail user is aware of their infinite set of addresses, and they’re aware of the phishing attacks that this can expose them to, this user is unlikely to pick up on it, because the user interfaces of Gmail and Inbox don’t hint anything about a possible scam. In fact it barely even acknowledges that the email was to a non-standard address. The only clue in the screenshot above is that the interface says “to james.hfisher”, instead of “to me”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gmail team should combat this kind of phishing. They should officially acknowledge that dots-don’t-matter is a misfeature. Indeed, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gmail.googleblog.com/2008/03/2-hidden-ways-to-get-more-from-your.html&quot;&gt;the Gmail team admitted that dots-don’t-matter is “confusing” way back when they &lt;em&gt;announced&lt;/em&gt; the feature in 2008&lt;/a&gt;). Each Google account should have &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; variant configured as its standard address; I would set &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jameshfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; as standard, and maybe John would set &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;john.smith@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; as standard. If an email is sent to a non-standard address, it should be shown with a warning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/127e924431a9d2568d03cd7bfb28dc59274e385e/88b62/assets/2018-04-07/better.png&quot; alt=&quot;how to show phishing&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Gmail users should be able to opt out of dots-don’t-matter. I wish for any mail sent to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;james.hfisher@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; to bounce instead of reaching my inbox. The dots-don’t-matter feature should be disabled by default for any new Google accounts, and eventually retired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/follow?screen_name=MrJamesFisher&amp;amp;original_referer=https://jameshfisher.com/2018/04/07/the-dots-do-matter-how-to-scam-a-gmail-user.html&quot;&gt;Get updates on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote this because people need to know. This post is not associated with my employer.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 18:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>jamesfisher</dc:creator>
<og:title>The dots do matter: how to scam a Gmail user</og:title>
<og:type>website</og:type>
<og:image>https://jameshfisher.com/assets/jim_512.jpg</og:image>
<og:url>https://jameshfisher.com/2018/04/07/the-dots-do-matter-how-to-scam-a-gmail-user.html</og:url>
<og:description>I recently received an email from Netflix which nearly caused caused me to add my card details to someone else’s Netflix account. Here I show that this is a new kind of phishing scam which is enabled by an obscure feature of Gmail called “the dots don’t matter”. I then argue that the dots do matter, and that this Gmail feature is in fact a misfeature. Finally I’ll suggest some ways the Gmail team can combat such scams in future. But first, I’ll show you the email:</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://jameshfisher.com/2018/04/07/the-dots-do-matter-how-to-scam-a-gmail-user</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Richest 1% on target to own two-thirds of all wealth by 2030</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2018/apr/07/global-inequality-tipping-point-2030</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theguardian.com/business/2018/apr/07/global-inequality-tipping-point-2030</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;The world’s richest 1% are on course to control as much as two-thirds of the world’s wealth by 2030, according to a shocking analysis that has lead to a cross-party call for action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World leaders are being warned that the continued accumulation of wealth at the top will fuel growing distrust and anger over the coming decade unless action is taken to restore the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alarming projection produced by the House of Commons library suggests that if trends seen since the 2008 financial crash were to continue, then the top 1% will hold 64% of the world’s wealth by 2030. Even taking the financial crash into account, and measuring their assets over a longer period, they would still hold more than half of all wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2008, the wealth of the richest 1% has been growing at an average of 6% a year – much faster than the 3% growth in wealth of the remaining 99% of the world’s population. Should that continue, the top 1% would hold wealth equating to $305tn (£216.5tn) – up from $140tn today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysts suggest wealth has become concentrated at the top because of recent income inequality, higher rates of saving among the wealthy, and the accumulation of assets. The wealthy also invested a large amount of equity in businesses, stocks and other financial assets, which have handed them disproportionate benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New polling by Opinium suggests that voters perceive a major problem with the influence exerted by the very wealthy. Asked to select a group that would have the most power in 2030, most (34%) said the super-rich, while 28% opted for national governments. In a sign of falling levels of trust, those surveyed said they feared the consequences of wealth inequality would be rising levels of corruption (41%) or the “super-rich enjoying unfair influence on government policy” (43%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research was commissioned by Liam Byrne, the former Labour cabinet minister, as part of a gathering of MPs, academics, business leaders, trade unions and civil society leaders focused on addressing the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;u-responsive-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;gu-image&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; alt=&quot;Actor Michael Sheen, who is campaigning against high-interest lenders, supports the calls to rebalance global inequality.&quot; src=&quot;https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/9516096d76c9660f2c446e59cdc4a02231d9ff2a/1863_123_2415_3019/master/2415.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;q=55&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;usm=12&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;s=fcd26c0c0078a786ef64ff4f9f44d93d&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

Actor Michael Sheen, who is campaigning against high-interest lenders, supports the calls to rebalance global inequality. Photograph: Teri Pengilley for the Guardian
&lt;p&gt;The actor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/culture/michael-sheen&quot; data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;Michael Sheen&lt;/a&gt;, who has opted to scale back his Hollywood career to campaign against high-interest credit providers, was among those supporting the calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hope is to create pressure for global action when leaders of the G20 group of nations gather for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.g20.org/en/calendar&quot; title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot;&gt;summit in Buenos Aires in November&lt;/a&gt;. Byrne, who organised the first OECD global parliamentary conference on inclusive growth, said he believed global inequality was “now at a tipping point”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If we don’t take steps to rewrite the rules of how our economies work, then we condemn ourselves to a future that remains unequal for good,” he said. “That’s morally bad, and economically disastrous, risking a new explosion in instability, corruption and poverty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a sign of the concern about the accumulation of wealth in the hands of so few, the move has gained support from across the political divide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George Freeman, the Tory MP and former head of the prime minister’s policy board, said: “While mankind has never seen such income inequality, it is also true that mankind has never experienced such rapid increases in living standards. Around the world billions of people are being lifted out of poverty at a pace never seen before. But the extraordinary concentration of global wealth today – fuelled by the pace of technological innovation and globalisation – poses serious challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If the system of capitalist liberal democracy which has triumphed in the west is to pass the big test of globalisation – and the assault from radical Islam as well as its own internal pressures from post-crash austerity – we need some new thinking on ways to widen opportunity, share ownership and philanthropy. Fast.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demands for action from the group include improving productivity to ensure wages rise and reform of capital markets to promote greater equality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danny Dorling, professor of geography at the University of Oxford, said the scenario in which the super-rich accumulated even more wealth by 2030 was a realistic one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Even if the income of the wealthiest people in the world stops rising dramatically in the future, their wealth will still grow for some time,” he said. “The last peak of income inequality was in 1913. We are near that again, but even if we reduce inequality now it will continue to grow for one to two more decades.”&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 17:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>eplanit</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://www.theguardian.com/business/2018/apr/07/global-inequality-tipping-point-2030</og:url>
<og:description>World leaders urged to act as anger over inequality reaches a ‘tipping point’</og:description>
<og:image>https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/0ea892ad58eb3941f9c3f6fe4bf1775f76a42b0b/0_69_2200_1320/master/2200.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=630&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;fit=crop&amp;crop=faces%2Centropy&amp;bm=normal&amp;ba=bottom%2Cleft&amp;blend64=aHR0cHM6Ly91cGxvYWRzLmd1aW0uY28udWsvMjAxOC8wMS8zMS9mYWNlYm9va19kZWZhdWx0LnBuZw&amp;s=09543e40ea3a7b6e2b783eb13cf34f77</og:image>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Richest 1% on target to own two-thirds of all wealth by 2030</og:title>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2018/apr/07/global-inequality-tipping-point-2030</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>TextQL: Execute SQL Against CSV or TSV</title>
<link>https://github.com/dinedal/textql</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://github.com/dinedal/textql</guid>
<description>&lt;h3&gt;Readme.md&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;article class=&quot;markdown-body entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/dinedal/textql&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/971b67bb627a24dc6e3715bb10da30144de3fb47/68747470733a2f2f7472617669732d63692e6f72672f64696e6564616c2f74657874716c2e737667&quot; alt=&quot;Build Status&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/dinedal/textql.svg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://goreportcard.com/report/dinedal/textql&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/1ab1e88ac38e933ba3758d44db863a4ca4f15c28/687474703a2f2f676f7265706f7274636172642e636f6d2f62616467652f64696e6564616c2f74657874716c&quot; alt=&quot;Go Report Card&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;http://goreportcard.com/badge/dinedal/textql&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allows you to easily execute SQL against structured text like CSV or TSV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example session:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/43ca79fc6307d1f80c543bd68a4979a74919013c/68747470733a2f2f7261772e6769746875622e636f6d2f64696e6564616c2f74657874716c2f6d61737465722f74657874716c5f75736167652e676966&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/43ca79fc6307d1f80c543bd68a4979a74919013c/68747470733a2f2f7261772e6769746875622e636f6d2f64696e6564616c2f74657874716c2f6d61737465722f74657874716c5f75736167652e676966&quot; alt=&quot;textql_usage_session&quot; data-canonical-src=&quot;https://raw.github.com/dinedal/textql/master/textql_usage.gif&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Major changes!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there has been some time since the initial release of textql, I've made some improvements as well as made the project much more modular. There's also been a additional performance tweaks and added functionality, but this comes at the cost of breaking the original command line flags and changing the install command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changes since v1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Numeric values are automatically recognized in more cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date / Time / DateTime values are automatically recognized in reasonable formats. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqlite.org/lang_datefunc.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Time Strings&lt;/a&gt; for a list for accepted formats, and how to convert from other formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added join support! Multiple files / directories can be loaded by listing them at the end of the command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directories are read by reading each file inside, and this is non-recursive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can list as many files / directories as you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added flag '-output-file' to save output directly to a file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added flag '-output-dlm' to modify the output delimiter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &quot;short SQL&quot; syntax.
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For the case of a single table, the &lt;code&gt;FROM [table]&lt;/code&gt; can be dropped from the query.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For simple selects, the &lt;code&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt; keyword can be dropped from the query.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This means the v1 command &lt;code&gt;textql -sql &quot;select * from tbl&quot; -source some_file.csv&lt;/code&gt; can be shortened to &lt;code&gt;textql -sql &quot;*&quot; some_file.csv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The flag '-outputHeader' was renamed to '-output-header'.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Removals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dropped the ability to override table names. This makes less sense after the automatic tablename generation based on filename, joins, and shorter SQL syntax changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed '-source', any files / paths at the end of the command are used, as well as piped in data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bug fixes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Writing to a directory no longer fails silently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key differences between textql and sqlite importing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;sqlite import will not accept stdin, breaking unix pipes. textql will happily do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;textql supports quote escaped delimiters, sqlite does not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;textql leverages the sqlite in memory database feature as much as possible and only touches disk if asked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Is it any good?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3067434&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go 1.4 or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latest release on Homebrew (OS X)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
brew install textql
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build from source&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
go get -u github.com/dinedal/textql/...
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight highlight-source-shell&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  textql [-console] [-save-to path path] [-output-file path] [-output-dlm delimter] [-output-header] [-pretty] [-quiet] [-header] [-dlm delimter] [-sql sql_statements] [path ...]

  -console
        After all statements are run, open SQLite3 REPL with this data
  -dlm string
        Input delimiter character between fields -dlm=tab &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;tab, -dlm=0x## to specify a character code&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; hex (default &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
  -header
        Treat input files as having the first row as a header row
  -output-dlm string
        Output delimiter character between fields -output-dlm=tab &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-smi&quot;&gt;tab, -dlm=0x## to specify a character code&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; hex (default &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
  -output-file file
        Filename to write output to, &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; empty no output is written (default &lt;span class=&quot;pl-s&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;stdout&lt;span class=&quot;pl-pds&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)
  -output-header
        Display column names &lt;span class=&quot;pl-k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; output
  -quiet
        Surpress logging
  -pretty
        Pretty print output
  -save-to file
        SQLite3 db is left on disk at this file
  -sql string
        SQL Statement(s) to run on the data
  -version
        Print version and &lt;span class=&quot;pl-c1&quot;&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New MIT License - Copyright (c) 2015, 2016 Paul Bergeron &lt;a href=&quot;http://pauldbergeron.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://pauldbergeron.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See LICENSE for details&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 15:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>TAForObvReasons</dc:creator>
<og:image>https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/606028?s=400&amp;v=4</og:image>
<og:type>object</og:type>
<og:title>dinedal/textql</og:title>
<og:url>https://github.com/dinedal/textql</og:url>
<og:description>textql - Execute SQL against structured text like CSV or TSV</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://github.com/dinedal/textql</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>I miss Windows Phone</title>
<link>https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/7/17206174/microsoft-windows-phone-influence-editorial</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/7/17206174/microsoft-windows-phone-influence-editorial</guid>
<description>&lt;p id=&quot;t0qhmh&quot;&gt;I first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2014/12/11/7377021/ive-given-up-on-windows-phone&quot;&gt;gave up on Windows Phone&lt;/a&gt; back in December 2014. Microsoft’s mobile platform was being left behind, and I was tired of not getting access to the apps everyone else was using. It took Microsoft a few years to finally admit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/9/16446280/microsoft-finally-admits-windows-phone-is-dead&quot;&gt;Windows Phone is dead&lt;/a&gt;, and the company is no longer planning to release any new hardware running its mobile OS or update it with any features. I recently switched on an old Windows Phone to create a silly &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/980388677682679808&quot;&gt;April Fools’ joke&lt;/a&gt; about returning to using it as my daily device, and then it hit me: I really miss Windows Phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;mXX8UC&quot;&gt;Windows Phone debuted in 2010 with Microsoft’s Metro design philosophy, and a focus on glancing at your phone for information instead of digging in and out of apps. Two obvious features I miss from Windows Phone’s Metro design are the dark mode and Live Tiles. Android and iOS still don’t have system-wide dark modes, nearly 8 years after Windows Phone first introduced it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/23/17045944/android-phone-dark-mode-update-promised&quot;&gt;Google recently shut down the dream&lt;/a&gt; of that happening outside of the Pixel 2. I use my iPhone a lot in bed, and the white interface still feels like it’s lighting up the room even with Night Shift enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;a7CexJ&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y_zPYlhUSgk?rel=0&amp;amp;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;ZVyPRj&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Live Tiles were one of Windows Phone’s best features&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;YjXQ4A&quot;&gt;Live Tiles were one of Windows Phone’s most unique features. They enabled apps to show information on the home screen, similar to the widgets found on Android and iOS. You could almost pin anything useful to the home screen, and Live Tiles animated beautifully to flip over and provide tiny nuggets of information that made your phone feel far more personal and alive. I’m hopeful that Apple will eventually take the Live Tiles concept, or even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2014/5/30/5761732/this-striking-ios-8-concept-reinvents-the-homescreen&quot;&gt;one that was designed for iOS 8&lt;/a&gt;, and bring it to the iPhone. Widgets just aren’t enough. Rumors suggest Apple is planning to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/30/16949802/apple-ios-12-next-version-update-focus-reliability-performance-new-features&quot;&gt;refresh the iOS home screen soon&lt;/a&gt;, so there’s hope that iOS might move away from its static and dull home screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;WVpCIi&quot;&gt;Outside of the design features, there was plenty more that showed how Microsoft was truly innovative with Windows Phone. The software keyboard is still far better than the defaults on iOS and Android, and Microsoft even added a tracing option that let you swipe to write words like many Android keyboards do now. The Windows Phone keyboard always felt accurate, at a time when Apple was struggling with its iOS autocorrect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;5nLkGo&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u5n7vdUaQsg?rel=0&amp;amp;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;ikOTr2&quot;&gt;Microsoft also experimented with features that were different to other mobile platforms, and some of the concepts still haven’t really made their way to iOS or Android:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id=&quot;4GeWeh&quot;&gt;Kid’s Corner – this let parents share a separate account on their device with restricted apps and games for kids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;KvsKMU&quot;&gt;Dedicated search button – you could search anywhere (with Bing, hmm) in the OS, regardless of the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;xNvGQo&quot;&gt;Browser address bar – Microsoft placed its browser address bar at the bottom of the screen, making it easier to use your thumbs to navigate around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;ori1Oc&quot;&gt;People hub – Microsoft’s hub concepts meant the contacts on Windows Phone could pull photos and information from social networks straight into your address book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;S6UhEU&quot;&gt;Unified messaging – Microsoft’s messages hub let Windows Phone users chat via SMS or messaging apps like Skype in a single thread without needing to juggle separate apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/10599717/windowsphone7.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-dynamic-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAUEBAAAACwAAAAAAQABAAACAkQBADs&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-chorus-optimize-field=&quot;main_image&quot; data-cid=&quot;site/dynamic_size_image-1523169828_8951_109740&quot; data-cdata=&quot;{&amp;quot;asset_id&amp;quot;:10599717,&amp;quot;ratio&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;*&amp;quot;}&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/10599717/windowsphone7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;IpEcEG&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Windows Phone pushed Apple and Google to do better&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;J1vMWj&quot;&gt;One of the big reasons I still miss Windows Phone is because it pushed both Apple and Google to do better. Back when it launched, Microsoft had a good shot at creating a third mobile platform and unnerved the competition. Google refused to build Windows Phone apps, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2013/8/16/4627342/microsoft-google-battle-over-youtube-windows-phone&quot;&gt;public feud over a YouTube app&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2013/1/4/3836510/windows-phone-8-users-unable-to-access-google-maps/in/3603277&quot;&gt;blocking of services&lt;/a&gt; on Windows Phone devices made it clear Google would do anything to stop Windows Phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;UoeF5G&quot;&gt;Windows Phone has arguably changed Android and iOS, though. Microsoft aggressively pursued modern design principles at the time to launch Windows Phone with its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2013/6/8/4408756/microsoft-metro-design-concepts-windows-mobile-windows-phone&quot;&gt;Metro design&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2013/6/10/4407630/apple-announces-ios-7&quot;&gt;Apple responded with iOS 7&lt;/a&gt; and a flatter user interface. Google went one step further, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2014/6/25/5841044/material-design-new-google-interface-2014&quot;&gt;its Material Design&lt;/a&gt; that included bright colors, playful transitions, and a much flatter and simplified interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;6bCpDC&quot;&gt;Beyond design, Windows Phone also had some fundamental principles and features that can now be found on both iOS and Android. Windows Phone focused on deep data sharing between apps, to prevent you from having to switch in and out of apps. That’s something Apple now handles through iOS App Extensions, and Android has always had its Intents system. Both have been improved to the point that Microsoft’s Windows Phone contracts vision for app data sharing has been realized beyond its own platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;7SF4U0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0-U4Yr9UNBo?rel=0&amp;amp;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;[embedded content]&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;7hMLcD&quot;&gt;Microsoft also pushed the camera features of Windows Phone heavily, even forcing phone makers to include a dedicated camera button to take photos from the lock screen far more quickly. Both iOS and Android caught up with quick camera launch features, but at the time Windows Phone was ahead. Microsoft even added a controversial &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2014/4/14/5611992/windows-phone-8-1-review&quot;&gt;Wi-Fi Sense feature&lt;/a&gt; to Windows Phone that let you share Wi-Fi passwords to your contacts. The software maker &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2016/5/11/11655628/microsoft-windows-10-wi-fi-sense-password-sharing&quot;&gt;scrapped it in Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;, but Apple introduced an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/7/15757692/apple-ios-11-wifi-sharing-update-router-password&quot;&gt;identical feature in iOS 11 recently&lt;/a&gt;. Apple also added Live Photos to iOS 9, which is similar to an animated photo feature that was available on Nokia’s Lumia Windows Phone devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;JzrFTk&quot;&gt;There are probably many more examples of Windows Phone’s influence on Android and iOS, but now that it’s dead the competition has disappeared. Google recently launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/5/16736260/google-android-oreo-go-edition&quot;&gt;its Android Oreo Go edition&lt;/a&gt; for low-end phones, and it’s designed to make Android run better on phones with 512MB or 1GB of RAM. Windows Phone always worked well on a variety of hardware, but Microsoft &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2012/5/29/3049882/windows-phone-tango-everything-you-need-to-know&quot;&gt;launched low-cost devices in an identical push&lt;/a&gt; with just 256MB of RAM five years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__inner&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;e-image__image&quot; data-original=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3674654/continuumphonesinline.0.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;c-dynamic-image&quot; src=&quot;data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAUEBAAAACwAAAAAAQABAAACAkQBADs&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-chorus-optimize-field=&quot;main_image&quot; data-cid=&quot;site/dynamic_size_image-1523169828_7464_109741&quot; data-cdata=&quot;{&amp;quot;asset_id&amp;quot;:3674654,&amp;quot;ratio&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;*&amp;quot;}&quot;/&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3674654/continuumphonesinline.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;e-image__meta&quot;&gt;Windows 10 Mobile’s Continuum feature&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;c-float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;aside id=&quot;SUVG4K&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Windows Phone is dead, but I still miss it&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;MFdq2Z&quot;&gt;Samsung has also started creating its own version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/24/14696730/hp-elite-x3-lapdock-windows-mobile-continuum-review&quot;&gt;Windows Phone’s Continuum concept&lt;/a&gt;, that turns a phone into a PC. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/30/15120312/samsung-dex-microsoft-continuum-pc-phone-battle&quot;&gt;Samsung’s system is actually superior to Continuum&lt;/a&gt; in a number of ways and includes windowing and popular mobile apps. Ironically, it’s looking like Continuum could play heavily in Microsoft’s potential return to a mobile device form factor. Microsoft is now focusing on software &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/12/17108958/microsoft-windows-future-c-shell-andromeda-polaris&quot;&gt;modes like Continuum for clever new hardware&lt;/a&gt; projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;pNvzjf&quot;&gt;Windows Phone has no future, it’s over. Microsoft will continue supporting it, but with no new flagship hardware and no OS updates, it’s a forgotten and dead platform. Microsoft has been widely rumored to be working on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/15/16780124/microsoft-surface-notepad-foldable-tablet-hinge-rumors&quot;&gt;secret Surface notepad device with foldable dual displays&lt;/a&gt;. Patents have shown off hardware that looks very similar to Microsoft’s Courier concept of a digital notepad, and this could be the long-rumored “Surface Phone.” Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella has also previously promised that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/3/15528690/microsoft-surface-satya-nadella-phones-business-surface-hints&quot;&gt;Microsoft’s future “phones” won’t look like phones at all&lt;/a&gt;, and this type of device fits in with that message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&quot;4ODjLr&quot;&gt;The patents also show Microsoft’s mystery Surface device, codenamed “Andromeda,” adapts to become more than a notepad or a tablet, and into a laptop-like form factor. Microsoft might have one final stab at mobile with a device like this, but it won’t be the same as Windows Phone. Microsoft generated some genuine excitement around its platform with some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2013/4/29/4281894/new-windows-phone-ad-samsung-vs-apple-wedding-fight&quot;&gt;witty marketing&lt;/a&gt;, unique features, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2012/9/5/3293146/nokia-lumia-920-hands-on-photos-video&quot;&gt;forward-looking hardware&lt;/a&gt;. It just wasn’t enough, despite &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2013/8/8/4537802/windows-phone-third-party-unofficial-apps&quot;&gt;developers trying to save Microsoft’s mobile efforts&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll still miss it, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 13:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ducki</dc:creator>
<og:description>Microsoft’s mobile OS had great features</og:description>
<og:image>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YNLMzcqF8ijs5FR4EkeXcA98QNk=/0x55:759x452/fit-in/1200x630/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/10599925/windowsphoneold.jpg</og:image>
<og:title>I miss Windows Phone</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/7/17206174/microsoft-windows-phone-influence-editorial</og:url>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/7/17206174/microsoft-windows-phone-influence-editorial</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mailinator launches Disposable SMS</title>
<link>http://mailinator.blogspot.com/2018/04/mailinator-launches-disposable-sms.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://mailinator.blogspot.com/2018/04/mailinator-launches-disposable-sms.html</guid>
<description>Mailinator is known for fast, free, (public) disposable email. Today we're introducing fast, free (public) disposable SMS! The idea fits in with Mailinator's model extremely well. For example, Mailinator has always created an inbox when email arrives for it. Because of that every single email address you can think of (at mailinator.com) already exists. That includes every existing or potential phone number on earth. Inboxes say like 12016768877@mailinator.com have existed since Mailinator was born.&lt;p&gt;Now however, that inbox receives email sent to that address but also SMS text messages sent to that phone number. As always messages (now categorized as email or SMS) auto-delete in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find the Public SMS numbers on the left navigation of Mailinator's &quot;email&quot; page (which we should probably think about renaming, huh?) or follow the link below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mailinator.com/v2/inbox.jsp?zone=public&amp;amp;query=12016768877&quot;&gt;https://www.mailinator.com/v2/inbox.jsp?zone=public&amp;amp;query=12016768877&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hope our free users and our QA Testing subscribers find cool new uses for testing with SMS!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 11:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>zinxq</dc:creator>
<og:url>http://mailinator.blogspot.com/2018/04/mailinator-launches-disposable-sms.html</og:url>
<og:title>Mailinator launches disposable SMS</og:title>
<og:description>Mailinator is known for fast, free, (public) disposable email. Today we're introducing fast, free (public) disposable SMS! The idea fits in ...</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://mailinator.blogspot.com/2018/04/mailinator-launches-disposable-sms.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Backpage.com seized by U.S. justice authorities</title>
<link>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-backpage-justice/sex-marketplace-backpage-com-seized-by-u-s-justice-authorities-posting-idUSKCN1HD2QP</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-backpage-justice/sex-marketplace-backpage-com-seized-by-u-s-justice-authorities-posting-idUSKCN1HD2QP</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON (Reuters) - U.S. law enforcement agencies have seized the sex marketplace website Backpage.com as part of an enforcement action by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, according to a posting on the Backpage website on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container_2pnvl&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container_1tVQo&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container_1Z7A0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;amp;d=20180407&amp;amp;t=2&amp;amp;i=1248879570&amp;amp;r=LYNXNPEE351PC&amp;amp;w=20&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;caption_KoNH1&quot;&gt;An image of the current home page of the website backpage.com shows logos of U.S. law enforcement agencies after they seized the sex marketplace site April 6, 2018. backpage.com via REUTERS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groups and political leaders working to end forced prostitution and child exploitation celebrated the shutdown of Backpage, a massive ad marketplace that is primarily used to sell sex. But some internet and free speech advocates warned the action could lead to harsh federal limits on expression and the press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website posting said U.S. attorneys in Arizona and California, as well as the Justice Department’s section on child exploitation and obscenity and the California and Texas attorneys general had helped shut down the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department said late on Friday that a court in Arizona ruled the case remains sealed, which puts any legal information under wraps. In the posting about the seizure, the department had originally said more information would be made public on Friday evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Phoenix FBI official said that there was “law enforcement activity” at the Sedona, Arizona home of Michael Lacey, one of the founders of Backpage, but referred further inquiries to the Justice Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reuters was unable to reach representatives of Backpage for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Today, Backpage was shutdown. It’s a huge step. Now no child will be sold for sex through this website,” tweeted Senator Heidi Heitkamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heitkamp helped draft legislation passed by the Senate last month that makes it easier for state prosecutors and sex-trafficking victims to sue social media networks, advertisers and others that fail to keep sex trafficking and exploitative materials off their platforms..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump will sign the bill into law next week, said Heitkamp. The legislation, featured prominently in the popular Netflix documentary “I am Jane Doe,” amends the Communications Decency Act, which has shielded website operators from state criminal charges or civil liability if they facilitate sex ads or prostitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Shutting down the largest online U.S. marketplace for sex trafficking will dramatically reduce the profitability of forcing people into the commercial sex trade, at least in the short term,” said Bradley Myles, chief executive of Polaris, an international anti-slavery group that runs the National Human Trafficking Hotline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be “a dramatic shift in the marketplace starting tonight,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backpage and advocacy groups say the ads are free speech protected by the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backpage has affiliates across the country and around the world, and by 2014 brought in annual revenue of $135 million, the New York Times has reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court in January 2017 refused to consider reviving a lawsuit against Backpage that was filed by three young women, who accused it of facilitating their forced prostitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Center for Missing and Exploited Children has told Congress that nearly three quarters of the cases submitted to the center relate to ads posted on the site. The state of California has said that 90 percent of the site’s income were attributable to “adult ads.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Texas and California authorities raided the company’s Dallas headquarters and arrested chief executive Carl Ferrer and other former company executives on pimping-related charges. The judge in the case ruled the website was protected by the First Amendment, and it was not liable for the speech of third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container_28wm1&quot; readability=&quot;7.5&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;attribution_o4ojT&quot; readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;content_27_rw&quot;&gt;Reporting by Sarah Lynch and Lisa Lambert, Additional reporting by David Schwartz in Phoenix and Justin Mitchell in Washington, Editing by Toni Reinhold and Rosalba O'Brien&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 20:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>mzs</dc:creator>
<og:title>Sex ads website Backpage shut down by U.S. authorities</og:title>
<og:url>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-backpage-justice/sex-marketplace-backpage-com-seized-by-u-s-justice-authorities-posting-idUSKCN1HD2QP</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:description>U.S. law enforcement agencies have seized the sex marketplace website Backpage.com as part of an enforcement action by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, according to a posting on the Backpage website on Friday.</og:description>
<og:image>https://s2.reutersmedia.net/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20180407&amp;t=2&amp;i=1248879570&amp;w=1200&amp;r=LYNXNPEE351PC</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-backpage-justice/sex-marketplace-backpage-com-seized-by-u-s-justice-authorities-posting-idUSKCN1HD2QP</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>FCC approves SpaceX plan for satellite broadband network</title>
<link>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/29/fcc-approves-spacex-plan-for-4425-satellite-broadband-network/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/29/fcc-approves-spacex-plan-for-4425-satellite-broadband-network/</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;crunchbase-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/space-exploration-technologies/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-type=&quot;organization&quot; data-entity=&quot;space-exploration-technologies&quot;&gt;SpaceX&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-authorizes-spacex-provide-broadband-satellite-services&quot;&gt;a green light from the FCC&lt;/a&gt; to launch a network of thousands of satellites blanketing the globe with broadband. And you won’t have too long to wait — on a cosmic scale, anyway. Part of the agreement is that SpaceX launch half of its proposed satellites within six years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approval of SpaceX’s application was not seriously in doubt after &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/14/fcc-looks-to-approve-spacexs-satellite-internet-plan/&quot;&gt;last month’s memo&lt;/a&gt; from FCC Chairman Ajit Pai, who was excited at the prospect of the first U.S.-based company being authorized to launch a constellation like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have asked my colleagues to join me in supporting this application and moving to unleash the power of satellite constellations to provide high-speed Internet to rural Americans,” he wrote at the time. He really is pushing that “digital divide” thing. Not that Elon Musk disagrees:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed breakout&quot; readability=&quot;7.7189189189189&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; readability=&quot;9.0810810810811&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Today’s Falcon launch carries 2 SpaceX test satellites for global broadband. If successful, Starlink constellation will serve least served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/966298034978959361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SpaceX COO Gwynne Shotwell echoed the sentiment in a statement provided to TechCrunch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appreciate the FCC’s thorough review and approval of SpaceX’s constellation license. Although we still have much to do with this complex undertaking, this is an important step toward SpaceX building a next-generation satellite network that can link the globe with reliable and affordable broadband service, especially reaching those who are not yet connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed service, which will be called &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/20/spacex-might-name-its-satellite-broadband-internet-service-starlink/&quot;&gt;Starlink&lt;/a&gt;, was opposed by several existing satellite operators like OneWeb and Spire. They’re rightly concerned that another operator in space — especially one that wants to launch thousands of satellites — will crowd both spectrum and orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1598515&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;breakout size-full wp-image-1598515&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/spacex_sat.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1001&quot; height=&quot;611&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Illustration of SpaceX satellite coverage from the FCC application&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OneWeb, for example, said that SpaceX satellites shouldn’t be allowed to be deployed within 125 kilometers of altitude of its own. You do want to avoid interference, but really, it’s too much to ask for a 150-mile buffer zone around your gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One objection that did carry water, however, was the request for an extensive orbital debris mitigation plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unprecedented number of satellites proposed by SpaceX and the other [non-geostationary orbit fixed-satellite service] systems in this processing round will necessitate a further assessment of the appropriate reliability standards of these spacecraft, as well as the reliability of these systems’ methods for deorbiting the spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So SpaceX will have to provide more studies on this by the time it finalizes its designs and starts launching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that will have to be fairly soon. To move things along, the FCC requires SpaceX to get underway in a hurry or else, presumably, it will have to be reauthorized:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote readability=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SpaceX must launch 50 percent of the maximum number of proposed space stations, place them in the assigned orbits, and operate them in accordance with the station authorization no later than March 29, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/22/spacex-successfully-launches-falcon-9-carrying-starlink-demo-satellites/&quot;&gt;already launched&lt;/a&gt; test versions of the satellites, but the full constellation will need to go out more than two at a time. SpaceX eventually plans to launch 12,000 of the things, but this authorization is for the high-altitude group of 4,425; a separate authorization is necessary for the remaining number, since they’ll be operating at a different altitude and radio frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1601300&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; readability=&quot;32&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1601300&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/falcon-9-paz.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height=&quot;382&quot;/&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;The Falcon 9 carrying SpaceX’s test Starlink satellites launches on February 22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commissioner Rosenworcel, in a separate statement, also called for a general revisiting of regulations around commercial space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This rush to develop new space opportunities requires new rules,” she writes. “Despite the revolutionary activity in our atmosphere, the regulatory frameworks we rely on to shape these efforts are dated. Across the board, we need to prepare for the proliferation of satellites in our higher altitudes. In short, we have work to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 20:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>vinnyglennon</dc:creator>
<og:title>FCC approves SpaceX plan for 4,425-satellite broadband network</og:title>
<og:description>SpaceX has a green light from the FCC to launch a network of thousands of satellites blanketing the globe with broadband. And you won't have too long to wait — on a cosmic scale, anyway. Part of the agreement is that SpaceX launch half of its proposed 4,425 satellites within six years.</og:description>
<og:image>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/spacex-falcon-heavy-11.jpg?w=600</og:image>
<og:url>http://social.techcrunch.com/2018/03/29/fcc-approves-spacex-plan-for-4425-satellite-broadband-network/</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<dc:language>en-US</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/29/fcc-approves-spacex-plan-for-4425-satellite-broadband-network/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Immutable.rs: immutable data structures for Rust</title>
<link>http://immutable.rs</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >http://immutable.rs</guid>
<description>&lt;p&gt;This library implements several of the more commonly useful immutable data structures for Rust. They rely on structural sharing to keep most operations fast without needing to mutate the underlying data store, leading to more predictable code without necessarily sacrificing performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Rust is not a garbage collected language, and immutable data structures generally rely on some sort of garbage collection, values inside these data structures are kept inside &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/sync/struct.Arc.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Arc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s. Methods will generally accept either owned values or &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/sync/struct.Arc.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Arc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s and perform conversion as needed, but you'll have to expect to receive &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/sync/struct.Arc.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Arc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s when iterating or performing lookup operations. All caveats about using reference counted values apply in general (eg. reference counting is simplistic and doesn't detect loops).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A design goal of this library is to make using immutable data structures as easy as it is in higher level languages, but obviously there's only so much you can do. Methods will generally attempt to coerce argument values where they can: where an &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/sync/struct.Arc.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Arc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is called for, it will be able to figure out how to convert whatever is provided into an &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/sync/struct.Arc.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Arc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; if it isn't already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also been a design goal to provide as complete an API as possible, which in a practical sense has meant going over the equivalent implementations for Haskell to ensure the API covers the same set of use cases. This obviously doesn't include things like &lt;code&gt;Foldable&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Functor&lt;/code&gt; which aren't yet expressible in Rust, but in these cases we've tried to make sure Rust iterators are able to perform the same tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Care has been taken to use method names similar to those in Rust over those used in the source material (largely Haskell) where possible (eg. &lt;code&gt;Vector::new()&lt;/code&gt; rather than &lt;code&gt;Vector::empty()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;HashMap::get()&lt;/code&gt; rather than &lt;code&gt;HashMap::lookup()&lt;/code&gt;). Where Rust equivalents don't exist, terminology tends to follow Haskell where the Haskell isn't too confusing, or, when it is, we provide more readily understandable aliases (because we wouldn't want to deprive the user of their enjoyment of the word '&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/conlist/struct.ConsList.html#method.snoc&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;snoc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,' even though it's reportedly not an obviously intuitive term).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming with immutable values, meaning that references to values can be relied on to always point to the same value, means that you can stop worrying about other parts of your code tampering with a value you're working on unexpectedly, or from unexpected parts of your code, making it a lot easier to keep track of what your code is actually doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutable values are, generally, a huge source of unexpected behaviour that a lot of languages, like Haskell, Elm and Clojure, have been designed to avoid altogether. Rust, being what it is, does a good job of discouraging this kind of behaviour, and keeping it strictly controlled when it's necessary, but the standard library doesn't provide collection data structures which are optimised for immutable operations. This means, for instance, that if you want to add an item to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/vec/struct.Vec.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Vec&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; without modifying it in place, you first need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/clone/trait.Clone.html#tymethod.clone&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;clone&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the whole thing before making your change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data structures exist which are designed to be able to make these copies much cheaper, usually by sharing structure between them, which, because this structure is also immutable, is both cheap and safe. The most basic example of this kind of data structure is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/conslist/struct.ConsList.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ConsList&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where, if you have a list &lt;em&gt;L&lt;/em&gt; and you want to push an item &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; to the front of it, you'll get back a new list which literally contains the data &lt;em&gt;'item I followed by list L.'&lt;/em&gt; This operation is extremely inexpensive, but of course this also means that certain other operations which would be inexpensive for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/vec/struct.Vec.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Vec&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are much more costly for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/conslist/struct.ConsList.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ConsList&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—index lookup is an example of this, where for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/vec/struct.Vec.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Vec&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; it's just a matter of going to memory location &lt;em&gt;index times item size&lt;/em&gt; inside the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/vec/struct.Vec.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Vec&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;'s memory buffer, but for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/conslist/struct.ConsList.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ConsList&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; you'd have to walk through the entire list from the start, following references through to other list nodes, until you get to the right item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While all immutable data structures tend to be less efficient than their mutable counterparts, when chosen carefully they can perform just as well for the operations you need, and there are some, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/vector/struct.Vector.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Vector&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/hashmap/struct.HashMap.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HashMap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which have performance characteristics good enough for most operations that you can safely choose them without worrying too much about whether they're going to be the right choice for any given use case. Better yet, most of them can even be safely mutated in place when they aren't sharing any structure with other instances, making them nearly as performant as their mutable counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'll attempt to provide a comprehensive guide to the available data structures below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're not familiar with big O notation, here's a quick cheat sheet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;O(1)&lt;/em&gt; means an operation runs in constant time: it will take the same time to complete regardless of the size of the data structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;O(n)&lt;/em&gt; means an operation runs in linear time: if you double the size of your data structure, the operation will take twice as long to complete; if you quadruple the size, it will take four times as long, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;O(log n)&lt;/em&gt; means an operation runs in logarithmic time: for &lt;em&gt;log&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, if you double the size of your data structure, the operation will take one step longer to complete; if you quadruple the size, it will need two steps more; and so on. However, the data structures in this library generally run in &lt;em&gt;log&lt;sub&gt;16&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; time, meaning you have to make your data structure 16 times bigger to need one extra step, and 256 times bigger to need two steps. This means that, while they still count as O(log n), operations on all but really large data sets will run at near enough to O(1) that you won't usually notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;O(1)&lt;/em&gt;* means 'amortised O(1),' which means that an operation usually runs in constant time but will occasionally be more expensive, often O(n). Please note that this is not a common notation; it's just a convention I've used in these docs to save myself from having to type 'amortised' everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lists are ordered sequences of single elements, usually with cheap push/pop operations, and index lookup tends to be O(n). Lists are for collections of items where you expect to iterate rather than lookup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Constraints&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Order&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Push Front&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Pop Front&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Push Back&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Pop Back&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Append&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Lookup&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/vector/struct.Vector.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Vector&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;insertion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/catlist/struct.CatList.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CatList&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;insertion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(1)*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(1)*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/conslist/struct.ConsList.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ConsList&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td/&gt;
&lt;td&gt;insertion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maps are mappings of keys to values, where the most common read operation is to find the value associated with a given key. Maps may or may not have a defined order. Any given key can only occur once inside a map, and setting a key to a different value will overwrite the previous value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sets are collections of unique values, and may or may not have a defined order. Their crucial property is that any given value can only exist once in a given set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Values in sets, in practice, behave exactly like keys in maps, and are therefore normally implemented as maps from type &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; to type &lt;code&gt;()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Constraints&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Order&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Insert&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Remove&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Lookup&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/hashset/struct.HashSet.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;HashSet&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/hash/trait.Hash.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/cmp/trait.Eq.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Eq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;undefined&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/ordset/struct.OrdSet.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;OrdSet&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/cmp/trait.Ord.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ord&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;sorted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;O(log n)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of these data structures support in-place copy-on-write mutation, which means that if you're the sole user of a data structure, you can update it in place with a huge performance benefit (about an order of magnitude faster than immutable operations, almost as fast as &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/collections/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;std::collections&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;'s mutable data structures).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/sync/struct.Arc.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Arc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;'s reference counting, we are able to determine whether a node in a data structure is being shared with other data structures, or whether it's safe to mutate it in place. When it's shared, we'll automatically make a copy of the node before modifying it, thus preserving the usual guarantees you get from using an immutable data structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 18:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>tosh</dc:creator>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://docs.rs/im/10.0.0/im/</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Want to Be Happy? Think Like an Old Person</title>
<link>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/29/nyregion/want-to-be-happy-think-like-an-old-person.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/29/nyregion/want-to-be-happy-think-like-an-old-person.html</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/31/nyregion/31oldest-slide-96DV/31oldest-slide-96DV-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/31/nyregion/31oldest-slide-96DV/31oldest-slide-96DV-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;Jonas Mekas, pictured at a gallery in Bushwick and at home in Clinton Hill, still has several books and films to complete. After that, he said, &amp;#x201C;I&amp;#x2019;d like to travel.&amp;#x201D;&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/31/nyregion/31oldest-slide-96DV/31oldest-slide-96DV-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Jonas Mekas, pictured at a gallery in Bushwick and at home in Clinton Hill, still has several books and films to complete. After that, he said, “I’d like to travel.”&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;visually-hidden&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/31/nyregion/31oldest-slide-14FZ/31oldest-slide-14FZ-master675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;media-viewer-candidate&quot; data-mediaviewer-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/31/nyregion/31oldest-slide-14FZ/31oldest-slide-14FZ-superJumbo.jpg&quot; data-mediaviewer-caption=&quot;&quot; data-mediaviewer-credit=&quot;&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; itemid=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/31/nyregion/31oldest-slide-14FZ/31oldest-slide-14FZ-master675.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;137&quot; data-total-count=&quot;11817&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-15&quot;&gt;Francesco Ragazzi had a theory about Jonas Mekas. “In a way,” he said one morning in October, “everybody now can be Jonas Mekas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-6&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/29/nyregion/want-to-be-happy-think-like-an-old-person.html#story-continues-16&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;296&quot; data-total-count=&quot;12113&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-16&quot;&gt;Mr. Ragazzi, 33, an art curator from Milan, was in town to assemble an &lt;a href=&quot;http://e-ven.net/en/&quot;&gt;exhibition&lt;/a&gt; of Mr. Mekas’s work at a fashion boutique on Madison Avenue, and he was noting the resemblance between the diary-based films Mr. Mekas started making in the 1970s and the social media that followed decades later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;249&quot; data-total-count=&quot;12362&quot;&gt;“But,” he said, “there is only one Jonas Mekas still. So I think we need to ask ourselves why. Because I think if everybody will be Jonas Mekas one day, the world will be saved. We need to keep going in this direction, becoming Jonas Mekas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;216&quot; data-total-count=&quot;12578&quot;&gt;Mr. Mekas this year made progress toward a goal that has driven him since the start of the series: raising money to expand Anthology Film Archives, the nonprofit organization and theater he helped start in the 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;281&quot; data-total-count=&quot;12859&quot;&gt;On March 2, a crowd that included Greta Gerwig, Jim Jarmusch, John Waters and others bid nearly $2 million at an art auction to benefit the archives. Performing onstage, Patti Smith altered the lyrics to her biggest hit to “Because the night belongs to JONAS,” to big applause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;255&quot; data-total-count=&quot;13114&quot;&gt;For Mr. Mekas it was a year of reckoning: how much money the organization still needs to raise ($6 million); how far was too far to travel at age 95 (Seoul, where he did not attend an exhibition of his work); and how to make ends meet in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;172&quot; data-total-count=&quot;13286&quot;&gt;This last was a trickier matter. He could no longer afford the rent on his Brooklyn loft, he said. “I have to move to a cheaper place,” probably within a year, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;237&quot; data-total-count=&quot;13523&quot;&gt;But Mr. Mekas put the disruption in perspective. His life has been nomadic since the 1940s, including years in Nazi labor camps and United Nations camps for displaced persons. Moving to a smaller place somewhere in Brooklyn was a hiccup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;story-ad-7&quot; class=&quot;story-ad ad ad-placeholder nocontent robots-nocontent&quot;&gt;

&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/29/nyregion/want-to-be-happy-think-like-an-old-person.html#story-continues-17&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;170&quot; data-total-count=&quot;13693&quot; id=&quot;story-continues-17&quot;&gt;“It’s a necessity and it’s realistic and I need to do it and you do it,” he said. “It’s nothing. This is just another stop, and there will be another stop.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;360&quot; data-total-count=&quot;14053&quot;&gt;Mr. Mekas also published a book of anecdotes and autobiographical images this year, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://anthology.net/book/dance-fred-astaire/&quot;&gt;A Dance With Fred Astaire&lt;/a&gt;,” named for a Yoko Ono and John Lennon &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Imagine_(1972_film)&quot;&gt;movie&lt;/a&gt; in which Mr. Mekas and Mr. Astaire both make dancing cameos. Another five or six books were almost ready, and a couple of films still needed finishing. After that, he said, “I’d like to travel.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;329&quot; data-total-count=&quot;14382&quot;&gt;For now, he said, “I’m thinking about resistance. What does it mean, resistance? What kind of resistance do we need today? Technology is now being used, much of it, for negative purposes. So to resist all what is happening negatively in humanity or technology is to develop the — O.K., this banal word, spiritual aspect.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;343&quot; data-total-count=&quot;14725&quot;&gt;He remained sanguine, despite some reservations about current world leaders. Totalitarianism, in his experience, did not endure, whereas art, nature and the teachings of the saints all were as powerful as ever — they were what composed his life. He did not use the word optimistic, but he felt that solutions were more durable than problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;330&quot; data-total-count=&quot;15055&quot;&gt;“To go back and introduce into all the schools art, to cut down on sports but bring arts, philosophy back into all educational systems,” he said. “And that’s what’s being cut everywhere. And I think that’s one of the sad and tragic parts of where we are. Education is the resistance to everything that is bad today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;310&quot; data-total-count=&quot;15365&quot;&gt;So ends another year for four members of New York’s oldest old: not with a whimper, but with small joys to ease their aches. Each lost a little and moved a year closer to death, as we all did. But each welcomed another morning, the start of another year to come. All had beaten the odds just to get this far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text story-content&quot; data-para-count=&quot;74&quot; data-total-count=&quot;15439&quot;&gt;As Ms. Willig said, “You think we’ll make another year, you and me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;addenda&quot; class=&quot;addenda&quot; readability=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;story-addendum story-content theme-correction&quot; readability=&quot;34&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: December 31, 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;An earlier version of this article misspelled the surname of Helen Moses’ daughter. She is Zoe Gussoff, not Gusoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;visually-hidden skip-to-text-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/29/nyregion/want-to-be-happy-think-like-an-old-person.html#whats-next&quot;&gt;Continue reading the main story&lt;/a&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 18:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>seventyhorses</dc:creator>
<og:url>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/29/nyregion/want-to-be-happy-think-like-an-old-person.html</og:url>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:title>Want to Be Happy? Think Like an Old Person</og:title>
<og:description>In a series update, we catch up with a group of New Yorkers over age 90: warm, cranky, funny and three years older than when we first met them.</og:description>
<og:image>https://static01.nyt.com/images/2017/12/31/nyregion/31oldest-TOP/31oldest-TOP-facebookJumbo.jpg</og:image>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/29/nyregion/want-to-be-happy-think-like-an-old-person.html</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Google seeks to limit ‘right to be forgotten’ by claiming it’s journalistic</title>
<link>https://www.cjr.org/innovations/google-journalistic-right-to-be-forgotten-by-claiming-its-journalistic.php</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true" >https://www.cjr.org/innovations/google-journalistic-right-to-be-forgotten-by-claiming-its-journalistic.php</guid>
<description>&lt;span class=&quot;caption-top hidden-print&quot;&gt;Photo by Anna Dziubinska on Unsplash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the first “right to be forgotten”&lt;/strong&gt; case to reach England’s High Court, two men are fighting to keep their past crimes out of Google’s search results, and the tech giant is fighting back by claiming it’s “journalistic.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The case, which is actually two nearly identical cases, involves two businessmen who were both convicted of white-collar crimes in the ’90s, and requested that Google delist several URLs referencing their convictions, including news articles. When Google denied their requests, they sued under a 2014 European Union ruling which established the right of individuals to have information delisted from search indexes under certain conditions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In its defense, Google has argued that it should be protected under an exception for journalism because it provides access to journalistic content. Even as a legal sleight of hand, the argument is quite a departure from Google’s customary efforts to present itself as a disinterested arbiter of information, a position that has become more untenable with time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Gareth Corfield, a reporter for The Register who covered the cases from the courtroom, said it’s disingenuous of Google to put on the mantle of journalism only when it suits them. “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;They’ve gone through great lengths to say they don’t make any editorial judgement in processing results,” Corfield said, but&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;it now wants you to believe it is on a par with journalism.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As the first case to test the “right to be forgotten” in England’s High Court, its outcome will likely set some ground rules in the roiling debate between personal privacy and freedom of expression on the internet. Google’s sudden identification with journalism may be a legal gambit, but it could have far-reaching effects across the landscape of data protection laws.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RELATED: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/tow_center/qa-usc-annenbergs-mike-ananny-on-facebooks-fact-checkers-and-the-problem-with-a-marketplace-of-ideas.php&quot;&gt;Mike Ananny on Facebook, facts, and the problem with ‘a marketplace of ideas’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot; class=&quot;hidden-print&quot;&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;form-title-embed&quot;&gt;Sign up for &lt;span class=&quot;cjr-bold&quot;&gt;CJR&lt;/span&gt;'s &lt;nobr&gt;daily email&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The journalism argument&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The core of the London case is a classic clash of rights. The claimants, called NT1 and NT2 to protect their identities, argue that since their crimes are decades old, they should be able to move on from their past. The URLs they are requesting to delist include news articles in national publications, an excerpt of a book, and interviews given by NT2 to news outlets. Google counters that the information is in the public interest, and still relevant given that the nature of the claimants’ business has not changed dramatically in the ensuing years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Whether Google is motivated to protect the public interest or simply to expand its discretion, it has been given the power to do so.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In 2014, Europe’s top court ruled that a right to be forgotten existed under the EU’s Data Protection Directive, instituted in 1995. The court ordered Google to give Europeans the option of requesting to remove search results for their own names, if the information is “inadequate, irrelevant or excessive in relation to the purposes of the processing.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The ruling placed Google at the port-of-call between privacy and the public interest. Guidelines provided by the court direct the search engine to balance these rights when making a decision whether or not to delist, with primacy given to privacy except where it is overridden by a “preponderant interest of the general public.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So unless a requester sues, the decision is entirely up to Google’s discretion. The tech giant&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1H4MKNwf5MgeztG7OnJRnl3ym3gIT3HUK/view&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;reported&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;that it rejects more than half of the requests it receives, but did not provide insight as to why.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In this case, Google is defending its initial decision not to delist the URLs in question, suggesting that the court trust its discretion. But another piece of its defense makes a broader claim. Google says that it should be protected under the journalism exemption in the Data Protection Act from 1998, the UK version of the EU directive of 1995. The exemption allows any data processed for the “special purpose of journalism” to be exempt from data protection rules.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This argument directly challenges the EU court’s decision. In that case, the EU made a distinction between search engines and the third-party sites they link to. While the court can’t compel a news outlet like the BBC to remove content because it was published for journalistic purposes, it can compel Google to restrict access to it, because the search engine doesn’t enjoy the same protections.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Google is arguing that in some cases it should. In Google’s words, a broad definition of journalism could include the work of a search engine because “[t]he process of making search  results available is for the purpose of enabling users to access third party publishers’ content which discloses information, opinions, and ideas,” according to the documents filed with the court. Therefore, Google argues, “in appropriate cases” it can rely on the journalism exemption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;pullquote-2015&quot;&gt;In Google’s words, a broad definition of journalism could include the work of a search engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;England’s Information Commissioner dismissed Google’s argument and said that journalism presupposes a process that includes human editorial decision-making, something that Google’s very algorithmic service does not do. The commissioner warned that if the court sided with Google, it would completely defang the original ruling. “In effect,” she wrote, Google&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;“would be able to operate the right to be forgotten regime almost entirely free from regulatory oversight and control.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Google had previously argued for the journalism exemption in a case in Northern Ireland, involving the removal of 12 search results regarding a man’s sexual crimes. The judgment clarified that, according to Google, “to ask the question as to whether a search engine is journalism is to ask the wrong question.” The right question is “whether the material is journalistic material.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In other words, Google is making the case that where they provide access to journalistic content, they are a part of that journalistic process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rehabilitation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The case highlights one of the primary uses of the right to be forgotten, and a key area that the right hoped to solve: How to deal with a person’s criminal or legal history when the past lives forever in the digital sphere.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Twenty percent of requests to Google are from people seeking to erase their legal history, according to Google’s report, and that number increases to 35 percent for URL takedown requests to news sites in particular. The guidelines provided by the EU include the gravity and recency of the crimes as factors to be considered in determining whether or not to delist a link.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The UK has an explicit mandate, the Offenders Rehabilitation Act,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;and a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;robust legal tradition to support the rehabilitation of offenders. The act, which restricts what can be published about a person’s past crimes after a certain amount of time elapses, hasn’t aged well. When it passed in 1974, no one dreamed that one day you could pull up a 20-year-old article with a Google search. But it’s not yet a mandate for the digital sphere, or part of legislation like RTBF.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Meg Leta Jones, the author of the 2016 book&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ctrl+Z: The Right to be Forgotten&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;, says a decision that applies the rehabilitation act to digital intermediaries could open the floodgates. “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;To extend that out into a general search would be a really interesting and powerful move,” Jones said, because it would expand the act’s power beyond its initial intent.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;“Yo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;u could do that for a lot of legal issues. You could say, ‘Okay we’re going to extend this out into other platforms, we’re going to extend this out into social media.’”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In a meta application of this issue, t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;he court placed a reporting restriction order on the trial, with firm restrictions as to what news outlets can and cannot say about the claimants, including their names, their occupations, and the exact nature of their past crimes. If that information were shared, it would defeat the entire purpose of the case.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Corfield says the order is a draconian one by the standards of the court, and a gamble to boot. “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;If the decision goes against either of these two claimants, then everything they tried to keep under wraps is going to be shouted from the rooftops, so it’s a pretty high stakes game for them,” Corfield said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And a high-stakes game overall. “One of the major problems of [the] right to be forgotten is the privatizing of decisions which really ought to be made by public bodies or the courts,” says George Brock, a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Professor of Journalism at City University London, and the author of the 2016 book,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Right to be Forgotten&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Given the breadth of  the right to be forgotten decision, says Brock, “t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;here is a lot of scope for taking out of circulation that which should still be there for the public interest.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A spokesperson for Google says in a statement that, “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;We take great care not to remove search results that are clearly in the public interest and will defend the public’s right to access lawful information.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we go from here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The two cases have concluded in court, and judgment is expected in the coming weeks. It comes at a moment of intense debate over data protection, and as Europe gears up for an expected overhaul to their data protection regime.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In May, the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/tow_center_reports/understanding-general-data-protection-regulation.php&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;will go into enforcement in the EU, replacing the 1995 directive on which the right to be forgotten legislation is based. The UK is expected to update its own data protection rules later this year and, like the GDPR, includes language on the right to be forgotten (rechristened the “right to erasure”). After Brexit, there will be further changes to the application of the various legal schemas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With so much about the data protection regulations up in the air, a judgment on the right to be forgotten will likely serve as a foothold for future debate on the subject. If Google were to benefit from the journalism exemption, it could be seen as a win for public interest purists who would like to see less information delisted, but it would also muddy the waters by giving the already all-powerful Google a tool designed to protect the more vulnerable work of a free press.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICYMI:&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/business_of_news/metoo-fox-news.php&quot;&gt; Women who speak out about sexual harassment are often blacklisted by other news organizations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;post-survey-box&quot; class=&quot;hidden-print&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Has America ever needed a media watchdog more than now? Help us by &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssl.palmcoastd.com/18801/apps/MEMBER1?ikey=5**M02&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;joining CJR today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;small class=&quot;bio-overline&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chava Gourarie is a freelance writer based in New York and a former CJR Delacorte Fellow. Follow her on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ChavaRisa&quot;&gt;@ChavaRisa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 18:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>danso</dc:creator>
<og:title>Google seeks to limit ‘right to be forgotten’ by claiming it’s journalistic</og:title>
<og:type>article</og:type>
<og:url>https://www.cjr.org/innovations/google-journalistic-right-to-be-forgotten-by-claiming-its-journalistic.php</og:url>
<og:image>https://cdn.cjr.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/anna-dziubinska-348-unsplash-800x419.jpg</og:image>
<og:description>&lt;p&gt;In the first “right to be forgotten” case to reach England’s High Court, two men are fighting to keep their past crimes out of Google’s search results, and the tech giant is fighting back by claiming it’s “journalistic.” The case, which is actually two nearly identical cases, involves two businessmen who were both convicted of […]&lt;/p&gt;</og:description>
<dc:language>en</dc:language>
<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>https://www.cjr.org/innovations/google-journalistic-right-to-be-forgotten-by-claiming-its-journalistic.php</dc:identifier>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>